<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:43:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Twitter blocking all political ads globally starting in November</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594105</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Twitter's doing what Facebook remains committed not to.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1155294611-800x533.jpg" alt="A Twitter logo displayed on a smartphone."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1155294611.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3333" data-width="5000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A Twitter logo displayed on a smartphone. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/in-this-photo-illustration-a-twitter-logo-seen-displayed-on-news-photo/1155294611">Rafael Henrique | SOPA Images/LightRocket | Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Twitter might be the president's favored platform and a valued way for candidates to spread their messages far and wide, but starting next month, elected officials and candidates alike are going to have to make sure all that traffic comes organically. That's because they won't be allowed to pay for political advertising.</p>
<p>Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey has apparently taken a look at the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/no-you-apparently-cant-run-for-office-just-to-put-false-ads-on-facebook/">controversy</a> currently embroiling Facebook and decided he wants no part of it.</p>
<p>"We've made the decision to stop all political advertising on Twitter globally," Dorsey announced in, naturally, <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1189634377057067008">a tweet</a>. </p>
<p>He framed the choice as an opportunity for anyone with a message, rather than a penalty, adding, "A political message earns reach when people decide to follow an account or retweet. Paying for reach removes that decision, forcing highly optimized and targeted political messages on people. We believe this decision should not be compromised by money."</p>
<p>The ban applies not only to candidates and their campaigns but also to "issue ads" by any group, Dorsey continued, since those "present a way to circumvent" the ban on political advertising and would present a situation where "everyone but candidates" could pay to have their view on an issue promoted. He also added an apparent dig at Facebook:</p>
<blockquote><p>For instance, it's not credible for us to say: "We're working hard to stop people from gaming our systems to spread misleading info, buuut if someone pays us to target and force people to see their political ad... well...they can say whatever they want! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />"</p></blockquote>
<p>"This isn't about free expression," Dorsey went on. "This is about paying for reach. And paying to increase the reach of political speech has significant ramifications that today's democratic infrastructure may not be prepared to handle. It's worth stepping back in order to address."</p>
<h2>Direct challenge</h2>
<p>The stance comes in direct opposition to social media leader Facebook, which explicitly exempts both <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/facebook-confirms-its-standards-dont-apply-to-politicians/">posts</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/political-ads-can-lie-if-they-want-facebook-confirms/">advertisements</a> made by politicians from its community standards and fact-checking process. </p>
<p>Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg has repeatedly doubled down on his company's position amid a firestorm of criticism from lawmakers, political candidates, and even <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/facebooks-new-political-ad-policy-already-showing-cracks-loopholes/">employees</a>. In a congressional hearing last week, Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-N.Y.) directly challenged Zuckerberg on the company's policy.</p>
<p>"Do you see a potential problem here with the complete lack of fact-checking on political advertisements?" Ocasio-Cortez asked.</p>
<p>"Well, congresswoman, I think lying is bad," Zuckerberg replied. "I think if you're gonna lie, that would be bad." But that would be different from preventing people from "seeing that you had lied," he tried to explain.</p>
<p>"So you will take down lies, or you won't take down lies? I think this is a pretty simple yes or no," she pressed.</p>
<p>"In a democracy, I believe that people should be able to see for themselves what politicians that they may or may not vote down are saying," he answered. Any actions Facebook might take "depends on the context" in which a dishonest piece of content is posted, he added.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594105&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple releases macOS Catalina 10.15.1 and watchOS 6.1</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593945</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macOS Catalina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macOS Catalina 10.15.1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watchos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watchOS 6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watchOS 6.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593945</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Both follow closely after iOS, iPadOS, and tvOS updates yesterday.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/macOS-Catalina-Light-mode-800x570.jpg" alt="No operating system is an island, but macOS Catalina is named after one."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/macOS-Catalina-Light-mode.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1458" data-width="2048">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> No operating system is an island, but macOS Catalina is named after one. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.apple.com/">Apple</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Apple's habit of late has been to release most of its operating system updates for each platform all on the same day. But in one recent instance, though, macOS and watchOS came a single day after iOS, iPadOS, and tvOS updates.</p>
<p>The macOS update mainly adds features we already saw yesterday in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/everything-you-need-to-know-about-ios-and-ipados-13-2/">iOS and iPadOS 13.2</a>. That includes support for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/apple-announces-airpods-pro/">AirPods Pro</a>, the ability to opt in or out of sharing Siri recordings with Apple, new emoji, and new HomeKit feature support. There are also a number of macOS-specific bug fixes and the restoration of some lost Photos features.</p>
<p>Here are Apple's update notes for macOS Catalina 10.15.1:</p>
<blockquote><p>The macOS Catalina 10.15.1 update includes updated and additional emoji, support for AirPods Pro, HomeKit Secure Video, HomeKit enabled routers, and new Siri privacy settings, as well as bug fixes and improvements.</p>
<p><strong>Emoji</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Over 70 new or updated emoji, including animals, food, activities, new accessibility emoji, gender-neutral emoji, and skin tones selection for couple emoji</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>AirPods</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Introduces support for AirPods Pro</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Home app</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>HomeKit Secure Video enables you to privately capture, store, and view encrypted video from your security cameras and features people, animal, and vehicle detection</li>
<li>HomeKit-enabled routers let you control how your HomeKit accessories communicate over the Internet or in your home</li>
<li>Adds support for AirPlay 2-enabled speakers in scenes and automations</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Siri</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Privacy settings to control whether or not to help improve Siri and Dictation by allowing Apple to store audio of your Siri and Dictation interactions</li>
<li>Option to delete your Siri and Dictation history from Siri Settings</li>
</ul>
<p>This update also includes the following bug fixes and improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Restores the ability to view file names in the All Photos view in Photos</li>
<li>Restores the ability to filter by favorites, photos, videos, edited, and keywords in Days view in Photos</li>
<li>Fixes an issue where Messages would only send a single notification when the option to repeat alerts was enabled</li>
<li>Resolves an issue that caused Contacts to launch to the previously opened contact instead of the contact list</li>
<li>Adds a two-finger swipe gesture for back navigation in Apple News</li>
<li>Resolves issues that may occur in the Music app when displaying playlists inside folders and newly added songs in the Songs list</li>
<li>Improves reliability of migrating iTunes library databases into the Music, Podcasts, and TV apps</li>
<li>Fixes an issue where downloaded titles were not visible in the Downloads folder in the TV app</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>watchOS 6.1 is a very small update; its main purpose appears to be AirPods Pro support; users can now manage their active-noise-cancelation settings via the Watch for the new earphones. Additionally, Apple has brought watchOS 6 to the series 1 and series 2 Apple Watch devices as previously promised. (They were not supported by the first release of watchOS 6.)</p>
<p>Here are Apple's brief watchOS 6.1 update notes:</p>
<blockquote><p>watchOS 6.1 introduces support for ‌AirPods Pro‌ and includes improvements and bug fixes. This update also brings ‌watchOS 6‌ to ‌Apple Watch‌ Series 1 and Series 2.</p></blockquote>
<p>Additionally, Apple released a security update labeled watchOS 5.3.3 for Apple Watches not running watchOS 6. This is necessary even though watchOS 6 supports all Watch models now because watchOS 6 only works with iPhones that can run iOS 13, but some users are on older handsets.</p>
<p>Both updates should be available to all users today.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593945&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conscientiousness may matter less if you’re a lawyer than if you’re in sales</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593975</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathleen O'Grady]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behavioral science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personality traits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593975</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gigantic analysis pulls together conclusions from a century of research.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-925830614-800x533.jpg" alt="Image of wooden puzzle pieces"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-925830614.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1414" data-width="2121">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://photos.com/featured/close-up-of-hand-holding-wooden-toy-blocks-at-table-thanee-hengpattanapong--eyeem.html?product=art-print">Thanee Hengpattanapong / EyeEm</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Personality tests are two a penny, and most of them are no more meaningful than astrology (spoken like a true Capricorn). But there are ways to study personality empirically—they just involve accepting a lot of imperfection and fuzziness.</p>
<p>The "Big Five" personality traits do seem to get at something meaningful about human personality. They certainly don't capture everything, but Openness to Experience, Conscientiousness, Extraversion, Agreeableness, and Neuroticism are traits that can be measured with a high degree of stability from one test to the next. They change in predictable ways across people's lifespans and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2017/08/meta-analysis-shows-psychotherapy-leads-to-long-term-personality-change/">with therapy</a>, and they seem to be related in measurable ways to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2015/11/programmers-are-a-tiny-bit-introverted-but-otherwise-agreeable/">people's lives</a> outside the context of a personality test.</p>
<p>One of those traits—conscientiousness—is, unsurprisingly, strongly related to how people perform at work. But why, and in what settings? A paper published this week in PNAS used the data from more than 2,500 studies to summarize what we know about conscientiousness. Unexpectedly, the authors find that conscientiousness scores make less of a difference to people's performance when they're in high-complexity careers. Instead, they mainly seems to matter in low- or moderate-complexity jobs.</p>
<h2>More than just being neat</h2>
<p>Human personality is, obviously, an incredibly tricky thing to measure. People's personalities are somewhat stable from one week or month to the next, but how they're feeling on the day of the test will obviously change their answers to an extent. And the phenomenon of personality itself is obviously incredibly complex.</p>
<p>So a Big Five personality test doesn't try to carve people into distinct categories—either an extrovert or an introvert, agreeable or not. Instead, it places people on a sliding scale relative to other people on each of the five traits. You could be in the top 30% of extraverted people but still know people more extraverted than you.</p>
<p>Each trait breaks down into different facets that try to capture different components of it. The questions used to assess conscientiousness tap into a combination of someone's orderliness, cautiousness, self-discipline, dutifulness, achievement-striving, and a facet called "self-efficacy" (which is related to behaviors like finishing tasks properly). Together, these facets all get at slightly different angles of what it means to be "conscientious."</p>
<p>The Big Five traits offer a way of capturing people's personalities that is obviously imperfect, but  they still have a meaningful connection with how people behave in the real world. If you take a group of 1,000 people and test their conscientiousness and then their job performance, you'll find that higher conscientiousness and higher job performance go hand in hand. If you then randomly pull one very conscientious person out of the 1,000, there's a reasonably good chance (but no certainty!) that they'll do well at a job.</p>
<p>Measuring conscientiousness is obviously handy for employers trying to figure out who to employ. To cut through the variability inherent in individual studies, researchers Michael Wilmot and Deniz Ones threw together a huge amount of data from hundreds of studies to get a more precise estimate on how and why conscientiousness matters.</p>
<h2>Creatures of habit</h2>
<p>Wilmot and Ones went a step beyond using a meta-analysis and performed a meta-meta-analysis. They used 92 meta-analyses, which pulled data from more than 2,500 studies and more than a million participants. This should provide an unusually precise estimate of just how much conscientiousness matters.</p>
<p>Results from the huge dataset showed that conscientiousness was strongly related to positive work behaviors. For instance, people high in conscientiousness were good at setting goals and avoiding procrastination. They were less aggressive and less irresponsible than people with low conscientiousness.</p>
<p>But there were some results that won't sound quite so obvious. For instance, conscientiousness is related to conformity and security, so a "preference for more predictable environments" was a strong theme in the results, the researchers write.</p>
<p>Perhaps because of this, conscientiousness seemed to make more of a difference in some careers than others. In jobs that were high in complexity, it didn't make much of a difference at all. Meanwhile, in jobs that were moderate in complexity, like customer service and sales, conscientiousness made a much bigger difference.</p>
<p>The researchers suggest that high-complexity jobs, which require creative problem solving, aren't necessarily a great match for highly conscientious people who want structure and predictability in their work. But it might also be that complex jobs tend to attract conscientious people, and so everyone in those professions is already pretty high in conscientiousness, with less difference among them. Another possibility is that there are jobs where high conscientiousness is a minimum threshold for making it in and just one of a suite of traits that are necessary for doing well, says Marcus Credé, who researches conscientiousness but wasn't involved in the paper.</p>
<h2>Personality change</h2>
<p>The paper does a great job of pulling together a mountain of evidence on what researchers have suspected about conscientiousness, says Credé, but there are some caveats. The research itself isn't weak, but measuring people's personalities is just incredibly tricky. If you test someone's conscientiousness while they're filling in a job application, they're obviously going to presenting themselves in a certain way—so their answers will reflect not just their actual conscientiousness, but also their awareness of what an employer will be looking for.</p>
<p>Wilmot and Ones suggest that it would be a good idea to try improving conscientiousness in schoolkids. Credé, though, isn't so sure. Conscientiousness does tend to increase with age, but changing it intentionally is a different matter. "I'm not aware of any particularly successful intervention program," he says.</p>
<p>It's possible that some of the facets of conscientiousness could respond to training, he adds—safety training, for instance, could possibly increase people's cautiousness. But "getting someone to be more achievement-striving? It'd be lovely if you could! You could make a lot of money if you could figure that out."</p>
<p><em>You can take a Big Five test <a href="http://www.personal.psu.edu/~j5j/IPIP/ipipneo120.htm">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>PNAS, 2018. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1908430116">10.1073/pnas.1908430116</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593975&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No, you apparently can’t run for office just to put false ads on Facebook</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593859</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 19:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An attempt to call out Facebook's policy is working—just not on Facebook.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1151289735-800x501.jpg" alt="The Facebook app displayed on the screen of an iPhone."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1151289735.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2180" data-width="3481">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The Facebook app displayed on the screen of an iPhone. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/june-2019-baden-wuerttemberg-stuttgart-the-facebook-app-is-news-photo/1151289735">Fabian Sommer | picture alliance | Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Facebook about a month ago confirmed that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/facebook-confirms-its-standards-dont-apply-to-politicians/">politicians are exempt</a> from its speech policies and ad standards. That policy frees up holders of political jobs, and candidates seeking those jobs, to, basically, lie their entire faces off in Facebook ads if they choose to do so.</p>
<p>The Internet and the 21st century being what they are, of course, many people greeted this news with responses along the lines of: "Does that mean I can just sign up for any local race and then put any ads I want on Facebook?" One man decided to find out. And so far, at least, the answer seems to be: No. </p>
<p>Adriel Hampton lives in California and runs a digital marketing firm that promotes progressive causes. On Monday, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/10/28/tech/facebook-false-ads-california-governor/index.html">formally registered</a> as a candidate for the state's gubernatorial race, and his <a href="https://civichall.org/civicist/op-ed-its-time-to-challenge-techs-power-at-the-ballot-box/">stated platform</a> explicitly challenges both President Donald Trump and Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg.</p>
<p>His plan, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/10/28/tech/facebook-false-ads-california-governor/index.html">told CNN</a>, was to use his new status as a political candidate to buy ads on Facebook promoting false content about Trump, Zuckerberg, and others explicitly to call attention to Facebook's policies and force the company to change them.</p>
<h2>Who’s a politician?</h2>
<p>Hampton's bid to become the Golden State's next head honcho isn't his first foray into challenging Facebook's ad policies. In fact, it's not even his first headline-grabbing Facebook-related action in the last week.</p>
<p>Hampton also runs a political action committee, The Really Online Lefty League (TROLL), which a few days ago lived up to its name by purchasing a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-election-facebook/facebook-takes-down-false-ad-from-pac-on-republican-graham-idUSKBN1X50IZ">stunt advertisement</a> claiming Sen. Lindsay Graham (R-S.C.) supports the Green New Deal, a progressive policy package and the signature proposal of Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-N.Y). </p>
<p>Graham, who is a devoted Republican, is as ardent an opponent of the Green New Deal as you might expect and <a href="https://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2019/oct/28/blog-posting/no-lindsey-graham-does-not-support-green-new-deal/">has said</a>: "There's not one Republican going to vote for anything coming out of the Green New Deal 'cause it’s crazy."</p>
<p>Facebook suspended the ad's paid distribution. It said that—because the promotion came from a third-party PAC rather than directly from a candidate or politician—it was eligible for review and removal under the site's policy.</p>
<p>Launching a campaign doesn't appear to be enough to make Hampton a legitimately exempt advertiser in Facebook's eyes, though. Facebook <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/10/29/tech/facebook-california-candidate-false-ads/index.html">told CNN</a>, "This person has made clear he registered as a candidate to get around our policies, so his content, including ads, will continue to be eligible for third-party fact-checking."</p>
<p>Hampton responded to CNN that Facebook, "made a policy specific to me, and I am running for California governor to regulate Facebook," adding, "I am going to look at suing them—I will immediately seek all available legal options."</p>
<h2>Beyond stunts</h2>
<p>The fight around what Facebook does or does not allow on its site is already beyond exhausting—but it's almost certainly going to get worse before (or if) it manages to get better. US politicians on all sides are wading into the fray, and with the 2020 election <em>almost</em> finally less than a year away, tensions are only going to intensify.</p>
<p>The current fight over political ads on Facebook began when President Donald Trump's re-election campaign <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/political-ads-can-lie-if-they-want-facebook-confirms/">ran a false ad</a> about former Vice President Joe Biden, who is among the leading candidates seeking the 2020 Democratic presidential nomination. The site refused to pull the spot, kicking off outrage, especially from Biden's fellow Democrats.</p>
<p>Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.), another leading contender in the crowded 2020 field, herself <a href="https://twitter.com/ewarren/status/1183019880867680256?lang=en">launched a false ad</a> on Facebook earlier this month to draw attention to what she sees as the platform's failings. "Breaking news," the ad begins: "Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook just endorsed Donald Trump for re-election."</p>
<p>It immediately reveals the deception as it goes on:</p>
<blockquote><p>You're probably shocked, and you might be thinking, "how could this possibly be true?"</p>
<p>Well, it's not. (Sorry.) But what Zuckerberg *has* done is give Donald Trump free rein to lie on his platform—and then to pay Facebook gobs of money to push out their lies to American voters.</p></blockquote>
<p>Facebook inexplicably used its official news twitter account to <a href="https://twitter.com/fbnewsroom/status/1183162508846215168">challenge Warren</a>, comparing itself to legacy TV broadcasters, which are regulated by the Federal Communications Commission. Facebook, however, is not subject to regulation by the FCC—nor would company leadership particularly want it to be, one assumes.</p>
<p>"You're making my point here," Warren responded. "It's up to you whether you take money to promote lies. You can be in the disinformation-for-profit business, or you can hold yourself to some standards."</p>
<p>Investigations by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/10/28/pro-trump-super-pacs-draw-scrutiny-facebook-ads-seeking-voter-registration-data/">The Washington Post</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-election-latinos-analysis/vamos-to-victory-trumps-spanish-ads-skirt-immigration-warn-of-socialism-idUSKBN1X913E">Reuters</a>, and others, meanwhile, show that questionable political advertising by third parties is not only rampant, but also can stay up on Facebook until media attention causes the company to pull it down.</p>
<p>Employees, meanwhile, are reportedly <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/facebooks-new-political-ad-policy-already-showing-cracks-loopholes/">no happier with the contentious policy than anyone else</a>: more than 250 Facebook workers have signed onto an open letter asking the company to adopt new standards for political ads.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593859&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook permanently deletes the accounts of NSO workers</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594003</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 19:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nso group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whatsapp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594003</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Deletions come after allegations NSO exploit targeted 1,400 WhatsApp users. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/delete-800x534.jpg" alt="Extreme closeup photograph of a computer delete key."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/delete.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/ervins_strauhmanis/10135243453">Ervins Strauhmanis / Flickr</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A day after Facebook-owned WhatsApp sued NSO Group, the social media platform has permanently deleted the accounts of employees who work at the Israel-based spyware maker, according to message boards and a security researcher who spoke to one worker.</p>
<p>"Your account has been deleted for not following our terms," said a message sent to one employee by Facebook-owned Instagram. "You won't be able to log into this account, and no one else will be able to see it. We're unable to restore accounts that are deleted for these types of violations."</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='A message Instagram sent to an NSO Group employee.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nso-employee.jpeg" alt='A message Instagram sent to an NSO Group employee.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">A message Instagram sent to an NSO Group employee. </p></div>
<p>The action comes after WhatsApp <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/10/whatsapp-suit-says-israeli-spyware-maker-exploited-its-app-to-infect-1400-users/">sued NSO Group on Tuesday</a> for allegedly mass exploiting a critical vulnerability that targeted 1,400 devices with spyware. WhatsApp presented evidence that about 100 of the targets were lawyers, dissidents, human-rights advocates, and other members of civil society. The exploits allowed the attackers to install spyware on iOS and Android phones simply by making a video call to the device.</p>
<p>According to WhatsApp, the attackers made the calls from WhatsApp accounts that were created for the purpose of infecting other WhatsApp users. The attackers also relied on WhatsApp servers to communicate with NSO-operated attack servers. The actions, WhatsApp said, violated not just its terms of service, but also the US Computer and Fraud Abuse Act.</p>
<p>The lawsuit seeks, among other things, a permanent injunction barring all NSO employees from "accessing or attempting to access WhatsApp's or Facebook's services, platform, and computer systems."</p>
<p>A message board popular in Israel indicated that the deletion was widespread. "I had just personally verified it (I have friends working there)," one person <a href="https://rotter.net/forum/scoops1/582511.shtml#14">wrote</a>. "Ninety-eight percent of the company employees were blocked."</p>
<p>Another person who claimed to work at NSO responded to say he or she hadn't been blocked. Another person claiming to be an NSO employee <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/brennerguy_facebook-instagram-nso-activity-6595220156459307008-OKok/">complained bitterly on LinkedIn</a>. An Israel-based security researcher who spoke to an NSO employee said the deletions affected a much smaller percentage of the company's employees and didn't involve WhatsApp accounts.</p>
<p>WhatsApp representatives declined to comment. NSO representatives didn't immediately respond to an email.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594003&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AT&#038;T will slash $3 billion off its capital investments next year</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593951</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 18:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital expenditures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Net Neutrality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verizon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593951</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[AT&#38;T mostly stopped fiber-to-the-home deployment despite tax cut and deregulation.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/att-van-800x466.jpg" alt="An AT&T repair truck."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/att-van.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1012" data-width="1738">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> An AT&amp;T repair truck. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/jeepersmedia/14334280904/in/photolist-nQEWjd-nNG9PL-oU1WvJ-oNQRnt-p6kRwZ-oNRD7J-p65DRF-oNR8CA-oNRBLY-p6iSjG-oNR7rs-p6iR5Y-p65EGD">Mike Mozart / Flickr</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>AT&amp;T is planning to spend just $20 billion on capital investment in 2020, down from $23 billion this year.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T announced the $20 billion forecast for 2020 Monday in its <a href="https://about.att.com/story/2019/att_third_quarter_earnings_2019.html">quarterly earnings</a>. A year ago, <a href="https://investors.att.com/~/media/Files/A/ATT-IR/financial-reports/quarterly-earnings/2018/4q-2018/4Q18%20Earnings%20Release.pdf">AT&amp;T said</a> it would spend $23 billion on gross capital investment in 2019. (These numbers include network construction and vendor-financing payments but do not include some spending on AT&amp;T's FirstNet public safety network, which is reimbursed by the federal government.)</p>
<p>The company is on pace to exceed its 2019 goal as it averaged <a href="https://investors.att.com/~/media/Files/A/ATT-IR/financial-reports/quarterly-earnings/2019/3q-2019/3Q19_Trending%20Schedules.pdf">more than $6 billion per quarter</a> in the first three quarters. But with a forecast of $20 billion across all of 2020, AT&amp;T expects to spend about $5 billion per quarter on capital investments going forward. The company is under pressure from investors to control spending, in part because its TV business is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/10/att-loses-another-1-3-million-tv-customers-as-directv-freefall-continues/">tanking</a> and because of AT&amp;T's giant debt load stemming from the purchases of DirecTV and Time Warner.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T increased capital investment between 2018 and 2019, but its 2020 outlook would push the company's spending to lower than its 2018 total of $21.8 billion. AT&amp;T, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/05/att-promised-7000-new-jobs-to-get-tax-break-it-cut-23000-jobs-instead/">as you might remember</a>, promised increased capital spending and thousands of new jobs in exchange for a corporate tax cut and <a href="https://ecfsapi.fcc.gov/file/108302543725436/AT%26T%20reply%20comments%2017-108.pdf">claimed</a> that the now-repealed federal net neutrality rules harmed broadband-network investment. The tax cut alone <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/at-t-sees-big-benefit-from-tax-law-1517434789">reportedly</a> gave AT&amp;T an extra $3 billion in cash in 2018, and it continues to give the company <a href="https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/briefing-book/how-does-corporate-income-tax-work">lower tax rates</a> each year. Despite that, AT&amp;T <a href="https://investors.att.com/~/media/Files/A/ATT-IR/financial-reports/quarterly-earnings/2019/3q-2019/3Q19_Investor%20Briefing.pdf">said</a> it has cut its workforce from 269,280 employees to 251,840 employees in the past year.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's capital spending will decline next year despite the company's plan to roll 5G mobile service out nationwide. AT&amp;T already got much of the 5G spending out of the way by purchasing spectrum licenses, and AT&amp;T CEO Randall Stephenson <a href="https://investors.att.com/~/media/Files/A/ATT-IR/financial-reports/quarterly-earnings/2019/3q-2019/ATT%203Q19%20Transcript.pdf">told investors</a> that the company's "strong spectrum position will allow for lower capital intensity" over the next three years.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T has also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/06/att-cuts-another-1800-jobs-as-it-finishes-fiber-internet-buildout/">mostly stopped</a> its fiber-to-the-home broadband construction even though large portions of its 21-state territory still have only copper-based DSL service. Fiber deployment isn't stopping completely, as Stephenson said that "5G requires us to continue deploying fiber." But AT&amp;T customers who can't get modern broadband speeds or reliable wireline service in their homes would welcome more capital investment in their neighborhoods.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's capital investment has an outsized influence on the industry numbers as a whole. As Stephenson said, the $20 billion AT&amp;T plans in 2020 is "the most aggressive investment in the industry" even though it's low by AT&amp;T's recent standards.</p>
<h2>Tax cut, deregulation didn't boost investment</h2>
<p>AT&amp;T slashing $3 billion off its capital investment will hurt Federal Communications Commission Chairman Ajit Pai's attempts to claim that his deregulatory initiatives have raised broadband investment. Pai has repeatedly <a href="//cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/pai-capital.pdf">cited capital-expenditure numbers</a> in his <a href="https://transition.fcc.gov/Daily_Releases/Daily_Business/2017/db0426/DOC-344590A1.pdf">argument</a> that net neutrality rules caused broadband providers to reduce investment.</p>
<p>Pai has also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/02/ajit-pai-says-broadband-access-is-soaring-and-that-hes-the-one-to-thank/">taken credit</a> for AT&amp;T's fiber-to-the-home deployment, even though AT&amp;T completed that multi-year project as part of a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/07/att-gets-directv-merger-approval-must-deploy-fiber-to-12-5m-customers/">deal with Pai's predecessor</a>, Tom Wheeler. AT&amp;T's decisions to lower capital investment and stop expanding fiber-to-the-home broadband may force Pai to look elsewhere for data to support his deregulatory preferences.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's lower-than-expected spending forecast for 2020 "surprised Wall Street analysts," <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/mobile/5g/atandt-and-verizon-are-stingy-on-capex-despite-5g-deployments/d/d-id/755244">Light Reading reported today</a>. "The reduction was such that the analysts at Wall Street research firm Cowen lowered their capex forecasts for AT&amp;T to roughly $19 billion in 2021 and 2022, a decrease from their previous forecast of around $21 billion," the article said.</p>
<h2>Comcast, Charter cut cable spending</h2>
<p>Capital expenditures for other carriers are also lower than expected. "Comcast and Charter missed 3Q expectations for capex and guided 2019 lower than previously planned," analysts at Nomura's Instinet wrote in a note to investors, according to Light Reading. "We have lowered our combined 2019 capex forecast for Comcast and Charter from $14.6 billion to $14.2 billion."</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cmcsa.com/news-releases/news-release-details/comcast-reports-3rd-quarter-2019-results">Comcast said</a> its cable division's capital expenditures "decreased 6.7% to $1.8 billion" in the quarter." For the nine months ending September 30, Comcast cable's "capital expenditures decreased 11.7% to $4.8 billion," the company said. (Comcast's overall capital expenditures increased because of a rise in NBCUniversal spending.)</p>
<p><a href="https://ir.charter.com/static-files/76cf320f-4610-448b-9768-c1a27f2d2c2e">Charter said</a> that its third-quarter "capital expenditures totaled $1.7 billion compared to $2.1 billion during the third quarter of 2018."</p>
<p>"Charter currently expects capital expenditures, excluding capital expenditures related to mobile, to be slightly below $7 billion in 2019, versus $8.9 billion in 2018," the company said.</p>
<p>Verizon spent $4.4 billion in capital expenditures in the third quarter, "roughly $100 million below most Wall Street expectations," but Verizon still expects to hit its full-year forecast of $17 billion to $18 billion in 2019, Light Reading wrote.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: The Advance/Newhouse Partnership, which owns 13% of Charter, is part of Advance Publications. Advance Publications owns Condé Nast, which owns Ars Technica.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593951&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Army “hacker con” goes big: The return of AvengerCon</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593887</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 18:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[780th Military Intelligence Brigade (Cyber)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Army Cyber Command]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AvengerCon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacker conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Cyber Command]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gaining support of US Cyber Command, AvengerCon taps into a bigger community.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/191017-O-PX639-138-800x533.jpg" alt="Out-of-uniform soldiers attach banner of glass doors of convention center."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/191017-O-PX639-138.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3456" data-width="5184">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Soldiers of the 780th Military Intelligence Brigade (Cyber) set up for AvengerCon IV, a &quot;hacker&quot; event for members of the US Cyber Command and government cyber operations community at the US CYBERCOM DreamPort facility in Columbia, Maryland, on October 17 and 18, 2019. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.inscom.army.mil/msc/780mib/">780th Military Intelligence Brigade</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>COLUMBIA, Md.—In a business park that plays home to a number of tech and cybersecurity firms situated strategically between Washington, DC, and Baltimore, there's a two-story building that looks externally like many other office buildings, remarkable this day only for the food trucks in the parking lot and the stream of people in camouflage swarming in and out. The building, called <a href="https://dreamport.tech/index.php">DreamPort</a>, is a collaboration facility leased by US Cyber Command—and on October 18, it was the location of <a href="https://www.avengercon.com/">AvengerCon IV</a>, the latest incarnation of a soldier-led cybersecurity training event that takes the shape of a community hacking conference.</p>
<p>The event also offered USCYBERCOM a chance to show off DreamPort—and a chance for me to meet with <a href="https://www.cybercom.mil/About/Leadership/Bio-Display/Article/1651709/executive-director-uscybercom/">David Luber</a>, the Executive Director of USCYBERCOM.</p>
<p>"AvengerCon is an event that is attracting the very best talent both from our DoD participants and also from some of the folks that are working with us outside of the DoD," Luber said. "When you bring those very best cyber experts together, they get to learn, test out new ideas, and work in an environment that is hosted by and for DoD cyber operations community experts. They're working in a community of peers—they get to learn together, they get to fail together. And what we've seen from previous activities with AvengerCon is that it's an exhilarating, fun environment for them to work in, and they learn a ton while they're here. And the private sector benefits because as AvengerCon shows, we're all working on some of the same cyber challenges together."</p>
<p>AvengerCon is an effort to bring the learning environment provided by security conferences such as DEFCON to a military and government community that wouldn't otherwise be available because of cost and bureaucratic complexity. Originally a training event organized by the 781st Military Intelligence Battalion at Fort Meade involving about 100 soldiers, AvengerCon has grown to 600 attendees and has gained the backing of Army Cyber Command and USCYBERCOM.</p>

<p>"My job, in part, is trying to figure out how to properly train soldiers in a field that doesn't have decades of standard operating procedures and clear paths for training to get to success," Capt. Joseph Dooley, an organizer of AvengerCon, told Ars. He said that this type of event offered "a unique opportunity for soldiers to individually be in a more unstructured environment where they can set their own agenda"—where they can pick things that they're interested in or feel they need training in without the usual constraints of formal Army training.</p>
<p>The event "complements efforts in regular unit training," Dooley explained. "And it gives [attendees] the chance to collaborate with subject-matter experts [and] share and compare tradecraft, best practices, and ideas. This is a very good way to boost our other conventional training."</p>
<p>Sgt. 1st Class Craig Seiler, another member of the AvengerCon organizing committee, said that bringing together people from across the cyber operations community in government provided a boost to the learning opportunities. "What we've found is mixing all these different types of people—developers, people doing operations—they all do great things separately, but when they get together later on, they say, 'Hey, I really learned something from that analyst or that developer that I've picked up to bring to my current job.'"</p>
<p>I attended last year's AvengerCon, held on Fort Meade, at the invitation of the unit organizing the event, the 780th Military Intelligence Brigade (Cyber). While AvengerCon III was clearly a success, this year's expanded event puts AvengerCon on the scale of well-established regional security conferences. The keynote speaker was security researcher Daniel Cuthbert, who is Global Head of Cyber Security Research for Grupo Santander and co-author of the original Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) Testing Guide and the OWASP Application Security Verification Standard. He spoke largely on the issues surrounding information-sharing and collaboration in the cybersecurity realm.</p>
<h2>Beyond the base</h2>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/191017-O-PX639-242-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Keynote speaker Daniel Cuthbert addresses attendees at AvengerCon IV.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.inscom.army.mil/msc/780mib/">780th Military Intelligence Brigade</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Holding a "con" on a military post (and at Fort Meade in particular) can pose some logistical challenges—such as getting people cleared and onto the base itself, and limited space to stage the event. Fortunately, the success of AvengerCon drew the attention of US Cyber Command, and the organizers were offered the use of DreamPort for the event's next iteration.</p>
<p>AvengerCon fits neatly into DreamPort's mission to foster collaboration between US Cyber Command, the rest of the Department of Defense and intelligence community, and industry.</p>
<p>"We opened the facility here in Columbia, Maryland, back in the fall of 2018," Luber said, "created under a partnership intermediary agreement between US Cyber Command and the Maryland Innovation and Security Institute [MISI]. We've hosted over 14,000 visitors in this 40,000-square-foot facility, and in June of 2019, MISI signed an expansion lease to double the size of DreamPort by the end of 2020. So, we're really happy about the partnership that we've had so far."</p>
<p>Companies and individuals can come into the unclassified facility to demonstrate capabilities during "challenges" and events hosted by the facility looking at specific cybersecurity issues. These include critical infrastructure security events simulated in "Dream Valley," a scale model village connected to actual industrial control systems and other operational technology.</p>
<h2>Off base</h2>
<p>DreamPort's planned expansion is probably a good thing, considering how AvengerCon has grown. In the past, the event was limited to Army personnel, but now it includes attendees from across the Department of Defense and other government agencies tied to cyber operations, as well as students and representatives of industry.</p>
<p>"We felt we needed to branch out and start making sure that we are supporting the community better each year as we expand," said Seiler. "The growth is great, but it also brings in other woes and requirements." The logistics of getting people onto Fort Meade was one of them, Seiler explained—while it provided a natural level of security around the event, using the base made drawing on outside resources difficult and limited who could be brought in to attend.</p>
<p>"We found it works better if it's off base," he said.</p>
<p>Using DreamPort opened up the opportunity to add resources provided by outside organizations that "connect to our mission," Seiler said. Those included the "villages" at the event brought in by security community organizations—including ICS Village's industrial control systems "capture the flag" competition (in which attendees looked for ways to compromise simulated plant hardware) and the Voting Village's collection of voting-machine hardware and exploration of election security.</p>
<p>"The election thing was nice to have," said Seiler. "I don't know if it was our big thing, but lots of people are talking about it... it sparks conversation, which was the intent of accepting something like that. That's the intent of all the villages—to build the conversations."</p>
<p>The additional space allowed for the expansion of AvengerCon's training workshops, which included day-long classes in reverse-engineering and software "fuzzing." Additionally, the event hosted a simulation called "The Day After"—in which teams from the US Naval Academy, James Madison University, American University, and the University of Maryland, Baltimore County, simulated strategies for government agencies to respond to a large-scale cyberattack on the United States.</p>
<h2>More, better cyber</h2>
<p>The success of AvengerCon has prompted plans to replicate it in some form for the military and intelligence cyber community at Fort Gordon in Georgia. But the organizers also want to make sure that AvengerCon itself doesn't outgrow its grassroots, community feel. They also want it to stay focused on its mission. That fits into the overall USCYBERCOM strategy for DreamPort, which has an ongoing calendar of highly focused events surrounding the command's "Persistent Innovation" strategy.</p>
<p>"You know that cyberspace is under constant change," said Luber. "It requires us to constantly innovate, and innovation just doesn't happen in government. It's also happening in industry, academia. We need a place to work, we need a place to meet, and we need a place to innovate, and DreamPort provides that combination for us."</p>
<p>In addition to providing an environment for academic outreach to high schools and universities, Luber said DreamPort is "a mission accelerator, an incubator for US Cyber Command where projects are conducted with the goal of completing those projects within 90 days. So think of that innovation process where you've got an idea, you've got a concept, you want to run it quickly, and if you fail, you fail fast. And if you succeed, you've moved to the next step where you try and get it to operational capabilities."</p>
<p>Conducting those projects in an unclassified environment, Luber said, encourages the sharing of ideas and speeds up the creation of new solutions to cyber security issues.</p>
<h2>Rapid prototyping</h2>
<p>Some of those projects include rapid-prototyping events in which "we bring industry partners in from all different sizes, small businesses, large businesses, and then have them work the problem," Luber explained. "We've had six rapid-prototyping events over the course of the past year. We've seen even one-person companies outperform some of the bigger prime contractors that you might think that we're dealing with on a regular basis."</p>
<p>One of DreamPort's recent rapid-prototyping events was run by USCYBERCOM in partnership with the Office of the Secretary of Defense for Small Business and Manufacturing. It focused on protecting the security of small businesses within the Defense Industrial Base (DIB) with the application of "zero trust" network security, which is an architectural approach to handling application and information security that would help protect their security regardless of the overall security of the network environment.</p>
<p>The project looked at ways to apply zero-trust architecture, not just to the DIB, but to Department of Defense information systems and networks as well. "By bringing together talent from DISA, NSA, USCYBERCOM, and industry, we were able to really work on some interesting prototyping activities, and it's going to help us drive the future for the Department," Luber said.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593887&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leveling up: DeepMind’s AlphaStar achieves Grandmaster level in StarCraft II</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593543</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 18:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AlphaStar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepmind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google deepmind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reinforcement learning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Forget chess and Go: The new AI frontier is multiplayer video games.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft1-800x531.jpg" alt="AlphaStar (Protoss, in green) dealing with flying units from the Zerg players with a combination of anti-air units (Phoenix and Archon)."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="796" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> AlphaStar (Protoss, in green) dealing with flying units from the Zerg players with a combination of anti-air units (Phoenix and Archon). (credit: DeepMind)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Back in January, Google's DeepMind team <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/an-ai-crushed-two-human-pros-at-starcraft-but-it-wasnt-a-fair-fight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced that</a> its AI, dubbed AlphaStar, had beaten two top human professional players at <em>StarCraft</em>. But as <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/an-ai-crushed-two-human-pros-at-starcraft-but-it-wasnt-a-fair-fight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we argued at the time</a>, it wasn't quite a fair fight. Now AlphaStar has improved on its performance sufficiently to achieve Grandmaster status in <em>StarCraft II,</em> using the same interface as a human player. The team described its work in a new paper in Nature.</p>
<p>"This is a dream come true," said DeepMind co-author Oriol Vinyals, who was an avid <em>StarCraft</em> player 20 years ago. "AlphaStar achieved Grandmaster level solely with a neural network and general-purpose learning algorithms—which was unimaginable ten years ago when I was researching <em>StarCraft</em> AI using rules-based systems."</p>
<p>Late last year, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/12/move-over-alphago-alphazero-taught-itself-to-play-three-different-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we reported on</a> the latest achievements of AlphaZero, a direct descendent of DeepMind's AlphaGo, which made headlines worldwide in 2016 by defeating Lee Sedol, the reigning (human) world champion in Go. AlphaGo got <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature24270" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">a major upgrade</a> last year, becoming capable of teaching itself winning strategies with no need for human intervention. By playing itself over and over again, AlphaZero trained itself to play Go from scratch in just three days and soundly defeated the original AlphaGo 100 games to 0. The only input it received was the basic rules of the game. Then AlphaZero <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/362/6419/1140" target="_blank" rel="noopener">taught itself</a> to play three different board games (chess, Go, and shogi, a Japanese form of chess) in just three days, with no human intervention.</p>
<p>The secret ingredient: "reinforcement learning," in which playing itself for millions of games allows the program to learn from experience. This works because AlphaZero is rewarded for the most useful actions (i.e., devising winning strategies). The AI does this by considering the most probable next moves and calculating the probability of winning for each of them. The most recent version combined deep reinforcement learning (many layers of neural networks) with a general-purpose Monte Carlo tree search method. As chess grandmaster <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/362/6419/1087" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gary Kasparov wrote</a> in an editorial in Science last year, "Instead of processing human instructions and knowledge at tremendous speed, as all previous chess machines, AlphaZero generates its own knowledge."</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft3.jpg"><img alt='AlphaStar (Zerg, in red) defending an early aggression where the opponent built part of the base near AlphaStar&#039;s base, showcasing robustness.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft3-640x400.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft3.jpg 2x" alt='AlphaStar (Zerg, in red) defending an early aggression where the opponent built part of the base near AlphaStar&#039;s base, showcasing robustness.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft3.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">AlphaStar (Zerg, in red) defending an early aggression where the opponent built part of the base near AlphaStar's base, showcasing robustness.</a> (credit: DeepMind)</p></div>
<p>With AlphaZero's success, DeepMind's focus shifted to a new AI frontier: games of partial (incomplete) information, like poker, and multi-player video games like <em>Starcraft II</em>. <em>StarCraft II</em> is also a game of incomplete information, and there is no single best strategy, much like playing rock-paper-scissors. It requires long-range planning ability and real-time decision-making in a large action space. Not only is the gameplay map hidden to players, but they must also control hundreds of units (mobile game pieces that can be built to influence the game) and buildings (used to create units or technologies that strengthen those units) simultaneously. As Ars' Tim Lee (an avid <em>StarCraft</em> player) <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/an-ai-crushed-two-human-pros-at-starcraft-but-it-wasnt-a-fair-fight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote in January</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>"<em>StarCraft</em> requires players to gather resources, build dozens of military units, and use them to try to destroy their opponents. <em>StarCraft</em> is particularly challenging for an AI because players must carry out long-term plans over several minutes of gameplay, tweaking them on the fly in the face of enemy counterattacks. DeepMind says that prior to its own effort, no one had come close to designing a <em>StarCraft</em> AI as good as the best human players."</p></blockquote>
<p>That earlier version of AlphaStar also relied on deep reinforcement learning to teach the program to mimic human strategies. At that point, the AI was proficient enough to defeat Elite-level players roughly 95% of the time. Then the DeepMind team created variants of that AI, each adopting a different playing style, and placed them into a virtual <em>StarCraft</em> league. This allowed the agents to learn from their mistakes and evolve their strategies accordingly. Then DeepMind selected the five strongest agents and pitted them against two human professional players: Dario "TLO" Wunsch and Grzegorz "MaNa" Komincz. The AI defeated its human challengers in all ten games.</p>
<p>That said, it wasn't quite a fair fight. "The ultimate way to level the playing field would be to make AlphaStar use the exact same user interface as human players," <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/an-ai-crushed-two-human-pros-at-starcraft-but-it-wasnt-a-fair-fight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lee wrote</a> in January. "The interface could be virtualized, of course, but the game should get the same raw pixel inputs as a human player and should be required to input instructions using a sequence of mouse movements and keystrokes—with inputs limited to speeds that human hands can achieve. This is the only way to be completely sure that AlphaStar isn't giving its software an unfair advantage."</p>
<h2>Playing like a human</h2>
<p>This latest version of AlphaStar goes a long way toward addressing those issues, combining deep reinforcement learning with multi-agent learning and imitation learning directly from game data, honed once again via a virtual league. Per a blog post by Vinyals and fellow DeepMind co-author Wojciech Czarnecki, the new, improved AlphaStar was subject to the same constraints under which humans play, and it played on Battle.net "using the same maps and conditions as human players."</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft2.jpg"><img alt='AlphaStar (Zerg, in green) winning a final encounter using late-game, high-tech units.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft2-640x400.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft2.jpg 2x" alt='AlphaStar (Zerg, in green) winning a final encounter using late-game, high-tech units.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/starcraft2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">AlphaStar (Zerg, in green) winning a final encounter using late-game, high-tech units.</a> (credit: DeepMind)</p></div>
<p>"The key insight of the league is that playing to win is insufficient," Vinyals and Czarnecki wrote of the improvements to this latest incarnation of AlphaStar. "Instead, we need both main agents whose goal is to win versus everyone, and also exploiter agents that 'take one for the team.' focusing on helping the main agent grow stronger by exposing its flaws, rather than maximizing their own win rate. Using this training method, the current league learns all its complex <em>StarCraft II</em> strategy in an end-to-end fashion—as opposed to the earlier incarnation of our work, which stitched together agents produced by a variety of methods and algorithms."</p>
<p>The AI can also now play as or against the three races in <em>Starcraft II</em>: Protoss, Terran, and Zerg. (The earlier version only played Protoss vs. Protoss.) DeepMind pitted AlphaStar against human players in a series of online games. The AI was rated at Grandmaster level for all three <em>StarCraft II</em> races and above 99.8% of officially ranked human players. It's the first AI to achieve that status in a popular professional e-sport, without using a simplified version of the game. That's a strong indication that these types of general-purpose machine-learning algorithms could be used to solve complex real-world problems such as personal assistants, self-driving cars, or robotics—all of which require real-time decisions on the basis of imperfect information.</p>
<p>"At DeepMind, we're interested in understanding the potential—and limitations—of open-ended learning, which enables us to develop robust and flexible agents that can cope with complex real-world domains," Vinyals and Czarnecki wrote. "Games like <em>StarCraft</em> are an excellent training ground to advance these approaches, as players must use limited information to make dynamic and difficult decisions that have ramifications on multiple levels and timescales."</p>
<p>And this time around, it appears to have been a fair fight. "I've found AlphaStar's gameplay impressive," Wunsch said of this most recent incarnation. "The system is very skilled at assessing its strategic position, and knows exactly when to engage or disengage with its opponent. And while AlphaStar has excellent and precise control, it doesn't feel superhuman—certainly not on a level that a human couldn't theoretically achieve. Overall, it feels very fair—like playing a 'real' game of <em>StarCraft</em>."</p>
<p>DOI: <em>Nature</em>, 2019. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1724-z">10.1038/s41586-019-1724-z</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593543&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CRISPR used to edit rice DNA as defense against pathogen</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593491</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 17:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Gitig]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRISPR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593491</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Altering rice genes the pathogen needs renders rice strains resistant to blight.  
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Rice_900x506-768x432.jpg" alt="Image of a rice plant."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Rice_900x506-768x432.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="432" data-width="768">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://plantingseedsblog.cdfa.ca.gov/wordpress/?p=16734">CA Food and Agriculture</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Bacterial blight attacks rice crops in Southeast Asia and West Africa. It is a very well-studied crop disease, and it often serves as a model system to examine the interactions between microbes and their host plants. The pathogen is called Xoo, for <em>Xanthomonas oryzae</em> pathovar <em>oryzae</em>, and it makes its living by hijacking a number of rice genes that export sugars.</p>
<p>Now, researchers have figured out how to edit the rice's genome to block this hijacking.</p>
<h2>A TALe of sugars</h2>
<p>Xoo secretes TALes (transcription activator-like effector molecules) that bind to the DNA near the rice's SWEET genes, activating them. These SWEET genes (Sugars Will Eventually Be Exported Transporters) are ubiquitous in plants. As their name indicates, the SWEET proteins transport sucrose across the cell membrane. Their expression is required for susceptibility to Xoo.</p>
<p>Researchers thought that modifying the rice SWEET genes would confer resistance to Xoo, especially since natural-occurring resistance has arisen this way. But thus far, only a few Xoo strains have been characterized genetically, so it wasn't clear whether it had additional ways of attacking its host.</p>
<p>In order to see how to most efficiently render the rice resistant to Xoo—which of the rice's SWEET genes to change, and how—an international team of scientists first examined 63 strains of Xoo, 33 from Asia and 30 from Africa. All of them were found to use TALes to induce the expression of SWEET genes.</p>
<p>As a proof of concept, the scientists then used CRISPR to edit the DNA near three SWEET genes in Kitaake rice. This editing specifically targeted the DNA sequences that the TALe proteins stick to but left the surrounding DNA intact. It's far more specific than could be expected to occur simply by selecting for naturally occurring variants.</p>
<p>The engineered rice was resistant to all known Xoo strains. The Kitaake cultivar is a variety of <em>japonica</em> rice that is optimal for such studies since it has a quick flowering cycle and high regeneration. In the future, this new resistant line can serve as a diagnostic test to assess the virulence of any new Xoo strains that crop up.</p>
<h2>Testing on crops</h2>
<p>Since it is a variety of <em>japonica</em>, it can also be harnessed to breed the resistant trait into Japanese and Chinese rice. But it is not ideal for breeding with the <em>indica</em> varieties that are grown in most of Southeast Asia and Africa.</p>
<p>So next the team used CRISPR to modify two rice mega varieties—those grown over a million hectares. In paddy experiments, the edited rice grew normally and performed much like its unmodified parents in terms of plant height and other agriculturally relevant metrics. Critically, it was resistant to three representative strains of Xoo. Although encouraging, the researchers note that these results hardly provide a sound base for going out and planting fields of the stuff; much more extensive field trials are required, along with complete sequencing to ensure that CRISPR did not generate any off-target DNA edits.</p>
<p>Rice has over 20 SWEET genes, and only three are naturally targeted by Xoo. "Broad resistance to bacterial blight at the SWEET promoters will not prevent adaptation of the pathogen, and the durability of this approach will depend on the ability of Xoo populations to adapt to recessive resistance alleles," the authors sagely note. They suggest that making large changes in the SWEET gene promoters might delay Xoo's ability to overcome the engineered resistance.</p>
<p>Nature Biotechnology, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41587-019-0267-z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10.1038/s41587-019-0267-z</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593491&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lawsuit: Juul sold tainted e-liquids to users “drunk and vaping like mo-fo’s”</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593843</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 15:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contamination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-cigarettes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nicotine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593843</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whistleblower suit paints a dark picture of Juul's culture and management.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1168822427-800x533.jpg" alt="Mint and menthol pods for Juul Labs Inc. e-cigarettes are displayed for sale at a store in Princeton, Illinois, on Monday, Sept. 16, 2019. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1168822427.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2667" data-width="4000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Mint and menthol pods for Juul Labs Inc. e-cigarettes are displayed for sale at a store in Princeton, Illinois, on Monday, Sept. 16, 2019.  (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/menthol-pods-for-juul-labs-inc-e-cigarettes-are-displayed-news-photo/1168822427?adppopup=true">Getty | Bloomberg</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Leading e-cigarette-maker Juul knowingly sold a large amount of contaminated mint-flavored e-liquid, endangering public health in the name of profits, according to a<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/BrejavsJuul.pdf"> lawsuit brought by Siddharth Breja, the company’s former senior vice president of global finance</a>.</p>
<p>Breja filed the lawsuit Tuesday, October 29 in the US District Court for the Northern District of California.</p>
<p> Breja began working at the company in May of 2018 but alleges he was abruptly fired in March of 2019 after voicing concern that the company refused to issue a recall over the contaminated products or warn customers about the potential risk. Breja is suing Juul for retaliation for whistleblowing, wrongful termination, and other violations.</p>
<p>Overall, Breja’s complaint paints a dark picture of the company, which owns a lion’s share of the e-cigarette market in the US. The former executive claims that Juul’s senior management was motivated purely by profits and made many efforts to deceive regulators and customers, copying the despised tactics of Big Tobacco companies and trying to get customers addicted to their products.</p>
<p>Breja accuses ex-CEO Kevin Burns of managing the company like a dictator, operating in a “win-at-all-costs, reckless fashion,” and fostering a “culture of silence.”</p>
<p>When Breja raised concerns about the company selling expired or soon-to-be expired products, Burns allegedly responded: “Half our customers are drunk and vaping like mo-fo’s, who the fuck is going to notice the quality of our pods.”</p>
<h2>Toxic claims</h2>
<p>Perhaps more concerning, Breja alleges that Juul sold a large amount of contaminated products out of greed. According to Breja, the company struggled to keep up with demand for mint-flavored products after Juul decided <a href="https://newsroom.juul.com/juul-labs-action-plan/">to pull other flavors from its retail stores</a> late last year. The move was meant to dodge further public backlash for the rise in teen vaping, but it resulted in supply issues that threatened profits.</p>
<p>“You need to have an IQ of 5 to know that when customers don’t find mango they buy mint,” Burns allegedly said while berating Juul’s supply-chain team and its suppliers for the shortages.</p>
<p>In March of 2019, Breja learned that some batches of Mint eLiquid had been found to be contaminated. By that time, approximately 250,000 “Mint Refill Kits” containing the contaminated liquids had already been shipped to retailers and were being sold to customers. The contaminated kits were equivalent to one million pods, the lawsuit notes.</p>
<p>The lawsuit does not indicate what the contaminant might be. But Breja’s suit notes that the contamination issue arose “in the wake of consumers recently having reported suffering seizures due to the use of Juul’s products.”</p>
<p>In an emailed statement to Ars, a Juul spokesperson responded:</p>
<blockquote><p>Mr. Breja’s claims are baseless. He was terminated in March 2019 because he failed to demonstrate the leadership qualities needed in his role. The allegations concerning safety issues with Juul products are equally meritless, and we already investigated the underlying manufacturing issue and determined the product met all applicable specifications. The company will vigorously defend this lawsuit.</p></blockquote>
<p> Breja’s claims come at a critical time for Juul. The company is facing intense criticism for helping to light up an epidemic of youth vaping, particularly after revelations this summer that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/09/juul-gave-presentations-in-schools-to-kids-and-the-fda-is-fuming/">Juul directly pitched its products to teens while they were in school</a>.</p>
<p>Moreover, the country is dealing with a rash of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/10/vaping-linked-lung-illness-looks-like-exposure-to-mustard-gas-doctors-say/">unexplained lung injuries that have been linked to vaping</a>. Federal and state health investigators have not been able to determine what vaping products or contaminants could be causing the illnesses, but most cases have involved black-market products containing THC (the psychoactive component of cannabis)—not nicotine products or Juul products, specifically.</p>
<p>As of October 22, 2019, there have <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/basic_information/e-cigarettes/severe-lung-disease.html#latest-outbreak-information">been 1,604 reported cases of vaping-related injuries</a> in 49 states, including 34 deaths, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
<p>Kevin Burns stepped down as Juul’s CEO in September. He was replaced by K. C. Crosthwaite, the former chief growth officer at Altria Group Inc., formerly Philip Morris Companies, Inc., before the appointment. On Tuesday, the company confirmed plans to lay off 500 employees by the end of the year as part of a “<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/juul-to-cut-about-500-jobs-11572301778">necessary reset</a>.”</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593843&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian nuclear power plant’s network was hacked, officials confirm</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593755</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 14:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KKNPP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kudankulam Nuclear Power Plant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lazarus group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear power security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593755</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After initial denial, company says report of “malware in system" is correct.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-128808655-800x534.jpg" alt="Malware attributed to North Korea's Lazarus group is confirmed to have infected a system on the administrative network of Nuclear Power Corp.'s Kudankulam plant in India. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-128808655.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Malware attributed to North Korea's Lazarus group is confirmed to have infected a system on the administrative network of Nuclear Power Corp.'s Kudankulam plant in India.  (credit:  Bloomberg via Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) has acknowledged today that malware attributed by others to North Korean state actors had been found on the administrative network of the Kudankulam Nuclear Power Plant (KKNPP). The admission comes a day after the company <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/10/indian-nuke-plants-network-reportedly-hit-by-malware-tied-to-n-korea/">issued a denial</a> that any attack would affect the plant's control systems.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/432675681/NPC-Admission-on-Malware-Attack#download">press release today</a>, NPCIL Associate Director A. K. Nema stated, "Identification of malware in NPCIL system is correct. The matter was conveyed by CERT-In [India's national computer emergency response team] when it was noticed by them on September 4, 2019."</p>
<p>That matches the date threat analyst Pukhraj Singh said he reported information on the breach to India's National Cyber Security Coordinator.</p>
<p>"The matter was immediately investigated by [India Department of Atomic Energy] specialists," Nema stated in the release. "The investigation revealed that the infected PC belonged to a user who was connected to the Internet connected network used for administrative purposes. This is isolated from the critical internal network. The networks are being continuously monitored."</p>
<h2>Lazarus in the house</h2>
<p>It's not clear if data was stolen from the KKNPP network. But the nuclear power plant was not the only facility Singh reported being compromised. When asked by Ars why he called the malware attack a "casus belli"—an act of war—Singh, a former analyst for India's National Technical Research Organization (NTRO), said, "It was because of the second target, which I can't disclose as of now."</p>
<p>The malware in question, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/09/busy-north-korean-hackers-have-new-malware-to-target-atms/">named Dtrack by Russian malware protection company Kaspersky</a>, has been used in widespread attacks against financial and research centers, based on Kaspersky data collected from over 180 samples of the malware. Dtrack shares elements of code from other malware attributed to the Lazarus threat group, which, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/09/us-indicts-north-korean-agents-for-wannacry-sony-attacks/">according to US Justice Department indictments,</a> is a North Korean state-sponsored hacking operation. Another version of the malware, ATMDtrack, has been used to steal data from ATM networks in India.</p>
<p>DTrack appears to be an espionage and reconnaissance tool, gathering data about infected systems and capable of logging keystrokes, scanning connected networks, and monitoring active processes on infected computers. The malware may have been delivered by an "in-memory implant," Singh said, though he added that he is waiting for confirmation from other sources. He added that he had not seen any data indicating whether data had been stolen from the KKNPP network. "I didn't have the full indicators," Singh said.</p>
<p>While the attack may not have given direct access to nuclear power control networks, it could have been part of an effort to establish a persistent presence on the nuclear plant's networks. As a <a href="https://www.icrc.org/en/document/potential-human-cost-cyber-operations">paper published in May by the International Committee of the Red Cross on the human cost of cyber operations</a> pointed out, “the majority of the computer devices in the world are only one or two steps away from a trusted system that a determined attacker could compromise." Lukasz Olejnik, a security researcher who co-authored the paper, noted that "preemptive compromise of trusted systems would make attacks significantly easier," and that establishing a persistent presence on a network could aid in things such as supply-chain attacks—attempts to use software update processes or other potential opportunities to move to isolated networks to deliver an attack in the future.</p>
<p>That's similar to the route demonstrated by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2012/06/confirmed-us-israel-created-stuxnet-lost-control-of-it/">Stuxnet,</a> the malware attributed to US and Israeli intelligence that managed to jump an "air gap" into Iranian nuclear enrichment equipment controls. While the administrative network of KKNPP was likely not a good route for such an attack given standards for nuclear control systems security, it certainly could provide information about maintenance operations that would be useful for espionage—or for a future attempted cyber-attack.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593755&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For All Mankind imagines a space race that leaves fewer people out</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1592213</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For All Mankind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ron d moore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1592213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA["A look at what might have been—and what still might be."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_TV_For_All_Mankind_key_art_16_9-800x450.jpg" alt="Promotional image for Apple TV show For All Mankind."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_TV_For_All_Mankind_key_art_16_9.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2160" data-width="3840">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.apple.com/">Apple</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>At the heart of all good science fiction lies one vast and deceptively simple question: what if? <em>For All Mankind</em>, the latest outing from writer and producer Ron D. Moore, explicitly takes that <em>what if</em> as its core premise and logline, asking: what if the space race never ended?</p>
<p>The show's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/06/apple-debuts-first-trailer-for-sci-fi-tv-series-for-all-mankind/">first trailer</a> showed us the motivation for continuing the race: what if, at the height of the Cold War, the Soviet Union was first to put a man on the moon? What if Apollo 11, rather than a great leap for mankind, was a footnote in the history books? What would that <em>mean</em>, and what would happen next?</p>
<p>It feels intentional that Apple should launch its new streaming TV service with a show literally about launching, about refusing to accept second place as a loss, about the audacity of reaching for the literal stars. And it seems fitting that the company would have shared the first two episodes of that vision on the larger-than-life IMAX screen at the National Air and Space Museum in Washington, DC, surrounded by <a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/lunar-module-2-apollo">actual artifacts</a> of <a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/capsule-gemini-iv">crewed spaceflight</a> on all sides.</p>
<p>Alas that the screening was only two episodes because yours truly left the theater dying to see what comes next.</p>
<p><strong>(Very minor spoilers for the first two episodes of <em>For All Mankind</em> follow.)</strong></p>
<h2>Larger than life</h2>
<p>It has been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/series/apollo-the-greatest-leap/">50 years</a> since Neil Armstrong's "one small step" ricocheted around the world. The men who went to space on Apollo 11 are now iconic and legendary; most people can name either Buzz Aldrin or Neil Armstrong, if not both, even if they can't remember Michael Collins (who remained in orbit).</p>
<p>Astronauts captivated—continue to captivate—our imagination. A few hundred souls, out of all the billions who have ever lived, have escaped our world, seen it from the outside with their own eyes. The men of Apollo 11 were legends in their own time and in ours. And they, like their mission, are a sideline in <em>For All Mankind</em>, which instead elevates the stories of others to mythic status in their own right.</p>
<p>Instead, as the series begins, the figures looming over it are not those flying high above, but those feuding down below. Our story follows astronaut Ed Baldwin (Joel Kinnaman), a stand-in for real-life Apollo 10 commander Thomas Stafford. Apollo 10 served as a "dress rehearsal" for the eventual Moon landing, with astronauts in a lunar module descending to within about eight miles of the lunar surface before returning to orbit.</p>
<p>In our history, where Apollo 11 was a success, that level of preparation and testing seemed wise. In an alternate history, where Apollo 11 came too late, the choice <em>not</em> to land earlier suddenly looms large, kicking off internecine political conflict at every level.</p>
<p>Baldwin is joined by colleague and foil Gordo Stevens (Michael Dorman), a replacement for real-life Apollo 10 lunar module pilot Eugene Cernan. Where Baldwin is the square-jawed, right-stuff astronaut trope made manifest, Stevens embodies the hard-drinking, philandering, hotshot fighter pilot. Each of the men of course has a wife to match, and the women, too, are foils to each other. Karen Baldwin (Shantel VanSanten) seemingly strives to be the housewife and mother the still-military atmosphere of NASA circa 1969 demands, while Tracy Stevens (Sarah Jones) exhibits markedly less patience for the constraints that life can bring with it.</p>
<p>The plot also makes room for two other threads, both telling the stories of girls and women who chafe against their circumstances. Margo Madison (Wrenn Schmidt) replaces the real-life <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/2019/07/inside-apollo-mission-control-seen-by-first-woman-engineer-poppy-northcutt/">Poppy Northcutt</a> as the first (and, at the time, only) woman sitting inside mission control during Apollo. Madison is a protégé of Wernher von Braun (Colm Feore), the real-life director of the Marshall Space Flight Center and <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/centers/marshall/history/vonbraun/bio.html">architect</a> of the Saturn V rocket.</p>
<p>The challenges Madison faces are perhaps the ones you might expect for a woman trying to be taken seriously in an all-male workplace in the 1960s. What you might not expect, however, is the third plot thread, which follows young Aleida Rosales (Olivia Trujillo) and her family as they emigrate from Mexico to Houston in pursuit of the good-old American dream.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_03.jpg"><img alt='Astronaut Ed Baldwin (Joel Kinnaman) flying the Apollo 10 mission.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_03-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_03-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Astronaut Ed Baldwin (Joel Kinnaman) flying the Apollo 10 mission.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_03.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Astronaut Ed Baldwin (Joel Kinnaman) flying the Apollo 10 mission.</a> (credit: Apple)</p></div>
<h2>As real as fiction gets</h2>
<p>I would be remiss to discuss a show made with the budget and care applied to <em>For All Mankind</em> and not address the obvious hook: the space porn.</p>
<p>The scenes taking place in space, screened at a state-of-the-art IMAX facility, were a joy. Every shot of the <em>Columbia</em> and <em>Eagle</em> gliding silently (yes, silently) through space, of a massive rocket readying for liftoff, of Baldwin and Stevens folded into a lander that would never land, delivers all the wonder that feats of human engineering deserve. And in every element, <em>For All Mankind</em> displays painstaking attention to detail.</p>
<p>"We said from the beginning of the production to all the departments that we thought it was really important for the show to have a sense of authenticity to it, even though you were doing something that was fundamentally not true," Moore said during a Q&amp;A panel after the screening.</p>
<p>Moore added:</p>
<blockquote><p>The closer it was to reality, the more likely it was that the audience would go on this journey—take the risk and laugh and cry with the characters along the way. So, every department on the show, in the writers' room, had researchers and historians. We went back to the original NASA plans whenever possible.</p>
<p>Our production designer, Dan Fisher, who designed all the sets of the show, recreated Mission Control in such exacting detail that even the ceiling tiles [are] the same as the ceiling tiles in the original mission control. When we were on set, we had technical consultants and former astronauts who were actually there, who would walk the cast through how to operate the command module and the lunar module. We had people that would talk to the background players in Mission Control, so that people weren't just randomly pushing buttons—they knew exactly what the console did and who they were talking to on those headsets, and that permeated the entire production.</p></blockquote>
<p>The sense of authenticity shoots straight through every scene. Interstitial moments use as much original footage as possible for key political figures such as Presidents John F. Kennedy and Richard M. Nixon, and the soundtrack drips with 1960s rock and pop throughout, helping ground the audience in a strong sense of time and place.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_05.jpg"><img alt='Man on the moon? Eh... what about women?'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_05-640x320.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_05-1280x639.jpg 2x" alt='Man on the moon? Eh... what about women?' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/For_All_Mankind_Unit_Photo_05.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Man on the moon? Eh... what about women?</a> (credit: Apple)</p></div>
<h2>What still might be</h2>
<p>Moore's previous work, both in the Star Trek franchise and especially with <em>Battlestar Galactica</em>, makes clear that he does not shy away from the implications of politics in his work. And indeed, both the workaday questions of funding and who saves face, as well as the grander philosophical questions were already on display in just two episodes.</p>
<p><em>Mankind</em> begins during the early months of the Nixon administration, locked into the Manichean worldview of the Cold War. But in the same way <em>Battlestar</em> was grappling with a post-9/11 world, <em>Mankind</em> is in every way, inescapably, a show made in and about the Trump era. Moore and company ask us in the subtext of almost every single scene not only to grapple with the <em>what ifs</em> underlying US politics and the history of NASA but also something much more profound.</p>
<p>Sometime after the third episode, we know from the trailers, the alternate-universe NASA of <em>For All Mankind</em> is going to try something that our real NASA <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/04/netflix-film-examines-why-nasa-shunned-women-astronauts-in-early-days/">had already rejected</a> in 1969: admitting women as astronaut candidates (including wronged wife Tracy Stevens).</p>
<p>According to promo photos, at least one of the potential women astronauts in this alternate universe is African-American. In the real world, an American woman would not reach orbit until 1983, when Sally Ride became the first. It also took until 1983 for Guion Bluford, the first black US astronaut, to reach space. (Although NASA was at least <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/16/us/ed-dwight-was-set-to-be-the-first-black-astronaut-heres-why-that-never-happened.html">thinking about desegregating space</a> in the 1960s.) Almost another decade had to go by before NASA sent a black woman, Mae Jemison, into space on a 1992 mission.</p>
<p>What if we were motivated to try something new and different decades earlier due to an embarrassing Cold War loss? </p>
<p>The show is both "a look at what might have been—and what still might be," Moore said in introductory remarks, and even in the first two episodes, <em>For All Mankind</em> demands of the viewer a reckoning. The first shots of an eager world watching the Moon landing take place not in Florida, Houston, or Washington, DC, or even in Soviet Russia. They happen in Mexico. In one of the most profoundly human moments of the first episode, a family comes together, speaking subtitled Spanish, to watch one of humanity's greatest achievements to date and remember.</p>
<p>In the second episode, an influential congressman wants to leverage a disillusioned astronaut into a showboating hearing that will allow him to move the players around Washington like pawns on a chessboard. The astronaut chooses to go to Washington—but then shoulders responsibility and blame himself rather than offloading it onto the congressman's chosen target.</p>
<p>What if, rather than dodging responsibility, our leaders embraced it?</p>
<p>What if, the show asks us, over and over again, in scene after scene after scene. What if we respected our rivals' accomplishments and used them to spur our own advancement? What if we expanded our view of who matters? What if duty, honor, and country were genuinely guiding principles?</p>
<p>The pointed parallels are too many to ignore. If <em>For All Mankind</em> is truly a look at what still might be, then it wants us to think beyond space and look around closer to home to consider what that means.</p>
<p>For All Mankind <em>premieres with three episodes on Apple TV+ on Friday, November 1, before moving to a weekly release format for the remainder of the season.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1592213&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>HBO Max will bring up the streaming-video rear in May 2020 for $15/mo</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593719</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 11:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Machkovech]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game of Thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hbo max]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nbc peacock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video streaming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593719</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Even NBC Peacock will launch earlier; joined by reveal of <em>Game of Thrones</em> prequel.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/hbo-logo-800x450.png" alt="HBO Max will bring up the streaming-video rear in May 2020 for $15/mo"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/hbo-logo.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1440" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: WarnerMedia)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>AT&amp;T Time Warner subsidiary WarnerMedia hosted an hours-long presentation on Tuesday to confirm everything under the sun about HBO Max, the company's new streaming-video service slated to launch next year. We had already seen <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/07/att-starts-restricting-time-warner-shows-to-its-own-streaming-service/">a number of announcements about existing and classic series</a> coming to the service, but now we know <a href="https://pressroom.warnermediagroup.com/na/media-release/hbo-max/warnermedia-unveils-hbo-max">its launch window and price</a>: $14.99/month, starting in May 2020.</p>
<p>Let's start with some asterisks on that price point. While $15 is the highest point in the current streaming-video fray, AT&amp;T Time Warner already charges $15/mo for HBO Now, and HBO Max will effectively make the existing service redundant. Should you already pay for HBO as part of an AT&amp;T cable-TV subscription package, you'll get HBO Max access for free. However, that may not be the case if you pay for HBO through other cable providers; "we are in active discussions with our distributors and look forward to offering their customers seamless access to this great product," the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, if you don't pay for HBO but subscribe to any of AT&amp;T's "premium video, mobile, and broadband services," you <em>might</em> be offered free HBO Max service... if you upgrade to a new AT&amp;T bundle package "at no additional charge." Whether those new bundles will require specific terms or additional purchases remains unclear, however.</p>
<p>After its paid launch in 2020, WarnerMedia plans to launch an "ad-supported" version of HBO Max in 2021, but the company wasn't ready to reveal how that would work (ie, whether such a product would combine a monthly fee and advertisements a la the ad-supported Hulu tier). In terms of regions, WarnerMedia says HBO Max will premiere in the US in 2020 and will expand to Latin America and Europe by 2025. (Really? No hints about Canada yet?)</p>
<h2><em>House</em> odds</h2>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/hbo-got-prequel-980x1452.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Arguably the biggest announcement at Tuesday's HBO Max event was an announcement of a new <em>Game of Thrones</em> series, but it's likely not an HBO Max exclusive.                      [credit:
                        WarnerMedia                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>We already knew that HBO Max had secured the streaming rights to TV series like <em>Friends</em> and <em>Fresh Prince of Bel-Air</em>, along with a truckload of content from the likes of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/08/hbo-max-secures-exclusive-usa-streaming-rights-for-dr-who-other-bbc-series/">BBC America</a>. The past week has seen WarnerMedia announce <a href="https://pressroom.warnermediagroup.com/na/brands/hbo-max/media-releases">a bunch of new, original direct-to-Max content</a>, and the company capped off its Tuesday event with a few more announcements.</p>
<p>Arguably the biggest, albeit least surprising, was official word that a previously announced <em>Game of Thrones</em> prequel series has a name: <em>House of the Dragon</em>. As anticipated, this series, which has at least one ten-episode season on order, will be based on the 2018 George R. R. Martin book, <em>Fire &amp; Blood</em>, so it will revolve around the history of House Targaryen 300 years before the events of the primary <em>Game of Thrones</em> book and TV series.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/heres-what-we-know-so-far-about-long-awaited-game-of-thrones-prequel/">Multiple prequel projects had been rumored</a>, however, and it's unclear whether to expect others. (In fact, on Tuesday, we heard word that <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/game-of-thrones-prequel-pilot-dead-hbo-jane-goldman-naomi-watts-1202771609/">one rumored prequel project was canceled</a> before being officially announced.) WarnerMedia did not confirm whether <em>House of the Dragon</em>, or any of the company's other freshly announced shows and one-off specials, would be ready in time for the service's May 2020 launch.</p>
<p>HBO Max finally claimed dibs on <em>Raised by Wolves</em>, a ten-episode TV series from showrunner and Director Ridley Scott, which had originally been pegged as a TNT original series. Meanwhile, the company's comic-minded teams at DC Entertainment showed up to announce <a href="https://pressroom.warnermediagroup.com/na/media-release/hbo-max/greg-berlanti-announces-new-dc-projects-hbo-max-strange-adventures-and-green-lantern">a few live-action HBO Max exclusives</a>, including a high-school drama produced by Elizabeth Banks (<em>Pitch Perfect</em>), a superhero anthology series with criss-crossing tales, and a very vaguely worded "Green Lantern-inspired series." (This three-series coup, on top of other DC-related exclusives on HBO Max, sure make us wonder how long the standalone DC Universe streaming service will last.)</p>
<p>In addition to today's list of new series, WarnerMedia announced the following existing series would become streaming exclusives on HBO Max during its "first year" of operation: <em>South Park</em>, <em>Rick &amp; Morty</em>, <em>The O.C.</em>, <em>Aqua Teen Hunger Force</em>, <em>Robot Chicken</em>, <em>Space Ghost Coast to Coast</em>, <em>The Bachelor</em>, <em>Impractical Jokers</em>, <em>The Closer</em>, <em>Rizzolli and Isles</em>, <em>Major Crimes</em>, <em>The Alienist</em>, <em>The West Wing</em>, <em>United Shades of America with Kamau Bell</em>, <em>This is Life with Lisa Ling</em>, and <em>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown</em>. Of everything on that list, <em>South Park</em> is arguably the biggest WarnerMedia coup, since that likely means a deal was worked out with Viacom—which already operates CBS All Access, itself a paid streaming-video service.</p>
<p>Really, thinking about the ecosystem of existing streaming services leads us to ask: will HBO Max land with a bang or a thud? By the time May 2020 rolls around, we will have already seen months of activity from this November's new services, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/see-on-apple-tv-less-game-of-thrones-more-unintentionally-funny-syfy/">Apple TV+</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/we-now-know-what-disney-will-look-like-plus-a-few-new-exclusive-series/">Disney+</a>, not to mention the April 2020 launch of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/09/nbc-peacock-adds-to-streaming-glut-next-april-with-15000-hours-of-shows/">NBC Peacock</a>. Will the "costs the same as HBO Now" argument help WarnerMedia's new service rise to the top of the competitive streaming pool? We suppose that depends on whether potential subscribers have been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/08/disney-fights-streaming-account-sharing-with-help-from-cable-industry/">sharing accounts</a> this whole time.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593719&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guidemaster: Our favorite accessories for iPhones and iPads</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1587051</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 11:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidemaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile accessories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1587051</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We tested dozens of keyboards, chargers, and more to find the iOS gear worth buying.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1020683020-800x511.jpg" alt="Guidemaster: Our favorite accessories for iPhones and iPads"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1020683020.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3817" data-width="5981">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=Sitthiphong%20Thadakun%20%2F%20EyeEm&amp;assettype=image&amp;agreements=pa:66427&amp;family=creative&amp;sort=best#license"> Sitthiphong Thadakun / EyeEm</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>With the popularity of the iPhone and iPad comes a sea of accessories for both devices. While iPhones and iPads are powerful devices on their own, they can be enhanced by accessories that protect them, let you use them in different ways, and make them work harder for you.</p>
<p>But sifting through the plethora of cases, cables, keyboards, adapters and other accessories available today is a daunting task. It's made even harder thanks to all the different companies making accessories—while that means you can find iPhone and iPad accessories to fit any budget, it also means that not all of those accessories are worth buying (the cheapest option isn't always the way to go, nor is the most expensive option the best out there).</p>
<p>To make things easier for you, Ars has spent the fall testing a slew of iPhone and iPad accessories in order to find the best and most useful ones that are worth your hard-earned dollars.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h3 data-no-jump>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul class="toc">
      <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h1">Best Lightning-to-USB-C cable</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h2">Anker PowerLine+ II</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h3">Best portable battery pack</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h4">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h5">ZMI PowerPack 20000</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h6">Best wall charger</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h7">Nekteck 4-port 72W USB-C PD Charger</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h8">RAVPower PD Pioneer 45W GaN Wall Charger</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h9">Best wireless charger</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h10">RAVPower Fast Charger RP-PC034</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h11">Best W1/H1 headphones</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h12">Beats Powerbeats Pro</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h13">Best 3.5mm to Bluetooth adapter</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h14">Fiio &mu;BTR</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h15">Best portable speaker</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h16">UE Wonderboom 2</a>
      </li>
              <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h17">Best Lightning flash drive</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h18">SanDisk iXpand</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h19">Best USB-C flash drive</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h20">SanDisk Ultra Dual Drive USB Type-C</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h21">Best USB-C hub for iPad</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h22">OWC Travel Dock</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h23">Best game controller</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h24">Microsoft Xbox One Wireless Controller (Model 1708)</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h25">Sony DualShock 4</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h26">Best iPhone and iPad stands</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h27">Pop Socket</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h28">Tomtoc Play Stand</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h29">Stump Stand</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h30">Best iPhone cases</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h31">Speck Presidio Pro</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h32">Otterbox Commuter</a>
      </li>
              <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h33">Best photo/video accessory</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h34">DJI Osmo Mobile 3</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h35">Best iPad stylus</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h36">Apple Pencil</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h37">Best iPad keyboard case</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h38">Apple Smart Keyboard</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-2">
                <a href="#h39">Best keyboard</a>
      </li>
          <li class="depth-3">
                <a href="#h40">Logitech K780</a>
      </li>
        </ul>

<h2>Best Lightning-to-USB-C cable</h2>
<h3>Anker PowerLine+ II</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerlightningtousbc1.jpg"><img alt='Anker&#039;s PowerLine+ II USB-C to Lightning cable.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerlightningtousbc1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerlightningtousbc1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Anker&#039;s PowerLine+ II USB-C to Lightning cable.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerlightningtousbc1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Anker's PowerLine+ II USB-C to Lightning cable.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>One lightning cable is never enough, even if you just have one Apple device. <a href="https://amzn.to/31H1lQe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker's PowerLine+ II</a> family of cords are arguably better than Apple's own lightning cables because they're built to last longer and they're MFi-certified. The double-braided nylon cables won't break or fray like others might, and they come in different lengths so you don't have to be so physically close to a power source while you're charging your iPhone or iPad. They also support iPhone fast charging when connected to Apple or other Anker PD chargers. While a charging cable is only one part of the puzzle in terms of power delivery and charging speed, Anker's Powerline+ II cords are solid options that provide all of the features you'd get from an Apple cable plus even better build quality and value for the money.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerpl-300x375.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerLine+ II USB-C to Lightning Cable product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerLine+ II USB-C to Lightning Cable                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_50698746" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/31H1lQe" target="_blank">
                                $21.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best portable battery pack</h2>
<h3>Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</h3>
<h3>ZMI PowerPack 20000</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ZMI-and-Anker-battery-packs-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The ZMI PowerPack 20000 (left) and the Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux (center) next to a 10.5-inch iPad Air.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The benefits of a portable battery should be obvious by now: when your iPhone or iPad is low on power and there’s no outlet in sight, it’ll keep your device kicking. If you need a battery to primarily charge an iPhone, get <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-Bank-Max-10000mAh-18W-Pro-USB-C-More-iPad-Charger-S10-11-11-11-Anker-PowerCore-2018-Portable-Redux-PD-3-3XL-10000-8-X-XS-Delivery-Samsung-Powe%2F257587388&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker’s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a>. It’s not the cheapest device in its class, but it has an 18W USB-C Power Delivery (PD) that can safely charge newer iPhones (and most other <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/08/samsung-makes-the-galaxy-note-10-official/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">non-Galaxy Note 10+</a> phones) at maximum speeds. The battery itself can recharge quickly at 18W through that USB-C PD port. There’s a USB-A port rated at 12W beyond that, though the whole pack can only output 18W in total at a time.</p>

<p>Still, its 10,000mAh (or 36Wh) capacity is enough to get an iPhone 11 roughly two charges. There’s a USB-C to USB-C charging cable in the box. And most notably, it’s supremely portable, weighing less than seven ounces and measuring just 106×52.3×25.5mm. That means it can easily fit in a pants pocket or handbag. Having this kind of fast-charging power in a design that’s this small and well-built makes the PowerCore 10000 PD Redux ideal for travel. Just remember that you need an MFi-certified <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/guidemaster-ars-tested-and-found-the-best-usb-c-accessories-you-can-get-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C</a> to Lightning cable like the PowerLine+ II above to actually take advantage of its fast charging speeds with an iPhone.</p>
<p>If you need a battery pack for charging a newer iPad, meanwhile, get the <a href="https://amzn.to/2JwHcpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ZMI PowerPack 20000</a>. It includes a 45W USB-C PD port that’s powerful enough to charge the latest iPad Pros—and various 12- and 13-inch laptops—at their fastest possible rate. (Those laptops just have to charge at 15V/3A, as the PowerPack maxes out at 40W of power at a 20V charge.) There are two USB-A ports that output around 12W of power alongside that, though the whole pack can only output a maximum of 45W at any given time. The 20,000mAh (or 72Wh) capacity is enough to give roughly</p>
<p>one and a half charges to an 11-inch iPad Pro. It’s not USB-IF certified, but we’ve used it safely for about a year now, and there are no widespread reports of failure across the Web. Again, the PowerPack 20000 stands out in the design department: its metallic finish feels premium, and at 14 ounces and 160×82×21mm, it’s more compact than most power banks with this level of power. Plus, at $70, it’s more affordable than most of its peers, and it includes a USB-C to USB-C fast charging cable in the box.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerpd-300x375.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_56187878" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-Bank-Max-10000mAh-18W-Pro-USB-C-More-iPad-Charger-S10-11-11-11-Anker-PowerCore-2018-Portable-Redux-PD-3-3XL-10000-8-X-XS-Delivery-Samsung-Powe%2F257587388&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_56187878">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-Bank-Max-10000mAh-18W-Pro-USB-C-More-iPad-Charger-S10-11-11-11-Anker-PowerCore-2018-Portable-Redux-PD-3-3XL-10000-8-X-XS-Delivery-Samsung-Powe%2F257587388&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $45.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/36bB7sv">Amazon $45.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-Bank-Max-10000mAh-18W-Pro-USB-C-More-iPad-Charger-S10-11-11-11-Anker-PowerCore-2018-Portable-Redux-PD-3-3XL-10000-8-X-XS-Delivery-Samsung-Powe%2F257587388&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/36bB7sv"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/zmi-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="ZMI PowerPack 20000 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">ZMI PowerPack 20000                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_93030230" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2JwHcpQ" target="_blank">
                                $68.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best wall charger</h2>
<h3>Nekteck 4-port 72W USB-C PD Charger</h3>
<h3>RAVPower PD Pioneer 45W GaN Wall Charger</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/RavPower-and-Nekteck-chargers-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The RAVPower PD Pioneer 45W GaN Wall Charger (left) and Nekteck 4-port 72W USB-C PD Charger (right).
                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Though Apple now includes an 18W fast charger in the box with new iPhone 11 Pros, the vast majority of iOS devices continue to ship with power adapters that don’t take full advantage of their charging capabilities. Unfortunately, you still have to pay extra for a good third-party USB-C PD wall charger in order to refill most iPhones and iPads as fast as possible.</p>
<p>We have a couple of preferred options: if you need a charger for your desk, try <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGalaxy-C-Wall-S8-Pixel-S8-Black-4-port-USB-IF-Nekteck-Pro-Charger-72W-60W-MacBook-Type-C-USB-Plus-Station-2017-PD-XL-Note-8-Certified-Delivery-Charge%2F618192493&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nekteck’s 4-port 72W USB-C PD Charger</a>. It’s a small brick that plugs into an outlet and carries four charging ports, including a 60W USB-C PD port that can easily charge all iPhones and iPads at max speeds (and charge various laptops to boot). There are three 12W USB-A ports as well, so you can refill an iPhone and iPad simultaneously, albeit with one device charging at less-than-optimum speeds. (As its name implies, the device can output a maximum of 72W at once.) There’s a USB-C to USB-C charging cable in the box, and the charger is USB-IF certified, meaning it has been verified to work safely by the body that maintains the USB standard.</p>
<p>For a wall charger that you can take with you more easily, we like <a href="https://amzn.to/2NnIp3G" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RAVPower’s PD Pioneer 45W GaN Wall Charger</a>. As you might guess, this charger uses gallium nitride (GaN), a semiconductor that allows chargers like this to provide the power of traditional silicon in a smaller footprint. Its rectangular design measures 72×54×14.2mm and weighs 2.6 ounces, which makes it significantly smaller and slimmer than a traditional wall charger. It’s more elongated than other GaN chargers like <a href="https://amzn.to/32VvpZE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker’s PowerPort Atom PD 1</a>, so it might take up more room on a power strip, but its foldable prongs and slim profile makes it easier to squeeze into tighter spaces. (Between an outlet and a piece of furniture, for instance.)</p>
<p>There’s only one port here, but it’s a 45W USB-C PD connector that, again, is capable of charging all iPhones and iPads as fast as possible. This one isn’t USB-IF certified and technically goes against the official USB-C spec by supporting Quick Charge 3.0 over its port, but various chargers have done that in the past without issue. We couldn’t find any sustained complaints over reliability online, and we’ve tested the charger with various devices over the past several months with no problems. It’s not the most affordable 45W wall charger, and you’ll need to supply your own USB-C to Lightning or <a href="https://amzn.to/2WuRegx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to USB–C cable</a>, but we think the combination of power and travel-friendly design is worth a few bucks extra.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/necteck-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Nekteck 72W USB-C PD Charger product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Nekteck 72W USB-C PD Charger                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_70182177" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGalaxy-C-Wall-S8-Pixel-S8-Black-4-port-USB-IF-Nekteck-Pro-Charger-72W-60W-MacBook-Type-C-USB-Plus-Station-2017-PD-XL-Note-8-Certified-Delivery-Charge%2F618192493&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_70182177">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGalaxy-C-Wall-S8-Pixel-S8-Black-4-port-USB-IF-Nekteck-Pro-Charger-72W-60W-MacBook-Type-C-USB-Plus-Station-2017-PD-XL-Note-8-Certified-Delivery-Charge%2F618192493&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $29.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/346CAOX">Amazon $29.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGalaxy-C-Wall-S8-Pixel-S8-Black-4-port-USB-IF-Nekteck-Pro-Charger-72W-60W-MacBook-Type-C-USB-Plus-Station-2017-PD-XL-Note-8-Certified-Delivery-Charge%2F618192493&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/346CAOX"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/rpower-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="RAVPower PD Pioneer 45W GaN Charger product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">RAVPower PD Pioneer 45W GaN Charger                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_97046422" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NnIp3G" target="_blank">
                                $31.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best wireless charger</h2>
<h3>RAVPower Fast Charger RP-PC034</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ravpower1_1.jpg"><img alt='RAVPower&#039;s RP-PC034 wireless charger.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ravpower1_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ravpower1_1-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='RAVPower&#039;s RP-PC034 wireless charger.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ravpower1_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">RAVPower's RP-PC034 wireless charger.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>

<p><a href="https://amzn.to/32GnTC1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RAVPower's Qi fast charger</a> may not stick out in a bucket of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/04/guidemaster-the-best-qi-wireless-charging-pads-for-your-smartphone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wireless charging pads</a>, but it sets itself apart by providing the most energy in a short amount of time. On average, smartphones had 34% juice after just one hour sitting on the RAVPower charging pad, so you'll get a solid amount of juice in your device even if you have little time to spare for charging. It may not be the fanciest looking charger or even the thinnest we've come across, but it still has a solid design that is made better by rubberized rings on its top and bottom that prevent the pad from moving and prevent your smartphone from sliding off.</p>
<p>We also appreciate that RAVPower includes a fast-charge capable AC adapter with this pad, so you're guaranteed to get max charging speeds without needing any additional adapters. If you want a wireless charging pad that looks a bit nicer, <a href="https://amzn.to/2q2yo49" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mophie's Charge Stream Pad+</a> is a good option that performs nearly as well in terms of charging time, but it costs a bit more money.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/51Vxr2JGnqL._SL1000_ravpower034-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="RAVPower RP-PC034 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">RAVPower RP-PC034                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_37006859" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32GnTC1" target="_blank">
                                $29.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best W1/H1 headphones</h2>
<h3>Beats Powerbeats Pro</h3>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Beats-Powerbeats-Pro.jpg"><img alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Beats-Powerbeats-Pro-640x363.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Beats-Powerbeats-Pro-1280x726.jpg 2x" alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Beats-Powerbeats-Pro.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Beats Powerbeats Pro.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>For better or worse, modern iOS devices are adamant about making you use Bluetooth headphones. The iPhone ditched the headphone jack back in 2016, the iPad Pro followed suit last year, and neither looks likely to bring it back any time soon. Along the way, Apple has furthered a trend in which a manufacturer’s headphones work best with its own platform.</p>
<p>In this case, headphones with Apple’s H1 and W1 wireless chips—which are currently exclusive to Apple’s AirPods and headphones from the company’s Beats subsidiary—are more convenient to use with iPhones and iPads. They have a simplified pairing process, immediately get remembered across your iCloud devices, keep a more stable and power-efficient wireless connection, and, with H1 headphones, let you access Siri just by saying “Hey Siri.” So while there are <em>tons</em> of pairs that sound better and may be more comfortable to wear, Apple’s own pairs present the least friction—again, for better or worse.</p>
<p>We're still in the process of testing the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/apple-announces-airpods-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just-announced AirPods Pro</a>, but if you don’t mind giving in to ecosystem lock-in, our favorite Apple-made headphones<em> for now</em> are the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beats Powerbeats Pro</a>. They’re true wireless earphones that do everything the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regular AirPods</a> do, but better. They have a more dynamic sound, for one: like any true wireless headphone, they’re still limited in soundstage and finer detail, but their bass-forward profile is lively and fun, if not exactly accurate. This is largely due to the Powerbeats Pro creating a tighter seal in the ear: it’s not <em>airtight</em>, so the outside wo­rld won’t be blocked out completely, but it lets in far less noise than the AirPods, which can be difficult to use in louder environments.</p>
<p>The Powerbeats Pro’s battery life is far superior to any other true wireless headphone we’ve used, lasting about 11 hours per charge in our testing—where we stream music to headphones continuously at 67% volume—with a total of 24 hours advertised through its charging case. By comparison, Apple rates the AirPods and AirPods Pro at five hours each, again bumped up to 24 with their charging cases. Either way, the Powerbeats Pro pair just as easily with iOS devices and keep just as reliable a Bluetooth connection—they can still experience dropouts in extremely hectic environments (think something like Times Square) but that remains the case with most true wireless pairs.</p>
<p>Their design is more agreeable, too. Whereas the AirPods can tend to hang loose in the ear, the sporty ear hooks of the Powerbeats Pro keep them nice and secure, even during intense workouts and runs. Their IPX4 sweat-resistance rating is relatively mild for exercise-minded earphones, but it’s equal to the AirPods Pro and a step up from the AirPods, which have no formal rating at all. Beyond that, they have physical playback and volume buttons that are mirrored on each earpiece, instead of relying on less precise touch controls. (And in the AirPods Pro's case, having no built-in volume controls whatsoever.)</p>
<p>There are two major drawbacks to the Powerbeats Pro. First, their case is almost comically huge, to the point where it could be difficult to fit in most pants pockets. You’ll usually want to leave it at home or in a separate bag. Second, they're undeniably expensive: at $250, and without any special app-driven features or active noise cancellation a la the AirPods Pro, they certainly carry the “tax” that typically comes with the Beats/Apple branding. The AirPods and the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FBeats-Solo3-Wireless-On-Ear-Headphones%2F54594385&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on-ear Beats Solo 3 Wireless</a> are decent alternatives with similar W1/H1 chip benefits if you want something slightly more affordable. But if you can pay the premium (or just see them on sale), the Powerbeats Pro are arguably the best true wireless headphones for anyone, let alone iOS users.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bpb-300x210.jpg"
                                    alt="Beats Powerbeats Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Beats Powerbeats Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_40088173" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_40088173">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $199.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2PpKRcL">Amazon $199.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $199.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2PpKRcL"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best 3.5mm to Bluetooth adapter</h2>
<h3>Fiio μBTR</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Fiio-UBTR-2-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The Fiio μBTR can make your older wired headphones (like the Koss Porta Pro here) work over Bluetooth.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>If you’ve already invested in a good pair of wired headphones, though, there are a couple of ways to continue using them with an iPhone or iPad Pro. The simplest would be to <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=iOSAccessoriesGM&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLightning-to-3-5-mm-Headphone-Jack-Adapter%2F54738078" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buy a Lightning-to-3.5mm dongle</a>: it’s not an elegant solution, and it’s frustrating that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/09/apple-wont-include-a-headphone-jack-dongle-with-new-iphones-anymore/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple no longer packages one</a> with new iPhones, but it’s only $9 and works easily enough. With newer iPad Pros, it’s the same deal, only you’d need a <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=iOSAccessoriesGM&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FUSB-C-to-3-5-mm-Headphone-Jack-Adapter%2F152170496" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to 3.5mm dongle</a>.</p>
<p>If you want at least some of the convenience of a wireless headphone, however, you could buy a Bluetooth headphone adapter. This pairs with your phone or tablet over Bluetooth, receives that source device’s audio, and sends it to whatever pair of 3.5mm headphones you plug into the adapter. You’re then free to keep your device charging across the room, keep it in a separate pocket or bag, and generally use it without any wires attached.</p>
<p>Of the Bluetooth headphone adapters we’ve tested, our favorite is the <a href="https://amzn.to/32TeBCF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fiio μBTR</a>. It paired as easily as any other modern Bluetooth device and presented no significant connection hiccups or latency issues in testing. Sending audio over Bluetooth means an inherent loss in audio quality compared to a wired connection, but for what it is the μBTR doesn’t sacrifice too much fidelity. Importantly, it supports the AAC audio codec, which makes music sound noticeably sharper on an iPhone or iPad than the default SBC codec. (It also supports aptX if you ever use it with a Mac or Android device.) Just know that if your headphones have a particularly high impedance, you’ll likely need to turn up the volume a bit higher than usual.</p>
<p>The μBTR’s stick-style design is tiny and easily portable, with a built-in clip that neatly attaches to a pants or shirt pocket. There are dedicated buttons for volume, pause/play, and voice assistant activation, though its volume level won’t sync with your source device. Its 8-9 hours of battery life should be enough to get through a typical workday, and it charges quickly through a USB-C port. The built-in mic isn’t great for making calls or using Siri, but it’s at least there in a pinch. It’d still be nice if your iPhone didn’t make devices like this desirable in the first place, but for $30, the μBTR isn’t a huge investment for something that effectively makes your most beloved headphones more convenient on the go.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/filo-300x194.jpg"
                                    alt="Fiio μBTR product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Fiio μBTR                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_29581625" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32TeBCF" target="_blank">
                                $27.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best portable speaker</h2>
<h3>UE Wonderboom 2</h3>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"><img alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The UE Wonderboom 2.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>While the built-in speakers on iPhones and iPads have improved as the years have rolled on—particularly on recent iPad Pro models—they still aren’t the best for truly enjoying music. A good Bluetooth speaker can address that. We wouldn’t recommend paying a ton here given the inherent compromises with Bluetooth audio: you typically need to pay a premium for something large enough to sound passable, and at that point you might as well buy a Wi-Fi speaker that’ll sound significantly better. But for less than $100, the <a href="https://amzn.to/3481m0Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UE Wonderboom 2</a> achieves most of the things you’d want a portable wireless speaker to do well.</p>
<p>Chief among those: it’s <em>really </em>portable, with a squat candle-like shape that’s just 104mm high and 95.3mm wide. It’s also supremely durable, with an IP67 rating—meaning it’s waterproof and dustproof—and a fabric- and rubber-coated design that floats in water and can withstand drops from five or so feet without any signs of scuffing. A built-in elastic loop makes it easy to clip to a bag or hang from a towel hook. The giant volume buttons and playback controls on top are generally easy to comprehend and operate, though you can only skip tracks forward, not backward. Battery life is fine, if not spectacular, at about 9-10 hours a charge, but the speaker disappointingly charges over microUSB instead of a faster USB-C standard.</p>
<p>No Bluetooth speaker this small will produce fantastic audio in a vacuum. The Wonderboom 2 doesn’t change that: it can distort at the highest volumes, it loses detail with more complex tracks, and it has just about nothing when it comes to deep sub-bass. But given the context, it plays loud and relatively balanced, with good mids that make vocals nicely clear. You usually won’t hear the whole of a song, but you’ll get enough to make it enjoyable. You can use a second Wonderboom speaker to play in stereo as well. On its own, we found the Wonderboom 2 to sound cleaner than the <a href="https://amzn.to/2Pubptq" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Soundcore Flare</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/2Jyh7GI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribit StormBox</a>, two speakers we’ve recommended in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/08/guidemaster-the-best-back-to-school-gadgets-to-aid-studying-woes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">past gift guides</a>, so it more than holds its own in the sub-$100 range.</p>
<p>In all, the Wonderboom 2 is something of an ideal portable Bluetooth speaker: it’s rugged, travel-friendly, easy to use, good-looking, and fun-enough sounding. For the shower, pool parties, or just better personal listening at home, it’s a nifty complement to your iPhone or iPad.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ue-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="UE Wonderboom 2 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">UE Wonderboom 2                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_51165986" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/3481m0Z" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_51165986">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/3481m0Z">Amazon $79.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FUltimate-Ears-WONDER-BOOM-2-Speaker-System%2F208849505%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $99.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $79.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/3481m0Z"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FUltimate-Ears-WONDER-BOOM-2-Speaker-System%2F208849505%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Best Lightning flash drive</h2>
<h3>SanDisk iXpand</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/iXpand1.jpg"><img alt='SanDisk&#039;s iXpand Lightning flash drive.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/iXpand1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/iXpand1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='SanDisk&#039;s iXpand Lightning flash drive.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/iXpand1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">SanDisk's iXpand Lightning flash drive.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Lots of people in my life could use more storage on their iPhones. Even if 32GB iPhones are a thing of the past, it’s still easy to fill up your phone’s storage with photos, videos, games, music, and the like. <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSanDisk-32GB-iXpand-USB-3-0-Lightning-Flash-Drive-for-your-iPhone-and-iPad%2F174300526&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SanDisk’s iXpand</a> Flash Drive make it easy to keep track of all your digital belongings while freeing up space on your iPhone or iPad. Its Lightning connector plugs into your device and, using the iXpand app, lets you choose which content you want to transfer to the drive and erase from your device.</p>
<p>The iXpand app takes nothing to learn how to use, and you can see the files on the drive and those on your iPhone from directly in the app. I use mine to remove vacation photos from my iPhone so I can transfer them to my PC, and I appreciate that the iXpand drive saves the image as well as a .mov file for those images that were taken as Live Photos. The drive also supports an auto backup feature that will save all your content every time you plug it in. Starting at $59, it’s an affordable way to make your iPhone or iPad feel a bit more like new.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ixpand-300x169.jpg"
                                    alt="SanDisk iXpand product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">SanDisk iXpand                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_91923470" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/31LRysg" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_91923470">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/31LRysg">Amazon $22.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSanDisk-32GB-iXpand-USB-3-0-Lightning-Flash-Drive-for-your-iPhone-and-iPad%2F174300526&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $23.08</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-ixpand-32gb-usb-3-0-lightning-flash-drive%2F5061603.p%3FskuId%3D5061603&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $27.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/31LRysg"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSanDisk-32GB-iXpand-USB-3-0-Lightning-Flash-Drive-for-your-iPhone-and-iPad%2F174300526&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-ixpand-32gb-usb-3-0-lightning-flash-drive%2F5061603.p%3FskuId%3D5061603&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best USB-C flash drive</h2>
<h3>SanDisk Ultra Dual Drive USB Type-C</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sandiskusbc2.jpg"><img alt='SanDisk&#039;s Ultra Dual Drive USB-C flash drive.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sandiskusbc2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sandiskusbc2-1280x855.jpg 2x" alt='SanDisk&#039;s Ultra Dual Drive USB-C flash drive.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sandiskusbc2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">SanDisk's Ultra Dual Drive USB-C flash drive.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>In the same vein as the iXpand is <a href="https://amzn.to/31HilG3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SanDisk's Ultra Dual Drive</a>, a USB-C flash drive that can help those with USB-C smartphones free up space on their devices. With max 150MB/s read speeds, it's not as fast as some USB-C adapters or hubs, but those devices only serve as bridges between two devices sharing data. SanDisk's drive is handy to have if and when you run out of storage unexpectedly and need to free up space immediately <em>without</em> losing any of your existing data. It's also a convenient sharing device thanks to its retractable design that lets it connect to both USB-C and USB-A devices. As more laptops and smartphones switch to USB-C, SanDisk's dual drive could end up being the only flash drive you need going forward to connect to new and old devices.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sandiskdd-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="SanDisk Ultra Dual Drive USB Type-C product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">SanDisk Ultra Dual Drive USB Type-C                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_23600990" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/31HilG3" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_23600990">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/31HilG3">Amazon $8.97</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-ultra-32gb-usb-3-1-usb-type-c-flash-drive%2F5219000.p%3FskuId%3D5219000&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $11.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/31HilG3"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-ultra-32gb-usb-3-1-usb-type-c-flash-drive%2F5219000.p%3FskuId%3D5219000&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best USB-C hub for iPad</h2>
<h3>OWC Travel Dock</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/owctraveldock1.jpg"><img alt='The OWC Travel Dock.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/owctraveldock1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/owctraveldock1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The OWC Travel Dock.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/owctraveldock1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The OWC Travel Dock.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>The USB-C ports on the newest iPad Pros open the tablets up to a new world of capabilities and accessories, including hubs and docks. While almost any USB-C hub would enhance the versatility of the iPad, <a href="https://amzn.to/32HSFu9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OWC's Travel Dock</a> provides the best combination of features, speed, and portability.</p>
<p>The new hockey-puck-sized hub connects to the iPad (and other USB-C devices) using a built-in cable that hides neatly on its underside when not in use. In our testing, it had solid data transfer speeds that were close to those of docks and hubs that are designed to be stationary on a desk. It has one USB-C port for PD pass-through, two USB-A 3.1 Gen 1 ports, one HDMI port, and one SD card reader—ports that should be enough to keep your iPad connected (and charged up) no matter where you are. We wish it had an Ethernet port, but that's a small price to pay for an otherwise solid portable hub that doesn't break the bank at $39.99.</p>
<p>Apple's own adapters, such as its <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-USB-C-to-USB-Adapter%2F195852567&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to USB-A adapter</a>, are good alternatives if you only need one specific port or prefer not to have a hub hanging off of your computer.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/owc-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="OWC Travel Dock product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">OWC Travel Dock                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_35471710" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32HSFu9" target="_blank">
                                $39.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best game controller</h2>
<h3>Microsoft Xbox One Wireless Controller (Model 1708)</h3>
<h3>Sony DualShock 4</h3>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Xbox-One-Controller-and-DualShock-4.jpg"><img alt='The Xbox One Wireless Controller and Sony&#039;s DualShock 4 controller.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Xbox-One-Controller-and-DualShock-4-640x435.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Xbox-One-Controller-and-DualShock-4-1280x869.jpg 2x" alt='The Xbox One Wireless Controller and Sony&#039;s DualShock 4 controller.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Xbox-One-Controller-and-DualShock-4.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Xbox One Wireless Controller and Sony's DualShock 4 controller.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>With <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/06/apple-tv-games-will-work-with-ps4-xbox-one-s-controllers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iOS 13 adding formal support</a> for <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-One-Bluetooth-Wireless-Controller-Black-6CL00005%2F111779721&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft’s Xbox One Wireless Controller</a> and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Controller-Black%2F55013075&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony’s DualShock 4</a> gamepad, figuring out the best game controller for the iPhone and iPad has become much simpler: just buy whichever console controller you prefer. If you’ve ever used an Xbox One (or Xbox 360) or PlayStation 4, chances are you already know which design you find more comfortable.</p>
<p>Personally, despite using the PS4 as my primary console for most of this past generation of consoles, I gravitate toward the Xbox One pad. Its asymmetrical joystick layout feels more natural to my hands, its triggers are springier, and its d-pad is less mushy. It requires AA batteries—unless you pay an extra $20-25 for <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-xbox-one-play-charge-kit-black%2F9008298.p%3FskuId%3D9008298&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft’s rechargeable battery kit</a>—but it gets much more battery life per “charge” than the DualShock 4’s built-in unit, which tends to degrade to a fairly poor level over time. (Investing in a good set of rechargeable AA batteries and a charger is a good idea anyway.) And if you ever want to play games on the PC, the Xbox One pad is easier to set up on Windows, particularly with clients besides Steam.</p>
<p>That said, the DualShock 4’s joysticks are larger and softer to the touch, and the whole pad is a better fit for smaller hands. Naturally, it’s also better suited for the PS4 Remote Play app. And both are a breeze to pair with an iOS device. It’s really something of a toss-up: if you don’t want to just use whichever controller already came with your chosen console, the right answer is usually whichever is cheaper at the time.</p>
<p>Either way, there’s some fine print to keep in mind here. iOS games are still meant to be played with your fingers first, and while more and more titles do have controller support—including <a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/3439826/here-are-all-the-apple-arcade-games-that-can-support-controllers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many of those</a> included in Apple’s new Arcade service—there’s no guarantee their interfaces will match the icons on your gamepad. One game’s A button may be your controller’s X button. Rumble support and other advanced features may not always work, either. And if you opt for the Xbox One pad, you’ll need to make sure it’s a model 1708 controller, which launched alongside the Xbox One S and includes Bluetooth support. The link below is safe as of this writing, but you can verify you have the right model by checking the label within the battery compartment of your gamepad or by ensuring the surface around the Xbox button isn’t glossy.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/xbox-300x211.jpg"
                                    alt="Microsoft Xbox One Wireless Controller product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Microsoft Xbox One Wireless Controller                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_93152562" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-One-Bluetooth-Wireless-Controller-Black-6CL00005%2F111779721&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_93152562">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-One-Bluetooth-Wireless-Controller-Black-6CL00005%2F111779721&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $39.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2Js8TQk">Amazon $39.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-wireless-controller-for-xbox-one-and-windows-10-black%2F5621843.p%3FskuId%3D5621843&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $39.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-One-Bluetooth-Wireless-Controller-Black-6CL00005%2F111779721&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2Js8TQk"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-wireless-controller-for-xbox-one-and-windows-10-black%2F5621843.p%3FskuId%3D5621843&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/dualshock-300x282.jpeg"
                                    alt="Sony DualShock 4 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Sony DualShock 4                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_18355222" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Controller-Black%2F55013075&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_18355222">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Controller-Black%2F55013075&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $43.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2NqMy6T">Amazon $43.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-dualshock-4-wireless-controller-for-sony-playstation-4-gold%2F5871323.p%3FskuId%3D5871323&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $46.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Controller-Black%2F55013075&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2NqMy6T"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-dualshock-4-wireless-controller-for-sony-playstation-4-gold%2F5871323.p%3FskuId%3D5871323&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best iPhone and iPad stands</h2>
<h3>Pop Socket</h3>
<p>I’ve had friends admonish me for using <a href="https://amzn.to/33VoXSv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pop Sockets</a> on my smartphone cases, but I brush this off every time. While they may be the staple accessory for teens and college kids alike, Pop Sockets are actually great smartphone stands that aren’t stationary. Some will prefer an actual desk accessory that props your smartphone up, but I love the portability of Pop Sockets. Stick one or two to your smartphone case (or to the smartphone itself—don’t worry, you can get them off if you really have to)—and you have a relatively unobtrusive kickstand of sorts that props the smartphone up in landscape mode quite well.</p>
<p>I regularly use my Pop Socket to make watching videos on my iPhone easier and to make viewing photos, documents, and other things more convenient when I’m on the go. I also use these little popping disks to grip my smartphone more easily, and that comes in handy when I’m taking photos (selfies and regular photos) or when I have a bunch of other things to hold and only have two fingers to grip my smartphone.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/popsocket-300x303.png"
                                    alt="Pop Socket product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Pop Socket                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_38381542" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/33VoXSv" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_38381542">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/33VoXSv">Amazon $9.98</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPopSockets-PopGrip-Black%2F269416121&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $9.97</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fpopsockets-popgrip-dove-white-marble%2F6331958.p%3FskuId%3D6331958&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $9.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/33VoXSv"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPopSockets-PopGrip-Black%2F269416121&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fpopsockets-popgrip-dove-white-marble%2F6331958.p%3FskuId%3D6331958&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h3>Tomtoc Play Stand</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Tomtoc-Play-Stand-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The Tomtoc Play Stand.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>If you’re just not into the Pop Socket’s style, we also like <a href="https://amzn.to/2WjwOGU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tomtoc’s Play Stand</a>. While Tomtoc technically markets it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/08/guidemaster-the-best-nintendo-switch-accessories-you-can-buy-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for the Nintendo Switch</a>—and it works great for that purpose—it’s just as useful for an iPhone or iPad mini. Its aluminum frame feels sturdy and substantial, with small rubber grips on the base and “lip” that keep an iPhone and the stand itself steadily in place. Since it’s designed to hold a Switch, that lip provides plenty of room for whatever case you may have protecting your device.</p>
<p>The stand as a whole is highly adjustable, with a couple of freely movable hinges that don’t restrict your device to fixed heights and angles. It can fold it up flat, making it particularly easy to stash in a bag or purse, and a hole in the back lets you run a charging cable to your device without having to take it off the stand. It's going for $12 as of this writing, which is good value.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/tomtoc-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Tomtoc Play Stand product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Tomtoc Play Stand                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_56643992" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2WjwOGU" target="_blank">
                                $11.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h3>Stump Stand</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Stump-Stand-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The Stump Stand.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>For larger iPads, meanwhile, consider the <a href="https://amzn.to/2C1Bk3P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stump Stand</a>. This little chunk of silicone isn’t as portable or adjustable as our other picks, but its weighted base and grippy bottom keep it stuck in place—and keep your device from shaking heavily when you need to use it. It only allows for three viewing angles—almost straight up, almost down flat, and one angle in between—and it’s somewhat heavy at 9.5 ounces, but the design is far from oversized and keeps a low profile. If your iPhone or iPad still has a Home button, there’s also a small cutout for pressing that without having to pick up your device. The $25 asking price is a bit high, but for a stand that’ll keep your iPad reliably in place without eating up too much desk space, it’s a good buy.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/stumpstand-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Stump Stand product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Stump Stand                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_66957326" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2C1Bk3P" target="_blank">
                                $24.95 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best iPhone cases</h2>
<h3>Speck Presidio Pro</h3>
<h3>Otterbox Commuter</h3>
<p>I never have a naked smartphone because I want my most used device to be protected at all times. While you can find affordable iPhone cases almost anywhere you go, there's something to be said for spending a bit more on a case if you value protection over fashion.</p>
<p>Two of my favorites are the <a href="https://amzn.to/348AZYP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speck Presidio Pro</a> case and the <a href="https://amzn.to/2PrSGPg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Otterbox Commuter</a> case, and I use them both for different reasons. Speck's Presidio Pro is more of an everyday case because it's a great combination of protection and fashion—it protects your iPhone from drops up to 10 feet, and its soft matte finish is more luxurious than that of a flimsy, plastic case.</p>
<p>I break out the Otterbox Commuter case when I'm going on a day trip or a full vacation. Whether I'm hiking in a national park or hoofing it around an unfamiliar city, the Commuter case gives my iPhone extra drop protection, and I like the added Lightning cover that prevents dust from getting inside the charging port. It's bulkier than the Presidio Pro, but the extra protection is worth the added heft in those particular situations. It's also quite easy to get my iPhone in and out of the Commuter case thanks to its double-layer design.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speck-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Speck Presidio Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Speck Presidio Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_18914473" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/348AZYP" target="_blank">
                                $39.95 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/otterbox-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Otterbox Commuter product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Otterbox Commuter                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_35501541" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2PrSGPg" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_35501541">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2PrSGPg">Amazon $35.96</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fotterbox-commuter-series-case-for-apple-iphone-11-pro-black%2F6361888.p%3FskuId%3D6361888&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $39.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2PrSGPg"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fotterbox-commuter-series-case-for-apple-iphone-11-pro-black%2F6361888.p%3FskuId%3D6361888&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-3'></a></div>
<h2>Best photo/video accessory</h2>
<h3>DJI Osmo Mobile 3</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"><img alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">DJI's Osmo Mobile 3.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>If you do anything more strenuous with your smartphone camera than take photos of your cat, the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DJI Osmo Mobile 3</a> will make things better. The newest version of DJI’s gimbal makes smartphone photography and videography easier with a plethora of features, but it’s even better now because it’s foldable. It may still be an awkwardly shaped accessory (both when in use and when folded), but now it won’t take up nearly as much space in your bag as previous models did.</p>
<p>The Osmo Mobile 3 has all the same features that the Osmo Mobile 2 did, including gesture control, active track, and now improved on-device controls (there’s a grand total of five buttons on the handle). It also has a USB port so you can charge your smartphone while you’re using it in the gimbal. At $139, it’s a great value accessory that can visibly improve your photo and video skills without breaking the bank.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/dji-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="DJI Osmo Mobile 3 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">DJI Osmo Mobile 3                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_36492283" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2PfygbN" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_36492283">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2PfygbN">Amazon $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196">Walmart $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $139.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2PfygbN"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best iPad stylus</h2>
<h3>Apple Pencil</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Apple-Pencil-1-and-2.jpeg"><img alt='The Apple Pencil.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Apple-Pencil-1-and-2-640x420.jpeg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Apple-Pencil-1-and-2-1280x839.jpeg 2x" alt='The Apple Pencil.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Apple-Pencil-1-and-2.jpeg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Apple Pencil.</a> (credit: Samuel Axon)</p></div>

<p>The <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Pencil-2nd-Generation%2F949679706&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Pencil</a> opens up a whole new world of things you can do on iPads. While the experience of writing or drawing on a tablet is never quite the same as doing so with a pen and paper, the Apple Pencil will get you as close to that experience as you can get. Its design mimics a real pencil or pen (just a slightly longer one), and there’s little to no latency when using it to write on an iPad’s screen. Pressure sensitivity lets you create thinner or thicker lines depending on how hard you press, and the Pencil pairs wirelessly and automatically when it snaps magnetically to your iPad’s edges. The second-gen Pencil charges wirelessly as well.</p>
<p>Like most of Apple’s accessories, the Pencil is the best stylus option for the iPad because it was designed specifically to work with iPadOS. But it is on the expensive side ($129 for the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/11/2018-ipad-pro-review-whats-a-computer/3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">second-gen</a> and $99 for the first-gen), leaving room for the $54 Logitech Crayon to be a good, affordable alternative. It’s not pressure sensitive like the Apple Pencil, and it has a chunkier design, but it’s nearly as good in terms of latency and is less of a hassle to charge than the first-gen Apple Pencil, thanks to its built-in Lightning port.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/applepencil2-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple Pencil (2nd gen) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple Pencil (2nd gen)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_99311470" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/361526w" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_99311470">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/361526w">Amazon $120</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Pencil-2nd-Generation%2F949679706&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $120</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-pencil-2nd-generation%2F6252354.p%3FskuId%3D6252354&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $120.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/361526w"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Pencil-2nd-Generation%2F949679706&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-pencil-2nd-generation%2F6252354.p%3FskuId%3D6252354&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best iPad keyboard case</h2>
<h3>Apple Smart Keyboard</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple-Smart-Keyboard-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Apple's Smart Keyboard with a 10.5-inch iPad Air.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>While Apple posits the iPad Pro as its true <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/11/2018-ipad-pro-review-whats-a-computer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">what’s-a-computer laptop replacement</a>, the iPad Air and 10.2-inch iPad are capable of getting some level of work done as well, particularly when it comes to word processing. You’ll need an external keyboard to make that work, though. If you’d prefer that keyboard to double as an iPad case, Apple’s own <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Smart-Keyboard-for-iPad-7th-Generation-and-iPad-Air-3rd-Generation-US-English%2F502019273&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Keyboard</a> (for the 3<sup>rd</sup>-gen iPad Air and 7<sup>th</sup>-gen iPad) and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Smart-Keyboard-Folio-for-11-inch-iPad-Pro-3rd-Generation-US-English%2F857650547&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Keyboard Folio</a> (for the latest iPad Pros) are your best bets. (We dismissed iPad mini keyboard cases here as they’re too cramped to use comfortably.)</p>
<p>The big draw here is that these keyboards are two of the only devices that make use of Apple’s Smart Connector, which requires no Bluetooth pairing process or battery management. You snap them to the iPad and everything just works. Each device is lightweight and adds little bulk to an iPad, while the fabric-coated keys are water-resistant and easy to keep clean of gunk, since there are no crevices or openings on the boards to begin with. When you’re not typing, the keyboards serve as handy iPad stands, though the standard Smart Keyboard only lets you position your iPad at one angle, whereas the Folio supports two.</p>
<p>Actually typing with the Smart Keyboard isn’t what we’d call a revelation, but it’s fine. This is a far cry from a Lenovo ThinkPad, borrowing more from the super low travel of recent MacBook keyboards instead. Slamming on them for several hours straight could get fatiguing, and there's no backlight whatsoever. But the keys are raised and spaced out well enough to avoid mistakes, the low travel makes them relatively fast to use, and that fabric coating does have a nice, smooth feel.</p>
<p>Both Smart Keyboards are priced higher than we’d like, and the lack of a rear cover on the 7<sup>th</sup>-gen iPad and 3<sup>rd</sup>-gen iPad Air model is something Apple probably should have addressed by now. But the convenience of the Smart Connector adds up over time, and for the kind of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/ipados-review-the-ipad-is-dead-long-live-the-ipad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">genuine-but-not-heavy-duty work</a> for which iPadOS is best suited, the actual keyboard is comfortable and pleasant enough to not be a bother.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/smartkeyboard-300x248.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple Smart Keyboard product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple Smart Keyboard                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_57953031" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Smart-Keyboard-for-iPad-7th-Generation-and-iPad-Air-3rd-Generation-US-English%2F502019273&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_57953031">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Smart-Keyboard-for-iPad-7th-Generation-and-iPad-Air-3rd-Generation-US-English%2F502019273&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $119.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/36fleRG">Amazon $119.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-smart-keyboard-for-apple-ipad10-2-7th-generation-2019-10-5-ipad-pro-and-ipad-air%2F5822276.p%3FskuId%3D5822276&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $119.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Smart-Keyboard-for-iPad-7th-Generation-and-iPad-Air-3rd-Generation-US-English%2F502019273&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/36fleRG"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-smart-keyboard-for-apple-ipad10-2-7th-generation-2019-10-5-ipad-pro-and-ipad-air%2F5822276.p%3FskuId%3D5822276&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best keyboard</h2>
<h3>Logitech K780</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Logitech-K780-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The Logitech K780 wireless keyboard.                      [credit:
                        Jeff Dunn                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>If you do the majority of your iPad work in one place, however, we’d forego the case and get a dedicated keyboard in the form of the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-K780-Multi-Device-Wireless-Keyboard%2F178820743&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGMhttps://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-K780-Multi-Device-Wireless-Keyboard%2F178820743&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech K780</a>. Given that it weighs roughly two pounds and includes a number pad, it’s not the easiest thing to take on the road. But at 158mm×380mm×22mm, it’s still smaller than most full-size keyboards, and that weight helps it stay nice and steady on a desk or table. A built-in device cradle also makes it easy to stash an iPad right in front of you while you work. Its rounded keys may feel peculiar at first, but they’re distinguished and largely satisfying to type on—not as deep or tactile as a good mechanical keyboard, but quiet and comfortable for a wireless multi-device option.</p>
<p>That multi-device aspect means the K780 can pair with up to three devices at once, either via Bluetooth or a USB-A dongle. A trio of buttons at the top of the keyboard let you quickly switch between profiles, so you can easily jump from typing on an iPhone to an iPad to a Mac. Logitech rates its battery life at two years through a pre-installed pair of AAA batteries; we’ve yet to require a new set after more than a year of use.</p>
<p>The downsides here aren’t insignificant: there’s no backlighting, and while the shrunken arrow keys help reduce the K780’s overall footprint, they can be a pain to use. But for $60 or so, it’s a good value for a dedicated keyboard that lends itself well to working on an iOS device. If you don’t think the device stand or number pad are worth it, though, Logitech sells a <a href="https://amzn.to/2MVnOF1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">smaller model called the K380</a> that has a similar key feel and costs $30-40.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/k780-300x300.jpeg"
                                    alt="Logitech K780 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Logitech K780                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_67608993" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2BR4x12" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_67608993">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2BR4x12">Amazon $56.10</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-K780-Multi-Device-Wireless-Keyboard%2F178820743&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Walmart $56.10</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-k780-wireless-keyboard-white%2F5592420.p%3FskuId%3D5592420&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM">Best Buy $59.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2BR4x12"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-K780-Multi-Device-Wireless-Keyboard%2F178820743&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-k780-wireless-keyboard-white%2F5592420.p%3FskuId%3D5592420&amp;subid1=iOSAccessoriesGM"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>


<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1587051&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An end in Vue: Sony will shutter its streaming video service</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593445</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playstation vue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The cable-replacement service will end operations on January 30, 2020.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/sonylogo-640x360.jpg" alt="A Sony sign at a company HQ"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Sony does a lot of things, but the PlayStation brand is a huge part of its profits. Vue? Not so much. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/xsix/4961956583/">xsix / Flickr</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Sony today <a href="https://blog.us.playstation.com/2019/10/29/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-shut-down-playstation-vue/">announced</a> that it will soon shut down PlayStation Vue, its streaming TV service that served as a lighter alternative to traditional cable for live-TV viewers. The company's short blog post on the subject says that Vue will continue to operate until January 30, 2020, but that it will become inoperable after that date.</p>
<p>"Unfortunately, the highly competitive Pay TV industry, with expensive content and network deals, has been slower to change than we expected," Sony wrote. "Because of this, we have decided to remain focused on our core gaming business."</p>
<p>Sony will continue to offer movies and TV episodes for purchase on-demand through the PlayStation Store, however; this closure only affects the live-TV service, which licensed channels traditionally found on cable for streaming in an interface that was available on PlayStation game consoles, Roku, Apple TV, and other platforms.</p>
<p>PlayStation Vue was the first major service of its type when it launched in the United States in 2015. It was followed by offerings from Hulu, YouTube, and others that sought to provide the basic live-TV cable experience streaming over the Internet with more modern interfaces and built-in features like cloud-based DVR and without long-term contract commitments. However, despite its early start, the Vue service lagged competitors in terms of subscribers. And since Sony had less leverage in the entertainment business than say, Disney (which is the majority owner of Hulu), it reportedly found itself paying more than competitors for already extremely pricy content deals with TV networks.</p>
<p>Just a few days ago, a report claimed that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/sony-seeks-to-bail-from-streaming-tv-business-by-selling-off-playstation-vue/">Sony had sought to find a buyer for the Vue service</a>, which has never been profitable. Any buyer would have acquired Vue's subscribers and technology but not necessarily its content agreements, which are difficult to secure. The report indicated that Sony was struggling to find an interested party.</p>
<p>The effort to reimagine the cable bundle for streaming devices has been slow to gain traction even for some of the other top players that have outperformed Vue. As we noted in our previous article on the company's efforts to sell Vue, the wind seems to be strongly behind a channel-based, a la carte ecosystem of low-priced ($6-15/month) streaming services dedicated primarily to producing and distributing original content rather than licensing entire channels or big content packages from other companies.</p>
<p>Netflix, Amazon, Hulu, HBO, Showtime, CBS, and others have already found varying levels of success with the strategy, and major new competitors like <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/we-now-know-what-disney-will-look-like-plus-a-few-new-exclusive-series/">Disney</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/09/nbc-peacock-adds-to-streaming-glut-next-april-with-15000-hours-of-shows/">Comcast/NBC Universal</a> are poised to enter the field soon, as well. Cable subscriptions are also declining, albeit slowly; consumers seem to be voting with their dollars for a different model than traditional live-TV bundles, and Sony seems to have learned that the hard way.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593445&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50 years ago today, the Internet was born. Sort of</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593459</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 22:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593459</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The precursor to the Internet carried its first login request on October 29, 1969.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G69Dec-800x571.jpg" alt="Basic sketch of first computer network."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G69Dec.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="628" data-width="880">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The early ARPANET, the predecessor of the modern Internet, was born on this day in 1969. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/?q=arpa-e-site-page/about">ARPA</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>On October 29, 1969, at 10:30pm Pacific Time, the first two letters were transmitted over ARPANET. And then it crashed. About an hour later, after some debugging, the first actual remote connection between two computers was established over what would someday evolve into the modern Internet.</p>
<p>Funded by the Advanced Research Projects Agency (the predecessor of DARPA), ARPANET was built to explore technologies related to building a military command-and-control network that could survive a nuclear attack. But as Charles Herzfeld, the ARPA director who would oversee most of the initial work to build ARPANET put it:</p>
<blockquote><p>The ARPANET was not started to create a Command and Control System that would survive a nuclear attack, as many now claim. To build such a system was, clearly, a major military need, but it was not ARPA's mission to do this; in fact, we would have been severely criticized had we tried. Rather, the ARPANET came out of our frustration that there were only a limited number of large, powerful research computers in the country, and that many research investigators, who should have access to them, were geographically separated from them.</p></blockquote>
<p>In its infancy, ARPANET had but four "nodes":</p>
<ul>
<li>The University of California-Los Angeles' Network Measurement Center, with its SDS Sigma 7 computer;</li>
<li>Stanford Research Institute's Network Information Center, with its SDS 940 computer running NLS (an early hypertext system and precursor to the World Wide Web);</li>
<li>The University of California, Santa Barbara's Culler-Fried Interactive Mathematics Center, with its IBM 360/75 running OS/MVT; and</li>
<li>The University of Utah School of Computing, with its Digital Equipment Corp PDP-10 running the TENEX operating system.</li>
</ul>
<p>Rather than being directly connected, the computers were connected via Interface Message Processors (IMPs), which were the first network routers. This would allow additional systems to be added as nodes to the network at each site as it evolved and grew. This idea came from <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/28/business/wesley-a-clark-made-computing-personal-dies-at-88.html?ribbon-ad-idx=4&amp;rref=technology&amp;module=Ribbon&amp;version=origin&amp;region=Header&amp;action=click&amp;contentCollection=Technology&amp;pgtype=article">physicist Wesley Clark</a>, who is also credited with designing the LINC, the world's first personal computer.</p>
<p>The first letters transmitted, sent from UCLA to Stanford by UCLA student programmer Charley Kline, were "l" and "o." On the second attempt, the full message text, <em>login</em>, went through from the Sigma 7 to the 940. So, the first three characters ever transmitted over the precursor to the Internet were L, O, and L.</p>
<p>By the time I was first exposed to ARPANET, it had grown significantly, but it was still primarily a connection between researchers and military organizations. ARPANET was operated by the military until 1990, and until then, using the network for anything other than government-related business and research was illegal. By that time, ARPANET was largely being supplanted by the National Science Foundation Network (NSFnet). Even though the Defense Department had split off its own networks as MILNET in the mid-1980s, parts of the military still referred to its network connections as ARPANET in many internal documents into the early 1990s, as I found when I was working as a network engineering contractor at Army Test Lab at Aberdeen in 1992.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G76Jul.jpg"><img alt='A map of ARPANET, circa 1980.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G76Jul-640x388.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G76Jul.jpg 2x" alt='A map of ARPANET, circa 1980.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/G76Jul.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A map of ARPANET, circa 1980.</a> </p></div>
<p>When it was shut down, Vinton Cerf, one of the fathers of the modern Internet, wrote a poem in ARPANET's honor:</p>
<blockquote><p>It was the first, and being first, was best,<br />
but now we lay it down to ever rest.<br />
Now pause with me a moment, shed some tears.<br />
For auld lang syne, for love, for years and years<br />
of faithful service, duty done, I weep.<br />
Lay down thy packet, now, O friend, and sleep.</p></blockquote>
<p>Without ARPANET, there would have been no Internet. So pour one out for the original tonight if you happen to be basking in the Internet's glow.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593459&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp suit says Israeli spyware maker exploited its app to target 1,400 users</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593555</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 22:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nso group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spyware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whatsapp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593555</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Clickless exploit targeted attorneys, journalists, activists, dissidents, and others.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/whatsapp-icon-800x533.jpg" alt="Extreme closeup image of WhatsApp on smartphone."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/whatsapp-icon.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="682" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/140988606@N08/25076398627">Christoph Scholz / Flickr</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Facebook and its WhatsApp messenger division on Tuesday sued Israel-based spyware maker NSO Group. This is an unprecedented legal action that takes aim at the unregulated industry that sells sophisticated malware services to governments around the world. NSO vigorously denied the allegations.</p>
<p>Over an 11-day span in late April and early May, the suit alleges, NSO targeted about 1,400 mobile phones that belonged to attorneys, journalists, human-rights activists, political dissidents, diplomats, and senior foreign government officials. To infect the targets with NSO's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/04/found-quite-possibly-the-most-sophisticated-android-espionage-app-ever/">advanced and full-featured spyware</a>, the company exploited a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/05/whatsapp-vulnerability-exploited-to-infect-phones-with-israeli-spyware/">critical WhatsApp vulnerability</a> that worked against both iOS and Android devices. The clickless exploit was delivered when attackers made a video call. Targets need not have answered the call or taken any other action to be infected.</p>
<h2>Routing malware through WhatsApp servers</h2>
<p>According to the complaint, NSO created WhatsApp accounts starting in January 2018 that initiated calls through WhatsApp servers and injected malicious code into the memory of targeted devices. The targeted phones would then use WhatsApp servers to connect to malicious servers allegedly maintained by NSO. The <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/context/read-the-whatsapp-complaint-against-nso-group/abc0fb24-8090-447f-8493-1e05b2fc1156/">complaint</a>, filed in federal court for the Northern District of California, stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>In order to compromise the Target Devices, Defendants routed and caused to be routed malicious code through Plaintiffs' servers—including Signaling Servers and Relay Servers—concealed within part of the normal network protocol. WhatsApp's Signaling Servers facilitated the initiation of calls between different devices using the WhatsApp Service. WhatsApp's Relay Servers facilitated certain data transmissions over the WhatsApp Service. Defendants were not authorized to use Plaintiffs' servers in this manner.</p>
<p>Between approximately April and May 2019, Defendants used and caused to be used, without authorization, WhatsApp Signaling Servers, in an effort to compromise Target Devices. To avoid the technical restrictions built into WhatsApp Signaling Servers, Defendants formatted call initiation messages containing malicious code to appear like a legitimate call and concealed the code within call settings. Disguising the malicious code as call settings enabled Defendants to deliver it to the Target Device and made the malicious code appear as if it originated from WhatsApp Signaling Servers. Once Defendants' calls were delivered to the Target Device, they injected the malicious code into the memory of the Target Device—even when the Target User did not answer the call.</p></blockquote>
<h2>100 civil society members from 20 countries</h2>
<p>Critics of the spyware industry have long said that NSO and its competitors sell products and services to oppressive governments that use them to target attorneys, journalists, human-rights advocates, and other groups that pose no legitimate threat. Citizen Lab, a University of Toronto research group that tracks hacking campaigns sponsored by governments, volunteered to help Facebook and WhatsApp investigate the attacks on its users. Citizen Lab said among those targeted in the campaign were 100 members of "civil society" from 20 countries.</p>
<p>Citizen Lab said the targets included:</p>
<ul>
<li>multiple prominent women who have been targeted by cyber violence</li>
<li>prominent religious figures from multiple religions</li>
<li>well-known journalists and television personalities</li>
<li>human-rights defenders</li>
<li>lawyers working on human rights</li>
<li>officials at humanitarian organizations</li>
<li>individuals who have faced assassination attempts and threats of violence, as well as their relatives</li>
</ul>
<p>"The commercial spyware industry is one that has tried to carve out an unaccountable space for itself, cozying up to the governments that it sells stuff to while simultaneously denying any responsibility for abuses conducted with its tools," John Scott-Railton, a Citizen Lab senior researcher, told me. "WhatsApp's lawsuit, which is important and precedent-setting, shatters that false distinction and makes it clear that they are willing to hold NSO accountable for the Wild West that exists in the spyware industry generally and is reflected in the target set."</p>
<p>In an email, NSO representatives wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the strongest possible terms, we dispute today's allegations and will vigorously fight them. The sole purpose of NSO is to provide technology to licensed government intelligence and law enforcement agencies to help them fight terrorism and serious crime. Our technology is not designed or licensed for use against human-rights activists and journalists. It has helped to save thousands of lives over recent years.</p>
<p>The truth is that strongly encrypted platforms are often used by pedophile rings, drug kingpins, and terrorists to shield their criminal activity. Without sophisticated technologies, the law enforcement agencies meant to keep us all safe face insurmountable hurdles. NSO's technologies provide proportionate, lawful solutions to this issue.</p>
<p>We consider any other use of our products than to prevent serious crime and terrorism a misuse, which is contractually prohibited. We take action if we detect any misuse. This technology is rooted in the protection of human rights–including the right to life, security, and bodily integrity–and that's why we have sought alignment with the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights, to make sure our products are respecting all fundamental human rights.</p></blockquote>
<p>The suit said that targeted users had WhatsApp numbers with country codes from the Kingdom of Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, and Mexico. Public reports—including those <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90322618/nso-group-pegasus-cyberweapon-targeted-the-widow-of-a-slain-mexican-journalist;">here</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/31/world/middleeast/hacking-united-arab-emirates-nso-group.html">here</a>, and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/may/18/israeli-firm-nso-group-linked-to-whatsapp-spyware-attack-faces-lawsuit">here</a>—have listed the governments of all three countries as NSO customers.</p>
<p>Facebook and WhatsApp <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/05/whatsapp-vulnerability-exploited-to-infect-phones-with-israeli-spyware/">shut down the attacks</a> on May 13 with a software update that patched the critical vulnerability. According to the complaint, an NSO employee responded to the move by saying: "You just closed our biggest remote for cellular... It's on the news all over the world." According to a <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/help/video-calling-cyber-attack">statement from WhatsApp</a>, company officials sent a special message to the approximately 1,400 targeted users informing them of the attack.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2019/10/29/why-whatsapp-is-pushing-back-nso-group-hacking/">op-ed published by The Washington Post</a>, Will Cathcart, the head of WhatsApp, wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>This should serve as a wake-up call for technology companies, governments, and all Internet users. Tools that enable surveillance into our private lives are being abused, and the proliferation of this technology into the hands of irresponsible companies and governments puts us all at risk.</p>
<p>NSO has previously denied any involvement in the attack, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-48262681">stating that</a> "under no circumstances would NSO be involved in the operating... of its technology." But our investigation found otherwise. Now, we are seeking to hold NSO accountable under US state and federal laws, including the <a href="https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/criminal-ccips/legacy/2015/01/14/ccmanual.pdf">US Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Cathcart added: "“While their attack was highly sophisticated, their attempts to cover their tracks were not entirely successful.”</p>
<p>Tuesday's complaint alleges that NSO violated the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, the California Comprehensive Computer Data Access and Fraud Act, and a California law governing breach of contract. The action seeks a permanent injunction barring NSO from accessing WhatsApp servers, creating or using WhatsApp or Facebook accounts, or further violating WhatsApp terms of service.</p>
<p>Besides Facebook and WhatsApp apps and servers, NSO allegedly used servers owned by Amazon Web Services and smaller hosts Choopa and Quadrant. The leased servers connected targeted devices to a network of remote servers that were designed to distribute malware and send commands to devices once they were infected. Tuesday's complaint said that an IP address assigned to one of the malicious servers was previously used by a subdomain operated by NSO.</p>
<p>Now that Facebook and WhatsApp have taken the unprecedented step of suing a spyware provider for using its servers to target its users, it will be interesting to see if Amazon and the other server hosts mentioned in the complaint follow suit. So far, they haven't responded to emails seeking comment.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593555&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Force won’t be with them: David Benioff and D.B. Weiss exit Star Wars</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593169</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 21:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D.B. Weiss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game of Thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593169</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The <em>Game of Thrones</em> showrunners cited time constraints from big Netflix deal.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/benioffweiss-800x529.jpg" alt="Two smug men in business suits."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/benioffweiss.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="794" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> David Benioff and D.B. Weiss have opted to focus on their lucrative development deal with Netflix. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.hbo.com/">Jeff Kravitz/HBO</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Former <em>Game of Thrones</em> showrunners David Benioff and D.B. Weiss will no longer be developing the next Star Wars film trilogy for LucasFilm, <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/star-wars-setback-game-of-thrones-duo-david-benioff-d-b-weiss-exit-trilogy-1202771184/">Deadline Hollywood reports</a>. Instead, they'll be focusing on developing new films and series for Netflix, part of a <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/08/game-of-thrones-creators-netflix-overall-deal-david-benioff-d-b-weiss-1202663930/">lucrative nine-figure deal</a> they signed in August with the streaming giant.</p>
<p>"We love Star Wars," Benioff and Weiss <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/star-wars-setback-game-of-thrones-duo-david-benioff-d-b-weiss-exit-trilogy-1202771184/">told Deadline Hollywood</a>. "When George Lucas built it, he built us, too. Getting to talk about Star Wars with him and the current Star Wars team was the thrill of a lifetime, and we will always be indebted to the saga that changed everything. There are only so many hours in the day, and we felt we could not do justice to both Star Wars and our Netflix projects. So we are regretfully stepping away."</p>
<p>Benioff and Weiss signed onto Star Wars back in February 2018, before the much-maligned (by fans) final season of <em>Game of Thrones</em> aired on HBO earlier this year. They had been developing a series called <em>Confederates</em> for HBO, a fictionalized alternative history of the US where the South won the Civil War and slavery remained legal. The series was tabled, ostensibly due to scheduling conflicts rather than in response to an online outcry over the controversial premise. Then came the backlash against the <em>GoT</em> finale, even sparking an <a href="https://gizmodo.com/game-of-thrones-petition-to-remake-season-8-reaches-a-m-1834875436">online petition</a> with 1.75 million signatories calling for a remake. (As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/05/here-is-our-super-spoiler-y-review-of-the-game-of-thrones-series-finale/">we noted</a> in our review of the finale, that's not how any of this works.)</p>
<p>The duo has kept a fairly low public profile since then before igniting a fresh controversy with <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2019/10/game-of-thrones-david-benioff-d-b-weiss-panel">a panel appearance</a> over the weekend at the Austin Film Festival. The men adopted a self-deprecating stance that didn't land well with the audience, joking about their lack of experience and marveling that George R.R. Martin entrusted his life's work into their hands as they pretty much learned the ropes on the job. So the news that Benioff and Weiss are no longer involved with <em>Star Wars</em> might be seen as good news by many.</p>
<p>It does kind of throw a fork in the works for Lucasfilm's long-range plans for the franchise. Currently, <em>The Mandalorian</em> <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/disney-leans-hard-into-space-western-territory-in-new-mandalorian-trailer/">debuts on</a> the new Disney+ streaming service November 12, and <em>Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker</em>—the final installment in the most recent trilogy that concludes the long-running "Skywalker saga"—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/final-trailer-for-star-wars-the-rise-of-skywalker-plays-up-the-reylo-angle/">hits theaters</a> December 20. The Benioff and Weiss project was intended to launch the next stage of the Star Wars cinematic saga, slated for 2022.</p>
<h2>Full plate</h2>
<p>Fortunately, Lucasfilm still has plenty of other projects in the works, most notably a Star Wars spinoff series <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/08/obi-wan-kenobi-ewan-mcgregor-disney-series-shooting-next-year-all-scripts-ready-d23-1202703228/">featuring Obi-Wan Kenobi</a>, with Ewan McGregor reprising his role as the iconic character. It <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/08/ewan-mcgregor-confirms-he-will-return-as-obi-wan-for-new-star-wars-series/">was announced</a> at Disney's annual D23 Expo in August, along with another Star Wars spinoff ("Untitled Spy Series") for Disney+ featuring <em>Rogue One</em>'s Cassian (Diego Luna) and his best droid buddy, K2 (Alan Tudyk).</p>
<p>It sounds like Lucasfilm President Kathleen Kennedy isn't closing the door entirely on having the duo in the Star Wars fold at some point in the future, however. "David Benioff and Dan Weiss are incredible storytellers," she told Deadline Hollywood. "We hope to include them in the journey forward when they are able to step away from their busy schedule to focus on Star Wars."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593169&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Collision liquified the 4th-largest asteroid, turning it into a dwarf planet</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593455</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 19:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asteroids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dwarf planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planetary science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593455</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[New images show a nearly perfect sphere without large craters.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/eso1918a-800x515.jpg" alt="Alien sphere against a black background."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/eso1918a.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="824" data-width="1280">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Image of Hygiea made using a ground-based telescope. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.eso.org/public/images/eso1918a/">ESO/P. Vernazza et al./MISTRAL algorithm</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The bodies of our Solar System's asteroid belt have violent pasts. Some, like the dwarf planet Ceres, have seen their interiors restructured under the force of gravity while having their surfaces blasted by collisions. Smaller asteroids have experienced collisions that completely shattered them, leaving their debris' weak gravity to pull the pieces together into a rubble pile. Now, new images of the fourth-largest body in the asteroid belt, Hygiea, suggest it has a history that's somewhere between the two. After suffering a shattering collision in the distant past, the body's remains had enough gravitational pull to shape it into a dwarf planet.</p>
<h2>History vs. observations</h2>
<p>We know Hygiea has experienced a collision in the past, because we can see its remains. An entire family of small asteroids are found in orbits that suggest they originated from the asteroid about two billion years ago.</p>
<p>In other cases where we've seen asteroid families like this, the body on which they originated is either pockmarked with craters and/or has suffered at least one extremely large collision. So, planetary scientists probably had similar expectations in mind when they turned the Very Large Telescope at the European Southern Observatory toward Hygiea in 2017.</p>
<p>Instead, the body they imaged was remarkably smooth and nearly spherical—its average radius is 217km and likely only varies from 225km to 212km. It was also rotating at roughly twice the rate that we thought it had been.</p>
<p>None of that is quite what was expected: "None of our images and their associated contours revealed the large impact basin expected from the large size of the Hygiea [asteroid] family."</p>
<p>To figure out how the asteroid family could have formed, the researchers built a model that allowed them to try out different collisions, testing different impactor sizes and angles of impact. After using these collision models to generate debris, the researchers let gravity take over to figure out what the re-formed Hygiea and its remaining debris (which would go on to form the asteroid family) would look like.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qhTEQsH2xMA?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">A simulation of Hygiea's destruction and re-formation. </p></div>
<p>Rather than forming a large crater, the collisions that worked instead completely shattered the asteroid. This could be done either by a head-on collision with a 75km object or an off-center collision with a 150km object. The off-center collisions, however, tended not to leave any large bodies in the debris (other than Hygiea itself); since some members of the resulting asteroid family are larger, the researchers conclude that a head-on collision is most likely.</p>
<h2>Liquified</h2>
<p>In addition to liberating a debris field, the collision turned the remains of Hygiea into a fluid, which underwent large-scale oscillations for about four hours after the event. This allowed the debris to evenly mix and equilibrate, producing the body's current spherical shape. This was probably enabled by the relatively low density of the material; the researchers estimate that Hygiea is less than twice as dense as water.</p>
<p>This is similar to the density of Ceres, the largest body in the asteroid belt. The authors suggest that the two formed further out than the "snow line" of water, the point where material was far enough from the Sun for water to remain frozen.</p>
<p>The authors also argue that the collision may have incidentally turned Hygiea into a dwarf planet. As they note, anything in the asteroid belt orbits the Sun and isn't orbiting a larger body, fulfilling two of the four requirements for dwarf planet status. These bodies should also have cleared their orbit; that depends somewhat on the orbits of the other material in the same asteroid family—presumably, if they were close enough, they'd already have been incorporated back into Hygiea.</p>
<p>That leaves one last hurdle: does Hygiea have enough mass to form a spherical shape under the force of its own gravity? It's not clear what Hygiea looked like before the collision, as some other large asteroids like Eros have pretty irregular shapes. But after its disruption, Hygiea's gravity was clearly sufficient to shape it into a sphere. As a result, the researchers suggest it should be designated a dwarf planet, the smallest one yet.</p>
<p>Nature Astronomy, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41550-019-0915-8">10.1038/s41550-019-0915-8</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593455&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA shares details of lunar surface missions—and they’re pretty cool</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593099</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 18:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593099</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But there is a catch if you want to bring back Moon rocks.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/artemis-16-980x534.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Look! Here's an artist's conception of an astronaut on the Moon. It appears as though she is installing a geophone.                       [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>There are a lot of reasons to be skeptical that NASA will actually enact the Artemis Moon program to land astronauts on the Moon by 2024—Congress <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/10/a-house-budget-committee-has-likely-killed-the-2024-moon-landing/">may not fund it</a>, NASA's large, costly rocket remains <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/07/nasas-large-sls-rocket-unlikely-to-fly-before-at-least-late-2021/">far behind schedule</a>, and history <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2017/10/the-unhappy-history-of-presidential-plans-for-human-space-exploration/">has been unkind</a> to deep-space exploration programs since Apollo. However, should lunar landing missions occur during the next decade, they have the potential to go far beyond what NASA accomplished with the Apollo program half a century ago.</p>
<p>NASA scientists John Connolly and Niki Werkheiser spoke Wednesday at the annual meeting of the Lunar Exploration Analysis Group, and they provided more details about the agency's plan for human missions in the 2020s.</p>
<h2>Nearly a week</h2>
<p>The first mission to the Moon's surface, consisting of two crew members, will remain on the surface for 6.5 days—this is double the longest period of time any of the Apollo missions spent on the surface. The two astronauts will conduct up to four spacewalks on the surface of the Moon, performing a variety of scientific observations, including sampling water ice. "We will have a very robust science program from the very beginning," Connolly said.</p>
<p>One big difference between this first mission and Apollo is that NASA intends to pre-position equipment on the surface, including an unpressurized rover for astronauts to use during their spacewalks. The agency intends for this rover to have the capability to be controlled remotely—it will be like Tesla's "Smart Summon" feature, only on the Moon.</p>
<p>Connolly discussed Artemis landing locations near the South Pole of the Moon, noting that several "permanently shadowed regions" could be reached by short forays of 5km to 15km, well within the range of the aforementioned rover. Scientists believe that, over billions of years, ice has become trapped in these darkened areas where crater walls prevent sunlight from shining.</p>

<p>NASA has also been studying the illumination of the South Pole along the ridges of these craters, where there is near-continual sunlight during the lunar summer. For example, Connolly said the period from October 2024 through February 2025 along the rim of Shackleton Crater (at 89.8 degrees south) will have near-constant illumination. This is important for solar power generation.</p>
<p>Another Artemis mission is scheduled to follow in 2025, followed by delivery of a pressurized rover as early as 2026. This would enable much longer forays from the landing site. Before the end of the decade, NASA says it could evolve the crew size to four people, for 14-day missions, and begin to establish facilities for mining water ice and producing oxygen.</p>
<h2>Sample return?</h2>
<p>The goal, Connolly said, would be to go to the Moon to stay, while also building up capabilities for eventual human missions to Mars. "We are going to do some testing for Mars on the Moon, but we are also looking at a long-term lunar surface presence," he said.</p>
<p>Scientists at Wednesday's lunar meeting were also interested in rock samples from the Moon. In a discussion of the human landers NASA plans to use in 2024 and beyond, Greg Chavers, an engineer at Marshall Space Flight Center, said the agency has plans for this. Companies bidding to build the lander for NASA will be required to provide a minimum sample return capability of 35kg, with the goal of 100kg. Companies will be evaluated, in part, on their sample return capacity, he said.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/artemis-5-980x482.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          This map shows illumination at some potential landing sites near South Pole craters on the Moon.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>One of the limitations on returning samples is the Orion spacecraft, which will carry astronauts back from lunar orbit to Earth. Chavers said the Orion spacecraft does not have any designated space for a box of sample rocks taken from the lunar surface. "We just don't know what the capability will be," Chavers said of bringing rocks back to Earth inside Orion. This would seem to be an important detail to nail down.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593099&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>