<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 15:43:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The genetic basis of Peruvians’ ability to live at high altitude</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601367</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 15:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Gitig]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altitude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hypoxia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sherpas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601367</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It involves changes in the basic oxygen sensing system.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1140594268-800x566.jpg" alt="Image of people in front of a flock of llamas."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1140594268.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="724" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Many Peruvians are well adapted to high-altitude life in the Andes. (credit: Eric Lafforgue/Art in All of Us)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Sherpas are physiologically adapted to breathing, working, and living in the thin air of the Himalayas, enabling them to repeatedly schlep stuff up and down Mount Everest. The Quechua, who have lived in the Andes for about eleven thousand years, are also remarkably capable of functioning in their extremely high homes. New work suggests that these adaptations are the result of natural selection for particular genetic sequences in these populations.</p>
<p>Both populations live above 14,000 feet (4,267m), under chronic hypoxia—lack of oxygen—that can cause headaches, appetite suppression, inability to sleep, and general malaise in those not habituated to altitude. Even way back in the 16th century, the Spaniards noted that the Inca tolerated their thin air amazingly well (and then they killed them).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2017/05/28/530204187/the-science-behind-the-super-abilities-of-sherpas">Metabolic adaptations</a> give these highlanders have a notably high aerobic capacity in hypoxic conditions—they get oxygenated blood to their muscles more efficiently. But the genetic basis for this adaptation has been lacking. Genome Wide Association Studies, which search the entire genome for areas linked to traits, had found tantalizing clues that one particular gene might be a site of natural selection in both Andeans and Tibetans. It encodes an oxygen sensor that help cells <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/10/medicine-nobel-goes-to-discovery-of-how-our-bodies-sense-oxygen-levels/">regulate their response to hypoxia</a>.</p>

<p>This new work looked for genetic variants that were more common in the Quechua population compared to white lowlanders from Syracuse, New York. The researchers then tried to correlate the variants with the Quechua’s high aerobic capacity at altitude. But none of the the genetic differences showed a significant association with high aerobic capacity, probably because the sample size—429 Quechua and 94 lowlanders was too small to detect one.</p>
<p>So the researchers subjected the data to a more sensitive statistical analysis. This analysis found five variants of the gene that were significantly associated with the Quechua’s adaptive high aerobic capacity in hypoxic conditions; they also appeared significantly more frequently in the Quechua population than in lowlanders. This observation was buttressed by analysis of a second, independent cohort of Quechua compared to global populations from the <a href="https://www.internationalgenome.org/home">1000 Genomes Project</a>.</p>
<p>All of the adaptive variants were in the regulatory region of the gene—DNA that controls when and where the gene is active. None were in the part of the gene that encodes a protein. So, the location and timing of the protein's activity seems to be more important than the protein itself in the Quechua.</p>
<p>A number of conditions must be met to claim that a population is genetically adapted to specific conditions. First, that there is in fact an adaptation; in this case, enhanced aerobic capacity under hypoxia. Check. Next, that that adaptation is associated with a genetic variant, and that that variant occurs in the population of interest at rates indicating that it is being selected for. That’s what this most recent work did.</p>
<p>But it has not shown that the adaptation has increased the group’s fitness, in terms of improving fertility and/or limiting mortality. And it is not absolutely certain that aerobic capacity is the trait being selected for; it is possible that this gene does something else oxygen-related that is really the trait being selected for, and the observed enhanced aerobic capacity is just a bonus side effect.</p>
<p>Tibetans have alterations to the protein encoded by this gene, which is intriguing. Even more so is that the Tibetan variants are not associated with high aerobic capacity in hypoxia, but with <em>low</em> hemoglobin. Counterintuitively, this seems to help Tibetans at altitude by increasing their blood flow to an extent that compensates for the fact that the blood carries less oxygen.</p>
<p><em>PNAS</em>, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1906171116">10.1073/pnas.1906171116</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/ science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601367&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford v Ferrari review: A big-budget, big-screen take on racing in the 1960s</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602489</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 14:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christian Bale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford vs Ferrari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matt damon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602489</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not perfect but a better racing movie than we've seen in years.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ford-v-ferrari-DF-08613_R_CC_rev_rgb-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Matt Damon (L) as Carroll Shelby and Christian Bale (R) as Ken Miles star in <em>Ford v Ferrari</em>, a new film about Ford's attempt to win the 24 Hours of Le Mans in the 1960s.                      [credit:
                        20th Century Fox                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>In the early 1960s, the Ford Motor Company was in need of a little pizzazz. Its <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/07/lee-iaccoca-who-gave-us-the-minivan-and-the-mustang-dies-at-94/">then-General Manager Lee Iacocca</a> had some ideas on how to do that. One of them was the Ford Mustang, which invented a new class of car that looked cool but was both cheap to buy and profitable to sell, thanks to heavy use of the corporate parts bin. Another was to get FoMoCo some racing glory, this being back in the days when "win on Sunday, sell on Monday" really worked. What happened next is the topic of <em>Ford v Ferrari</em>, the latest attempt by Hollywood to translate motorsport to the silver screen.</p>
<p>As the name might suggest, the film tells the story of a Detroit auto giant taking on the tiny but extremely successful Italian sports car maker at its own game. Ford tried to buy Ferrari, you see, until Enzo Ferrari pulled the plug over concerns that his potential new master could veto his eponymous race team's participation in races like the Indianapolis 500. Incensed with having been led up the garden path, Ford president and scion Henry Ford II commissioned a full factory-backed race program with the goal of beating Enzo at his own game, specifically at marquee endurance races like the 24 Hours of Daytona, the 12 Hours of Sebring, and the most important race of the year, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/24_Hours_of_Le_Mans">24 Hours of Le Mans</a>. To do it, Ford would develop a purpose-built race car, one that has entered the pantheon of the greats: the GT40.</p>
<p><em>Ford vs Ferrari</em> stars Matt Damon as Carroll Shelby and Christian Bale as Ken Miles. Shelby was a larger-than-life Texan who won Le Mans with Aston Martin in 1959 before his driving career was sidelined due to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/09/whats-atrial-fibrillation-and-whys-your-watch-telling-you-about-it/">atrial fibrillation</a>. For his next act, Shelby turned his hand to building cars, finding plenty of success when he married the lithe but underpowered AC Ace roadster with Ford V8 power, starting a relationship with the Blue Oval that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/10/the-2020-ford-mustang-shelby-gt500-packs-plenty-of-smiles-per-mile/">carries on today</a>. Bale takes on the role of Ken Miles, a British engineer and racing driver who relocated to California in the '50s and raced for Shelby in the early '60s.</p>
<h2>The danger of knowing too much</h2>
<p>It's always a worry when Hollywood comes to visit a topic you know well. Historical accuracy, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2009/02/science-and-hollywood-needs-catchy-title-fp-aaas-content/">much like scientific accuracy</a>, is often the first casualty of storytelling, and so it is the case here. Students of motorsport history will need to steel themselves, because there is much that Director James Mangold excised from the GT40's story. We see little to nothing of Eric Broadley, whose Lola Mk6 was chosen as the forerunner of the GT40. Nor John Wyer, legendary team boss at Aston Martin, then Ford, then Gulf Racing. We don't get to see Ford stumble at its first attempt in 1964, although we hear Miles listening to the race on the radio from Shelby's race shop in California.</p>
<p>And for a film named <em>Ford and Ferrari</em>, we don't see much of Ferrari at all. There's a brief visit to Maranello in Italy (where Ferrari is based), then nothing again until the final act of the film, which takes place at the 1966 running of Le Mans. (In some markets the film is called <em>Le Mans '66</em>, probably a more accurate title.)</p>
<p>I won't lie, I also had trouble suspending disbelief on a few occasions. For one thing, racing drivers can't shout at each other mid-race, not when their cars are powered by extremely powerful and mostly unsilenced V8 engines. Enzo Ferrari famously didn't speak English, although he manages a few words here, which I don't entirely buy. And I had real problems with one scene where Miles intentionally drives into another GT40 on track. That kind of behavior is (sadly) more common now but was much rarer in the days when racing was "a professional bloodsport," to quote Steve McQueen's character in <em>Le Mans</em>.</p>
<p>For the racing nerd, <em>Le Mans</em> always lurks in the background. It was McQueen's passion project, filmed at the height of his stardom in a costly and undisciplined shoot that took place on the actual French roads used for the race. McQueen starred alongside a whole gaggle of actual Porsche 917s and Ferrari 512 race cars, with carefully choreographed racing scenes that have never quite been matched. A true cinematic love-letter to racing, it's true that the plot is weak and the dialogue ropey, but that doesn't stop people like me from popping the Blu-Ray into the machine every year or two anyway.</p>
<p>If you count yourself among that crowd, know that <em>Ford vs Ferrari</em>'s racing scenes won't quite live up. You can do a lot with CGI, and the production used real cars for plenty of physical effects, but there's only so many times Road Atlanta in Georgia can stand in for Le Mans. On the other hand, it's a much better portrayal of racing than that other recent big budget take on the sport, Ron Howard's <em>Rush</em>.</p>
<h2>A tired trope</h2>
<p>But it still falls prey to the tired trope where a driver pushes his accelerator pedal <em>extra hard</em> to eke out an on-track pass. Please, cinematographers—stop this, because at Le Mans back then you were flat on the loud pedal on the exit of Tetre Rouge all the way until a possible lift at the Mulsanne kink two miles down the road. And while we're on the subject, why just show someone's feet changing gear <em>really hard</em> when you could film the balletic footwork that is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heel-and-toe_shifting">heel-and-toe shifting</a>?</p>
<p>A less racing-literate audience will probably have no such complaints. Bale is wonderful as Miles, and his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brummie_dialect">Brummie accent</a> is note-perfect. Damon chews less scenery but holds his own, and you get a great sense of the camaraderie between the two men. Josh Lucas does a great job as the film's real villain—not Enzo Ferrari but Leo Beebe, head of Ford's racing activities and a man who is a little hard done-by in this dramatization. The film doesn't capture what it must have been like to race these fragile and dangerous cars at 200mph+ quite as well as <em>Le Mans</em>, but it's a damn sight more entertaining than <em>Driven</em>, or <em>Michel Valliant</em>, or even the aforementioned <em>Rush</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602489&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the newly released Checkra1n jailbreak means for iDevice security</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602451</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkm8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkra1n]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jailbreaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are reasons to embrace it. There are reasons to be wary of it. Here's the breakdown.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/checkra1n-800x547.jpeg" alt="What the newly released Checkra1n jailbreak means for iDevice security"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/checkra1n.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="615" data-width="900">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://twitter.com/checkra1n/status/1185594297225240582">@Checkra1n</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>It has been a week since the <a href="https://checkra.in/#release" target="_blank" rel="noopener">release of Checkra1n</a>, the world’s first jailbreak for devices running Apple’s iOS 13. Because jailbreaks are so powerful and by definition disable a host of protections built into the OS, many people have rightly been eyeing Checkra1n—and the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/09/developer-of-checkm8-explains-why-idevice-jailbreak-exploit-is-a-game-changer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Checkm8 exploit</a> it relies on—cautiously. What follows is a list of pros and cons for readers to ponder, with a particular emphasis on security.</p>
<h2>The good</h2>
<p>First, Checkra1n is extremely reliable and robust, particularly for a tool that’s still in beta mode. It jailbreaks a variety of older iDevices quickly and reliably. It also installs an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SSH server</a> and other utilities, a bonus that makes the tool ideal for researchers and hobbyists who want to dig into the internals of their devices.</p>
<p>“I expected it to be a little rougher around the edges for the first release,” Ryan Stortz, an iOS security expert and principal security researcher at the firm Trail of Bits, said in an interview. “It’s really nice to be able to install a new developer beta on your development iPhone and have all your tooling work out of the box. It makes testing Apple's updates much much easier.”</p>
<p>Another benefit of Checkra1n is that it promises to work reliably on a wide array of hardware. Those models include devices from the iPhone 5s all the way to the iPhone X running iOS 12.3 or later. (At the moment, the Checkra1n beta doesn’t support the iPad Air 2, first generation iPad Pro, and fifth generation iPad. Users may also experience problems when running this beta on the iPhone 5s, iPad mini 2, and iPad mini 3. These incompatibilities will likely be fixed in time, as new Checkra1n updates become available.)</p>
<p>Also significant, Checkm8-based jailbreaks will work permanently on these devices. Unlike most jailbreaks, which exploit vulnerabilities in iOS, Checkm8 targets a flaw in the <a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Bootrom" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boot ROM</a>, which is the first code that runs when an iDevice is turned on. This code is burned into the hardware itself and can’t be patched. This is the reason Checkra1n will work with every new release of iOS over the lifetime of a vulnerable phone.</p>
<p>This means that people can continue to enjoy the benefits and security fixes available in new iOS releases without losing the ability to jailbreak their devices (new versions of iOS inevitably fix jailbreaking vulnerabilities). This is a far cry from jailbreaks over the past decade that forced users to run outdated versions of iOS. The last time a jailbreak targeted the Boot ROM was in 2010 when hacker George Hotz (aka <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/george-hotz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geohot</a>) developed one for the iPhone 3GS and iPhone 4.</p>
<p>Checkra1n is also helpful because it makes it painfully obvious it has been used. A large Checkra1n logo displays during bootup. And the home screen will include the Cydia and Checkra1n apps, neither of which appear when an iDevice runs normally.</p>
<p>And like all Checkm8-based jailbreaks, Checkra1n requires physical access to the vulnerable device and a reboot, which means user data and Touch ID and Face ID are inaccessible until the next time a PIN is entered to unlock the device. This means that remote exploits aren’t possible.</p>
<h2>The bad</h2>
<p>Checkm8-based jailbreaks, including Checkra1n, come with some notable limitations that many jailbreaking enthusiasts consider deal-breakers. First, Checkm8 doesn’t work on iDevices introduced in the past two years, specifically those with A12 and A13 CPUs. That limits the jailbreak to older devices, most of which—but not all—are no longer sold in retail outlets.</p>
<p>The other major limitation is that Checkm8-based jailbreaks are “tethered,” meaning they don’t survive a reboot. Each time the device is restarted, it must first be connected to a Mac—eventually Windows versions of Checkra1n are expected—and jailbroken all over again. Untethered jailbreaks, by contrast, are much more popular because they allow iDevices to boot normally, without being connected to a computer each time.</p>
<p>Another drawback to any jailbreak is that it’s an inevitably risky thing, since it unbinds an iDevice from the protections and quality assurances Apple has painstakingly built into iOS over more than a decade. Apple warns <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201954" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a> that jailbreaking can “cause security vulnerabilities, instability, shortened battery life, and other issues.” The stakes are raised further by the beta status of Checkra1n. The <a href="https://checkra.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Checkra1n website</a> warns: "This release is an early beta preview and as such should not be installed on a primary device. We strongly recommend proceeding with caution."</p>
<p>Then there are the risks of error by inexperienced users who are drawn to Checkra1n's reliability, robustness, and its promise to work—on older devices, anyway—in perpetuity.</p>
<p>“The biggest threat from Checkra1n is how easily a non-technical user can jailbreak their device, which then leaves it vulnerable to additional attacks,” Christoph Hebeisen, head of security research at mobile security provider Lookout, said. One protection that Checkra1n deactivates is the iOS sandbox, which cordons off sensitive parts of iOS from the apps it runs. The risk is heightened by the ability of jailbroken devices to run any app. Normally iPhones and iPads can run only apps that are available in the App Store, which vets submissions for security and stability before allowing them in.</p>
<p>One other warning: the site checkrain[.]com is an <a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/2019/10/checkrain-click-fraud.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">imposter site that installs a malicious profile</a> onto the end-user device. Readers should steer clear.</p>
<h2>The (more subtly) bad</h2>
<p>There’s a more subtle threat posed by Checkra1n's ease in almost completely unpairing a device from the protections that have made iOS arguably the world’s most secure OS. As noted earlier, it would be hard for someone to use this jailbreak maliciously against someone else. But Stortz, the iOS security expert at Trail of Bits, said that Checkra1n’s release demonstrates just how powerful it could be should its capabilities fall into the wrong hands.</p>
<p>“The threat is more real now because a sophisticated exploit is available to everyone,” he said. He went on to theorize cases of attackers reverse-engineering Checkra1n and combining its jailbreaking capabilities with rootkits or other malicious code. All attackers might need to use this malicious Checkra1n-derived jailbreak is very brief access to an iDevice. This type of attack could covertly steal text messages, login credentials, cryptographic keys, and all kinds of other sensitive data. These attacks would be particularly effective against iPhones and iPads that don’t use fingerprints or face scans for unlocking. He explained:</p>
<blockquote><p>Checkm8 allows someone to undermine the trust of the iOS secure boot chain. Checkra1n makes it easy to do. It’s true that checkra1n puts a nice logo on it and installs development tools, but that doesn’t need to happen. Someone will modify checkra1n to remove the logo and install a rootkit instead. [In that scenario] having a PIN-only passcode is a poor choice. You’ll pick up your phone [after Checkra1n is surreptitiously installed] and unlock it, allowing the rootkit full access to your personal data.</p></blockquote>
<p>It has been possible to create this type of malicious jailbreak since late September, when the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/09/unpatchable-bug-in-millions-of-ios-devices-exploited-developer-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Checkm8 exploit became public</a>. But that kind of attack required huge amounts of time and skill. Now, Stortz said, “no one would do that when Checkra1n exists and is so well done.”</p>
<p>The take-away from the sort of scenario Stortz hypothesizes is this: for journalists, dissidents, and other high-value targets who use iOS devices and can afford to, it’s best to use hardware that has an A12 or higher CPU. An iDevice introduced in the past two years will ensure that it’s safe from Checkra1n-derived attacks at border crossings, in hotel rooms, or in other situations that involve brief separations.</p>
<p>For iOS users who can’t afford a newer iPhone or iPad, using Touch ID or Face ID can lower the chances of malicious jailbreaks since users can be tipped off that something is amiss if the iDevice unexpectedly requires a PIN. And whenever the device has been out of the user’s control, even briefly—or users suspect anything else is amiss—they should reboot it.</p>
<p>This level of scrutiny is probably overkill for most users of vulnerable iPhones and iPads. Unfortunately, for users belonging to more targeted groups, these precautions are a natural consequence of a post-Checkra1n era.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602451&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guidemaster: The best Qi wireless charging pads for your smartphone</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1446745</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 13:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidemaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless charging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless charging pads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1446745</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wireless charging can be tricky to understand—these devices make it a no-brainer.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/wcp_lead3-800x533.jpg" alt="Guidemaster: The best Qi wireless charging pads for your smartphone"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/wcp_lead3.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1080" data-width="1620">Enlarge</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p>  </figure>




      <p><em><strong>Update:</strong> Ars has stayed busy after publishing this guide in April 2019. We've tested a number of new Qi wireless chargers available since and have updated our top picks ahead of the 2019 holiday shopping season.</em></p>
    

<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Wireless charging has a long way to go before it replaces wired charging, but the technology has advanced dramatically in the past few years. Everyone with the newest smartphones, wearables, and other gadgets can get behind the idea—simply place your device on a charging pad or stand and let it sit. Within a few minutes, you'll have more battery power than you did before, and you didn't have to fuss with wires or cables to get it.</p>
<p>But quite a bit of technology goes into making an accessory that makes your life that much easier. Most wireless chargers come in the form of circular or rectangular pads, some of which are propped up on legs to make stands that take up minimal space and work well as nightstand or desk accessories. But don't be fooled by their minimalist exteriors—there are a number of things you should know before investing in a wireless charging pad. To navigate this murky world, Ars tested out some of the most popular Qi wireless chargers available now to see which are worth buying.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>The short version</h2>
<ul>
<li>Standing strong as <strong>our favorite Qi wireless charging pad</strong> is <a href="https://amzn.to/2ISwV7R" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RavPower's RP-PC034 Fast Charger</a>, a well-rounded wireless charger at the decent price of $24.99. It has the best combination of necessary features and added perks of any wireless charging pad we tested. Its design is simple, but the added rubberized ring on its surface area prevents smartphones from sliding off while charging. It also comes with an AC adapter, something that many cheaper Qi wireless charging pads do not include. But what makes it stand out the most is its speedy charging capabilities—most smartphones will get 30 to 40 percent battery power after just one hour of charging. All of that in a $24.99 device is a great value.</li>
<li>Mophie holds the title of <strong>runner up</strong> with its <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cvwg8e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$41 Charge Stream Pad+</a>. A lot of the things we like about RavPower's charger we also like about Mophie's charger, particularly its TPU-encased design that prevents smartphones from sliding off as well as the charger itself from moving on hard surfaces. The Charge Stream Pad+ is almost as efficient in terms of charging speed as RavPower's charging pad as well. But its more expensive price tag places it in the runner-up spot—it's essentially a more luxurious version of our top pick.</li>
<li><strong>Our favorite budget pick</strong> is the <a href="https://amzn.to/2JQ7tiT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerWave Stand</a> that costs just $15.99. Anker made a stable stand with this device, and smartphones can be placed on it both in portrait or landscape mode. That makes it even easier to use your smartphone while it's charging without too much hassle. We also like stand's rubberized base that keeps it in place, and its larger indicator light that shows when your device is charging successfully. It's not as quick to charge smartphones, but it's not painfully slow either. Lower-watt charging is one of the sacrifices you can expect to make when paying just $15.99 for a wireless charger, but thankfully Anker doesn't make you sacrifice much else with its PowerWave Stand.</li>
<li>A solid <strong>multi-device charger</strong> is <a href="https://amzn.to/2WIiQys" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mophie's Dual wireless charging pad</a>. It can wirelessly charge two devices at once, be it two smartphones or one smartphone and a pair of AirPods, and a third device via an included USB-A port on its back edge. This is the closest thing you'll get to Apple's idealized version of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/03/apple-cancels-airpower-wireless-charging-mat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AirPower</a> (now an abandoned project), making it a convenient option for those that want to be able to wirelessly charge more than one device at the same time using just one accessory—but you have to pay a more expensive price of $80 to get it.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Best overall</h2>
<h3>RavPower RP-PC034 Fast Charger</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/ravpower1_1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          RavPower's RP-PC034 charger comes with a USB cable and an AC adapter.                      [credit:
                        Valentina Palladino                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<table class="specifications right" width="300">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left" colspan="2">Specs at a glance: RavPower RP-PC034 Fast Charger</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td>$24.99</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Standard W</strong></td>
<td>5W</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Max W</strong></td>
<td>10W, 7.5W (iPhones only)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>LED indicator</b></td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>Included adapters</b></td>
<td>USB charging cable, AC adapter</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone case support</strong></td>
<td>Yes, max 3mm thick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone orientation support</strong></td>
<td>Vertical, horizontal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Extras</strong></td>
<td>HyperAir cooling</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>While we tested a number of eye-catching wireless chargers, the humble <a href="https://amzn.to/2ISwV7R" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RavPower Fast Charger RP-PC034 pad</a> was the best of the bunch. Not only is it designed well (not flashy—we'll explain), but it also powered up each smartphone quickly and efficiently.</p>
<p>This wireless charging pad could be mistaken for many others. It's a simple black circle, stamped by the RavPower logo in the middle and "HyperAir" directly below it. The company's HyperAir technology promises 15 percent faster heat dispersion than other wireless charging pads.</p>
<p>We didn't see a huge difference in device temperature among any of the wireless charging pads we tested, but smartphones powered up by the RP-PC034 pad were consistently on the low side of the temperature scale. In fact, temperature after a full charge appeared to be more dependent on the smartphone itself, with the Note 9 almost always being a few degrees hotter than the other smartphones we benchmarked.</p>
<p>Aside from keeping smartphones cool, the RP-PC034 wireless charging pad keeps smartphones in place thanks to a rubberized circle that sits along the pad's inner circumference. While most wireless charging pads are flat where the smartphone is supposed to sit, some have a slight curve or even a raised design on them. The few that we tested that were like that didn't make the cut because smartphones, particularly the iPhone XS and XS Max, slid off of them a few times.</p>
<p>We hypothesize that the reason for that is two-fold: the wireless charging pads didn't have a completely flat surface on which the smartphone could sit, and the iPhones' slippery glass backs made them prone to sliding off.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/UPDATE-11-2019-Wireless-charging-pad-benchmarks-PICKS.001-980x735.jpeg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                                [credit:
                        Valentina Palladino                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>But none of the smartphones we benchmarked fell off the RP-PC034 wireless charging pad (or any of the others that made our top picks). You can truly throw your smartphone onto this wireless charging pad and forget about it, because no matter the position in which it lands, it will be recharged to some degree when you return.</p>
<p>The RP-PC034 pad proved to be excellent in our benchmarking tests as well: after an hour, every smartphone we benchmarked (save one) had at least 40 percent battery life after charging from a completely drained battery on the RP-PC034. The only exception was the Pixel 3, which was consistently slow to charge on everything but the Pixel Stand. The RP-PC034 pad also powered up the smartphones to 100 percent faster than all of the wireless charging pads we tested. On average, it took 198 minutes, or a little more than three hours, to get from 0 percent to 100 percent battery.</p>
<p>To top it off, the RP-PC034 wireless charging pad costs just $24.99. That's a good price for a wireless charging pad that not only powers up smartphones relatively quickly but also comes in a simple, compact design. We also appreciate that the price includes a braided USB cable that connects the pad to the included AC adapter. Many wireless charging devices under $50 don't come with an AC adapter, making RavPower's RP-PC034 pad a gem.</p>
<h3>The Good</h3>
<ul>
<li>Quick and efficient charging pad at a great price.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The Bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>HyperAir cooling doesn't provide incredible cooling gains over other charging pads.</li>
</ul>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/51Vxr2JGnqL._SL1000_ravpower034-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="RavPower RP-PC034 Charging Pad product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">RavPower RP-PC034 Charging Pad                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_71752084" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2ISwV7R" target="_blank">
                                $24.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Runner up</h2>
<h3>Mophie Charge Stream Pad+</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/mophie1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Mophie's Charge Stream Pad+ comes with a USB cable and an AC adapter.                      [credit:
                        Valentina Palladino                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<table class="specifications right" width="300">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left" colspan="2">Specs at a glance: Mophie Charge Stream Pad+</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td>$40.59</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Standard W</strong></td>
<td>5W</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Max W</strong></td>
<td>10W, 7.5W (iPhones only)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>LED indicator</b></td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>Included adapters</b></td>
<td>USB charging cable, AC adapter</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone case support</strong></td>
<td>Yes, max 3mm thick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone orientation support</strong></td>
<td>Vertical, horizontal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Extras</strong></td>
<td>Internal circuitry to prevent overheating</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>RavPower's Fast Charger RP-PC034 pad and <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cvwg8e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mophie's Charge Stream Pad+</a> have a lot in common, and the main differences between them are brand name and price. Mophie's wireless charging pad looks like a higher-end version of RavPower's with its disk shape and all-encompassing TPU coating. Whereas RavPower's charging pad has a rubberized circle inside its circumference, the entirety of Mophie's charging pad is covered with a similar type of material. Needless to say, your smartphone—naked or in a case—will not fall off this charging pad. Extending the TPU coating to the underside of the pad also means the charger won't easily slip off your desk or bedside table.</p>
<p>Similarly to RavPower's device, Mophie's charging pad has internal circuitry that's designed to prevent overheating and overcharging. However, heat wasn't a huge issue in general for all of the wireless charging pads we tested.</p>
<p>The Charge Stream Pad+ comes with a USB cable and an AC adapter, and we appreciate how Mophie hid the microUSB port inside the charging pad. The port sits inside a small hole that has been cut out of the charging pad's back-end. Most other wireless charging pads have an exposed connecting port, which could be more easily damaged if you handle the device roughly or carelessly. It's a small design touch that could make a big difference in the lifetime of the charging pad.</p>
<p>Mophie's wireless charging pad was up there with RavPower's in terms of speed and efficiency: all smartphones except for the Pixel 3 powered up to at least 40 percent after one hour of charging, and it took an average of 197 minutes, or about three hours, to charge each handset from 0 percent to 100 percent battery.</p>
<p>RavPower's and Mophie's wireless charging pads share the same pros and cons—both have attractive, minimalist designs that will stay securely wherever you put them (and that will keep your smartphone secure while charging). They both also provide reliable charging for all kinds of smartphones, so even if you only have a half-hour to spare, you'll get some more juice in your smartphone that could carry you through the rest of the day. Ultimately, Mophie's Charge Stream Pad+ is our runner-up because of its $49 price tag—you're paying for the Mophie name and the clout that comes with it, as well as a slightly more attractive design.</p>
<h3>The Good</h3>
<ul>
<li>Efficient charging pad with non-slip TPU coating on the entire device.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The Bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>On the expensive side.</li>
</ul>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mophie-300x161.jpg"
                                    alt="Mophie Charge Stream Pad Plus product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Mophie Charge Stream Pad Plus                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_38919922" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2Cvwg8e" target="_blank">
                                $40.59 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best budget charger</h2>
<h3>Anker PowerWave Stand</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpowerwave1-980x654.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Anker's PowerWave Qi charging stand.                      [credit:
                        Valentina Palladino                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<table class="specifications right" width="300">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left" colspan="2">Specs at a glance: Anker PowerWave Stand</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td>$15.99</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Standard W</strong></td>
<td>5W</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Max W</strong></td>
<td>10W, 5W (iPhones only)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>LED indicator</b></td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>Included adapters</b></td>
<td>USB charging cable</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone case support</strong></td>
<td>Yes, max 5mm thick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone orientation support</strong></td>
<td>Vertical, horizontal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Extras</strong></td>
<td>None</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Replacing our old budget favorite, RavPower's RP-PC063 charging pad, is <a href="https://amzn.to/2JQ7tiT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker's $16 PowerWave Stand</a>. We like Anker's device more because its stand design lets you use your smartphone more easily while it's charging, and it's just as efficient in terms of charging as RavPower's device is.</p>
<p>The structure of Anker's PowerWave Stand is more of a selling point than the actual build quality. The stand itself is just wide enough to comfortably hold large smartphones like the iPhone 11 Pro Max and the Galaxy Note 9, and its square base is covered in a rubberized material that helps keep the stand in place.</p>
<p>But the stand does feel like a $16 device thanks to the lightweight plastic that makes up most of its design. Manufacturers have to make sacrifices when producing affordable accessories, and using plastic like this in an affordable wireless charger is not uncommon. We do, however, like that Anker put a larger than average indicator light right on the front of the stand—you can easily tell when your smartphone is placed properly on the charger to receive power because the ring of light will instantly light up in a light blue color.</p>
<p>Smartphones can sit on the PowerWave Stand in either portrait or landscape mode, letting you use apps, watch videos, and even use features like Apple's FaceID more easily. This makes the stand a good accessory for your nightstand, but especially for your desk because you can easily see notifications, incoming calls, and more without craning your neck over a flat charging pad.</p>
<p>Anker's stand is not as quick to charge smartphones as our top pick, but it gets the job done. It has a standard charging speed of 5W and it supports 10W fast-charge for Samsung smartphones. In most cases, you'll get at least 20 percent battery power after leaving your handset on the stand for an hour, and it shouldn't take more than five hours to go from 0 percent to 100 percent battery.</p>
<p>If speed and efficiency are your top priorities, it's worth it to go with a slightly more expensive device that can charge devices at higher max voltages. A big difference to note is that our top pick and runner up can both charge the newest iPhones at up to 7.5W while the PowerWave Stand maxes out at 5W for those devices.</p>
<p>Anker also cut cost by forgoing an AC adapter with this stand—one does not come in the box, so you'll have to provide your own. Most wireless charging pads do not come with an AC adapter, so this isn't a strange omission. However, a number of higher-end pads (typically those above $30) include an AC adapter in the box.</p>
<p>I expect sacrifices like this in a wireless charging pad that only costs $15.99. At that low of a price, Anker's PowerWave Stand is a solid option for those who want a basic yet reliable wireless charger that can fit within a strict budget.</p>
<h3>The Good</h3>
<ul>
<li>Slim design that lets you use your smartphone in both portrait and landscape mode while charging.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The Bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>No included AC adapter.</li>
</ul>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpw-300x282.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerWave Stand product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerWave Stand                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_30650417" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2JQ7tiT" target="_blank">
                                $15.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Best multi-device charging pad</h2>
<h3>Mophie Dual wireless charging pad</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mophiedual1-980x654.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Mophie's dual wireless charging pad and its AC adapter.                      [credit:
                        Valentina Palladino                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<table class="specifications right" width="300">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left" colspan="2">Specs at a glance: Mophie Dual Wireless Charging Pad</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Price</strong></td>
<td>$79.95</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Standard W</strong></td>
<td>5W</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Max W</strong></td>
<td>10W (7.5W for iPhones)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>LED indicator</b></td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><b>Included adapters</b></td>
<td>USB charging cable, AC adapter</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone case support</strong></td>
<td>Yes, max 3mm thick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Phone orientation support</strong></td>
<td>Vertical, horizontal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Extras</strong></td>
<td>USB-A port for passthrough charging</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Not long after we found out that Apple abandoned its AirPower ambitions, Mophie came out with a couple of multi-device charging pads include the <a href="https://amzn.to/2WIiQys" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mophie Dual wireless charging pad</a>. This long oval is, essentially, two wireless charging pads in one, allowing you to charge two devices at one time.</p>
<p>The pad itself is a good one—its shiny black surface area looks slick, and its rubberized edges help prevent smartphones from sliding off. Two silver lines indicate where you should position your smartphones on the pad for them to successfully charge, but I found that you can deviate from that indicator slightly. It's actually best to position smartphones in portrait mode closer to the rounded edges of the pad, but you can also put a handset on one side of the pad askew and it will begin charging as well. Your placement doesn't have to be perfect, and you can always check the two indicator lights on the pad's edge to ensure that your smartphone is actually receiving power after you set it down.</p>
<p>Having space on one charging pad for two smartphones is convenient, but most individuals don't own two smartphones. But Mophie's Dual wireless charging pad also supports wireless charging for Apple's AirPods, making it an attractive choice for Apple diehards. In general, the pad will work with most Qi-compatible devices, so there are a number of electronics (not just smartphones) that you could charge up with this device.</p>
<p>Mophie's Dual wireless charging pad also has a hidden USB-A port on its back edge, so it can actually charge three devices at once: two on the wireless pad itself, and one via the USB port. This makes cable management much easier, and can turn the accessory into a charging hub of sorts for all your most-used devices.</p>
<p>The dual charging pad provides decent power to smartphones and will charge the newest iPhones at a maximum of 7.5W. In most cases, you'll get 30 percent battery after leaving your handset on the pad for an hour. It took a bit longer than most (roughly 4.5 hours on average) to charge smartphones from 0 to 100 percent, though, but that won't be too much of an issue for those that charge their smartphones most completely overnight.</p>
<p>Wireless chargers are all about convenience, and that makes a dual wireless charger overkill for most people. The best things about multi-device chargers, including Mophie's, are that they help keep all your wireless charging devices in once place and they reduce the number of cords in your life. If those things are most important to you, and you're willing to pay a bit more and sacrifice speed, then Mophie's Dual wireless charging pad is a solid option.</p>
<h3>The Good</h3>
<ul>
<li>Charges up to three devices at the same time (two wirelessly, one via USB port).</li>
</ul>
<h3>The Bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>Charging cable cannot be removed from AC adapter.</li>
</ul>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mophiedual-300x127.jpg"
                                    alt="Mophie Dual wireless charging pad product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Mophie Dual wireless charging pad                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_60966746" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2WIiQys" target="_blank">
                                $79.95 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Testing Methodology</h2>
<h2>How does wireless charging work?</h2>
<p>Modern wireless chargers for smartphones use inductive charging to transfer energy between the charging pad and a mobile device. A loop of coiled wires sits inside the charging pad with a magnet in the center. As electric current passes through these wires, it creates an electromagnetic field around the magnet. That field can then transfer energy to a nearby receiver coil that's found in smartphones and other mobile devices that support wireless charging.</p>
<p>The amount of power that can be transferred from the inductor (the charging pad) to the receiver (the mobile device) is dependent on many things, including the number of wire coils in both devices, the strength of the magnet in the inductor, and the distance between the inductor and the receiver. The latter explains the design of most wireless chargers today: smartphones need to sit very close to (i.e., directly on top of) the wireless charger to receive the most amount of energy possible.</p>
<h2>Qi standard and your smartphone</h2>
<p>Within the past couple of years, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/how-qi-wireless-charging-works-and-why-it-hasnt-taken-over-yet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Qi (pronounced "chee") wireless charging standard</a> has emerged victorious over other competing standards. At the start of 2018, Powermat, which pushed the PMA charging standard, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/01/powermat-gives-in-to-qi-moves-wireless-charging-closer-to-uniformity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">joined</a> the Wireless Power Consortium, the organization that represents the Qi standard. Powermat's CEO stated at the time that Qi had become the "dominant wireless charging standard on the market," and it only continues to exert its dominance by pushing other standards out of the game.</p>

<p>Knowing that a wireless charging pad follows the Qi standard simply means knowing that it uses Qi's method of inductive power transfer and that it will power Qi-friendly smartphones. All Qi "base stations" (charging pads, stands, etc.) derive energy from a power source (typically an outlet) and activate only when a Qi-compatible mobile device has been placed on it. The base sends test signals to the device to ensure that it's compatible, and once it has confirmed this, it starts inductively transmitting power to the receiving mobile device.</p>
<p>The underlying goal of Qi's wireless charging technique is to power the compatible mobile device only to 100 percent. The receiving device and the base constantly communicate through signals that tell the base how much more power is necessary to power the mobile device's battery in full. Once that's achieved, the base essentially goes into standby mode, automatically stopping its transfer of power.</p>
<p>All of the wireless charging pads we've tested in this guide are Qi-compatible, so you'll need a Qi-compatible smartphone to use them. Many recent flagship smartphones including the iPhone 11, iPhone 11 Pro, iPhone 11 Pro Max, Galaxy S10, and Pixel 4 support Qi-wireless charging. If you have a smartphone that came out in the last two years, it probably supports wireless charging through the Qi standard.</p>
<p>But you can't just throw your smartphone onto the charging pad and expect it to be powered up when you return hours later. Most Qi chargers follow the "guided positioning" principle, which means that the mobile device needs to be precisely placed on the pad so that its internal receiving hardware is lined up with the coiled wires and magnets that live in the charging pad.</p>
<p>So if your phone lands even just a few millimeters off of the intended placement, it may not charge while sitting on the base. Qi charging pads employ a few tricks to help users position their devices correctly, like visual and tactile design elements. Some bases even have internal coils that move to align with a user's mobile device.</p>
<h2>Wired or wireless charging?</h2>
<p>If your top priorities are speed and efficiency, you should stick with wired charging. Plugging your smartphone into a charging cable that's connected to a power outlet will almost always charge your device faster than a wireless charging pad. By its nature, wireless charging technology isn't as efficient as wired charging, so you will not see the same rate of energy transfer that you would when charging with a wire.</p>
<p>However, wireless charging can be more convenient. Whether you have a charging pad or a stand, it's easy to set your smartphone down and come back a little while later to a topped-up device. That's why wireless charging pads are popular accessories for bedroom nightstands and office desks—they leave the environment free from messy cables while still providing a convenient method of charging your mobile device.</p>
<p>But wireless charging has hardware and software limitations. Be sure to check the wattage of your wireless charger and the compatible wattage on your smartphone. For example, iPhones running the latest version of iOS support 7.5W wireless charging. Even if you have a 10W charger, the iPhone will max out at 7.5W of wireless charging. While Apple has vaguely described faster wireless charging capabilities (up to 10W) in the iPhone XS and XS Max, there's no official documentation or details to support this.</p>
<h3>A note about Qualcomm Quick Charge</h3>
<p>During our testing, Qualcomm <a href="https://9to5google.com/2019/02/25/quick-charge-wireless-qi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> it began working with the UL and Wireless Power Consortium to officially bring its Quick Charge technology to Qi-compatible wireless chargers. Not only does Qualcomm want to do this because the industry is slowly shifting away from wired charging, but it also wants to make it clear which devices support Quick Charge and which do not (some devices falsely claim to support the technology now).</p>
<p>These plans are still in the works, so we're eager to update this guide when more Qualcomm-approved, Quick Charge-capable devices become available. Some of the devices we tested for this guide claim "fast charge" capabilities, but we mostly ran our tests (see below) to judge just how quickly each device could charge a smartphone.</p>

<h2>How we tested</h2>
<p>We tested some of the most popular wireless chargers on the market and judged them based on design, power, price, and charging efficiency. To benchmark each charger, we used a few smartphones: <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/09/iphone-11-review-the-sweet-spot-iphone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPhone 11</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/09/iphone-11-pro-and-11-pro-max-review-high-quality-for-high-prices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPhone 11 Pro, iPhone 11 Pro Max</a>, Google Pixel 4, and the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/08/galaxy-note9-hands-on-samsung-ships-a-bigger-battery-not-much-else/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung Galaxy Note 9</a>. Before testing each charger, we powered up each smartphone from 0 percent battery life using its included charging cable to obtain standard charging reference points. We then ran the following tests three times per smartphone and averaged the data to get a final score.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>One-hour charge:</strong> Charge smartphone wirelessly for one hour, starting at 0 percent battery, and record the result in percentage-charged.</li>
<li><strong>Full battery charge:</strong> Charge smartphone wirelessly, starting at 0 percent battery, until battery level reaches 100 percent, and then record the result in minutes-charged.</li>
</ul>
<p>If a wireless charging pad came with an AC adaptor, we used that adapter in our testing. If a pad didn't come with an AC adapter, we used the <a href="https://amzn.to/2HzIQr9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Dual USB PowerPort II 24W Charger</a> along with the cables provided with the device (every wireless charging pad we tested came with a cable). In addition to charging percentage and time, we also recorded the temperature of each smartphone after it was fully charged using the <a href="https://amzn.to/2YffROB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Etekcity Lasergrip 774 Digital Laser Infrared Thermometer</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1446745&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ars To-Be-Read: Five books we’re most excited to read in 2020</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593377</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anticipated reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ars Holiday 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sci-fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593377</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Start 2020 off right by reading these intriguing sci-fi, fantasy, and nonfiction books.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/GettyImages-1005735718-800x533.jpg" alt="Stock photo of a blanket-wrapped woman reading a book."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/GettyImages-1005735718.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3147" data-width="4721">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.istockphoto.com/"> iStock / Getty Images Plus</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>As "best of 2019" lists flood in, we're looking toward the future—the literary future, to be precise. After another solid year of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/staff/2019/05/staffsource-ars-staffers-share-their-favorite-books-to-get-lost-in-this-summer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reading in 2019</a>, we're excited for new releases to come in the early months of 2020. Below are some of our most anticipated reads that you can get your hands on within the first three months of 2020.</p>

<p>Hugo-award-winner N.K. Jemisin will be releasing the first novel in a new series in March, while German author-songwriter Marc-Uwe Kling has a satirical novel about our addiction to convenience coming out in English for the first time. We know setting New Year's resolutions can be hard, but we think you'll want to put all five of these upcoming releases at the top of your TBR list.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2><em>The City We Became</em> by N.K. Jemisin</h2>
<section class="page-section g">
<div class="page-section__generator page-section__generator--top g12-xs g11-md g10-lg g8-xl">
<div class="page-generator__text page-generator__text--top js-generator-text">
<div id="output" class="page-generator__output js-generator-output">
<div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/jemisin.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/jemisin-300x463.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/jemisin.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/jemisin.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Hachette)</p></div>
<p>N.K. Jemisin returns with her first new novel after her three-year Hugo-winning streak for her <em>Broken Earth</em> trilogy. New York, Jemisin's hometown, is the setting for <a href="https://amzn.to/36IrvWB" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The City We Became</em></a> (out March 24, 2020), but it's not the New York that we're familiar with. Five New Yorkers are brought together as avatars of the city, destined to fight together to defend their home from a supernatural, ancient evil.</p>
<p>The New Yorkers don't know what lies ahead of them, and nor do they know that the city they call home faces an existential threat that could wipe out everyone and everything in it. However, the severity of the situation becomes apparent when the city begins fighting against them as the evil lurking throughout its streets and back alleys starts taking over.</p>
<p>An extension of a short story in Jemisin's collection <em>How Long 'til Black Future Month</em> (<a href="https://www.tor.com/2016/09/28/the-city-born-great/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">which can be read at Tor.com</a>), <em>The City We Became</em> is the first in a new series in which major cities become characters themselves, and those who live in them must fight for the soul of their hometowns. While the subject matter is very different from Jemisin's <em>Broken Earth</em> trilogy, lovers of fantasy will get lost in Jemisin's signature, lyrical prose, and those who gravitate to stories imbued with the age-old struggle between good and evil will also enjoy <em>The City We Became</em>.</p>
<h2><em>Qualityland</em> by Marc-Uwe Kling</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img left medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/qualityland.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/qualityland-300x453.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/qualityland.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/qualityland.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: QualityLand)</p></div>
<p>Welcome to QualityLand, the best nation on Earth—because it was built for you. In QualityLand, everything is automated to make your life more convenient: digital personal assistants find everything from the best food to the best friends for you, a universal ranking system decides which social class you'll excel in and what career you should pursue, while advanced algorithms from the most successful company on Earth, TheShop, deliver necessities to your door without you needing to order them. Everything is easy, everything is personal, everything is <em>quality</em>.</p>
<p>But one day, a resident of QualityCity in QualityLand named Peter Jobless receives a package from TheShop he definitely knows he does not want. He decides, against his better judgement, to return it—and thereby call into question the foundations of QualityLand as a whole.</p>
<p>Translated from German into English for the first time, <a href="https://amzn.to/2K62uee" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Qualityland</em></a> (out January 7, 2020) is full of laugh-inducing absurdities that come dangerously close to a possible, not-too-distant future. Some of the features of QualityLand (like TouchKiss, a "more forge-proof" method of biometric authentication that makes citizens kiss their tablets when they need to pay for food at a restaurant, receive delivered packages, and the like) are both ridiculous and uncanny because they are totally feasible, albeit unlikely, things that could happen in our world today. Kling's witty, satirical look at technology and our dependence on it is a must-read if you're intrigued by dystopian futures that hit a little too close to home. HBO will also <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/mike-judge-solidifies-hbo-future-rich-deal-pair-series-orders-1193760" target="_blank" rel="noopener">turn <em>Qualityland</em> into a series</a> in the future, so be sure to check out the book before that happens.</p>
<h2><em>Bagels, Bumf, and Buses</em> by Simon Horobin</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bbb.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bbb-300x482.jpeg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bbb.jpeg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bbb.jpeg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Oxford University Press)</p></div>
<p>Wordsmiths will relish reading <a href="https://amzn.to/2K1931m" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Bagels, Bumf, and Buses: A Day in the Life of the English Language</em></a> (out January 1, 2020) by Simon Horobin. A professor of English and literature at Oxford, Horobin takes readers through a typical day in a typical person's life, examining all of the ubiquitous words that we encounter on the way. Have you ever wondered, while munching on your Wheaties, where the word "cereal" comes from? Has the origin of the word "pants" ever struck you while you got dressed to go to work? Even if these thoughts are foreign to you, Horobin's informative-yet-engaging writing style will make you curious.</p>
<p>Most of us take the English language for granted, but <em>Bagels, Bumf, and Buses</em> will give you a new appreciation for the words you likely use many times each day. Horobin fascinatingly takes commonplace words like "office" and "gymnasium," as well as new lingo like "meme" and "hashtag," and traces their origins back to multiple languages and associated words from the past.</p>
<p>He also explains how words have evolved and changed over time (like how "lunch" used to be a fancier version of "luncheon," not the other way around) and shows how evolutionary language was and continues to be as we humans use and abuse it. Anyone with a passion for language or a burning desire to learn more trivia should check out <em>Bagels, Bumf, and Buses.</em></p>
<h2><em>A Witch in Time</em> by Constance Sayers</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img left medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/awit.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/awit-300x462.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/awit.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/awit.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Redhook)</p></div>
<p>Recently divorced Helen Lambert goes on a first date with a man who's clearly not her type. But this man, Luke, talks to Helen as if he has known her for years—decades even. Readers of <a href="https://amzn.to/36NGe2g" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>A Witch in Time</em></a> (out February 11, 2020) are then thrown into Helen's story, which is also the story of Juliet LaCompte, a woman living in late 19th-century France who's having an affair with a married Parisian painter. The decision by Juliet's mother, a witch, to curse her daughter's lover inadvertently ties Juliet to him through time—dooming her to relive the same love affair over and over for centuries to come.</p>
<p>Juliet lives multiple different lives since her first one in France, all of which have been watched over by Luke, who's actually a demon in charge of maintaining this botched curse. But Luke isn't merely a passive observer as he follows Juliet (and Nora, and Sandra, and Helen, and all the names she takes over the years) through time—he's more attached than she knows. But as Helen starts to remember some of the details of her past lives, she discovers that she might be able to break the curse once and for all.</p>
<p>While <em>A Witch in Time</em> has a romanticism akin to that in <em>Outlander</em> and <em>The Time Traveler's Wife</em>, it's also an intriguing romp through history and an interesting look at one woman's identity as it literally changes as the decades come and go. Sayers balances a lot of elements in this story—it's part historical fiction with a time-travel twist, part romance with a supernatural kick. Readers who enjoy stories chronicling one person's life (however many lives they have) will want to read <em>A Witch in Time</em>.</p>
<h2><em>The Wolf of Oren-Yaro</em> by K.S. Villoso</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/twooy.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/twooy-300x463.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/twooy.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/twooy.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Hachette)</p></div>
<p>Talyien is a woman devoted to her people and her nation of Oren-Yaro. In order to bring peace to the factions of her nation, Talyien is promised to the son of her father's rival. But the night before she's crowned queen, Talyien commits a startling act, and her husband leaves.</p>
<p>Fast forward a few years and Queen Talyien is struggling to rule on her own when she receives a request to meet her estranged husband in a distant nation. Knowing that the consequences of not going would be worse than anything else, Talyien leaves with only her most trusted guards to meet her husband. But things quickly turn sour when their secret meeting is ambushed and assassins attempt to kill Talyien. Now, stuck in a foreign nation, Talyien must find her way home and rescue her husband without losing her own life.</p>
<p>Fans of Villoso's existing <em>Agartes Epilogues</em> series will find similarities between it and <a href="https://amzn.to/34MYbvZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Wolf of Oren-Yaro </em></a>(out February 18, 2020). But the new series is by no means derivative—Villoso is an expert at world-building, and the pace of the novel forces you to move as quickly as Talyien does from one precarious situation to another. <em>The Wolf of Oren-Yaro</em> is a high-fantasy thrill ride that fans of the genre will appreciate, particularly those thirsting for a strong female main character.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593377&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jedi: Fallen Order game review: More like, the Force goes back to sleep</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1599799</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 04:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Machkovech]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respawn Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1599799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[EA finally releases a single-player <em>Star Wars</em> game, but promising intro falls apart.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-1627-980x551.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          If you do nothing but look at images of this game in action, you'll wonder why I have anything ho-hum to say. At its best, <em>Jedi: Fallen Order</em> is one of 2019's prettiest games. (All images in this article are captured from real-time PC gameplay.)                      [credit:
                        EA / Respawn / Lucasfilm                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

Years after <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/05/the-future-of-star-wars-games-belongs-to-ea/">EA paid ridiculously for the rights to <em>Star Wars</em>'s gaming universe</a>, the game publisher has finally arrived with what fans wanted from it in the first place: a solid single-player adventure. Low as that bar might be, that's the archetype that the most beloved '80s and '90s <em>Star Wars</em> fare delivered on, and it's the kind of experience we haven't seen <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2010/06/force-unleashed-ii-has-dual-lightsabers-sameish-gameplay/">for nearly a decade</a>.</p>
<p>Really, 2010's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2010/06/force-unleashed-ii-has-dual-lightsabers-sameish-gameplay/"><em>Star Wars: The Force Unleashed II</em></a> is an appropriate reference point as we peel back the EA-ization of <em>Star Wars</em> games—from <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2011/12/forever-alone-stars-wars-the-old-republic-as-a-single-player-game/">MMO-related bloat</a> to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/report-eas-beleaguered-open-world-star-wars-game-is-no-more/">cancellations</a> to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2017/11/can-ea-fix-whats-broken-with-star-wars-battlefront-iis-economy/">loot boxes</a>—and dive into <em>Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order</em>. Respawn Entertainment's new game, out now on PCs and consoles, pits you (and a suite of Force powers) against armies of AI-controlled foes. Sounds familiar, right? And is that a good thing?</p>
<p>After playing its 12-hour campaign, I can only muster a shoulder shrug as a response. I guess. Sure. If you want.</p>
<p>That's not to say <em>Fallen Order</em> isn't polished or, at times, quite impressive. But it's also a painfully <em>safe</em> game, built to check a list of "hardcore gamer" boxes instead of forging particularly new paths for the Jedi power fantasy. Respawn was given the unenviable task of winning back some of the most opinionated fans in the world, and the developer charted a tried-and-true course of doing so: a third-person adventure that combines lightsaber waving and a healthy mix of Force superpowers. (You know, like <em>Force Unleashed II</em>.)</p>
<p>Because it hews to a safe archetype, <em>Jedi: Fallen Order</em> may not earn much patience from players for its issues and slip-ups. Every time the game's dialogue turns hackneyed, that stands out in an otherwise fine-if-rote <em>Star Wars</em> adventure. Every time combat glitches on a bad hitbox or polygon collision, that stands out among otherwise been-there-slashed-that combat. And every time a level suffers from a back-and-forth retread or an unsatisfying puzzle, that stands out from a bunch of levels that borrow liberally from games we've played before: <em><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/uncharted/">Uncharted</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/nintendo-throws-out-metroid-prime-4-work-restarts-with-retro-studios/">Metroid Prime</a>, and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/dark-souls/">Dark Souls</a>.</em></p>
<p>Worst of all, <em>Fallen Order</em>'s brief campaign doesn't land in short-and-sweet territory. Just short.</p>
<h2>Is that a lightsaber in your pocket, or...</h2>
<p>We begin in the shoes of Cal Kestis, a young-and-plucky mechanic working on an ornate Empire outpost. We meet him after the events of the film series' <em>Episode III</em>, and we hear banter about the great Jedi Purge while Cal jumps, scampers, and wall-climbs his way to fix a particularly broken machine at his workplace. It's a tough job, he's warned, but he makes quick-if-dramatic work of it.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this sequence turns deadly, which forces Cal to reveal the secret he's been harboring amongst the Empire's faithful for years: he's a Jedi, and a trained one at that. How was he not sniffed out all this time? How was he hiding a <em>lightsaber</em> in his pocket for so long? And how come a Resistance crew happens upon his location, there to save him, the moment his lightsaber is belatedly discovered by troopers? The abruptness of his identity's reveal is a bit patchy in the logic department, and it sets a tone for too many wait-hold-on jumps in logic or abrupt fast-forwards in the plot's timeline.</p>
<p>Cal's rescue comes with a catch: the human soldier Cere wants to reboot the Jedi Order, and she has a few vague clues to uncovering other Jedi who survived and escaped the Purge. She needs a true Jedi's help to unlock their meaning and move forward. Help her, Cal Kestis. You're her only hope.</p>
<p>You do so by following the <em>Force Unleashed</em> series' archetype of lightsaber combat and force tactics, as mashed up with the outdoor-world traversal of <em>Uncharted</em>, the get-powers-and-backtrack formula of <em>Metroid</em>, and some <em>Dark Souls</em>-inspired combat tweaks. It's sometimes easy to ignore the failings of this game-inspiration mash-up, seeing as how each major landscape, tomb, catacomb, fortress, prison, and crash site looks so danged good.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/vlcsnap-2019-11-12-21h49m04s556-980x634.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Cal will need to remember all of his lost Jedi training before he can expect to defeat the Second Sister.                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Respawn was freed from the usual EA restriction of making 3D games out of the Frostbite Engine (developed primarily by EA subsidiary DICE), and its pivot to Unreal Engine 4 has paid off in terms of massive, architecturally rich, and foliage-filled environs. Volumetric light shafts cut through dramatically lit skies and bounce realistic, material-based lighting off every surface. Cal's lightsaber glows impressively in dark chambers and caves, whether held at his side or aloft as a makeshift torch. And massive structures tower in the distance of every new planet, served on a platter of impressive draw distances as a preview of Cal's next adventuring destination.</p>
<h2>An <em>Uncharted</em> climb through charted territory</h2>
<p>That visual bounty carries <em>Jedi: Fallen Order</em>'s opening hours impressively. Once that sheen faded, however, my patience with the gameplay's fumbles dwindled quickly—a fact that wasn't helped when the visuals in later levels began to suffer from serious copy-and-paste syndrome. One forest moment, in particular, saw my character soar above a tree-filled world, but the vast view from above suffered from minimal geometry, badly baked geometry, and a derpy, super-sized companion that showed up in that moment.</p>
<p>In terms of failings, let's start with the new game's <em>Uncharted</em> inspirations. Do you like climbing on clearly marked walls of moss or girded metal? <em>J:FO</em> has these in spades, and on a rare occasion, these moments are delightful—like when you have to board an AT-AT and must climb the grassy patches on its legs and torso as it marches in formation through murky waters toward a combat zone. But most of the time, these moments feel like overlong padding, and they miss the point of <em>Uncharted</em>'s climbing sections. In <em>J:FO</em>, there's no dramatic pulling-back of the camera while climbing to set any cinematic scope of a new zone or tomb. You're zoomed on Cal's butt, following automatic climbing lines. Meh.</p>
<p>More critically, <em>J:FO</em> breaks up its combat sections with a few <em>Uncharted</em>-esque puzzle sections, which usually revolve around triggering or moving the right objects in the right order. The first significant puzzle requires moving giant orbs with your force powers and triggering gusts of wind to shoot them to the correct puzzle-solving locations. Its careful balance between tricky challenge and clear progress got my hopes up for more clever puzzle coolness to come.</p>
<p>But there really aren't many of these puzzles here, and the others either play out too automatically or come with agonizingly unclear solutions. I lost nearly an hour to one puzzle because the game's "clue" button kept dispensing advice that relied on terminology I'd never heard before and wasn't in the game's pause-screen glossary. I eventually came up with a solution that in no way resembled the spoken advice I was given. I'm still not sure whether I solved that puzzle as Respawn intended.</p>
<h2>Combat has <em>Souls</em>, not soul</h2>
<p>Then there's combat, which only comes in two flavors: wimpy peons, or <em>Dark Souls</em>-caliber death traps. With the former, you can ignore most of your cool Force powers and mash the "quick slice" button to mow down waves of foes. Once you unlock the Force-push move, you'll appreciate how often the game's basic enemies stand near ledges; the modeling of their "AAHHHHhhhh..." yelps never gets old. But generally, you can ignore most of your useful Force powers in these cases—especially because the game is painfully stingy about letting you use them.</p>
<p>Every time you activate <em>any</em> Force-related power, you drain a huge percentage of Cal's "Force meter." Even the prototypical "strong attack" for your lightsaber requires the Force. Use one time-dilation, one Force-pull, and one strong attack, and... that's it for at least 10 seconds. Your Force meter is toast. This issue persists throughout the campaign, even as you dump level-up stats into options like a Force meter upgrade. Battling the game's wimpy peons could've been more fun if Respawn had been more generous with Force powers or the meter's recharge. Instead, the constant nag of a "meter's empty" notice aggravated me so much that I redirected my fanboy energy to just tapping the "quick attack" lightsaber button.</p>
<p>The tougher fights exacerbate this annoyance. Most of your coolest Force powers are worthless against big-league foes, who are identified by a different on-screen interface when they appear. They ignore your temporary time-freeze and your Force-push powers, and that means you're reduced to a wimp, forced to study movement patterns and get into a dodge-and-react pattern. That's fine on its face, but no other combat in the game emphasizes tactics, and the game never sits down with players to clarify that it will abruptly switch from kill-all-the-dummies simplicity to pause-and-study brutality. (Plus, you only get one weapon "upgrade" option in terms of strike timing, and it feels absolutely meager compared to the combat specialization that great Souls-like combat often revolves around.)</p>
<p>If you hand <em>J:FO</em> to a young gamer who's only played <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2006/09/5413/"><em>LEGO Star Wars</em> games</a>, this aspect alone will be the most frustrating, as these fights are obnoxiously tough even at "normal" difficulty.</p>
<p>As if to support this <em>Souls</em>-ification of occasional harder combat, the game also comes with an "every enemy respawns when you pause to 'meditate' and heal" system. That's much like the bonfires found in <em>Dark Souls</em>. But as I've already pointed out, this combat isn't in the same realm as <em>Dark Souls</em>, not by a longshot. (All of this ignores some glaring issues with combat hitboxes, by the way; on too many occasions, the game's toughest creatures either swiped through Cal without causing damage or knocked him down over a good foot away from contact. And that's not even speaking of the polygon glitching through geometry I faced when a tough foe pinned me against a wall.)</p>
<p>Why did Respawn implement this when roughly 80% of <em>J:FO</em>'s combat is through annoying waves of simple peons? Did the creators not sit and play <em>Dark Souls</em> games enough to understand what its bonfire risk-and-reward system was really about? The fact that <em>J:FO</em> bonfires exist, yet never mesh with the combat on offer, leads me to believe that something in the game's production cycle got rushed or streamlined. Maybe Respawn had a clearer <em>Souls</em>-like vision once upon a time, but something got lost in a rush to meet a Q4 deadline and get "<em>Souls</em>-like" on the box.</p>
<h2>Backtrack for a new... coat of paint?</h2>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/jedi-fallen-order-map-980x551.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The game revolves around four explorable planets. Most of their zones are gated off by required Force powers, which you unlock over the course of the campaign.                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>You might think of <em>Star Wars</em> plus <em>Metroid</em> as the action-adventure mash-up of your dreams, where you unlock cool new Force powers, then return to previous worlds to expose new traversal and battling possibilities. To some extent, this plays out as advertised. You'll find blocked entrances or weird-looking obstacles early in the game, and you'll salivate the first time you get an upgrade like the Force push, which is clearly designed to tear through blocked doorways.</p>
<p>But once you go back to those doors and passages and rip their barriers open, you're rewarded with garbage. Nearly every hidden, tricky, and Force-gated treasure chest in <em>J:FO</em> comes with one of three cosmetic items: a new color of cloak for Cal, a new paint job for your robo-companion BD-1, or a coat of paint for the ship that auto-flies from one level to the next. As a very rare exception, you'll actually find hidden upgrades to your health or Force meters, but these are always marked as floating purple orbs, not treasure chests.</p>
<p>As a result, whenever I saw a treasure chest around a corner or through a blown-open doorway, I found myself loudly sighing. These things don't add experience points (which I can use to unlock new Force powers), let alone the Force meter upgrades I so desperately want (which are still way too meager for the sake of fun, Force-juggling combat). You'll also often find brief plot details in the game's hidden corners, which at least dole out tiny experience-point boosts, but the stories attached are snoozers. None revolve around interesting new characters, let alone flesh out details about popular <em>Star Wars</em> locations or film-series events.</p>
<p>Back to that <em>Metroid</em> comparison: yes, you're backtracking to previously visited planets to unlock new zones and complete new objectives, but the result is that the game is inherently reduced to roughly eight "levels" of content, and every new zone is clearly demarcated as a separate straight-line path. Respawn hasn't arrived to reinvent the wheel of compelling criss-crossing zones or play fancifully with how old and new paths might intersect in interesting "oh, <em>now</em> I see what's happening" ways. Worse, while each of the four planets include landing zones that sparkle with incredible and unique environs, each of their revealed-later paths suffers from that copy-paste syndrome I mentioned earlier.</p>
<p>Respawn at least makes sure to include 1-2 wholly new enemies with each zone, which is absolutely welcome. But the new heavies don't spice combat up very much, and they certainly don't make up for the newer zones' blatant reuse of temple assets, similar-looking tunnels, or a gratuitous lean on repetitive wall-climbing and mud-sliding sequences.</p>
<h2>My opinion was not Force-pushed in a good direction</h2>
<p><em>Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order</em> has incredibly good elements, and they play out exceptionally well in its first three hours. Force-power diversity, combat animations, beautiful opening zones, clever puzzles, and Jedi-salvation stakes could lead anybody to believe they were in for a <em>Star Wars</em> single-player epic worth investing in.</p>
<p>The trouble is, the game begins to run on fumes after those three hours. The presentation declines. The combat suffers from a hamstrung approach to difficulty balance and Force-power generosity. The plot becomes a painfully telegraphed "morality tale," burdened in particular by terribly sold "conflicts" between Cal and his accomplices. The incentives for so much backtracking get bungled.</p>
<p>Each of those issues would be easier to swallow if it appeared in isolation, surrounded otherwise by a game that turned out to be solid-but-redundant in its 12-hour romp. But as a combo platter, the whole package misses its "three great tastes taste great together" sales pitch. I left <em>J:FO</em> unmoved as both a <em>Star Wars</em> fan and an action-adventure gaming fan. Despite its polish and best ideas, I wish I'd just reinstalled both <em>Force Unleashed</em> games, and I encourage anybody eager for a fun, Force-filled, third-person <em>Star Wars</em> experience this year to do the same.</p>
<h2>The good:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The game's opening hours combine a promising story, accessible combat, beautiful setpieces, and a lovable new droid in masterful fashion.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The bad:</h2>
<ul>
<li>12-hour campaign would be easier to stomach if it didn't run out of steam so quickly.</li>
<li>Dark Souls-ification of combat feels more like a ticked-off box than a fitting system for this game's combat.</li>
<li>By the end of the game, the story feels rote and utterly disposable in the Star Wars universe, and it loses its logical train of thought along the way.</li>
<li>Metroid-like backtracking system feels annoying thanks to mostly worthless, cosmetic loot.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The ugly:</h2>
<ul>
<li>I hope Respawn issues a patch that increases players' access to Force powers during encounters; in its current state, the game taunts Star Wars fans with such meager access to Jedi superpower juggling.</li>
<li>Glitchy hitbox issues make the game's tougher combat sequences harder to swallow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Verdict</strong>: Since the paid Origin Access Basic subscription service <a href="https://answers.ea.com/t5/General-Discussion/Star-Wars-Jedi-origin-access/td-p/7795678">didn't make <em>J:FO</em> eligible for its usual 10-hour trial</a>, I can only recommend renting or avoiding altogether (unless you already pay for <a href="https://www.origin.com/usa/en-us/store/origin-access">Origin Access Premier</a> on PC, which includes full <em>J:FO</em> access).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1599799&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robert F. Kennedy Jr. is the single leading source of anti-vax ads on Facebook</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602431</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 02:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602431</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researchers dig into Facebook's ad library.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/GettyImages-472995698-800x598.jpg" alt="A man in a suit addresses a small crowd."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/GettyImages-472995698.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2242" data-width="3000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Anti-vaccine advocate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. during a public hearing on vaccine-related bills in 2015.  (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/robert-f-kennedy-jr-testifies-during-public-hearing-in-news-photo/472995698?adppopup=true">Getty | Portland Press Herald</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Just two organizations were responsible for the majority of anti-vaccine advertisements on Facebook before the social media giant restricted such content in March of this year, according to <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0264410X1931446X?via%3Dihub">a November 13 study in the journal Vaccine</a>.</p>
<p>Of 145 anti-vaccine Facebook advertisements that ran between May 31, 2017 and February 22, 2019, the World Mercury Project and a group called Stop Mandatory Vaccination together ran 54% of them.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/robert-f-kennedy-jr-launches-the-world-mercury-project-300364404.html">The World Mercury Project</a>, which ran the most ads of any single source, is an organization closely aligned with the anti-vaccine group <a href="https://childrenshealthdefense.org/">Children's Health Defense</a>. Both are spearheaded by Robert F. Kennedy Jr., an environmental lawyer turned prolific peddler of dangerous anti-vaccine misinformation. He and his organizations promote conspiracy theories about vaccine safety, including the roundly debunked claim that safe, life-saving immunizations are linked to autism. More recently, Kennedy has become <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/06/anti-vaxxers-defeated-ny-bans-exemptions-as-doctors-vote-to-step-up-fight/">a prominent opponent</a> of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/07/anti-vaxxers-lose-again-ny-judge-upholds-ban-on-religious-exemptions/">laws aimed at increasing vaccination rates</a> among school children.</p>
<p>Stop Mandatory Vaccination is a for-profit venture run by a man named Larry Cook. He, too, trumpets vaccine misinformation and fear-mongers. On Facebook and other platforms, Cook runs advertisements and campaigns making dubious links between the vaccines and tragic baby deaths. One such ad was <a href="https://www.asa.org.uk/rulings/larry-cook-a18-457503.html">banned by the UK's Advertising Standards Authority</a> last year. The regulator determined the ad to be "misleading," "unsubstantiated," and "likely to cause undue distress." In other instances, he has claimed that the pro-vaccine medical community is covering up the "slaughter" of children.</p>
<p>Cook has raised tens of thousands of dollars via crowd funding. (He was <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/gofundme-bans-anti-vaxxers-who-raise-money-to-spread-misinformation">banned earlier this year from GoFundMe</a>). The money goes not only to Cook's disturbing anti-vaccine misinformation campaigns but also to his own pockets. In <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/anti-vaxxer-larry-cook-has-weaponized-facebook-ads-in-war-against-science">an interview with The Daily Beast</a> in February, Cook declined to disclose how much of the donations he receives go to himself and how much go to his anti-vaccine activities. He told the outlet: "I'm not a non-profit. I don't need to report any income—we are in a capitalist society and anyone can raise and spend how we want."</p>
<h2>Weaponized advertising</h2>
<p>The academic study drawing attention to Kennedy's and Cook's efforts is based on data mined from Facebook's Ad Library. The library is an <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ads/library/?active_status=all&amp;ad_type=political_and_issue_ads&amp;country=US&amp;impression_search_field=has_impressions_lifetime">open, searchable repository of advertisements</a> that the social media giant deems related to politics and "issues of national importance." Facebook set up the repository as an effort to appear more transparent in the wake of scandals, namely the misappropriation of data by Cambridge Analytica and the revelation that Russian operatives had weaponized Facebook ads to meddle in US politics.</p>
<p>While the data is in some ways vague and incomplete, it clearly shows that anti-vaccine propaganda was unified in promoting perceived harms of vaccines, conspiracy theories, and the idea of vaccine choice.</p>
<p>Compared with pro-vaccine Facebook ads, the anti-vaccine ads had slightly higher budgets and more reach. Anti-vaccine ads also had fewer sponsors—27 unique buyers of 145 anti-vaccine ads compared with 83 unique buyers of 163 pro-vaccine ads.</p>
<p>The study's authors, led by public health researchers at the University of Maryland, criticized Facebook for further politicizing the non-controversial issue of life-saving immunizations. They conclude that "the extent to which Facebook's advertisements, coupled with other social media channels, undermine public trust in vaccinations, and more broadly, the government agencies charged with protecting the public's health, is beyond simply worrisome."</p>
<p>After the study was complete, Facebook announced a crackdown on anti-vaccine misinformation, including ditching anti-vaccine ads. Though some of the changes have gone into effect—including the banishing of some ads—the authors cautiously note that the "full impact of these policies remains to be seen."</p>
<p>Vaccine, 2019. DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.10.066">10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.10.066</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602431&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google gives up on US carriers, will roll out its own RCS chat system</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602127</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 23:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Amadeo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602127</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the carriers shun Google RCS, Google rolls its own service out to the US.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/15-800x365.jpg" alt="Promotional image of two smartphones."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/15.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="722" data-width="1582">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Promotional image of two smartphones. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://about.google/">Google</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Will RCS ever matter? The standard has been hanging around for years as an upgrade to the aging carrier SMS texting standard, but since the carriers are in charge of it, the Rich Communication Service (RCS) has been going nowhere fast. Google is apparently tired of waiting for the carriers, and after launching its own RCS service in the UK and France <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/06/google-ninth-attempt-at-a-messaging-service-will-be-based-on-rcs/">earlier this year</a>, the industry giant is now <a href="https://blog.google/products/rcs/upgrading-messaging-android-us-rcs/">bringing its own RCS implementation</a> to the United States, carriers be damned.</p>
<p>Google is rolling out RCS through the Google Messages app, Google's ninth messaging app after Google Talk, Google Voice, Google Buzz, Google+ Messenger, Hangouts, Spaces, Allo, and Hangouts Chat. Users of Google's app will eventually see a notification to "Do more with Messages," and then they'll be able to "enable chat features," which is RCS. Google says it will start enabling this for US users "in the coming weeks," and the service will be "broadly available in the US by the end of year."</p>
<p>RCS is pretty lame as a messaging standard in 2019, but remember this is a replacement for SMS—the spec that has been driven by the carriers that are members of the GSMA. So you've got to lower your expectations. RCS upgrades carrier messaging with functionality like typing indicators, presence information, location sharing, group messages, longer messages, and better media support. These are all things you would expect from any over-the-top instant messaging app in the modern era, but as a carrier-integrated replacement for SMS, these basics are still not there yet.</p>
<p>The service isn't end-to-end encrypted, so Google or your carrier (<a href="https://www.eff.org/nsa-spying">or the NSA</a>) could read your messages. It also treats your phone number as your primary identity, giving carriers an unnecessary amount of power over your identity. Again, this makes a ton of sense when carriers are designing the spec. They want to make themselves the center of your communication life, and clear text gives them a better opportunity for monetization. Why would a non-carrier want to use this standard, though?</p>
<p>Since RCS is so basic, it isn't really a great standard for a messaging service. The only power RCS has comes from the fact that your carrier might do it, which would instantly upgrade the baseline messaging service it offers on (at least new) phones. RCS's power comes from it being the default. Google's version of RCS isn't the default, though. You need to download the Google Messages app to use it, and Google Messages isn't the default texting app on most phones. The app is not required to ship alongside the Play Store like Gmail, Google Maps, Search, and other top-tier Google apps, so most OEMs don't ship it at all. Instead, they opt for their own messaging app.</p>
<p>Most users would have to download the app, dig into the system settings to make it the default app, and then dig into the Google Messages settings to turn on RCS. By removing RCS' defaultness, Google basically took a limited, poorly crafted chat standard and rolled its own over-the-top messaging service with it. And what's the point of that?</p>
<p>It <em>is</em> possible for RCS implementations to be federated with a feature called "Universal Profile," which allows for something like Google RCS to talk to carrier RCS. For this to work, carriers would need to <em>Do The Right Thing</em> and opt-in to interoperability, though, and the whole reason Google is rolling its own RCS service is because carriers <em>can't</em> be relied on to do the right thing. So far, only Sprint and US Cellular have implemented Universal Profile. It is also assumed that Apple will never support RCS on its devices, as it could threaten the dominance of iMessage in places like the United States.</p>
<p>And as far as instant messaging services go, Google's "Messages" app is bad. A big part of the appeal of iMessage and Google Hangouts is that there are clients for everything, so your messages don't have to be locked to your smartphone anymore. Google Hangouts has apps for Android phones and tablets, iOS phones and tablets, an always-on Chrome app that works on Windows, Mac, Linux, and Chrome OS, a website at hangouts.google.com, integration with Gmail.com, and even apps for smartwatches.</p>
<p>Google Messages has... an Android app? Oh, there's also a website that requires you to log in with your phone, instead of just logging in with your Google account. Hangouts and Google Messages RCS are nowhere near comparable, and RCS is an across-the-board downgrade, aside from the fact that Google actually cares about the Messages app, for now, and the company <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/01/the-great-google-hangouts-shutdown-begins-october-2019/">wants to kill</a> Hangouts.</p>
<p>Google's original plan was to get carriers onboard with its RCS implementation, which it created when it acquired <a href="https://jibe.google.com/">Jibe Mobile</a> in 2015. The carriers were not interested in turning over messaging control to Google, though, and after years and years of petitioning from Google and consumers, eventually Verizon, AT&amp;T, Sprint, and T-Mobile went behind Google's back to create the "<a href="https://investors.sprint.com/news-and-events/press-releases/press-release-details/2019/ATT-Sprint-T-Mobile-and-Verizon-Form-Joint-Venture-to-Transform-Messaging-Experience/default.aspx">Cross Carrier Messaging Initiative (CCMI)</a>" in October 2019. The four carriers will now begin to implement RCS together and hope to launch a new app by sometime next year.</p>
<p>Google seemed completely <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20931202/us-carriers-rcs-cross-carrier-messaging-initiative-ccmi-att-tmobile-sprint-verizon">caught off guard</a> by the development and eventually issued a response, saying, "We remain committed to working with the Android ecosystem to further enhance the messaging experience on Android with RCS."</p>
<p>The earlier Google RCS launch in the UK and France might have been a warning shot, but it seems with the carriers declaring they're doing RCS on their own, Google is less worried about stepping on toes with its version of RCS. Google has failed at messaging an astonishing number of times—is a very basic messaging platform with no encryption and limited platform compatibility really enough for it to succeed this time?</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602127&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple plans a Prime-like subscription bundle, but that has News+ publishers worried</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602259</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 22:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apple made deals with publishers to include their content in such a bundle.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/AppleTVPlus-800x500.png" alt="A man in business casual gives a presentation in front of a monstrous video screen."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/AppleTVPlus.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="800" data-width="1280">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Tim Cook announces Apple TV+ at an event on March 25, 2019. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="http://live.arstechnica.com/apples-march-25-2019-its-show-time-event/">Ron Amadeo</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>According to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-14/apple-mulls-bundling-digital-subscriptions-as-soon-as-2020">report</a> in Bloomberg, Apple may be planning to launch a bundled subscription service that would include services like Apple News+, Apple TV+, and Apple Music as soon as 2020. This strategy would be similar to that of Amazon Prime, though not as far-reaching—at least at first.</p>
<p>The report says that, at a minimum, Apple has left the door open for this in its contracts with Apple News+ content providers. Its sources say that there is "a provision that Apple included in deals with publishers that lets the iPhone maker bundle the News+ subscription service with other paid digital offerings."</p>
<p>While this would likely be appealing to consumers and could bolster Apple's services revenue, not all stakeholders in the decision are likely to be happy about it. Bloomberg's sources said they believed that publishers could see reduced revenues from Apple News+ because they'd likely be sharing a smaller piece of the subscription pie than they do under the $10/month Apple News+ service. Currently, Apple pockets 50% of the money that comes in to Apple News+, while the other 50% is split between publishers based on how much their content is read and engaged with.</p>
<p>Publishers have already been concerned about the money they've been getting from News+. A CNBC story <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/14/apple-news-has-struggled-to-add-subscribers-since-march-launch.html">published today</a> reported that the service's subscriber base has not grown substantially since it first launched. Apple hasn't put a lot of weight into marketing Apple News+ since its launch—nowhere near as much as Apple Music and Apple TV+. Additionally, some magazine and newspaper publishers Ars has spoken with are pessimistic about Apple News+ as a revenue source adequate to the industry's serious financial challenges because Apple's privacy policies preclude some sophisticated advertising techniques that involve targeting specific readers based on collected data.</p>
<p>Apple is looking to services like these to bolster its revenue as iPhone sales slow due to market saturation, longer-lasting devices, and the company's difficulty entering developing markets where its products are too expensive for many consumers.</p>
<p>Despite News+'s apparent struggles, Apple Music is growing its user base and generating substantial revenues. We don't want to prematurely make proclamations about Apple TV+'s health or growth one way or the other, and it faces a very different set of challenges and opportunities than Music or News+ because its content is produced in-house at Apple, not licensed from other content creators. The Bloomberg sources' story did not indicate whether Apple Arcade, the company's games subscription service, would also be included in this bundle. Some game development studios that Ars has spoken with have indicated that Arcade has been a success for them so far.</p>
<p>In any case, this would not be Apple's first attempt at bundling subscriptions; it has already bundled Apple TV+ with Apple Music for students.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602259&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another company is dialing back expectations for self-driving taxis</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602067</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 21:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daimler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Embark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gm Cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Optimus Ride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starsky Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voyage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The key question about self-driving is which applications will be viable first.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1174694983-800x501.jpg" alt="Ola Källenius of Daimler AG."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1174694983.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3426" data-width="5472">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Ola Källenius of Daimler AG. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/">Christoph Schmidt/picture alliance via Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Daimler is planning to "rightsize" its spending on self-driving taxis, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-daimler-autonomous/daimler-ceo-says-robotaxis-business-is-not-realistic-idUSKBN1XO1FM?utm_source=reddit.com">Chairman Ola Källenius said</a> on Thursday. Getting self-driving cars to operate safely in complex urban environments has proved more challenging than people expected a few years ago, he admitted.</p>
<p>"There has been a reality check setting in here," Källenius said, according to Reuters.</p>
<p>He is just the latest executive to acknowledge that work on self-driving taxi technology is not progressing as fast as optimists expected two or three years ago. Earlier this year, Ford CEO Jim Hackett sought to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-09/ford-ceo-tamps-down-expectations-for-first-autonomous-vehicles">dampen expectations</a> for Ford's own self-driving vehicles. Industry leaders Waymo and GM's Cruise missed self-imposed deadlines to launch driverless commercial taxi services in 2018 and 2019, respectively.</p>
<p>There has been a lot of focus over the years on asking when self-driving cars will become a reality. But a better question to ask is: which applications of self-driving technology will be viable first?</p>
<h2>Many roads to self-driving</h2>
<p>Experts have long known that it won't be feasible to go directly to market with a vehicle that can drive itself everywhere, in all weather and traffic conditions—something referred to in the industry as "level 5 automation." Rather, companies have tried to start with narrower, less-demanding use cases that could be technologically and economically viable long before full level 5 autonomy is ready.</p>
<p>Different companies are pursuing different strategies:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Tesla</strong> is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/04/teslas-autonomy-event-impressive-progress-with-an-unrealistic-timeline/">betting</a> that it can gradually upgrade its driver-assistance technologies—first Autopilot and now Smart Summon—until they become fully autonomous driving technologies.</li>
<li>Companies like <strong>Waymo</strong> and <strong>Cruise</strong> are seeking to develop taxi services that are geographically limited to a single metropolitan area. Waymo chose suburban Phoenix because its sunny weather, wide streets, and predictable grid make it a relatively easy environment for software to understand.</li>
<li>Other startups are pursuing taxi or shuttle services in much more restricted areas. A startup called <strong>Voyage</strong> is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/06/how-startups-are-building-driverless-cars-without-googles-billions/">building a taxi service</a> for one of the nation's largest retirement communities. Another, <strong>Optimus Ride</strong>, gets paid by real estate developers to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/10/how-self-driving-shuttles-could-enable-car-free-living-in-the-suburbs/">ferry passengers around</a> large planned communities.</li>
<li>Some startups, including <strong>Nuro</strong>, are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/06/dominoes-will-start-robot-pizza-deliveries-in-houston-this-year/">focusing on package delivery</a>. This is an appealing first use case for self-driving technology because there's no need to worry about the comfort or safety of people inside the vehicle, allowing engineers to focus on the safety of people outside the vehicle.</li>
<li>A number of startups, including <strong>Ike</strong>, <strong>Embark</strong>, <strong>Starsky Robotics</strong>, and <strong>TuSimple</strong> see <a href="https://www.ttnews.com/articles/tech-startups-cite-progress-path-self-driving-trucks">long-haul trucking</a> as the lowest-hanging fruit. They're working to develop technologies that will allow a truck to drive itself on freeways. They have different strategies for navigating the "last mile" of city streets. Some envision using remote-teleoperation by human drivers. Others envision transferring a trailer from a self-driving truck to a human-driven one for the final few miles of each delivery.</li>
</ul>
<p>The disappointments of the last couple of years suggest that the most ambitious projects on this list may be biting off more than any company can chew. Tesla's self-driving progress has been much slower than CEO Elon Musk predicted three years ago. Waymo and Cruise have found that it's quite difficult to develop a metro-wide driverless taxi service—even if you have the vast resources of Alphabet or GM at your disposal.</p>
<h2>The power of starting simple</h2>
<p>In the last year, I've <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/02/googles-waymo-risks-repeating-silicon-valleys-most-famous-blunder/">become more bullish</a> about companies that are pursuing the simplest initial markets—particularly delivery startups like Nuro and small-scale taxi services like Voyage and Optimus Ride.</p>
<p>A big advantage all these companies enjoy is that their cars never need to go faster than 25 miles per hour. That means shorter stopping distances that reduce the risk of a crash. And it means a much lower chance that someone will die if one of the cars were to hit something. That means they may be able to bring their products to market more quickly than bigger companies pursuing more complex and challenging applications.</p>

<p>Once one of these companies has a commercially viable, fully driverless service, gradually expanding its service territory should be fairly straightforward. A company learns a lot from running a real service with real customers. And once you have a large fleet of cars doing real work, it's easy to collect additional sensor data to use in the next iteration of your technology.</p>
<p>But larger companies also seem to be making progress. Waymo has recently started <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/11/waymo-finally-let-a-reporter-ride-in-a-fully-driverless-car/">testing</a> fully driverless rides with ordinary passengers. However, Waymo isn't yet charging customers for these rides, and it's not clear how close Waymo is to being able to do this on a commercial scale.</p>
<p>Cruise seems to be far from able to launch a commercial service—particularly because its home base of San Francisco is one of the most challenging driving environments in the United States.</p>
<p>Tesla continues to insist that it's making steady progress toward full autonomy, even as evidence of this progress is a bit hard to see from the outside. Tesla released its parking lot self-driving technology, Smart Summon, in September. Early customer reviews indicate that the technology <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/10/i-watched-over-100-tesla-smart-summon-videos-heres-what-i-learned/">still needs a fair amount of work</a>, and of course driving safely in a parking lot at 5mph is an easier problem than driving safely through a multi-lane intersection at 55mph.</p>

<p>In his Thursday remarks, Daimler's Källenius signaled pessimism about driverless taxis but was more bullish on long-haul driverless freight delivery. But I'm skeptical that the long-haul trucking market will prove easier to tackle. Freeway driving is an easier problem than urban driving in some respects—there are clearly marked lanes and many fewer unpredictable (and vulnerable) obstacles like pedestrians and bicycles.</p>
<p>The problem is that if a driverless truck malfunctions on a busy freeway, the consequences could be catastrophic. It's not obvious how a company can test freeway truck driving software throughly enough to be sure it's safe enough to start doing fully driverless trips at freeway speeds.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602067&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stadia what? Xbox game streaming will become part of Game Pass in 2020</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602287</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 21:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Machkovech]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google stadia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Xcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XBox]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602287</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But Xbox is currently playing coy about whether xCloud access will cost extra.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Project-Xcloud-controller-800x450.png" alt="Sea of Thieves streaming to a smartphone with an attached Xbox One controller."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Project-Xcloud-controller.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1080" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> This controller attachment was shown in Microsoft's xCloud promo video, and Bluetooth wireless controller support is also planned. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2018/10/08/project-xcloud-gaming-with-you-at-the-center/">Microsoft</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>At Microsoft's annual X0 fan conference in London on Thursday, Microsoft confirmed a huge piece of news for its game-streaming platform, Project xCloud. The service will launch with full compatibility for all Xbox software in "2020," meaning that it will work with "all games you own, or games you purchase in the future," according to xCloud reps.</p>
<p>What's more, Xbox may have just thrown the gauntlet down in the game-streaming price wars by announcing a clear tie between the Project xCloud streaming service and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/06/psa-upgrade-three-years-of-xbox-live-to-game-pass-ultimate-for-just-1/">the paid Xbox Game Pass</a> subscription service.</p>
<p>"Next year, we will bring game streaming to Xbox Game Pass, so that you are free to discover and play anywhere and everywhere," xCloud General Manager Catherine Gluckstein told the X019 crowd on Thursday.</p>
<p>Xbox representatives did not directly answer Ars' questions about pricing information—particularly whether this "free to discover and play" statement means Xbox Game Pass will come with unfettered streaming access to its 100+ game library at no additional charge. Instead, they responded to our questions with the following statement: "We want to offer choice in how players stream games from the cloud. We'll have more details to share at a later date."</p>
<p>If Game Pass winds up including free game streaming as an option, that would put Xbox's $10/month service in an entirely different tier of value and convenience than <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/google-stadia-will-be-missing-many-features-for-mondays-launch/">Google Stadia</a>. Google's upcoming service, set to launch November 19 in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/06/google-stadia-requires-130-upfront-10-per-month-at-november-launch/">an early Founders Edition bundle</a>, currently requires its users to pay full retail price for each of its titles, which can then be streamed to compatible devices. At launch, this will be limited to compatible Chromecast Ultra devices, though options will broaden to mobile devices, Chrome Web browsers, and more.</p>
<p>Stadia users can also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/google-stadia-launching-at-9-a-m-pst-november-19/">pay $10/mo for a "Stadia Pro" tier</a>, which adds free games at a "regular cadence" and upgrades its streaming signal to 4K resolution. Next year, Google will roll out a "Stadia Base" tier, which will let users buy and stream games at 1080p resolution without paying an additional monthly fee.</p>
<p>Today's X019 announcement also included news that Project xCloud will arrive on Windows 10 PCs in 2020, on top of its current beta-test availability on Android devices. Next year will also see xCloud reach more regions for both its testing phase (which is currently live in the United States, Korea, and the UK for invited beta users) and its live, final version. That's good news for hopeful streaming players in Canada, India, Japan and Western Europe. And controller compatibility with xCloud will be broader by 2020, as well, including discrete support for Sony's DualShock 4 controller via a Bluetooth connection.</p>
<p>Current beta testers, meanwhile, just got a new slew of games to test today, jumping from <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/project-xcloud-preview-serves-as-a-passable-portable-xbox-one/">the initial test's four-strong selection</a> to over 50 games. It's a meaty library, too, full of some particularly recent games—and while it's not a mirror of the Xbox Game Pass library, it certainly stands in stark contrast to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/only-12-games-will-be-available-on-google-stadia-in-time-for-nov-19-launch/">the 12 games available for early Stadia users starting next week</a>. The full xCloud testing list is below, with previously available games marked with asterisks.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Absolver</em></li>
<li><em>Ace Combat 7</em></li>
<li><em>ARK: Survival Evolved</em></li>
<li><em>The Bard's Tale IV: Director's Cut</em></li>
<li><em>Battle Chasers: Nightwar</em></li>
<li><em>Bloodstained: Ritual of the Night</em></li>
<li><em>Borderlands 2</em></li>
<li><em>Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel</em></li>
<li><em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em></li>
<li><em>Conan Exiles</em></li>
<li><em>Crackdown 3 </em>(campaign)</li>
<li><em>Darksiders III</em></li>
<li><em>Dead Island Definitive Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Devil May Cry 5</em></li>
<li><em>F1 2019</em></li>
<li><em>Forza Horizon 4</em></li>
<li><em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Gears 5*</em></li>
<li><em>Halo 5: Guardians*</em></li>
<li><em>Halo Wars 2</em></li>
<li><em>Hellblade: Senua's Sacrifice</em></li>
<li><em>Hello Neighbor</em></li>
<li><em>Hitman</em></li>
<li><em>theHunter: Call of the Wild</em></li>
<li><em>Just Cause 4</em></li>
<li><em>Killer Instinct*</em></li>
<li><em>Madden NFL 20</em></li>
<li><em>Mark of the Ninja: Remastered</em></li>
<li><em>Mutant Year Zero</em></li>
<li><em>Ori and the Blind Forest: Definitive Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Overcooked</em></li>
<li><em>Puyo Puyo Champions</em></li>
<li><em>RAD</em></li>
<li><em>Recore</em></li>
<li><em>Sea of Thieves*</em></li>
<li><em>Shadow of the Tomb Raider</em></li>
<li><em>Sniper Elite 4</em></li>
<li><em>Soul Calibur VI</em></li>
<li><em>State of Decay 2</em></li>
<li><em>Subnautica</em></li>
<li><em>Tales of Vesperia: Definitive Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Tekken 7</em></li>
<li><em>Tera</em></li>
<li><em>Vampyr</em></li>
<li><em>Warhammer: Vermintide 2</em></li>
<li><em>West of Dead </em>(beta)</li>
<li><em>World of Final Fantasy Maxima</em></li>
<li><em>World of Tanks: Mercenaries</em></li>
<li><em>World of Warships: Legends</em></li>
<li><em>World War Z</em></li>
<li><em>WRC 7 FIA World Rally Championship</em></li>
<li><em>WWE 2K20</em></li>
<li><em>Yoku's Island Express</em></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602287&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New 3D display combines visuals, haptic feedback, and sound</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602249</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 21:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D display]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holograph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ultrasound]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602249</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A small sphere levitated on sound can be moved around fast enough to be a display.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Plenty of technology development comes in areas where we've already settled on an efficient design. Wind turbines are a great example. Several decades ago, some radical ideas were floating around, touted as providing heightened efficiencies. But wind turbines have since stabilized on a standard design, and most research now goes into figuring out how to get the most out of that design. In a lot of ways, it's boring compared to the lingering potential for a complete reinvention.</p>
<p>Right now, 3D displays are back in the much more fun "radical ideas" phase. While various VR technologies are on the market, they're unsatisfying in various ways. A handful of technologies has been demonstrated that provide 3D images without the need for goggles or glasses. But these ideas have their own problems, including slow refresh and complicated hardware, and they lack a standardized mode of user interaction. One company has developed a 3D display that can be <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2017/11/new-hardware-lets-any-computer-run-an-interactive-3d-interface/">manipulated by hand</a>, but without any feedback, this can be tricky.</p>

<p>This week, researchers are describing a new take on a recent 3D display development that mixes in a key ingredient: sound. The use of ultrasound allows the researchers to both run the display and provide haptic feedback for interactions with it. As an added bonus, the new display can allow audible sound to originate from objects within the display itself.</p>
<p>Conceptually, the display borrows heavily from one <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/01/3d-volume-filled-imagery-created-with-hovering-dots/">we described early last year</a>. The light emitted by the display comes from lasers reflected off the surface of a tiny, hovering sphere. As long as the sphere is reflective, it can display any of the colors you might need for an image. To display an object, the sphere has to be moved around rapidly enough that the human eye registers the line traced by its movement as a single object, rather than detecting that it's the product of motion.</p>

<p>The earlier system controlled the movement of the display dot using lasers, which generate a small bit of force as they reflect off the dot. The low amount of force provided limited the movement of the dot and thus made it harder to trace out large objects quickly enough to trick the eye into not seeing the motion.</p>
<p>The new display swaps out the lasers for ultrasound generators, which produce significantly more force. While this has also been attempted previously, the team has achieved the fastest motion of a display dot yet, being able to cover nearly nine meters a second vertically and another 3.75 meters/second horizontally. That makes for a far better display. In something <a href="https://arstechnica.com/author/laserboy/">Chris Lee</a> would consider an obvious negative, the researchers forgo lasers entirely. Instead, they use colored LEDs to reflect light from the dot and simply paint all of its surroundings black to avoid stray reflections.</p>
<p>In addition to powering the display dot to much higher speeds, the ultrasound generators also provide two other features that led the device's developers to name it a multimodal acoustic trap display. One of these is audible sound, generated by controlling the interactions of multiple ultrasound generators. While adding speakers to a display isn't a very big ask, this has the ability to allow sound to be generated at the location where an object is displayed, which could provide some interesting effects.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Image-two.image_.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Image-two.image_-640x641.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Image-two.image_-1280x1282.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Image-two.image_.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Eimontas Jankauskis)</p></div>
<p>More significantly, however, the use of ultrasound provides haptic feedback within the display itself. In other words, if you want to push a button displayed by the device, the ultrasound can be used to make it feel like you actually touched something physical.</p>
<p>This is a bigger advance than it seems. I've tried a 3D display technology that allowed interaction by registering the position of your finger within the display. This was challenging, because if your gestures produced the wrong response (or no response at all), it was difficult to tell whether you were using the interface wrong or had simply not correctly lined up your finger with the display. Haptic feedback should make these interactions far more certain and specific.</p>
<p>The "multimodal" aspects do come at a cost. As more of the ultrasound generators are diverted to being used to generate sound or feedback, the display dot slows down, with speed being cut nearly in half. Providing both sound and tactile feedback at the same time isn't possible.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ziz2kSEtUrg?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Some video of the display in action. </p></div>
<p>That's not ideal, but the bigger problem is that interactions are going to be necessarily limited by the fact that the dot is levitating on a bed of sound. Any gestures that interfere with that—the placing of a finger anywhere underneath something visible—could cause the dot to fall out of the display. This can be avoided to an extent through software, but it will still prevent the display of anything above a location where people are poking at the display.</p>
<p>That said, there's a <em>lot</em> of room for improvements. The researchers put this together from existing commercially available hardware. It's cheap, and anyone can potentially build one, but specialized, dedicated hardware could possibly provide better performance. Brighter light sources are an option the authors mention, as well. But perhaps the biggest potential comes from the fact that they haven't built a detailed model of how the ultrasound interacts with the display dot. More detailed modeling "would allow better exploitation of the observed maximum speeds and accelerations, enabling larger and more complex visual content."</p>
<p>So, there's a bunch of pros and cons to this design, which is about where you'd expect things to be in an era that's focused on trying out different tech rather than revising a tech standard. But the fact that there's still enough space to try out an entirely different type of hardware to drive the display shows why this is still an exciting field.</p>
<p>Nature, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1739-5">10.1038/s41586-019-1739-5</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602249&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA report finds Boeing seat prices are 60% higher than SpaceX</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602219</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 20:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA["Boeing has made significant investments in the commercial crew program."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/NHQ201909090001_medium-800x514.jpg" alt="People in safety gear work on a spacecraft mockup in the desert."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/NHQ201909090001_medium.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="823" data-width="1280">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Teams from NASA, Boeing, and the White Sands Missile Range rehearse landing and crew extraction from Boeing’s CST-100 Starliner on Monday, Sept. 9, 2019. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>On Thursday, NASA's inspector general <a href="https://oig.nasa.gov/docs/IG-20-005.pdf">released a report</a> on the space agency's commercial crew program, which seeks to pay Boeing and SpaceX to develop vehicles to transport astronauts to the International Space Station.</p>
<p>Although the report cites the usual technical issues that the companies are having with the development of their respective Starliner and Dragon spacecraft, far more illuminating is its discussion of costs. Notably, the report publishes estimated seat prices for the first time, and it also delves into the extent that Boeing has gone to extract more money from NASA above and beyond its fixed-price award.</p>
<p>Boeing's per-seat price <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/04/spacex-likely-to-win-nasas-crew-competition-by-months-for-billions-less/">already seemed like it would cost more than SpaceX</a>. The company has received a total of $4.82 billion from NASA over the lifetime of the commercial crew program, compared to $3.14 billion for SpaceX. However, for the first time the government has published a per-seat price: $90 million for Starliner and $55 million for Dragon. Each capsule is expected to carry four astronauts to the space station during a nominal mission.<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='Comparison of Boeing&#039;s Starliner and SpaceX&#039;s Dragon vehicles.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/seat-prices.png" alt='Comparison of Boeing&#039;s Starliner and SpaceX&#039;s Dragon vehicles.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Comparison of Boeing's Starliner and SpaceX's Dragon vehicles. (credit: NASA Inspector General)</p></div></p>
<p>What is notable about Boeing's price is that it is also higher than what NASA has paid the Russian space corporation, Roscosmos, for Soyuz spacecraft seats to fly US and partner-nation astronauts to the space station. Overall, NASA paid Russia an average cost per seat of $55.4 million for the 70 completed and planned missions from 2006 through 2020. Since 2017, NASA has paid an average of $79.7 million.</p>
<p>Beyond these seat prices, Inspector General Paul Martin's report also notes that Boeing received additional funding from NASA, above and beyond its fixed-price award.</p>
<h2>“Not consistent”</h2>
<p>"We found that NASA agreed to pay an additional $287.2 million above Boeing’s fixed prices to mitigate a perceived 18-month gap in ISS flights anticipated in 2019 and to ensure the contractor continued as a second commercial crew provider, without offering similar opportunities to SpaceX," the report states.</p>
<p>According to Martin, who had extensive access to NASA officials in the preparation of the report, Boeing in 2016 proposed pricing for its third through sixth crewed missions using the "single 2016 mission price," which was substantially higher than NASA and Boeing had originally agreed upon. In response to this, NASA's Office of Procurement determined this was "not consistent with the terms of the contract and did not match the contract’s fixed-price table."</p>
<p>However, Boeing continued to press NASA for additional funding. After "prolonged negotiations," according to Martin, Boeing offered some benefits to NASA, such as reduced lead times before the missions and a variable launch cadence. NASA then agreed to pay the additional $287.2 million for these four missions, which are likely to fly in the early 2020s.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most striking rationale for approving the additional funds was that Boeing may have discussed backing out of the commercial crew program (CCP). Martin writes, "According to several NASA officials, a significant consideration for paying Boeing such a premium was to ensure the contractor continued as a second crew transportation provider. CCP officials cited NASA’s guidance to maintain two US commercial crew providers to ensure redundancy in crew transportation as part of the rationale for approving the purchase of all four missions at higher prices."</p>

<p>A spokesman for Boeing, Josh Barrett, denied that Boeing had threatened to end its commercial crew participation. "Boeing has made significant investments in the commercial crew program, and we are fully committed to flying the CST-100 Starliner and keeping the International Space Station fully crewed and operational," he told Ars.</p>
<p>The report notes that as NASA was agreeing to pay Boeing extra for these benefits, a similar deal was not offered to SpaceX. "In contrast, SpaceX was not notified of this change in requirements and was not provided an opportunity to propose similar capabilities that could have resulted in less cost or broader mission flexibilities," Martin writes.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602219&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCC sued by dozens of cities after voting to kill local fees and rules</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602185</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 20:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preemption]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Cities challenge FCC vote to preempt local fees and broadband regulations.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getty-lawsuit-800x536.jpg" alt="A pen and book resting atop a paper copy of a lawsuit."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/getty-lawsuit.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1417" data-width="2116">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/editorial-images">Getty Images | eccolo74</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The Federal Communications Commission faces a legal battle against dozens of cities from across the United States, which sued the FCC to stop an order that preempts local fees and regulation of cable-broadband networks.</p>
<p>The cities filed lawsuits in response to the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/pais-fcc-orders-cities-and-towns-to-stop-regulating-cable-broadband/">FCC's August 1 vote</a> that limits the fees municipalities can charge cable companies and prohibits cities and towns from regulating broadband services offered over cable networks.</p>
<p>"At least 46 cities are asking federal appeals courts to undo an FCC order they argue will force them to raise taxes or cut spending on local media services, including channels that schools, governments, and the general public can use for programming," Bloomberg Law <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/tech-and-telecom-law/dozens-of-cities-sue-fcc-over-get-out-of-fees-cable-tv-order">wrote Tuesday</a>.</p>
<p>Various lawsuits were filed against the FCC between August and the end of October, and Bloomberg's report said that most of the suits are being consolidated into a single case in the US Court of Appeals for the 9th Circuit. An FCC motion to transfer the case to the 6th Circuit, which has decided previous cases on the same topic, is pending.</p>
<p>The 9th Circuit case was initially filed by Eugene, Oregon, <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eugene-vs-fcc.pdf">which said</a> the FCC order was arbitrary and capricious and that it violated the Administrative Procedure Act, the Constitution, and the Communications Act. The cities' arguments and the FCC's defense will be fleshed out more in future briefs.</p>
<p>Big cities such as Los Angeles, Chicago, Philadelphia, San Antonio, San Francisco, Denver, and Boston are among those suing the FCC. Also suing are other municipalities from Maine, Pennsylvania, Delaware, Virginia, Maryland, Georgia, Indiana, Iowa, Minnesota, South Dakota, Nebraska, Oklahoma, Texas, Arizona, California, Oregon, and Washington, according to a Bloomberg graphic. The state of Hawaii is also suing the FCC, and New York City is supporting the lawsuit against the FCC as an intervening party.</p>
<h2>FCC lost net neutrality preemption battle</h2>
<p>Chairman Ajit Pai's FCC already lost one attempt to preempt local regulation throughout the country. When it repealed federal net neutrality rules, the FCC also preempted states from imposing net neutrality laws. While a federal appeals court upheld the repeal of the US-wide regulations, it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/net-neutrality-still-dead-but-judges-rule-that-fcc-cant-preempt-state-laws/">ruled that the FCC can't preempt</a> all state laws in one fell swoop. The state of Washington <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/net-neutrality-is-still-the-law-in-washington-state/">continues to enforce</a> its net neutrality law, and other states may do so in the future.</p>
<p>The FCC <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/why-ajit-pais-unhinged-net-neutrality-repeal-was-upheld-by-judges/">lost its preemption battle</a> on net neutrality largely because it had given up its primary authority to regulate broadband. "[I]n any area where the Commission lacks the authority to regulate, it equally lacks the power to preempt state law," the appeals court <a href="https://www.cadc.uscourts.gov/internet/opinions.nsf/FA43C305E2B9A35485258486004F6D0F/$file/18-1051-1808766.pdf">ruling</a> in that case said.</p>
<p>When the FCC preempted local cable regulation, a consumer advocate pointed out a similarity with the net neutrality case. The cable decision "is consistent with the commission's current perplexing view that it has no statutory authority over broadband but can nevertheless preempt states and local authorities from exercising their own authority," John Bergmayer, legal director of consumer advocacy group Public Knowledge, <a href="https://www.publicknowledge.org/press-release/public-knowledge-responds-to-fcc-vote-to-preempt-local-regulation-of-broadband/">said</a> after the August 1 vote.</p>
<p>The FCC <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/ajit-pai-has-yet-another-plan-to-stop-local-broadband-regulation/">argues</a> that states and localities cannot collect fees and impose requirements that aren't explicitly allowed by Title VI, the cable-regulation section that Congress added to communications law with the Cable Act of 1984. The FCC acted partly in response to an Oregon State Supreme Court <a href="https://law.justia.com/cases/oregon/supreme-court/2016/s062816.html">decision</a> that upheld a 7% "telecommunications" license fee the city of Eugene imposed on Comcast. The FCC wants to get that fee and others off the books.</p>
<p>The US cable law prevents local authorities from collecting more than 5% of a cable operator's gross revenue in any 12-month period. The FCC said that some local governments have been requiring in-kind contributions from cable operators to get around the 5% cap and ruled that most in-kind contributions must count toward that cap.</p>
<p>Pai claimed that the preemption will spur companies to expand broadband networks, but Democratic FCC Commissioner Jessica Rosenworcel pointed out that ISPs haven't actually promised to deploy more broadband in exchange for the regulatory favor from the FCC. She added that "there is no enforceable obligation to expand broadband capacity."</p>
<p>Five groups representing local governments detailed some of the arguments against the preemption in a <a href="https://ecfsapi.fcc.gov/file/100832956088/FCC%20Motion%20for%20Stay%20621%20Order.pdf">filing with the FCC last month</a>. They argued, among other things, that the FCC "has exceeded its authority, inserting itself where Congress provided no authority or direction to do so in a manner contrary to the clear and unambiguous terms of the Cable Act." The local-government groups also said the FCC order violates the <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/tenth_amendment">10th Amendment</a> by overriding states' rights, specifically by "directing state and local governments to surrender their property and management rights to 'advance... federal policies' related to broadband deployment."</p>
<p>Local governments also say the FCC order will make it harder to provide public, educational, and government access (PEG) programming. More generally, they say the FCC has "commandeered" the municipalities' "budgets and other resources... for the purpose of compensating cable operators in violation of legitimately adopted local franchises and state laws."</p>
<p>Separately, the FCC is facing another <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/10/cities-will-sue-fcc-to-stop-2-billion-giveaway-to-wireless-carriers/">lawsuit filed by cities</a> over the federal agency's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/09/ajit-pai-slams-cities-and-towns-as-fcc-erases-2-billion-in-local-fees/">September 2018 decision</a> to preempt about $2 billion worth of fees related to deployment of wireless equipment such as small cells used for 5G.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602185&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTC head asks Congress for real privacy laws he can enforce</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602063</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 20:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laws]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602063</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Simons has several times expressed frustration that the FTC can't do more.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1168930161-800x533.jpg" alt="A man in a suit speaks into a microphone."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1168930161.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3447" data-width="5171">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> FTC Chairman Joseph Simons testifying about antitrust matters before a Senate committee in September 2019. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/joseph-simons-chairman-of-the-federal-trade-commission-news-photo/1168930161">Alex Edelman | Bloomberg | Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In testimony before a House subcommittee Wednesday, Federal Trade Commission Chairman Joseph Simons renewed his call for Congress to pass new privacy legislation, telling representatives, essentially, he can't enforce a law that doesn't exist.</p>
<p>Simons was on Capitol Hill testifying in a <a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/legislation/hearings/online-platforms-and-market-power-part-4-perspectives-antitrust-agencies">hearing</a> on "Online Platforms and Market Power," the probe the House Antitrust subcommittee <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/06/congressional-hearings-signal-growing-antitrust-problems-for-big-tech/">launched in June</a> to dig into Apple, Amazon, Facebook, and Google. </p>
<p>At the highest level, the FTC is responsible for basically two things: protecting competition and protecting consumers. To that end, it's one of the two bodies with antitrust oversight, sharing responsibility with the Justice Department for reviewing mergers and challenging anticompetitive behavior.</p>
<p>As part of the consumer protection half of its mandate, the FTC also regulates the gulf between what companies say they will do and what they actually do. As such, the agency has become the closest thing the United States has to a privacy regulator. But its actions and authority are limited under the law, and when it comes to privacy, the commission can more or less only intervene when a prior agreement has been broken—it can't just impose fines or other penalties for behavior that feels like it should be illegal but isn't.</p>
<p>During the hearing, Rep. Joe Neguse (D-Colo.) pressed Simons on the FTC's track record with privacy enforcement. "I want to talk briefly about the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/ftc-fines-facebook-5-billion-imposes-new-privacy-oversight/">settlement with Facebook</a> earlier this year," Neguse said, asking Simons to explain the "methodology" the commission used to reach the $5 billion agreement.</p>
<p>"I'm very disappointed that you all are disappointed" in the settlement, Simons replied, defending the settlement as "very aggressive." But, he added: "Even if we wanted to do more, we don't have the authority to do more. We do not have the authority to impose fines or, on our own, increase the injunctive relief. We have to go to court. So what we did is we negotiated very long and hard with Facebook to get the best relief we could in a settlement and then compare that to what we would have gotten if we had gone to court." </p>
<p>Neguse cut Simons off there, but he added, "Ultimately, one point that I think we both agree on is that the tools that the FTC has under existing statute, in my view, could be strengthened, given the trend and the challenges that your agency faces." Simons agreed.</p>
<p>Later in the hearing, Simons reiterated the sentiment, telling the chamber, "I think if you want us to do more on the privacy front, then we need help from you," Simons said. "We've done as much as we can do with the tools we have."</p>
<h2>A frequent refrain</h2>
<p>Simons has rung the alarm about this particular enforcement gap several times already this year. The FTC in July announced not only the Facebook settlement but also a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/equifax-to-pay-575m-for-data-breach-promises-to-protect-data-next-time/">$575 million settlement with Equifax</a> over its massive consumer data breach. With each announcement, Simons called on Congress to act.</p>
<p>"The CFPB and the states were able to obtain civil penalties for this massive breach by a major financial institution. The FTC could not," Simons said in a press conference about the Equifax case. "Fortunately other agencies were able to fill in the gap this time. That will not always be the case, which sends the wrong signal regarding deterrence." </p>
<p>During a separate press event about Facebook a week later, he echoed the sentiment, saying "We are a law enforcement agency without the authority to promulgate general privacy regulations. Our authority in this case comes from a 100-year-old statute that was never intended to deal with privacy issues like the ones that we address today."</p>
<p>Members of Congress likewise have been calling on their colleagues to do something about federal privacy laws. Sen. Ron Wyden (D-Ore.) last month <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/privacy-bill-would-give-ftc-actual-authority-land-lying-executives-in-jail/">proposed a bill</a> that would not only drastically expand the FTC's scope and resources but also would impose criminal penalties for company officers found responsible for mishandling consumer data.</p>
<p>The House has likewise taken up the call: this month, Reps. Anna Eshoo and Zoe Lofgren, both Democrats from California, introduced an <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/new-bill-would-create-digital-privacy-agency-to-enforce-privacy-rights/">Online Privacy Act</a> earlier this month. Their bill would not only create new standards but also take their enforcement out of the hands of the FTC altogether, instead creating a Digital Privacy Agency to handle it.</p>
<p>In the meantime, regulators have been doing the best they can to consider whether matters of consumer data and privacy fall under <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/antitrust-101-why-everyone-is-probing-amazon-apple-facebook-and-google/">antitrust law</a>. DOJ antitrust chief Makan Delrahim has several times discussed ways in which poor privacy controls that harm consumers may be considered a result of poor competition.</p>
<p>"As a foundational matter, we must acknowledge that data has economic value, and some observers have said it is analogous to a new currency," Delrahim said in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/assistant-attorney-general-makan-delrahim-delivers-remarks-harvard-law-school-competition">a speech last week</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Like other features that make a service appealing to a particular consumer, privacy is an important dimension of quality. For example, robust competition can spur companies to offer more or better privacy protections. Without competition, a dominant firm can more easily reduce quality—such as by decreasing privacy protections—without losing a significant number of users.</p>
<p>As I have said before, these non-price dimensions of competition deserve our attention and renewed focus in the digital marketplace.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602063&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dealmaster: Get discounts on board games, AirPods Pro, Xbox Game Pass, and more</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602011</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 18:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealmaster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Plus deals on USB-C hubs, Apple battery cases, Bose sports headphones, and more.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111419-800x444.png" alt="Dealmaster: Get discounts on board games, AirPods Pro, Xbox Game Pass, and more"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111419.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1200" data-width="2160">Enlarge</a> (credit: Ars Technica)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Greetings, Arsians! The Dealmaster is back again with a new round of discounts and price drops. We'll admit, though, that we're in the calm before the Black Friday storm. With more and more retailers detailing their holiday sales plans, the number of worthwhile deals available <em>right now</em> has understandably shrunk. Tons of games, gear, and gadgets are still on sale, but the Dealmaster is hesitant to recommend various items that'll drop further in a couple of weeks.</p>
<p>That said, the deals landscape isn't totally barren for those who would rather shop before the holiday rush. Today's roundup is highlighted by a $15 discount on <a href="https://amzn.to/2OhjRK6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple's new AirPods Pro</a> earbuds (albeit with a fairly sizable shipping wait as of this writing), an offer for new Xbox Game Pass Ultimate users to get <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-game-pass-ultimate/CFQ7TTC0KHS0/?activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three months of service for $1</a>, and sales on a few well-regarded board games, including <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCatan-Strategy-Board-Game-5th-Edition%2F49605951&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Catan</em></a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/2QhtN9e" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Pandemic</em></a>, and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F7-Wonders-Strategy-Board-Game%2F30655387&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>7 Wonders</em></a>. Beyond that, we've also got deals on USB-C hubs and chargers, various discounts on Amazon services like Audible and Music Unlimited, a nice drop on Bose's wired SoundSport earphones, and more. Have a look at the full list for yourself below.</p>
<div class="ars-component-layout ars-newsletter-callbox full" data-list-id="248915">
    <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-container">
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-header">    
            <h5 class="ars-newsletter-callbox-title">
                Dealmaster: An Ars newsletter
            </h5>
            <span class="ars-dotted-pattern"></span>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-content">    
            <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-description">The Dealmaster is launching its very own newsletter! Sign up to receive a shorter, tightly curated list of the very best tech deals on the Web—no nonsense, direct to your inbox, and often before they make it to the Ars homepage.</div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-button-container">
            <a class="button button-orange ars-newsletter-callbox-button" href="https://arstechnica.com/newsletters?subscribe=248915">Sign Me Up!</a>  
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Top 10 deals of the day</h2>
<ul>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-game-pass-ultimate/CFQ7TTC0KHS0/?activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$1</strong> at Microsoft (normally $44.99).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/33Pssu3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Music Unlimited</a> four-month membership for <strong>$0.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $39.96).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OhjRK6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple AirPods Pro</a> true wireless noise-cancelling headphones for <strong>$234.98</strong> at Amazon (shipping in 1-3 months - normally $249).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KnQy7w" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Premium 5-in-1 USB-C Hub</a> - 3x USB-A (data only), SD slot, 5Gbps for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (use code: <strong>ANKERA771 </strong>- normally $25.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-XS-Smart-Battery-Case-Black%2F794695846&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Battery Case</a> for iPhone XS for <strong>$79</strong> at Walmart (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FBose-SoundSport-In-Ear-headphones-Android-Charcoal%2F101898376&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose SoundSport</a> wired in-ear sports headphones for <strong>$34</strong> at Walmart (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2O8SguG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link RE220</a> AC750 Wi-Fi range extender for <strong>$18.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $5 coupon</strong> and use code: <span class="postCouponContainer"><span class="code"><strong>20BLKFRDY </strong>- normally $29.99).</span></span></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33T5bHC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a> six-month membership for <strong>$29.97</strong> at Amazon (normally $59.94).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCatan-Strategy-Board-Game-5th-Edition%2F49605951&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Catan</a> </em>board game for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $39.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2QhtN9e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pandemic</a> </em>board game for <strong>$23.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $35.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Laptop and desktop PC deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNVIDIA-G-Strix-1660-FHD-GTX-IPS-Intel-GeForce-8GB-DDR4-II-includes-NVMe-120Hz-ROG-i5-9300H-SSD-Asus-512GB-Laptop-Gladius-Mouse-Ti-GL531GU-WB53-B-Gami%2F359426903&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Asus ROG Strix G</a> gaming laptop - Intel Core i5-9300H, 15.6-inch 1080p 120Hz, 8GB RAM, 512GB SSD, GTX 1660 Ti 6GB + Asus ROG Gladius II gaming mouse for <strong>$899</strong> at Walmart (normally $1,299).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32tfmRO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple MacBook Pro</a> (latest model) laptop - 1.4GHz Intel Core i5-8257U, 13.3-inch 2560x1600, 8GB RAM, 256GB SSD for <strong>$1,299.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $1,429).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33HSHlZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24-inch Dell UltraSharp U2415</a> monitor - 1920x1200, IPS, 60Hz for <strong>$199.90</strong> at Amazon (normally $214.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Gaming deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCatan-Strategy-Board-Game-5th-Edition%2F49605951&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Catan</a> </em>board game for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $39.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2QhtN9e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pandemic</a> </em>board game for <strong>$23.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $35.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F7-Wonders-Strategy-Board-Game%2F30655387&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>7 Wonders</em></a> board game for <strong>$29.92 </strong>at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/31PwEs4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $36.99).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-game-pass-ultimate/CFQ7TTC0KHS0/?activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$1</strong> at Microsoft (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-wireless-controller-for-xbox-one-and-windows-10-black%2F5621843.p%3FskuId%3D5621843&amp;subid1=dealmaster102219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Xbox Wireless Controller</a> for Xbox One and Windows 10 - compatible with iOS 13 for <strong>$39.99</strong> at Best Buy and <a href="https://amzn.to/32EdFSw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $49.99).</li>
<li><a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster102219&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerA-Wireless-Controller-for-Nintendo-Switch-GameCube-Style-Purple-1507452-01%2F436100675" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PowerA Wireless GameCube-Style Controller</a> for Nintendo Switch for <strong>$33.93 </strong>at Walmart (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g920-driving-force-racing-wheel-for-xbox-one-and-windows-black%2F4223402.p%3FskuId%3D4223402&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G920 Driving Force</a> racing wheel controller for Xbox One and PC for <strong>$199.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $219.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-G203-Prodigy-Wired-Gaming-Mouse-Optical-6-Buttons%2F342327342&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G203 Prodigy</a> wired RGB gaming mouse for <strong>$20.99</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g203-prodigy-wired-optical-gaming-mouse-with-rgb-lighting-black%2F5799700.p%3FskuId%3D5799700&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://amzn.to/33gIcWV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $26.49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36PuDjd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corsair K95 RGB Platinum</a> wired mechanical gaming keyboard - Cherry MX Speed for <strong>$129.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fcorsair-k95-rgb-platinum-mechanical-gaming-keyboard-cherry-mx-speed-rgb-led-backlit-black%2F5713210.p%3FskuId%3D5713210&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $164.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHitman-2-Warner-Bros-PlayStation-4-883929639571%2F755532848&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Hitman 2</em></a> (PS4, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHitman-2-Warner-Bros-Xbox-One-883929639564%2F817700036&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XB1</a>) for <strong>$17.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2qJcCTg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $24.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2q62TGD" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Collection of Mana</a> </em>(Switch) - includes <em>Final Fantasy Adventure</em>, <em>Secret of Mana</em>, <em>Trials of Mana </em>for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fcollection-of-mana-standard-edition-nintendo-switch%2F6352162.p%3FskuId%3D6352162&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $39.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2CDvp58" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Final Fantasy XV Royal Edition</a> </em>(PS4) for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Worlds-Warner-Bros-PlayStation-4-883929561803%2F234060369&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Worlds</a> </em>(PS4) for <strong>$12 </strong>at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2reXFsx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $15.99).</li>
<li>Pre-order: <em><a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Brothers-PlayStation-4-883929689613%2F786104378" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cyberpunk 2077</a></em> (PS4, <a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Bros-Xbox-One-883929689620%2F973645137" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XB1</a>) for <strong>$49.94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2LwLwXn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $59.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>TV and home entertainment deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Qczm91" target="_blank" rel="noopener">55-inch Vizio M558-G1 M-Series Quantum</a> (2019 model) 4K LED TV for <strong>$478.17</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FVIZIO-55-Class-M-Series-Quantum-4k-Ultra-HD-2160p-HDR-Smart-TV-M558-G1-2019-Model%2F239027548&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Walmart</a> (normally $548).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fvizio-65-class-m-series-quantum-led-smart-4k-uhd-2160p-tv-with-hdr%2F6345460.p%3FskuId%3D6345460&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">65-inch Vizio M658-G1 M-Series Quantum</a> (2019 model) 4K LED TV for <strong>$649.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $748).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZnGKO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polk Audio Command Bar</a> smart soundbar for <strong>$199</strong> at Amazon (normally $239.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Electronics deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OhjRK6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple AirPods Pro</a> true wireless noise-cancelling headphones for <strong>$234.98</strong> at Amazon (shipping in 1-3 months - normally $249).</li>
<li>My Best Buy members only: <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-watch-series-4-gps-40mm-gold-aluminum-case-with-pink-sand-sport-band-gold-aluminum%2F5543401.p%3FskuId%3D5543401&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Watch Series 4</a> (Gold/Pink, 40mm) for <strong>$299</strong> at Best Buy (normally $349).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-5-inch-iPad-Pro-Wi-Fi-512GB-Space-Gray%2F55900706%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10.5-inch Apple iPad Pro</a> (512GB, 2017 model) for <strong>$599</strong> at Walmart (normally $879).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FBose-SoundSport-In-Ear-headphones-Android-Charcoal%2F101898376&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose SoundSport</a> wired in-ear sports headphones for <strong>$34</strong> at Walmart (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2O8SguG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link RE220</a> AC750 Wi-Fi range extender for <strong>$18.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $5 coupon</strong> and use code: <span class="postCouponContainer"><span class="code"><strong>20BLKFRDY </strong>- normally $29.99).</span></span></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KdTZxN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribit XSound Go</a> portable Bluetooth speaker for <strong>$23.39</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon </strong>and use code: <strong>KBPYCM7E </strong>- normally $32.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGarmin-Vivoactive-3%2F280563492%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Garmin Vivoactive 3</a> GPS smartwatch for <strong>$149.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2pWQy7P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $179.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZkHBV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FiiO μBTR</a> portable Bluetooth headphone adapter for <strong>$22.49</strong> at Amazon (normally $27.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34VO1ti" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eufy RoboVac 30C</a> robot vacuum for <strong>$191.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $100 coupon</strong> - normally $299.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/321a2oK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chamberlain MyQ Smart Garage Hub</a> smart garage door opener for <strong>$29.98</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fchamberlain-myq-smart-garage-hub-black%2F5900972.p%3FskuId%3D5900972&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FWD-My-Passport-4TB%2F692843877&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WD My Passport</a> (4TB) portable external hard drive for <strong>$94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/34dn43E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $109.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2oTcz6S" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 970 Evo Plus</a> (500GB) internal NVMe M.2 SSD for <strong>$99.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $114.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Accessories and miscellaneous deals</h2>
<ul>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/33Pssu3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Music Unlimited</a> 4-month membership for <strong>$0.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $39.96).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33T5bHC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a> 6-month membership for <strong>$29.97</strong> at Amazon (normally $59.94).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cbn9cv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Audible</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$6.95/month</strong> at Amazon (normally $14.95/month).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36xYgpm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung Evo Select</a> (512GB) microSDXC card for <strong>$77.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $89.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3757yte" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort I with 1 PD and 4 PIQ</a> wall charger - 30W USB-C PD, 60W total, 4x USB-A for <strong>$32.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $49.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KnQy7w" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Premium 5-in-1 USB-C Hub</a> - 3x USB-A (data only), SD slot, 5Gbps for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (use code: <strong>ANKERA771 </strong>- normally $25.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FiPhone-XS-Smart-Battery-Case-Black%2F794695846&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Battery Case</a> for iPhone XS for <strong>$79</strong> at Walmart (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34YD36n" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort III Nano</a> USB-C wall charger - 18W USB-C PD for <strong>$15.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2r8Hmgz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Alkaline</a> AAA batteries (24-pack) for <strong>$6.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon</strong> - normally $11.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32BRHP7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Keyboard</a> for 10.5-inch iPad Pro, 10.2-inch iPad, and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$99.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-smart-keyboard-for-apple-ipad10-2-7th-generation-2019-10-5-ipad-pro-and-ipad-air%2F5822276.p%3FskuId%3D5822276&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2X9sf2v" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Battery Case</a> for iPhone XR for <strong>$69</strong> at Amazon (normally $109.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2POBeV6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro for <strong>$30</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34yVMFo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro Max for <strong>$30</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2plGAfJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brydge 10.5</a> Bluetooth keyboard for 10.5-inch iPad Pro and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$69.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $87).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Ideas-LEGO-NASA-Apollo-Saturn-V-21309%2F55231379&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Ideas NASA Apollo Saturn V 21309</a> building kit (1,900 pieces) for <strong>$89.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $119.99).</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602011&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impeachment hearing reveals major White House phone security fail</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602095</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 17:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Sondland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imsi catchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opsec]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602095</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Diplomat's testimony of Sondland-Trump call just the latest apparent OPSEC lapse by administration.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183979452-800x652.jpg" alt="US Ambassador to the European Union Gordon Sondland's phone conversation with President Trump in June was overheard by embassy staffers with Sondland at a Kiev restaurant (and probably by other countries' intelligence services)."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183979452.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="835" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> US Ambassador to the European Union Gordon Sondland's phone conversation with President Trump in June was overheard by embassy staffers with Sondland at a Kiev restaurant (and probably by other countries' intelligence services). (credit:  Mark Wilson / Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In testimony yesterday before the House Intelligence Committee, diplomat William Taylor said that he had recently learned of a phone call between George Sondland—the US ambassador to the European Union—and President Donald Trump. Taylor, the senior diplomat for the US in Ukraine, said that his staff overheard Trump during a call with Sondland while at dinner with the ambassador at a restaurant in Kiev.</p>
<p>The contents of that discussion—that Trump asked Sondland about "the investigations" Trump wanted Ukraine to conduct as an alleged condition of releasing military aid—may or may not be damaging to the president's case that he was not seeking foreign assistance for his 2020 presidential campaign. But as anyone in national or diplomatic security will attest to, an open phone call between the president and an ambassador regarding topics of diplomatic interest in a public place like a restaurant—a place where any foreign intelligence organization could be monitoring for collection purposes—would be a major breach of operational (and national) security.</p>

<p>This is not the first time that the administration has let issues of national security play out before a public audience. In February of 2017, President Trump consulted with Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe regarding a North Korean ballistic missile test and made phone calls <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/02/how-to-not-do-presidential-opsec-do-crisis-management-over-dinner-in-public/">from the restaurant of his Mar-A-Lago resort in Palm Beach</a>, Florida, in plain view and within earshot of other diners—some of whom essentially live-streamed the situation from their cell phones. A few months later, Trump <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/05/trump-confirms-sharing-classified-intel-with-russias-foreign-minister/">shared intelligence data</a> with Russia's foreign minister and ambassador in an Oval Office meeting concerning an Islamic State plot to bring down passenger planes with laptops turned into bombs.</p>
<p>Most recently, Trump <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/president-trump-tweets-picture-of-sensitive-satellite-photo-of-iranian-launch-site/">impulsively declassified and tweeted</a> a sensitive surveillance image from a US spy satellite of the launch site of a failed Iranian satellite launch. As president, Trump can choose to declassify any information he sees fit. But the lack of security concern with regard to diplomatic and national security planning has raised concerns from many in the security community. Typically, these sorts of conversations between a president and his envoys occur either in person or over a secured phone line—from a secure compartmented information facility (SCIF) at an embassy or some other secured space.</p>
<p>Senior diplomats like Sondland would naturally be targeted for surveillance by both domestic and foreign intelligence agencies while traveling in another country—especially in a country like Ukraine, with its ongoing war with Russian-backed separatists. Last year, the Department of Homeland Security acknowledged that devices consistent with the behavior of "IMSI catcher" technology—devices that can be used to track and intercept cell phone communications—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/06/dhs-found-evidence-of-cell-phone-spying-near-white-house/">had been detected near </a><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/06/dhs-found-evidence-of-cell-phone-spying-near-white-house/">the White House</a>—raising concerns once again about the president's frequent use of an unsecured cell phone.</p>
<p>"There are a ton of risks there, but some of the biggest involve the fact that the call is traversing the foreign country's telco,"said Jake Williams a former National Security Agency operator and founder of Rendition Infosec. "Even if you trust that country not to spy on their own telcos, others probably have. There's a non-zero chance that some country (or multiple countries) are getting call data records (CDR). This definitely would have made for increased targeting on Sondland and his contacts. Honestly, if I saw that in CDR collection, my first thought would be, 'That has to be a troll, right?' That would be immediately followed by, 'Get full voice coverage on his phone (and everyone around him). These guys don't understand OPSEC.'"</p>
<p>Even if the call with Sondland was encrypted, his phone could have been tracked—and old-fashioned audio eavesdropping could have been used to capture communications. If Taylor's staff members could hear the president over Sondland's phone from across the table, there were definitely more people listening.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602095&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Maps translate feature will speak local place-names</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601995</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Amadeo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601995</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google Translate text-to-speech options let you communicate during foreign travel. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/11-800x587.jpg" alt="This new speaker button in Google Maps will verbally speak the location's name and address."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/11.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1409" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> This new speaker button in Google Maps will verbally speak the location's name and address. </p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Traveling the world but don't speak the local language? Google Maps should be <a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/speak-easy-while-traveling/">a bit more useful</a> soon, thanks to some new integration with Google Translate.</p>
<p>Typically if you're in a foreign-language country, Google Maps will show the English place-name followed by the name in the local language below it. Sometime this month, Google Maps will get a new speaker button next to the local place-name, which will fire up Google Translate's text-to-speech engine. Until now, if you needed to communicate with a driver or ask for directions, you might have handed over your smartphone and let them read the screen. Now, though, you'll be able to have your phone shout out the pronunciation in a synthesized Google Translate voice, or you can practice pronouncing the name yourself beforehand.</p>
<p>This all happens in a new pop-up window, which lets your phone speak the place-name or address in the local language.There's also a handy "get more translations" button at the bottom, which will kick you out to the full Google Translate app. The language selection is all based on the locale chosen in your system settings, which is then compared to the local language of the place you're looking up.</p>
<p>Google says the feature will "be rolling out this month on Android and iOS with support for 50 languages and more on the way."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601995&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Stadia will be missing many features for Monday’s launch</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602039</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 16:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stadia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Among the missing: 4K on PC, Achievement UI, Google Assistant, Family Sharing...]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/P6_FE_R03-980x572.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The hardware you get with the $129.99 Stadia "Founder's Edition."                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://about.google/">Google</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>As Google barrels forward toward streaming gaming with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/google-stadia-launching-at-9-a-m-pst-november-19/">Monday's planned launch of Stadia</a>, the company is talking about the many promised features that won't be available to Founder and Premier pre-order purchasers on day one.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Stadia/comments/dvv3tv/hi_reddit_andrey_from_the_stadia_team_here_and_im/">a wide-ranging Reddit AMA Wednesday</a>, Google employees said that missing features will "start popping up as soon as one week after launch." Director of Product Andrey Doronichev defended this by saying that Google products "always start with nailing the key user-journey and then proceed with releasing extra features. YouTube started with 'watch video.' For Stadia it’s 'Play the Game on your biggest screen.'"</p>
<p>Game platforms often launch with limited feature sets that <a href="//arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/09/hdr-gaming-coming-to-every-ps4-via-firmware-update-next-week/&quot;">get expanded</a> via <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/01/xbox-one-update-speeds-up-controller-syncing/">firmware updates</a> over <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/12/three-years-later-the-console-wars-are-more-confusing-than-ever/">multiple years</a>. That said, the list of promised features that won't be ready when Stadia launches next week is surprising in its breadth and variety.</p>
<p>Here's a brief rundown of the limitations early adopters will face on day one:</p>
<ul>
<li>"On day 1, PC Chrome gameplay won't support 4K, HDR, or 5.1 Surround Sound." Those features will be added in 2020 for PC players.</li>
<li><a href="https://stadia.dev/blog/stream-connect:new-possibilities-for-multiplayer-gameplay/">Stream Connect</a>, which allows one player's Stadia viewpoint to be integrated with another player's stream, will not be available in any launch games. The first game to use it is expected to launch by the end of the year.</li>
<li><a href="https://stadia.dev/blog/the-magic-of-state-share-explained/">State Share</a> (which lets users share save files via links) and <a href="https://stadia.dev/blog/jump-into-multiplayer-games-on-youtube-with-crowd-play/">Crowd Play</a> (which allows for quick jump-in multiplayer through a YouTube stream) won't be integrated into games until next year.</li>
<li>At launch, Google Assistant integration will be limited to the ability to turn on the TV and start a game. Soon after launch, the Assistant button on the Stadia controller will work on Chromecast's Stadia homescreen. Assistant support on PCs and phones and during gameplay will come sometime after that.</li>
<li>Family Sharing (which lets you buy a game once and share it with accounts held by family members) "is not supported on day one, so you’ll have to buy games for your child’s account." The feature is planned for addition "early next year."</li>
<li>There is no Stadia UI for Achievements or Achievement notifications on day one. But if you happen to perform an in-game feat that would earn a specific Achievement, it will show up when the feature is rolled out "shortly after launch."</li>
<li>Chromecast Ultra units included in the Founders/Premiere bundles are the only ones that will work with Stadia on day one. Other Chromecast Ultra units will be able to play Stadia games after an over-the-air update "soon after launch."</li>
<li>The "Buddy Pass" that lets early adopters offer a free three-month Stadia trial to a friend will be sent "about two weeks after you receive your bundle, barring some unknown unknowns popping up."</li>
<li>Currently, "the phone is needed for initial setup and buying games." Buying games through a Chromecast Ultra or the Web is not supported, and the AMA gave no indication if or when it would be added.</li>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/google-stadia-launching-at-9-a-m-pst-november-19/">As previously discussed</a>, mobile support will be limited to Google Pixel phones and ChromeOS tablets at launch. A timeline for general iOS and Android support is still to be determined, but Pixel will likely be the only mobile support "this year," according to the AMA. Google says it "want[s] Stadia to run on every screen eventually."</li>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/google-cant-fulfill-all-stadia-pre-orders-for-nov-19-launch/">As previously discussed</a>, the Stadia Controller's wireless functions will only work with Chromecast Ultra at launch. To use that controller with a phone or tablet, you'll need to plug it in with a USB-C cable. Generic USB controllers will also work with Stadia on PC or phones, but not on Chromecast.</li>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/only-12-games-will-be-available-on-google-stadia-in-time-for-nov-19-launch/">As previously discussed</a>, only 12 titles will be available for purchase on Stadia at launch, with 14 more promised by the end of the year. A handful of other previously announced "launch window" titles on Stadia are planned for early 2020.</li>
</ul>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/chrome_2019-03-19_13-14-15-980x551.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Google's Phil Harrison (you may remember him from his days at Sony).                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Some other interesting tidbits from the Stadia AMA:</p>
<ul>
<li>At the highest visual quality, the Stadia app warns that "data usage might reach 20 GB/hr." That's above <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/06/google-stadia-in-4k-might-push-you-past-your-home-internet-data-cap/">some previous estimates</a> that expected 15.75 GB/hr for a 4K HDr signal with 5.1 surround sound. Limiting the stream to 720p stereo quality via the app caps data usage at 4.5 GB/hr.</li>
<li>"You should expect regular games" as freebies with your $10/month Stadia Pro subscription, but Google can't commit to a solid schedule for their availability yet (beyond <em>Destiny 2</em> at launch). Similar services from Sony and Microsoft offer multiple free games per month.</li>
<li>A personal Stadia stream will continue to run for ten minutes after you shut down on one screen, allowing you time to switch to another device and pick up where you left off.</li>
<li>Stadia will use letterboxing to fit the game image on screens that are not set to the standard 1080p or 4K aspect ratios.</li>
<li>Google and PowerSupport have developed a Stadia controller grip, called the Claw, which holds a Stadia phone "centered and 'floating' over the controller," unlike generic phone/controller grips. It won't be included in pre-order bundles but will be available for purchase in the GStore "in the coming weeks."</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602039&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford opens its order books for Mustang Mach-E electric crossover</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602005</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 15:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Mustang Mach-E]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602005</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You can reserve one for $500 after Idris Elba reveals the Mach-E on Sunday.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mach-E-invite-980x735.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Ford sent us this faceted pony as an invite to the Mach-E reveal, which takes place on Sunday in Los Angeles. If you think you need a faceted pony in your life, it will be up for grabs in our end-of-year giveaway.                      [credit:
                        Jonathan Gitlin                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The glacial pace at which some of the world's major automakers are electrifying their product line-ups can be rather frustrating. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/03/heres-fords-badly-needed-plan-to-catch-up-on-hybrid-and-electric-cars/">I've been particularly critical of Ford</a>, although there's clear evidence that the Blue Oval wants that to change. It <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/04/ford-invests-500-million-in-electric-car-startup-rivian/">invested $500 million in Rivian</a>, an electric vehicle startup that has also seen big investment from Amazon. And <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/07/volkswagen-will-share-electric-car-platform-with-ford-says-reuters/">it's going to use Volkswagen's MEB architecture</a> to build battery EVs for European markets. But next year, before either of those efforts bears fruit, we'll get to see Ford's first in-house, long-range BEV hit the showroom. And now it's official—the new vehicle will be badged the Mustang Mach-E.</p>
<p>Right now there aren't really any more details to share. I've heard rumors of a 4-second 0-60 time and 300+ miles of range for the range-topping version. But I'm off to California tomorrow morning for an embargoed briefing on the new BEV, and you'll have to wait until the Mach-E is revealed to the world at 6:30pm ET on Sunday, November 17 to find out what I learned. You'll also be able to put a refundable $500 deposit down once the car is unveiled by Idris Elba via livestream, in both the US and EU.</p>
<p>As of now, all I have to officially share are the above photos of the plastic, faceted pony that Ford sent out as an invite and the augmented reality version taken with the event app that Ford made me download. If you're particularly taken with the stealth-horse, keep an eye out for our end-of-year charity drive, as it will be up for grabs (along with a very heavy <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/10/the-2020-ford-mustang-shelby-gt500-packs-plenty-of-smiles-per-mile/">Mustang Shelby GT500</a> supercharger paperweight).</p>
<p>There have been <a href="https://jalopnik.com/this-is-the-ford-mustang-inspired-suv-caught-almost-tot-1839701061">some spy shots of the Mach-E</a> that have escaped into the wild, which show that Ford is leaning into the Mustang styling link with the tail lights, which will no doubt inflame emotions among the Mustang's massive fanbase, many of whom are already livid about the pony car's name being given to a four-door crossover. If that's you, head to the comments now and unleash that invective! But people buy crossovers, and Ford wants to sell BEVs, so purists be damned, I guess.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1602005&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>