<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 21:14:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>DirecTV kept charging regional sports fee while channel was blacked out</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596243</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 20:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIRECTV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regional sports networks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Comcast gives partial credits for blackout, but DirecTV apparently hasn't done so.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/att-directv-tractorbeam.jpg" alt="Star Wars-themed illustration of the AT&T and DirecTV logos."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">(credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://arstechnica.com/author/aurich-lawson/">Aurich Lawson</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>DirecTV and Comcast are being investigated by Colorado Attorney General Phil Weiser, who objects to the TV providers continuing to charge regional sports network (RSN) fees despite not providing one of the major regional sports networks. While Comcast is giving customers partial bill credits, DirecTV apparently hasn't done so.</p>
<p>Weiser sent letters to the <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/COAG-Letter-to-DirecTV.pdf">AT&amp;T-owned DirecTV</a> and <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/COAG-Letter-to-Comcast.pdf">Comcast</a> on October 23, asking why the companies kept charging RSN fees after they stopped providing the Altitude Sports network. The network broadcasts games played by the state's major professional basketball, hockey, and soccer teams (the Denver Nuggets, Colorado Avalanche, and Colorado Rapids, respectively). The AG's letters said that Comcast's and DirecTV's conduct "may constitute a deceptive trade practice under the Colorado Consumer Protection Act" and "may result in the imposition of civil penalties up to $20,000 per violation." The letters also said the AG is investigating other potentially misleading fees.</p>
<p>Altitude was blacked out on both DirecTV and Comcast <a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2019/09/01/altitude-sports-dropped-distributors-comcast-directv/">two months ago</a> because the TV providers didn't want to pay Altitude as much as it asked for. Altitude finally reached a deal with DirecTV <a href="https://www.kktv.com/content/news/Nuggets-and-Avalanche-return-to-DIRECTV-564251981.html">a few days ago</a> but is still negotiating with Comcast. Altitude is also blacked out on Dish satellite TV, but Dish doesn't charge a regional sports network fee.</p>
<h2>Comcast giving partial bill credits</h2>
<p>Comcast responded to the AG's office with a <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Comcast-Response-to-October-23-2019-Letter.pdf">letter</a> on October 31, saying that it had already begun giving partial credits to customers. Comcast's RSN fee in Colorado is $8 a month, while DirecTV charges $8.50, according to the AG's letters.</p>
<p>Comcast wrote in its letter to the AG:</p>
<blockquote><p>Comcast has been proactive and has shared both publicly and in direct communications with its customers that we are providing a partial credit of the RSN fee, due to Comcast not currently carrying Altitude as part of our cable packages in Colorado. Comcast continues to provide other regional sports programming which accounts for the remaining RSN fee charged to customers.</p></blockquote>
<p>The other regional sports programming offered by Comcast includes the AT&amp;T SportsNet Rocky Mountain channel, which broadcasts Colorado Rockies baseball games, and the Pac-12 network that broadcasts college sports.</p>
<p>We asked Comcast how big of a credit it is giving to customers, but the company declined to provide a specific number. Comcast told us that "the amount of the partial credit varies based on what RSNs are available in the customers' area."</p>
<h2>AT&amp;T actions “very concerning”</h2>
<p>Weiser's office gave both companies until November 7 to respond. Comcast said it will provide an additional, more detailed response to the AG by then. AT&amp;T's DirecTV division hasn't responded to Weiser's office yet, Weiser's office told Ars today. We contacted AT&amp;T today and will update this article if we get a response.</p>
<p>The actions of DirecTV, which apparently hasn't offered credits to customers, have been "very concerning," <a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2019/11/01/colorado-attorney-general-investigation-directv-comcast-altitude-sports/">Weiser told The Denver Post</a>.</p>
<p>"Based on early conversations with DirecTV and AT&amp;T, we didn't believe they were taking the request with the seriousness that they should," a spokesperson for Weiser also told the Post.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T would have less of an excuse than Comcast to keep charging an RSN fee while Altitude was blacked out, because AT&amp;T itself owns the other major RSN for professional sports in Colorado. TV providers claim they need to charge customers RSN fees to cover the high carriage prices charged by regional sports networks. But when the TV provider owns the network, as AT&amp;T does with AT&amp;T SportsNet Rocky Mountain, those carriage payments are simply going from one part of the company to another.</p>
<p>Comcast also <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NBC_Sports_Regional_Networks">owns regional sports networks</a>, but none in Colorado.</p>
<p>While Weiser's inquiry to Comcast and DirecTV focused mainly on charging the RSN fee during the Altitude blackout, the AG is also conducting a broader investigation into fees charged by TV and broadband providers. The letters to Comcast and DirecTV said:</p>
<blockquote><p>In addition to investigating the assessment of a Regional Sports Fee, the OAG [Office of the Attorney General] has opened an investigation of other fees and charges that providers impose on subscribers of television and Internet services that have the potential to confuse and mislead consumers. The imposition of such fees and charges may violate [<a href="https://law.justia.com/codes/colorado/2016/title-6/fair-trade-and-restraint-of-trade/article-1/part-1/section-6-1-105/">state law on deceptive trade practices</a>].</p></blockquote>
<h2>Years of controversy</h2>
<p>The RSN fees have long been controversial. Comcast, DirecTV, and other providers don't include RSN fees in their advertised prices, so they contribute to the bill shock customers experience when they find out they're going to pay more than the companies claimed they would. TV providers also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/09/comcast-raises-sports-and-tv-fees-again-says-its-about-transparency/">routinely raise RSN fees</a> even while customers are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/11/comcasts-controversial-tv-and-sports-fees-rise-again-hit-18-25-a-month/">under contract</a>.</p>
<p>Comcast's regional sports fee was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/12/comcast-raises-controversial-broadcast-tv-and-sports-fees-48-per-year/">only $1 in 2015</a> but has increased eight-fold since then. Comcast told Ars that it "itemizes the RSN fee to be transparent with our customers about the factors driving pricing." TV providers have used the same approach with "broadcast TV" fees, which they say cover the cost of retransmission consent fees paid to broadcast networks.</p>
<p>Colorado is not the first state to investigate RSN fees. Minnesota Attorney General Lori Swanson sued Comcast <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/01/the-lies-comcast-allegedly-told-customers-to-hide-full-cost-of-service/">in December 2018</a>, alleging among other things that Comcast reps falsely told customers that the company's RSN and broadcast TV fees were mandated by the government and not controlled by Comcast itself. Comcast was also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/10/comcast-accused-of-falsely-promising-low-prices-hiding-bogus-fees/">sued by customers</a> over the sports and broadcast TV fees in 2016, but the case was <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.304161/gov.uscourts.cand.304161.171.0.pdf">settled in 2018</a>.</p>
<p>Separately, Cord Cutters News <a href="https://www.cordcuttersnews.com/comcast-has-been-removing-tv-channels-but-lowering-its-price/">reported last week</a> that Comcast has been removing other channels from TV packages but not lowering its prices.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596243&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok’s parent company facing national security review, report says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596019</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 19:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFIUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596019</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Regulators are having a second look at ByteDance's acquisition of the company.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183295805-800x549.jpg" alt="A stand of TikTok (Douyin) at The First International Artificial Products Expo Hangzhou on October 18, 2019 in Hangzhou, China."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183295805.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2104" data-width="3067">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A stand of TikTok (Douyin) at The First International Artificial Products Expo Hangzhou on October 18, 2019 in Hangzhou, China. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/stand-of-tiktok-is-pictured-at-the-first-international-news-photo/1183295805">Long Wei | VCG | Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A week after members of Congress <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/congress-concerned-teenagers-favorite-app-is-national-security-threat/">expressed concern</a> about Chinese ownership of popular short-form video app TikTok, national security regulators are taking a closer look.</p>
<p>Regulators are indeed now reviewing TikTok for national security concerns, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tiktok-cfius-exclusive/exclusive-u-s-opens-national-security-investigation-into-tiktok-sources-idUSKBN1XB4IL?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">Reuters reports</a>.</p>
<p>The review is being run by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, or CFIUS, a formerly obscure interagency group. CFIUS, based out of the Treasury Department, comprises members from a dozen different agencies who review transactions in which an international business acquires a US business for national security concerns. </p>
<p>TikTok and its parent company, ByteDance, are in talks with CFIUS "about measures it could take to avoid divesting" the US assets it acquired, people familiar with the matter said. Reuters granted its sources anonymity, as CFIUS does not comment publicly on its investigations and is barred from disclosing certain information.</p>
<h2>C-what-US?</h2>
<p>CFIUS has seen its profile increase amid rising trade tensions and sharp rhetoric between the US and China during the Trump administration. The committee made nationwide headlines for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-moneygram-intl-m-a-ant-financial/u-s-blocks-moneygram-sale-to-chinas-ant-financial-on-national-security-concerns-idUSKBN1ER1R7">blocking</a> the sale of US-based money-transfer company MoneyGram to China's Ant Financial in early 2018.</p>
<p>The committee has also become more involved in high-tech transactions in recent years. It blocked the sale of a US semiconductor firm to a Chinese government-backed investment firm <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/09/trump-blocks-chinese-purchase-of-us-chipmaker-over-national-security/">in 2017</a>, and in 2018 it recommended against allowing Broadcom to acquire Qualcomm (a deal that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/eu-orders-broadcom-to-halt-exclusivity-deals-while-investigation-deepens/">probably wasn't happening</a> anyway) a week before President Trump <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/president-trump-halts-broadcoms-bid-for-qualcomm-citing-national-security/">signed an executive order</a> blocking that deal on national security grounds.</p>
<p>CFIUS had its scope and mandate greatly expanded in 2018, when President Trump signed into law a "modernization" package that increased the committee's finding and hiring authority, as well as expanding the types of transactions that were subject to significant scrutiny.</p>
<h2>From Musical.ly to TikTok</h2>
<p>The startup short-form video app Musical.ly launched in 2014 and quickly gained both popularity and funding in the years after. In 2016 and 2017, Musical.ly signed deals with Warner Music and Apple Music allowing users to integrate a broader library of tunes into their videos. A division of Beijing-based ByteDance snapped up Musical.ly for close to $1 billion in late 2017, then in 2018 sunset the Musical.ly name and product. Instead, ByteDance <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/musically-and-tiktok-unite-to-debut-new-worldwide-short-form-video-platform-300690719.html">integrated</a> its two extremely similar apps under the TikTok name.</p>
<p>CFIUS did <em>not</em> review the Musical.ly acquisition in 2017, meaning the committee has the authority retroactively to examine the transaction at this time.</p>
<p>Senators Tom Cotton (R-Ark.) and Chuck Schumer (D-N.Y.) last week pushed the intelligence community to open a formal investigation into TikTok, saying, "TikTok's terms of service and privacy policies describe how it collects data from its users and their devices, including user content and communications, IP address, location-related data, device identifiers, cookies, metadata, and other sensitive personal information." They add, "While the company has stated that TikTok does not operate in China and stores US user data in the US, ByteDance is still required to adhere to the laws of China."</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Musical.ly reached a settlement with the Federal Trade Commission alleging it broke one of the <a href="https://consumerist.com/2016/09/20/how-much-control-do-you-actually-have-over-your-private-data/">few privacy laws</a> that actually exist in the United States: the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.</p>
<p>The company paid $5.7 million, at the time the largest civil penalty ever imposed by the FTC in a COPPA case, to settle claims that it knowingly harvested and used personal data from users under age 13 without obtaining parental consent.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596019&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Formula 1 gets radical new rules for 2021, plus a budget cap</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596127</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 19:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Formula 1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596127</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In two years, an F1 team will "only" cost $175 million—drivers not included.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/f1_2021_launch_rendering_track_1.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          A rendering of what a Formula 1 race car will look like in 2021.                      [credit:
                        FIA                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>On Sunday afternoon at the Circuit of the Americas in Austin, Texas, Lewis Hamilton sealed his sixth Formula 1 world championship. Unquestionably one of the sport's greats, he wowed fans even during his debut with McLaren in 2007, winning his first title for that team the following year. The rest of his titles have come at the wheel of a Mercedes-AMG, and all since 2014.</p>
<p>The year 2014 happens to be when F1's last big rule change happened, ushering in the current era of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2014/06/high-tech-hybrids-are-2014s-hottest-race-cars/">complicated and expensive turbocharged hybrid V6es</a>. During that time, the cars have gotten faster than ever before—even if they are approaching Le Mans prototypes in weight. They have also become even more ruinously expensive to design and operate, with little to no effect on the quality of the racing. But starting in 2021, that will change thanks to a new set of <a href="https://www.fia.com/multimedia/publication/2021-formula-1-technical-regulations-2019-10-31">technical rules</a> and more equitable sharing of the proceeds among the teams.</p>
<p>At least, that's what Liberty Media hopes. The US-based entertainment company <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/01/bernie-ecclestone-is-no-longer-running-formula-1/">bought the commercial rights to F1 in 2017</a>, and since then it has been trying to fix some of the huge structural problems with the sport. That's easier said than done; a more equitable sharing of the pie means the well-funded, politically powerful teams will get less, and politically powerful turkeys <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/11/new-hybrid-rules-for-f1-have-teams-in-a-tizzy-ferrari-threatens-to-quit/">rarely vote for Christmas</a>. But that's what happened—the FIA World Motor Sport Council just voted unanimously to approve Liberty's intended changes, despite worries that Ferrari <a href="https://www.racefans.net/2019/06/03/liberty-is-failing-f1-by-letting-ferrari-keep-its-veto/">would exercise its veto</a>.</p>
<h2>The cars</h2>
<p>To an untrained eye, the new car looks a lot like a current F1 machine—big wings at the front and back, exposed wheels, and an open cockpit. But as you look at the details, it's apparent this is actually a radical new direction by F1 standards. The front wing is much simpler than current iterations, and the rear wing has actually grown compared to those now in action. But neither is as important as what lies underneath; the new car's floor is shaped to create <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/09/how-a-day-driving-high-downforce-cars-at-vir-taught-me-im-ok-being-slow/">aerodynamic downforce via a ground effect</a>, a technique that was <a href="https://www.motorsportmagazine.com/history/f1/five-classic-formula-1-ground-effect-cars">last seen</a> in F1 in 1983.</p>
<p>It's <a href="https://www.motorsportmagazine.com/opinion/f1/how-f1s-2021-rules-should-bring-closer-racing-aero-changes-explained">one of a number of changes</a> that are intended to allow one car to follow another much more closely through the corners. A current F1 car can lose up to 80% of its front downforce as it drives in the wake of dirty air behind another car; preliminary wind tunnel tests show the penalty two years from now should be only a 10% reduction or less.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sn2eisHLwwk?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>That also explains the small winglets over the tops of the front wheels and even the spinning fairings that cover the wheels themselves. Wheels are growing to 18 inches in diameter, and the tires (still solely supplied by Pirelli) will be low-profile. That means that F1 suspension designers will have some decisions to make when it comes to springs—currently that role is performed by the massive sidewalls of the 13-inch tires now in use.</p>
<p>Clever hydraulic suspension systems will be banned, but plans to massively increase the use of standardized parts including gearboxes did not pass muster. Proposals to get rid of the complicated powertrains with their two hybrid systems similarly vanished, and the 2021 car will actually be even heavier than ever at 768kg (1,693lbs) to account for some added safety improvements.</p>
<h2>The money</h2>
<p>The changes to the sport's notoriously byzantine financial structure are probably much more wide-ranging. For many years, F1's business side was governed by a document called the Concorde agreement, signed by each team that participated in the championship. In later years, this was replaced with an even more opaque web of contracts with individual teams, signed to prevent breakaway series and guaranteeing some participants tens or even a hundred million dollars a year extra just for showing up. If that sounds like a recipe for disparities, you're right—since 2014, only Mercedes, Ferrari, and Red Bull have won races. The other eight teams have in effect fought each other in a <em>de facto</em> second division.</p>
<p>Cost caps have worked in sports like our own Jon Brodkin's beloved NFL where a salary cap keeps one team from hiring up all the talent. The idea of a cost cap in F1 was proposed once before, in 2009, when it was to be set at $40 million a year to get some new teams to sign up. But the idea died on the vine, as did those new teams lured in by the notion that F1 could ever be affordable. Now, the cap is a more realistic $175 million a year—for context, teams spend on average $312 million a year right now, although that's skewed by the three big spenders (Mercedes, Ferrari, and Red Bull).</p>
<p>The cap doesn't include driver salaries or the three highest non-driver salaries, marketing budgets, and the costs that some teams incur from running their old cars at heritage events or other non F-1 activities. Because the new financial rules are spelled out in an <a href="https://www.fia.com/multimedia/publication/2021-formula-1-financial-regulations-2019-10-31">official FIA document</a>, the series can impose sporting penalties on teams that break the cap. The series will conduct a dummy run of the process in 2020.</p>
<h2>The sport</h2>
<p>There are also provisions to increase the cap if necessary, because F1 might increase the number of races each year. Currently, this stands at 21—many more than we had in the old days—but the new <a href="https://www.fia.com/multimedia/publication/2021-formula-1-sporting-regulations-2019-10-31">sporting regulations</a> allow for up to 25 races a year, with a $1 million increase to the cost cap for each extra race above the current 21. F1 will also shorten its race weekend format from four to three days, with the scrutineering process happening on each Friday instead of Thursday.</p>
<p>The changes to F1 <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/07/formula-1-cars-are-about-to-go-through-a-big-change-but-is-it-good/">aren't as radical as some would like</a>; I'd ban hybrids, rear wings, and pit-to-car radios if it were up to me, for instance. But on balance they do seem headed in the right direction, and these tweaks are the product of a thoughtful collection of poachers-turned-gamekeepers like Ross Brawn, Pat Fry, and Nikolas Tombazis. I'm not particularly concerned that the new cars will be a few seconds slower across a lap, either, <a href="https://www.racefans.net/2019/11/01/raikkonen-if-the-racing-is-better-no-one-would-care-if-were-10-seconds-slower/">a sentiment shared by drivers</a> like Kimi Raikkonen and Daniel Ricciardo.</p>
<p>I am encouraged to see F1 try to grasp the nettle of inequality that's at the heart of the sport today. And I've got my fingers crossed that the wind tunnel and computational fluid dynamics work that gave us the 2021 technical regs correlates with the real world when the cars line up for that first race in March 2021.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596127&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Splatter master Jackson Pollock avoided “coiling” when creating his paintings</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595661</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 18:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coiling instability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fluid dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jackson Pollock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595661</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Contradicts earlier study's claim that coiling gave rise to curved lines in his work.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/pollockTOP-800x530.jpg" alt="Jackson Pollock working in his Long Island studio adjacent to his home in 1949."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/pollockTOP.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="795" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Jackson Pollock working in his Long Island studio adjacent to his home in 1949. (credit:  Martha Holmes/The LIFE Picture Collection via Getty Image)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Famed abstract expressionist Jackson Pollock notoriously relied on non-traditional painting techniques to create his masterpieces. Physicists have pondered the presence of curls and coils in his work, and whether the artist deliberately exploited a well-known fluid dynamics effect to achieve them. Now <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0223706">a recent paper</a> in PLOS One is claiming the opposite: Pollock deliberately avoided so-called "coiling instabilities" as he worked.</p>
<p>For the last few years, Roberto Zenit, a physicist with the National Autonomous University of Mexico and Brown University, has been studying the physics of fluids at work in novel painting techniques like those used by Pollock and Mexican muralist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Alfaro_Siqueiros">David A. Siqueiros</a>. Pollock, for instance, early on employed a "flying filament" or "flying catenary" technique before he perfected his dripping methods. The paint forms various viscous filaments, which are thrown against a vertical canvas. Zenit and several colleagues were able to recreate the fluid action by mounting a paint-filled brush on a rapidly rotating mechanical arm.</p>
<p>Pollock's dripping technique involved laying a canvas flat on the floor and then pouring paint on top of it. Sometimes he poured it directly from a can, sometimes he used a stick, knife, or brush, and sometimes he used a syringe. The artist usually "rhythmically" moved around the canvas as he worked. His style has long fascinated physicists, such as the <a href="https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/cocktail-party-physics/httpblogsscientificamericancomcocktail-party-physics20110718physicists-embrace-the-splatter-master/">controversy surrounding</a> the question of whether <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=100098X1555750&amp;isjs=1&amp;jv=13.24.0-stackpath&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fscience%2F2018%2F12%2Fstudy-modern-masters-like-jackson-pollock-were-intuitive-physicists%2F&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Farticles%2Fnature05398&amp;xguid=&amp;xs=1&amp;xtz=480&amp;xuuid=53ec6852fc328690b001a62295c89b2e">or not</a> Pollock's paintings show evidence <a href="http://discovermagazine.com/2001/nov/featpollock">of fractal patterns.</a></p>
<p>Most notably for this latest work, in 2011, Boston College physicist Andrzej Herczynski and Harvard mathematician Lakshminarayanan Mahadevan collaborated with art historian Claude Cernuschi on an <a href="http://discovermagazine.com/2001/nov/featpollock">article for <em>Physics Today</em></a> examining Pollock's use of <a href="http://cenblog.org/artful-science/2011/07/03/jackson-pollock-physics/">a "coiling instability"</a> in his paintings. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/12/study-modern-masters-like-jackson-pollock-were-intuitive-physicists/">As Ars reported</a> last year, this mathematically describes how a viscous fluid folds onto itself like a coiling rope—just like pouring cold maple syrup on pancakes.</p>
<p>The patterns that form depend on how thick the fluid is (its viscosity) and how fast it's moving. Thick fluids form straight lines when being spread rapidly across a canvas, but they will form loops and squiggles and figure eights if poured slowly. Herczynski <em>et al.</em> measured the thickness of lines and the radius of the coils in a Pollock painting showing this effect, and the team used that data to estimate the flow rate of the paint as the artist's hand moved across the canvas.</p>
<h2>An intuitive physicist</h2>
<p>According to Zenit, Pollock almost certainly relied heavily on physics as he painted, whether he did so deliberately or not. He liked to play with texture and viscosity when mixing his paints, often adding solvents to make them thicker or thinner. There's even <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6cgBvpjwOGo">1950 video footage</a> of Pollock at work, in which he asserts, "I can control the flow of paint. There is no accident." What's currently in question is whether or not the artist deliberately used coiling in his work.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/jackson1-980x707.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Schematic view of a small portion (lower right) of ‘Number 14: Gray’, by Jackson Pollock (1948).                      [credit:
                        R. Zenit et al./PLOS One                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>From a fluid mechanics perspective, the artist's famous technique isn't really "dripping" at all, according to Zenit <em>et al</em>. That technical term "refers to the break up of a fluid jet onto drops, resulting from a surface tension instability," they wrote. "For the condition under which Pollock painted, the fluid filaments rarely fragmented while they were applied." The authors chose Pollock's "<a href="https://www.jackson-pollock.org/number-14-gray.jsp">Number 14: Gray</a>" to illustrate the technique, because it was painted with just one color (black enamel paint over gesso-covered paper), making it easier to track the various lines, which differ in thickness and shape.</p>
<p>First, Zenit <em>et al</em>. carefully analyzed video of Pollock working in his studio—taken from the 1950 footage shot by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hans_Namuth#Jackson_Pollock">Hans Namuth</a>—and then they measured how quickly he moved, as well as the distance from the canvas as he dropped the paint. Next the researchers built an apparatus to mimic those movements—essentially a big syringe mounted on an adjustable stand. "We can vary one thing at a time so we can decipher the key elements of the technique," <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2019-10/bu-srt102919.php">Zenit said</a>. "For example, we could vary the height from which the paint is poured and keep the speed constant to see how that changes things."</p>
<p>They found that the vast majority of Pollock's traces were produced because the artist actively avoided coiling instabilities, contradicting the 2011 conclusions of Herczynski <em>et al</em>. "Specifically, Pollock moved his hand at sufficient high speed, and at a low-enough height as <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-fluid-mechanics/article/fall-of-a-viscous-thread-onto-a-moving-surface-a-fluidmechanical-sewing-machine/35A118A31F3A78E2BEA168EC6594715B">to suppress</a> the emergence of coiling. Like most painters, Jackson Pollock went through a long process of experimentation in order to perfect his technique," <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2019-10/bu-srt102919.php">said Zenit</a>. "What we were trying to do with this research is figure out what conclusions Pollock reached in order to execute his paintings the way he wanted. Our main finding in this paper was that Pollock's movements and the properties of his paints were such he avoided this coiling instability."</p>

<p>That said, this is not the final word on the matter. Zenit <em>et al.</em> note that the low resolution of the video footage means there's uncertainty regarding the measurements they were able to make. Specifically, they were unable to get simultaneous height and hand speed measurements, and hence they were unable to correlate those two variables. While they used a paint similar to those used by Pollock (a commercial black cellulose Nitrate lacquer), the materials used by Pollock likely had a different composition and hence different degrees of viscosity and density. Also, Pollock did not typically hold the stick he used to deposit paint vertically, often swinging it in wide arcs, although Zenit <em>et al</em>. determined this was not significant enough of an effect to alter their conclusions.</p>
<p>"This result could be of importance for authentication: a painting with too many coiled traces would indicate that the painting was not created by Pollock," the authors concluded. "Furthermore, understanding the conditions for which the coiling instability can be prevented could have implications in practical applications where such an effect needs to be prevented, as in the case of ink-jet printing or the fabrication of optic fibers."</p>
<p>DOI: <em>PLOS One</em>, 2019. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0223706">10.1371/journal.pone.0223706</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595661&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researchers hack Siri, Alexa, and Google Home by shining lasers at them</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595561</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[command injection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice control]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[MEMS mics respond to light as if it were sound. No one knows precisely why.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/google-home-light-commands-800x450.jpg" alt="Researchers hack Siri, Alexa, and Google Home by shining lasers at them"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/google-home-light-commands.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1080" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> (credit: Sugawara et al.)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Siri, Alexa, and Google Assistant are vulnerable to attacks that use lasers to inject inaudible—and sometimes invisible—commands into the devices and surreptitiously cause them to unlock doors, visit websites, and locate, unlock, and start vehicles, researchers report in a research paper published on Monday. Dubbed Light Commands, the attack works against Facebook Portal and a variety of phones.</p>
<p>Shining a low-powered laser into these voice-activated systems allows attackers to inject commands of their choice from as far away as 360 feet (110m). Because voice-controlled systems often don’t require users to authenticate themselves, the attack can frequently be carried out without the need of a password or PIN. Even when the systems require authentication for certain actions, it may be feasible to brute force the PIN, since many devices don’t limit the number of guesses a user can make. Among other things, light-based commands can be sent from one building to another and penetrate glass when a vulnerable device is kept near a closed window.</p>
<p>The attack exploits a vulnerability in microphones that use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microelectromechanical_systems">micro-electro-mechanical systems</a>, or MEMS. The microscopic MEMS components of these microphones unintentionally respond to light as if it were sound. While the researchers tested only Siri, Alexa, Google Assistant, Facebook Portal, and a small number of tablets and phones, the researchers believe all devices that use MEMS microphones are susceptible to Light Commands attacks.</p>
<h2>A novel mode of attack</h2>
<p>The laser-based attacks have several limitations. For one, the attacker must have direct <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line-of-sight_propagation">line of sight</a> to the targeted device. And for another, the light in many cases must be precisely aimed at a very specific part of the microphone. Except in cases where an attacker uses an infrared laser, the lights are also easy to see by someone who is close by and has line of sight of the device. What’s more, devices typically respond with voice and visual cues when executing a command, a feature that would alert users within earshot of the device.</p>
<p>Despite those constraints, the findings are important for a host of reasons. Not only does the research present a novel mode of attack against voice-controllable, or VC, systems, it also shows how to carry out the attacks in semi-realistic environments. Additionally, the researchers still don’t fully understand the physics behind their exploit. A better understanding in the coming years may yield more effective attacks. Last, the research highlights the risks that result when VC devices, and the peripherals they connect to, carry out sensitive commands without requiring a password or PIN.</p>
<p>“We find that VC systems are often lacking user authentication mechanisms, or if the mechanisms are present, they are incorrectly implemented (e.g., allowing for PIN bruteforcing),” the researchers wrote in a paper titled <a href="http://lightcommands.com/">Light Commands: Laser-Based Audio Injection Attacks on Voice-Controllable Systems</a>. “We show how an attacker can use light-injected voice commands to unlock the target’s smart-lock protected front door, open garage doors, shop on e-commerce websites at the target’s expense, or even locate, unlock and start various vehicles (e.g., Tesla and Ford) if the vehicles are connected to the target’s Google account.”</p>
<p>Below is a video explaining the Light Commands attack:</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ORji7Tz5GiI?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">LightCommands v3 2 </p></div>
<h2>Low cost, low power requirements</h2>
<p>The paper describes different setups used to carry out the attacks. One is composed of a simple laser pointer (price $18 for three), a <a href="https://www.teamwavelength.com/product/ld5cha-5-a-30-v-laser-diode-driver/">Wavelength Electronics LD5CHA</a> laser driver ($339), and a <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS22YWV/?tag=arstech20-20">Neoteck NTK059</a> audio amplifier ($27.99). The setup can use an optional <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001GKPOJK/?tag=arstech20-20">Opteka 650-1300mm</a> telephoto lens ($199.95) to focus the laser for long-range attacks. The laser driver and diodes are intended for lab use, a condition that requires an attacker to experience with lasers to successfully assemble and test the setups.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ihRAwc24nXw?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Light Commands demo with inexpensive setup. </p></div>
<p>Another setup used an infrared laser that’s invisible to the human eye for more stealthy attacks. A third setup relied on an <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=acebeam+w30&amp;hvadid=78615192598675&amp;hvbmt=be&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvqmt=e&amp;tag=mh0b-20&amp;ref=pd_sl_54wtf039wz_e">Acebeam W30 500 lumens</a> laser-excited phosphor flashlight to eliminate the requirement to precisely aim a light on a specific part of a MEMS microphone.</p>
<p>One of the researchers’ attacks successfully injected a command through a glass window 230 feet away. In that experiment, a VC device was positioned next to a window on the fourth floor of a building, or about 50 feet above the ground. The attacker’s laser was placed on a platform inside a nearby bell tower, located about 141 feet above ground level. The laser then shined a light onto the Google Home device, which has only top-facing microphones.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/building-to-building.jpg"><img alt='A diagram of the building-to-building attack using Light Commands.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/building-to-building-640x284.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/building-to-building.jpg 2x" alt='A diagram of the building-to-building attack using Light Commands.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/building-to-building.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A diagram of the building-to-building attack using Light Commands.</a> (credit: Sugawara et al.)</p></div>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EtzP-mCwNAs?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Building-to-building Light Commands attack. </p></div>
<p>In a different experiment, the researchers used a telephoto lens to focus the laser to successfully attack a VC device 360 feet away. The distance was the maximum allowed in the test environment, raising the possibility that longer distances are possible.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iK2PtdQs77c?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Light Commands in a corridor. </p></div>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Semantic gap</h2>
<p>The findings, the researchers wrote, identify a “semantic gap between the physics and specification of MEMS (microelectro-mechanical systems) microphones, where such microphones unintentionally respond to light as if it was sound.” The researchers are still determining precisely what causes MEMS microphones to respond this way. The microphones convert sound into electrical signals, but as the research demonstrates, the microphones also react to light aimed directly at them. By modulating the amplitude of a laser light, attackers can trick microphones into producing electrical signals as if they are receiving a specific audio sound, such as “Alexa, turn volume to zero” or “Siri, visit Ars Technica dot com.”</p>
<p>In an email, the researchers wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>We know that light triggers some sort of movement in the microphone’s diaphragm, and that mics are built to interpret such movements as sound (as they’re typically resulting from sound pressure physically hitting the diaphragm). However, we do not completely understand the physics behind it, and we are currently working on investigating this. The semantic gap is that we implicitly assume that mics pick up sound, and only sound, while actually also picking up light in addition (as our work shows).</p></blockquote>
<p>The lasers used in the experiments ranged from common pointers, requiring just 5mW of laser power, to lights powered by 60mW. While the latter type of lasers are powerful enough to damage eyes for even a brief period of exposure, they require only a small battery to produce light.</p>
<p>The Light Commands research is the product of a joint team of the following academic researchers: <a href="https://www.sugawara-lab.jp/member/sugawara_e">Takeshi Sugawara</a> of the <a href="https://www.uec.ac.jp/eng/">University of Electro-Communications</a> in Japan and, from the <a href="https://cse.engin.umich.edu/">University of Michigan</a>, <a href="https://benjamin-cyr.com/">Benjamin Cyr</a>, <a href="https://sararampazzi.com">Sara Rampazzi</a>, <a href="https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~genkin/">Daniel Genkin</a>, and <a href="https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~kevinfu/">Kevin Fu</a>.</p>
<p>In a statement, Amazon officials wrote: “Customer trust is our top priority and we take customer security and the security of our products seriously. We are reviewing this research and continue to engage with the authors to understand more about their work.”</p>
<p>Google's response, meanwhile was: "We are closely reviewing this research paper. Protecting our users is paramount, and we're always looking at ways to improve the security of our devices."</p>
<p>On background, an Amazon representative said the company doesn't think the research presents a threat to Alexa users, in part because the attack requires specialized equipment and line of sight to the device. Users can always set up PINs for sensitive functions and use the mute button to disconnect power to the mic or keep an eye on the device display to see if it's receiving or carrying out commands. A Google representative also said on background that the attack didn't pose a threat to users because it's based on conditions and setups that aren't common in homes. Google researchers will continue to investigate reports like this one, the representative added.</p>
<p>Apple officials declined to comment. Facebook wasn't immediately available for comment.</p>
<h2>Bypassing security protections</h2>
<p>The VC devices in the experiments had different security-related features. Some, for instance, required PINs or passwords to carry out sensitive tasks.</p>
<p>The researchers, however, found that it was possible to cause the devices to visit a specific website or, in the event they're connected to certain home security systems, to open a garage door with no PIN required. The devices also required no authentication when receiving a command to turn the volume to zero or turning on do-not-disturb settings. That last task can be useful in making the attacks more stealthy, since it prevents near-by users from hearing sound prompts when commands are being carried out. The researchers also found that, depending on the peripherals a VC system interacted with, it was possible to unlock doors or start or stop connected automobiles without providing a PIN.</p>
<p>Even when PINs are required, the researchers found that it was feasible to brute force four-digit codes. The researchers also believe that PINs are vulnerable to eavesdropping attacks. Another security protection is voice recognition, which accepts commands spoken only by an authorized user. But voice recognition is on by default only on the phones the researchers tested. What’s more, when voice recognition was enabled for Siri and Google Home, the devices verified only that wake words (“Siri” or “Hey Google”) were spoken in the authorized user’s voice. The commands that followed could be from any voice. This may make it easier to base attacks previously captured recordings or deep fakes that mimic a user’s voice.</p>
<p>Below is a summary of the results from experiments on various devices.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/device-table.jpg"><img alt='A list of devices tested for Light Commands attacks, along with results.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/device-table-640x254.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/device-table-1280x508.jpg 2x" alt='A list of devices tested for Light Commands attacks, along with results.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/device-table.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A list of devices tested for Light Commands attacks, along with results.</a> (credit: Sugawara et al.)</p></div>
<h2>A new threat model</h2>
<p>There are several ways that VC device makers may be able to prevent Light Commands attacks. One is to add a layer of authentication to the device by, for instance, requiring the user to provide a correct answer to a random question before carrying out a sensitive command. Manufacturers can also build devices with multiple microphones in them. Commands would be carried out only when a command was received by all the microphones, thwarting attacks that shined light into only one of them. Last, device makers can reduce the amount of light that reaches a microphone diaphragm by implementing barriers or covers that physically block light beams.</p>
<p>It’s almost a certainty that malicious Light Commands attacks haven't been used in the wild, and it’s likely attackers have much more work to do in making them practical. Still, the discovery of a viable way to inject light-based commands is significant, despite the limitations and challenges to making them work reliably and without detection in real-world settings. Until now, command-injection attacks required proximity to a targeted VC device. Light-based injections represent a novel attack vector that may require device makers to construct new defenses.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595561&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blizzard won’t reverse Hearthstone pro’s Hong Kong protest suspension</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595979</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 15:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595979</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blizzard boss shifts some blame for initial decisions to Chinese publishing partner.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-11.56.20-AM-800x500.png" alt="Ng &quot;Blitzchung&quot; Wai Chung declares his support for Hong Kong while two announcers duck behind their desks."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-Shot-2019-10-08-at-11.56.20-AM.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1600" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Ng &quot;Blitzchung&quot; Wai Chung declares his support for Hong Kong while two announcers duck behind their desks. (credit: Blizzard)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Blizzard President J. Allen Brack <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/blizzard-president-clarifies-decision-to-ban-hearthstone-player-and-two-casters-over-hong-kong-controversy/">said in an interview with PC Gamer this weekend</a> that the company will not be reversing <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-reinstates-hong-kong-protestors-prize-says-china-had-no-influence/">a six-month suspension</a> for Ng "Blitzchung" Wai Chung and two <em>Hearthstone</em> casters that were involved in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/blizzard-bans-pro-hearthstone-gamer-for-statement-supporting-hong-kong/">Hong Kong-related protests on a live esports stream last month</a>.</p>
<p>In explaining that decision,Brack reiterated the message that Blizzard supports free speech and encourages employees and players to say what they want in "all kinds of ways and all kinds of places." The one exception to that, he said, is "official broadcasts," including Blizzard-sponsored esports events, which the company wants to be "focused on the games."</p>
<p>"Again, it's not about the content of Blitzchung's message,"Brack said, echoing <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-reinstates-hong-kong-protestors-prize-says-china-had-no-influence/">previous comments</a> from Blizzard. "It's about the fact that it was not around the games. If we hadn't taken action, if we hadn't done something, you can imagine the trail that would be in our future around doing interviews. They would become times for people to make a statement about whatever they wanted to, on whatever issue. That's just a path that we don't want to go down. We really want the content of those official broadcasts to be focused on the games, and keep that focus."</p>
<p>Brack added that Blizzard employees, including "esports athletes, our Grandmasters, or anyone who is participating in esports [are] free to say and do whatever they want on their social channels." That seems to directly contradict the reported experience of Justin "Jayne" Conroy, assistant coach for the Dallas Fuel pro <em>Overwatch</em> team, who <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/sports/dallas-fuel/2019/10/09/fuel-assistant-coach-jayne-condemns-punishment-levied-hong-kong-hearthstone-pro-voiced-support-anti-government-protest/">told the Dallas Morning News last month</a> that Blizzard asked him to remove a tweet criticizing the Blitzchung decision.</p>
<p>Brack's interview comes after he issued a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/blizzard-president-gives-vague-apology-for-hong-kong-protest-response/">vague apology</a> from the Blizzcon stage Friday, in which he accepted "accountability" for the Blitzchung decision and said the company would "do better" in the future. The decision to keep the suspension in place comes despite pressure from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/11/1/20943761/hong-kong-protests-blizzcon-2019-blitzchung">Blizzcon protesters</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-belatedly-punishes-college-hearthstone-team-for-hong-kong-protest/">pro <em>Hearthstone</em> players</a>, <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer">Blizzard employees</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/boycottblizzard">Twitter hashtaggers</a>, and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/us-legislators-urge-blizzard-to-reverse-hong-kong-protest-player-ban/">a bipartisan group of US legislators</a>.</p>
<p>Brack also reiterated in the interview that Chinese regulations and business pressure has nothing to do with the company's decisions regarding Blitzchung. Though <em>Hearthstone</em> is available in China,Brack stressed that it was only through local publishing partner NetEase, and that Blizzard itself is "not legally allowed to operate or to publish games in China."</p>
<p>Brack also said NetEase was to blame for a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/dfjldg/blizzards_official_weibo_account_just_posted_an/">Weibo post from Blizzard China</a> shortly after Blitzchung's on-stream protest, which suggested the company would "always respect and defend the pride of [China]."Brack said directly that Blizzard "did not authorize [the post]. We did not approve it. We would not have approved it had they asked."</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the interview, though, Brack says that Blizzard Taiwan, <em>Hearthstone</em> leadership, and Blizzard's "esports team" were all "in conversation [with NetEase] around the issue." Together, Brack said, those groups "acted very rapidly and we acted very quickly" in handing out Blitzchung's initial ban, using an amount of haste that Brack now calls "the failure of this story."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595979&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starliner flies for the first time, but one of its parachutes failed to deploy</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595863</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 15:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595863</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Parachutes are an old technology, but they are very hard to get right.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/NASA-Live_-Official-Stream-of-NASA-TV-13-26-21-screenshot-980x551.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          A view of Starliner and its Service Module mounted for the test.                      [credit:
                        NASA TV                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>On a cold Monday morning in New Mexico, Boeing's Starliner spacecraft took flight for the first time. Under the power of its main launch abort engines, the capsule accelerated to 650mph in just 5 seconds during a demonstration of its escape system.</p>
<p>The pad abort test marked a critical milestone as Boeing seeks to fly humans to the International Space Station sometime in 2020. During Monday's 75-second test, Starliner appeared to successfully demonstrate its ability to rapidly escape from a problem with its Atlas V rocket during launch.</p>
<p>The test evidently proceeded nominally until the main parachutes deployed—only two rather than three emerged from the capsule as it descended to the desert floor. During the webcast, both Boeing's Jessica Landa and NASA's Dan Huot said the deployment of two parachutes fell within the safety requirements of the system, and that this result was "within the bounds" of this test.</p>

<p>However, the issue of parachutes have bedeviled both Boeing and SpaceX during their development of spacecraft to take humans into orbit for NASA's commercial crew program. Both companies have had failures during their test programs and have had to change their chute designs. Parachutes are an old technology, but they are very hard to get right and represent a single-point failure during a spaceflight.</p>
<p>While it is true that Starliner could return from space with just two of three parachutes functioning, it seems reasonable that NASA will want to spend some time studying this particular failure to fully understand its cause. Boeing has planned an orbital flight test of the Starliner vehicle—there will be no astronauts on board this mission—for December 17. If this test proceeds on schedule, it will send a strong signal that neither NASA nor Boeing is particularly concerned about this parachute failure.</p>
<p>One other notable event during Monday's test was the large amount of orange smoke from dinitrogen tetroxide propellant that emanated from Starliner's Service Module as it came down to the ground. Some of this drifted across the area where the capsule came to rest, potentially fouling the recovery site. It was not immediately clear whether this presented a real issue.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595863&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vikings killed off Iceland’s walruses</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595783</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 14:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extinction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iceland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viking age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vikings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walrus]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ancient DNA says the extinct Icelandic walruses were a genetically distinct population.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/NOR-2016-Svalbard-Sjuøyane-Phippsøya-Atlantic_Walrus_Odobenus_rosmarus_rosmarus_03-800x450.jpg" alt="Vikings killed off Iceland’s walruses"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/NOR-2016-Svalbard-Sjuøyane-Phippsøya-Atlantic_Walrus_Odobenus_rosmarus_rosmarus_03.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3250" data-width="5777">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=52270759">Andrew Shiva / Wikipedia</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>There are no walruses in Iceland, but, at one time, there were hundreds. The timing of the walruses' disappearance suggests that the population's loss may be one of the earliest known examples of humans driving a marine species to local extinction.</p>
<h2>The ghost of walruses past</h2>
<p>Walruses used to be a major feature of life in Iceland. Several settlements and landmarks along Iceland’s coast still bear names that refer to walruses, and a few of the medieval Sagas (the stories of the island’s early settler families) even mention them. The Saga of Hrafin Sveinbjarnarson, written down sometime in the late 1100s, tells the story of a chieftain who killed a walrus and brought its tusks and skull to Canterbury Cathedral in England. But the walruses themselves have been reduced to only a few ancient bones and tusks.</p>
<p>Did the walruses disappear before or after the Norse arrived? In other words, did the Norse kill off Iceland’s walruses, or did the population die of natural causes? Because Iceland has no living walruses today, historians have debated whether the place names referred to places where walruses were living when people arrived or just places where settlers found the skulls and tusks of long-dead animals. The walrus tusks that Hrafin Sveinbjarnarson delivered to England could have been part of a thriving Icelandic walrus population, but it could also have been only a lost wanderer from more distant shores.</p>
<p>To learn more about Iceland’s pinniped past, evolutionary genomicist Xenia Keighley of the University of Copenhagen and her colleagues radiocarbon dated and sequenced DNA from 34 samples of bones and tusks from walruses in the Icelandic Museum of Natural History. The DNA studies also showed that Iceland’s long-lost walruses were a distinct branch of the walrus family. The oldest walrus remains in the museum, dating to 5502-5332 BCE, were related to the ancestors of today’s Atlantic walrus population. More recent samples, though, belonged to a separate mitochondrial branch of the walrus family tree, genetically distinct from every group that’s known in the North Atlantic—including the older Icelandic walruses.</p>
<p>“I would suspect that the most recent clade represent a colonization event that replaced the lineage represented by the old sample, rather than the old sample being a direct ancestor to the more recent clade,” co-author Morten Olsen, also an evolutionary genomicist at the University of Copenhagen, told Ars.</p>
<p>Radiocarbon dates of the bones, combined with the walruses’ genomes, provided an estimate of the size of their breeding population, which suggested that walruses had lived on Iceland’s coasts for around 7,500 years. Although their numbers had been small—perhaps around 1,000 walruses at any one time—their foothold on the island had been pretty stable until around 1213-1330 CE, well after Norse settlement began in 870 CE.</p>
<h2>Blame the Vikings</h2>
<p>So what happened to Iceland’s walruses? As always, the answer is complex, but much of the blame falls squarely on the shoulders of the Norse. Settlers arrived in Iceland and began hunting walrus for the European ivory trade at a time when Iceland’s walrus population was already struggling with a shifting environment and a series of volcanic eruptions.</p>
<p>Walrus ivory was a major trade commodity in markets across Europe for much of the early Middle Ages, and the Norse hunted walrus around most of their territory in the North Atlantic. <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/full/10.1098/rspb.2018.0978">According to a 2018 study</a> of DNA from walrus skulls and tusks found in Western European archaeological sites, most of Europe’s supply of walrus ivory came from a walrus clade (a group of related animals with a common ancestor) living in Greenland, which was home to tens of thousands of walruses. Iceland’s much smaller walrus population would have been a drop in the bucket by comparison, but the ivory trade would still have put pressure on Iceland’s small population.</p>
<p>When the first Norse hunters reached them, Icelandic walruses were already facing challenges from the Medieval Warm Period (700 to 1100 CE). A few centuries of relatively warm climate in the North Atlantic were helpful to human explorers, but not so great for walruses, which rely on sea ice as a place to haul themselves out of the water. And at the same time, volcanoes erupted several times near some of the walruses’ key haul-out sites on land. It’s no wonder the walruses couldn’t survive all of that <em>and</em> Vikings.</p>
<p>Some evidence suggests that <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/full/10.1098/rspb.2018.0961">a Roman fishing industry may have wiped out grey whales</a> in the North Atlantic a few hundred years before the Viking Age, but otherwise the Norse may have been the first to wipe out a whole population of animals for profit.</p>
<p><em>Molecular Biology and Evolution</em>, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/ 10.1093/molbev/msz196">10.1093/molbev/msz196</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595783&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nest Wi-Fi is a big improvement over Google Wi-Fi. But is it enough?</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595701</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 13:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Salter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google wifi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nest wifi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595701</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nest Wi-Fi's strength is doing many things well, not doing one thing the best.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-plus-plume-hero-800x600.jpg" alt="Nest Wi-Fi is a big improvement over Google Wi-Fi. But is it enough?"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-plus-plume-hero.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3024" data-width="4032">Enlarge</a> (credit: Jim Salter)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Google says its new Nest Wi-Fi isn't just Google Wi-Fi plus a smart speaker—it's new, improved, and with better coverage. This is good news—despite the impressive sales numbers Google says it has for the original Google Wi-Fi, the product never ranked very well in performance tests at <a href="https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-wi-fi-mesh-networking-kits/">Wirecutter</a>, <a href="https://www.smallnetbuilder.com/wireless/wireless-reviews/33125-wi-fi-system-roundup?showall=&amp;start=4">Smallnetbuilder</a>, or <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/04/send-wi-fi-companies-floor-plans-receive-the-ultimate-mesh-networking-test/3/">here</a> at Ars.</p>
<p>In fact, Google claimed that the new Nest Wi-Fi would cover "up to 3,800 square feet." This raised our eyebrows immediately, since one square foot is very much not like another—my own 3,500-square-foot house is a particular bear to cover due to the downstairs floor having plenty of packed earth occluding the line-of-sight between that entire floor and the router, for example.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/top-floor-annotated-1-1440x971-980x661.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The top floor of our test house is relatively straightforward—although like many houses, it suffers from terrible router placement nowhere near its center.                      [credit:
                        Jim Salter                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>If you set up Wi-Fi systems in many houses, you'll also soon discover that even without an occluded sub-basement floor, a house shaped like one long Viking hall is very different from a house with similar volume but arranged in a mostly rectangular or L-shape. And heaven help you once you get into turn-of-the-century chicken-wire-and-daub walls, or apartments with central elevator shafts, and so forth.</p>
<p>The good news is, a two-piece Google Wi-Fi system <em>did</em> cover even my challenging 3,500-square-foot house—an impressive achievement and a clear win over the original Google Wi-Fi.</p>
<h2>Nest Wi-Fi is all new</h2>
<p>It wasn't clear from the launch announcements, but Nest Wi-Fi really is more than just Google Wi-Fi plus a smart speaker. The Nest Router is a 4×4 AC2200 access point and router, and the Nest Point is a 2×2 AC1200 access point. Each of the original Google Wi-Fi nodes was also an AC1200 2×2 access point, but Nest Wi-Fi points are updated with a newer and better wireless chipset, with additional RAM and a CPU nearly <a href="https://support.google.com/wifi/answer/6280668?hl=en">twice</a> as fast as the original's. Granted, a lot of that new CPU power and RAM is really there to power the Google Assistant—but also it comes in handy for general network use.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-wifi-tops-980x735.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The packaging for Nest Wi-Fi is very similar to that for the original Google Wi-Fi. Once you slip the box open, you see both pieces nestled into a plastic tray. Cables and such are hidden under the tray.                      [credit:
                        Jim Salter                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-right">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-wifi-slightly-scuffed-300x225.jpg"
                                    alt="Google Nest Wi-Fi product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Google Nest Wi-Fi                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_44135984" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NCJWTD" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_44135984">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2NCJWTD">Amazon starting at $169</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgoogle-nest-wifi-ac2200-wi-fi-router-snow%2F6382499.p%3FskuId%3D6382499&amp;subid1=NestWiFiReview">Best Buy starting at $169</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGoogle-Nest-Wifi-Router%2F324662712&amp;subid1=NestWiFiReview">Walmart starting at $169</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2NCJWTD"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgoogle-nest-wifi-ac2200-wi-fi-router-snow%2F6382499.p%3FskuId%3D6382499&amp;subid1=NestWiFiReview"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGoogle-Nest-Wifi-Router%2F324662712&amp;subid1=NestWiFiReview"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>
The original Google Wi-Fi really needed at least three nodes to adequately cover the test house, but Nest Wi-Fi managed it credibly with two. Google does still sell three-piece kits, as well as individual Points and Routers that can be added into existing networks, and we hope to update and retest with an additional Nest Point soon.</p>
<p>Although Nest Wi-Fi isn't <em>just</em> Google Wi-Fi with a smart speaker, the Assistant is a big piece of Google's sales pitch for the new kit. We don't feel there's much to say about it that hasn't already been said about the other Google Home Assistant products, though.</p>
<p>If you own a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/11/google-home-review-a-step-forward-for-hotwords-a-step-backward-in-capability/">Google Home</a> smart speaker, the Assistant in Nest Wi-Fi is going to seem very familiar—in everything from overall sound to listening ability to some occasional bugginess. The smart speaker functionality isn't in the Nest Router, though—only in the Nest Points. It's loud without being overpowering, sounds decent without really wowing you (think "that cheap jam box you had in college and liked okay"), and it listens well and accurately from significant distance. It seems to have a hard time coping with hearing around physical obstructions, though.</p>
<p>For the most part, the speaker in our Nest Point worked as you'd expect—we set timers, asked it to tell us jokes, and other normal things. With the Point atop the ten-foot tall island in the living room, it pretty much refused to accept voice commands unless we performed a chin-up and spoke to it without the cabinet in the way. We don't hold that against the device, though; while atop the island is the best place in my house for the second node in a two-node mesh kit, we don't expect many people will have similar home layout issues.</p>
<p>Sometimes, though, the Assistant was just plain stubborn. When asked "Hey Google, play House of Pain," our assistant said "Sure! Playing House of Pain on Google Play Music"—and then didn't play anything. After five tries in a row, we tried "Hey Google, play 'Jump Around' by House of Pain," and that worked. After that, asking for just the band and not a particular song worked fine.</p>
<p>We don't think this has anything to do with the Nest Point specifically, though, since sometimes the Google Assistant on Pixel phones gets similarly cranky.</p>
<h2>Prepare for a long setup process</h2>
<p>One of the drawbacks of bundling a Google Assistant with a mesh Wi-Fi kit is the sheer length of the setup process necessary to get both going at once. We were already familiar with the setup process for both Google Home and Google Wi-Fi but still ended up needing better than half an hour to get everything operational. We took thirty setup screenshots along the way—and deleted an awful lot more. There's a <em>lot</em> of "next" and "okay" and deciding whether to accept multiple different kinds of telemetry to get through before you can start playing.</p>
<p>If you're really, really excited about your new Nest Wi-Fi kit, this might be okay. For us, it produced significant "setup fatigue"—we feel this process could be streamlined substantially.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/google-home-setup-00-980x1960.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          You don't download a Nest Wi-Fi app—you use the Google Home app. We already had this installed due to playing around with Google Home and Google Home Mini last year.

This wasn't the most intuitive way to start the setup process, since Wi-Fi isn't actually mentioned anywhere yet.                      [credit:
                        Jim Salter                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>We'll spare you the entire panoply of steps, because there's nothing particularly interesting or difficult about them—it's just a lot of steps, a lot of time, and a lot of different privacy asks that seem like they really could have been combined into one section. We did note that Nest claims its voice print matching technology has gotten better—it noted that it had a voice print on file for me already, due to my playing around with a Google Home speaker in my office—but said it had "upgraded" the voice print and it would work "better" now. This did not necessitate any additional voice recordings.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Testing the Wi-Fi</h2>
<p>At Ars, we're always on the lookout for ways to improve our testing metrics. In the past, we've used <a href="https://github.com/jimsalterjrs/network-testing/blob/master/README.md">netburn</a> to variously model 4K streaming, HTTP downloads, Web browsing, and more. Each workload stresses a Wi-Fi network in different ways—but if your tests get too complex, they're difficult to interpret and may also not test all sites in your environment equally.</p>
<p>We think we've improved things significantly this time around by cutting it down to four basic tests.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Full rate download, all stations (STAs) simultaneously</strong>—in this test, we repeatedly download a 1MB file via HTTP as fast as possible from each of our four test stations (laptops) at once. Ideally we'll not only see lots of throughput, we'll see relatively <em>equal</em> throughput at all sites. Some Wi-Fi routers or mesh kits will allow one STA to "starve" others when they're all clamoring for bandwidth at once, and that's not what we want to see here.</li>
<li><strong>Full rate download, each STA solo</strong>—in this test, we repeatedly download a 1MB file via HTTP at each STA. Each station gets to fly solo, though—this is what you can expect for simple throughput in an uncongested network where you're not competing with neighbors, roommates, spouses, IoT gear, etc. for airtime.</li>
<li><strong>1080P streaming and browsing torture test—</strong>this is where it starts getting interesting! In this test, all four STAs emulate both a 1080P streaming session (fetching 1MB chunks of data by HTTP, rate-limited to 5Mbps by sleeping between fetches as necessary) and also a Web browsing workload (fetching "webpages" at 1Mbps; where each "page" consists of sixteen 128KB files, fetched in parallel over HTTP). We monitor both the streaming and browsing results. For the streams to succeed, they need to average 4.5Mbps or better; for the browsing to succeed, the mean latency should be under 1000ms maximum.</li>
<li><strong>4K streaming and browsing torture test</strong>—this is just like the 1080P torture test, but we're requesting 20Mbps per stream instead of 5Mbps. Few Wi-Fi networks will be able to feed four separate 4K streams to distant stations simultaneously. Even fewer will be able to do so <em>and</em> provide good Web browsing latency while they do.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Placement of STAs and APs</h3>
<p>Our four test laptops are located:</p>
<ul>
<li>Along the inside wall of the large upstairs bedroom</li>
<li>Underneath the living room TV (where a set-top box might go)</li>
<li>In the lower-right corner of the kitchen</li>
<li>Along the outside wall of the downstairs master bedroom</li>
</ul>
<p>The downstairs master bedroom is a particularly obnoxious place to cover, since it's blocked from the router by fifty feet or more of packed earth and a concrete slab. Even the second node of a two-piece kit has to reach it by way of both a wall and a floor/ceiling at a nasty oblique angle.</p>
<p>The upstairs master bedroom is also frequently a source of pain, as it's quite distant from both the router and second node. Multiple interior walls, cabinets, and more must be traversed to reach the upstairs master from either node.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/top-floor-annotated-1-1440x971-980x661.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The top floor of our test house is relatively straightforward—although like many houses, it suffers from terrible router placement nowhere near its center.                      [credit:
                        Jim Salter                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The APs—access points, as in the Nest Router and Nest Point—are placed in the router closet off the entryway hall and atop the big island in the living room, above the TV. The spot atop the island in the living room is by far the best place for a second point, since it can both reach the router closet with minimal distance and with a pretty clean line of sight, and also cover the downstairs floor directly.</p>
<p>That does it for Nest Wi-Fi—but since we updated our test protocols, we also needed a guinea pig to compare Nest Wi-Fi to. Since Plume's Superpods are our all-time heavyweight champions, we dusted them off and set them up again as well. Our Plume gear is a four-piece kit, and we placed one Superpod in the router closet, another atop the TV island, a third on the inside wall in the upstairs master bedroom, and a fourth in the den downstairs, directly beneath the living room TV.</p>
<p>We were running short on time, so Plume did not get its usual 24-hour break-in and training period—we just blew the dust off, plugged it in, and started testing right away.</p>
<h2>Cage match—Nest Wi-Fi vs Plume Superpods</h2>
<p>In one sense, this is an incredibly unfair contest—we didn't even get the three-piece Nest Wi-Fi kit, so we're pitting a $270 two-piece kit vs a $400 four-piece kit. That's without even getting into Plume's annually billed membership, which <em>does</em> offer a lot of features but adds to the cost. The whole "pay a subscription for your Wi-Fi" also rankles a lot of tech folks.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Google claims its two-piece kit would cover up to 3,800 square feet—so we gave it the chance to put its Wi-Fi where its mouth is.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-plume-chart-02-1-980x735.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          In the simplest test, we just max out the Wi-Fi bandwidth from each of our four test laptops, running solo. For the most part, Nest Wi-Fi does fine here—but look at that downstairs master bedroom. Yikes.                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>When looking at the absolute simplest metric—how much raw throughput can you get at each laptop when that STA is the only one active—Nest Wi-Fi hangs reasonably well with the Superpods. It did struggle in the downstairs master bedroom, but it was at least in the same ballpark with the Superpods everywhere else—it even beat them in the kitchen.</p>
<p>The real story when it comes to Wi-Fi isn't single device throughput, though—the real pain happens when you're competing with other devices. When we asked for all the throughput we could get from all four stations simultaneously, things got hairier. In the simultaneous throughput test, Nest Wi-Fi provided considerably less throughput in <em>all</em> locations than Plume did.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-plume-chart-03-980x735.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Four 1080P streams isn't a very big ask from a modern mesh kit. Both kits do a good job servicing the four laptops here. The real test is what happens when you try to browse websites while all this streaming is going on...                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>We still believe the real test of a Wi-Fi network isn't throughput at all—it's browsing latency, especially when the network is already congested. To that end, we ran simultaneous 1080P emulated streams <em>and</em> 1Mbps emulated webpage fetches on all four stations simultaneously. Nest Wi-Fi mostly succeeded here in providing all four 1080P streams, though it's still struggling with that downstairs bedroom. However, things go off the rails when we look at browsing latency.</p>
<p>It took nearly four seconds on average for Nest Wi-Fi to deliver a webpage to the downstairs bedroom, and about 1500ms to deliver one to the kitchen. It's worth noting that this really is an <em>average</em>—meaning many of the fetches took longer than that. That's not a good experience. And while we call this a "torture test," it's really not that far off from a normal day at many residences. There are two adults and three kids in my house, and it's not that uncommon for at least four of us to be watching different things on Rokus, tablets, and phones at once, while another of us tries to browse social media.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nest-plume-chart-05-980x735.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Now we've upped the stakes, replacing our four emulated 1080P streams with four 4K streams. The Superpods supply the four streams effortlessly. Nest Wi-Fi succeeds in the upstairs master bedroom, the living room, and (mostly) the kitchen, but fails sharply in the downstairs bedroom.                   </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Making matters worse, both of the Rokus at my house will default to 4K where available—and more and more of Netflix's catalog is 4K. So for the last pair of tests, we stepped things up and asked for four (emulated) 4K streams—requiring 20Mbps apiece—and, again, tried to do some (emulated) light Web browsing at the same time. This was a Herculean task because two of our four test stations were deliberately placed in very difficult-to-reach areas, and we didn't really expect either kit to succeed.</p>
<p>Nest Wi-Fi was able to deliver simultaneous 4K streams to the living room and the upstairs bedroom, and it probably succeeded in the kitchen as well. Although the kitchen didn't quite get the 20Mbps it asked for, anything more than 15Mbps generally suffices for real-world streaming.</p>
<p>Once again, though, Nest failed in the downstairs bedroom. At 6.5Mbps, it is a third of what we requested and less than half the bare minimum necessary for successful 4K streaming. It was no surprise that Nest Wi-Fi didn't do well on browsing latency during the 4K torture test, either—again, we expect that <em>nothing</em> short of wired LAN or at least wired APs could handle this workload.</p>
<p>But to our surprise, the Plume Superpods succeeded on both halves of the 4K torture test, delivering 19.9Mbps to each STA <em>and</em> supplying webpages with under 500ms browsing latency in all four locations.</p>
<h2>Conclusions</h2>
<p>Nest Wi-Fi is a big improvement over the original Google Wi-Fi—and, true to its claims, it did cover our unusually difficult 3,500-square-foot test house. Simply "covering" a house isn't the same thing as making everything work the way you want it to, though. We think many home users will expect a mix of video streaming and Web browsing by everyone in the house at once to work seamlessly.</p>
<p>Nest Wi-Fi is capable of getting that job done under most circumstances, but there's still room for improvement with how quickly, consistently, and reliably it does so in challenging environments. If all you're looking for is great Wi-Fi, you can do better—we don't see the value in buying Nest Wi-Fi if you aren't completely sold on the integrated smart speaker.</p>
<p>Given the price point and the good-but-not-amazing Wi-Fi in Nest, we see it as best suited to those people who are all-in on voice commands. If you want smart speakers everywhere <em>and</em> good Wi-Fi coverage, it's going to be difficult to beat Nest as an all-in-one product.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595701&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ISPs lied to Congress to spread confusion about encrypted DNS, Mozilla says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595109</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNS over HTTPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ISPs lobby against DNS encryption, but Mozilla tells Congress not to trust them.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-firefox-office-800x531.jpg" alt="A Firefox logo is seen outside Mozilla's office in San Francisco."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-firefox-office.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2136" data-width="3216">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Mozilla's office in San Francisco. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/">Getty Images | Iuliia Serova</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Mozilla is urging Congress to reject the broadband industry's lobbying campaign against encrypted DNS in Firefox and Chrome.</p>
<p>The Internet providers' fight against this privacy feature raises questions about how they use broadband customers' Web-browsing data, Mozilla wrote in a <a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mozilla-to-congress-dns-https.pdf">letter</a> sent today to the chairs and ranking members of three House of Representatives committees. Mozilla also said that Internet providers have been giving inaccurate information to lawmakers and urged Congress to "publicly probe current ISP data collection and use policies."</p>
<p>DNS over HTTPS helps keep eavesdroppers from seeing what DNS lookups your browser is making. This can make it more difficult for ISPs or other third parties to monitor what websites you visit.</p>
<p>"Unsurprisingly, our work on DoH [DNS over HTTPS] has prompted a campaign to forestall these privacy and security protections, as demonstrated by the <a href="https://www.ncta.com/sites/default/files/2019-09/Final%20DOH%20LETTER%209-19-19.pdf">recent letter</a> to Congress from major telecommunications associations. That letter contained a number of factual inaccuracies," Mozilla Senior Director of Trust and Security Marshall Erwin wrote.</p>
<p>This part of Erwin's letter referred to an <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/isps-worry-a-new-chrome-feature-will-stop-them-from-spying-on-you/">Ars article</a> in which we examined the ISPs' claims, which center largely around Google's plans for Chrome. The broadband industry claimed that Google plans to automatically switch Chrome users to its own DNS service, but that's not what Google says it is doing. <a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2019/09/experimenting-with-same-provider-dns.html">Google's publicly announced plan</a> is to "check if the user's current DNS provider is among a list of DoH-compatible providers, and upgrade to the equivalent DoH service from the same provider." If the user-selected DNS service is not on that list, Chrome would make no changes for that user.</p>
<h2>ISPs complain about “a plan that doesn’t exist”</h2>
<p>Mozilla actually is planning to switch Firefox users to a different DNS provider by default, specifically Cloudflare's encrypted DNS service. But ISPs are apparently less concerned about Firefox than Chrome because of Firefox's smaller market share.</p>
<p>In addition to the broadband-industry letter to Congress, Comcast has been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/comcast-fights-googles-encrypted-dns-plan-but-promises-not-to-spy-on-users/">giving members of Congress</a> a lobbying presentation that claims the encrypted-DNS plan would "centraliz[e] a majority of worldwide DNS data with Google" and "give one provider control of Internet traffic routing and vast amounts of new data about consumers and competitors." Comcast and other ISPs are urging Congress to intervene.</p>
<p>But a number of the arguments ISPs made to lawmakers are "premised on a plan that doesn't exist," Erwin told Ars last week, referring to the ISPs' claims about Google.</p>
<p>"The focus of the lobbying effort has been on using Google as a boogeyman, given a lot of the antitrust concerns that exist today, to drive a lot of uncertainty about the potential implications of DNS over HTTPS," Erwin said.</p>
<p>Mozilla's letter to Congress said the ISP lobbying against encrypted DNS amounts to telecom associations "explicitly arguing that ISPs need to be in a position to collect and monetize users' data. This is inconsistent with arguments made just two years earlier regarding whether privacy rules were needed to govern ISP data use."</p>
<p>Mozilla was referring to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/03/for-sale-your-private-browsing-history/">ISPs lobbying Congress</a> to kill broadband privacy rules in 2017. The federal government's decision to eliminate privacy rules at the broadband industry's request means that home and mobile Internet providers are not prohibited from using customers' browsing histories to sell targeted ads or from sharing customers' browsing histories with third parties.</p>
<h2>Mozilla cites ISPs’ history of abusing data</h2>
<p>ISPs have consistently claimed such rules aren't necessary because they aren't violating users' privacy. But their objections to DNS over HTTPS "has raised questions about how ISPs collect and use sensitive user data in their gatekeeper role over Internet usage," Mozilla told Congress. Mozilla said it believes the privacy upgrade has "become necessary to protect users in light of the extensive record of ISP abuse of personal data."</p>
<p>That ISP abuse includes mobile providers <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/01/t-mobile-sprint-and-att-still-selling-your-location-data-report-says/">selling real-time location data</a> "to third parties without user knowledge or meaningful consent;" ISPs such as Comcast "manipulat[ing] DNS to <a href="https://www.icsi.berkeley.edu/pubs/networking/redirectingdnsforads11.pdf">serve advertisements to consumers;</a>" Verizon's use of "<a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/03/verizons-supercookies-violated-net-neutrality-transparency-rule/">supercookies</a>" to track Internet activity; and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/09/att-to-end-targeted-ads-program-give-all-users-lowest-available-price/">AT&amp;T charging customers</a> an extra $29 per month to avoid "the collection and monetization of their browsing history for targeted ads," Mozilla told Congress.</p>
<p>Web users are tracked by Google, Facebook, and other advertising companies, of course. ISPs, though, have "privileged access" to users' browsing histories because they act as the gateway to the Internet, Erwin said to Ars.</p>
<p>There is already "remarkably sophisticated micro-targeting across the Web," and "we don't want to see that business model duplicated in the middle of the network," he said. "We think it's just a mistake to use DNS for those purposes."</p>
<h2>Mozilla’s plan for Firefox</h2>
<p>When Mozilla's plan is implemented, Firefox users will be automatically switched to a DNS provider that uses encrypted DNS and has a strong privacy policy. So far, Cloudflare is the only such provider that Mozilla is working with. Erwin said Cloudflare's privacy policy is "best in class" but said Mozilla is trying to bring on other "trusted" providers to give users a choice of which encrypted DNS service to use.</p>
<p>Mozilla is rolling encrypted DNS out to a small percentage of its user base for testing and intends to deploy it to all users in the US later on. The browser will notify users when encrypted DNS is turned on and provide a method for opting out, Erwin said. Users who don't want to wait can already opt in to DNS over HTTPS by <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/firefox-dns-over-https#w_manually-enabling-and-disabling-dns-over-https">following these instructions</a>.</p>
<p>"We think the default approach is the right one because consumers don't have the technical sophistication or even the time to make an opt-in decision on something like this," Erwin told Ars. "We think it's the appropriate role for the browser to set a strong privacy default."</p>
<p>Firefox won't automatically enable encrypted DNS in some cases, however. When Firefox detects parental controls, it will leave the user's existing DNS service in place, Erwin said. Firefox will also leave the existing DNS service in place for certain business users.</p>
<p>"Firefox will detect whether enterprise policies have been set on the device and will disable DoH in those circumstances. If an enterprise policy explicitly enables DoH, which we think would be awesome, we will also respect that," Mozilla said in an <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/09/06/whats-next-in-making-dns-over-https-the-default/">announcement in September</a>.</p>
<p>Mozilla answers other questions about how DNS over HTTPS will work in Firefox in <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/dns-over-https-doh-faqs">this FAQ</a>.</p>
<p>Mozilla has established <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Security/DOH-resolver-policy">specific policy requirements</a> that DNS providers have to meet to earn a spot in Firefox's encrypted-DNS program. For example, DNS resolvers must delete data that could identify users within 24 hours and only use that data "for the purpose of operating the service." Providers also "must not retain, sell, or transfer to any third party (except as may be required by law) any personal information, IP addresses or other user identifiers, or user query patterns from the DNS queries sent from the Firefox browser."</p>
<p>Mozilla's policy also forbids blocking or filtering content except when authorized by users or required by law. Mozilla further requires a public privacy notice that details the DNS provider's data-retention practices as well as annual transparency reports that document how the DNS provider "will handle law enforcement requests for user data and that documents the types and number of requests received and answered, except to the extent such disclosure is prohibited by law."</p>
<p>Mozilla's letter to Congress said that "ISPs often do not maintain privacy notices for their DNS services," so "it is unclear what data is being retained, how it is being used, or who it is being shared with." (<a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/comcast-fights-googles-encrypted-dns-plan-but-promises-not-to-spy-on-users/">Comcast said last month</a> that it does not track its broadband users' Web-browsing histories and that it deletes DNS queries generated by its Internet customers every 24 hours.)</p>
<p>Because there's so little regulation of broadband providers' privacy practices, Mozilla says it is up to browser makers to protect users. "Our approach with DoH attempts to close part of this regulatory gap through technology and strong legal protections for user privacy," Erwin wrote in the letter to Congress. But he urged Congress to act, too, writing that "to truly protect privacy, a combination of technical and regulatory solutions must be put in place."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595109&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mad Max meets Ferris Bueller in boldly outrageous Netflix series Daybreak</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1591973</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 19:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daybreak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1591973</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Adaptation of Brian Ralph's graphic novel is almost too smart for its own good. Almost.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2P9U41e75tE?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Angelica Green (Alyvia Aly Lind), Josh Wheeler (Colin Ford), and Wesley Fists (Austin Crute) are just trying to survive in their post-apocalyptic dystopia in <em>Daybreak</em>. </p></div>
<p>The adults are gone in the wake of a catastrophic event and teens rule what's left of society in <em>Daybreak</em>, a new post-apocalyptic teen dramedy from Netflix. With its whip-smart dialogue, killer soundtrack, and rich trove of sly pop culture references, the show is almost too smart for its own good. I say "almost," because this eclectic genre mashup turns out to be an outrageously over-the-top delight. If you liked Amazon's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/08/review-the-boys-is-the-perfect-therapy-for-chronic-superhero-fatigue/"><em>The Boys</em></a>, chances are you'll like <em>Daybreak</em>, too.</p>
<p><strong>(Some spoilers below, but no major twists are revealed.)</strong></p>
<p><em>Daybreak</em> is based on the graphic novel of the same name by Brian Ralph. His first graphic novel, <em>Cave-In</em>, was notable for having no words at all. <em>Daybreak</em> was groundbreaking in a different way, told entirely from the perspective (both narratively and visually) of an unnamed survivor to an apocalyptic event, breaking the fourth wall to address readers directly. The young man wakes up to find the world he once knew destroyed, before a one-armed man appears and takes him under his protective wing. They are joined by other survivors, teaming up to avoid zombie-like creatures that lurk in the shadows but are never fully shown. It's a quiet, understated post-apocalyptic story that has <a href="https://www.drawnandquarterly.com/daybreak">been described</a> as "<em>The Road</em> meets <em>Dawn of the Dead</em>."</p>
<p>Created by Brad Peyton and Aron Eli Coleite, the<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daybreak_(2019_TV_series)"> Netflix TV adaptation</a> is more "<em>Mad Max</em> meets <em>Ferris Bueller's Day Off</em>"—and in a nod to the latter, the original Ferris Bueller, Matthew Broderick, plays high school principal Michael Burr. Set in Glendale, California, our main protagonist is high school student Josh Wheeler (Colin Ford), who transfers to Glendale High right before a nuclear bomb/biological weapon combination hits the region. The few surviving adults have become "Ghoulies," doomed to crave human flesh and wander aimlessly in search of food while muttering the last thing they said before the bomb hit ("Why so many superhero movies?").</p>
<p>With no adult supervision, the teens stick with what they know, grouping into "tribes" based on stereotypical high school cliques to survive. The Jocks dominate all the other tribes, led by the brutal former star quarterback, Turbo "Bro Jock" Pokaski (Cody Kearsley), and his right hand, Mona Lisa (Jeante Godlock). There are also the Cheermazons, STEM Punks, 4H Club, Game Overs, Disciples of Kardashia, and so forth. It works about as well as you'd expect from teens with no governing experience who have watched way too many movies. Punishment is meted out according to the rules of ancient Rome, except the accused must perform onstage for "American Ninja Idol," hoping Turbo gives them a thumbs up to spare their lives.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/day11-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          New student Josh (Colin Ford) is befriended by Sam (Sophie Simnett).                      [credit:
                        Netflix                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Josh is a loner by choice, deftly evading Ghoulies, Jock bullies, and a mysterious figure known as Baron Triumph who hunts surviving kids and purportedly eats them. He is mostly living what he thinks is the high life, camping out in swank abandoned digs while looking for his missing girlfriend, Sam (Sophie Simnett), who he's hoping has managed to survive as well. But then he has a run-in with the Golf Club (a lowly subgroup of the Jocks, who don't consider it a real sport because of the tiny balls) and rescues 10-year-old Angelica (Alyvia Alyn Lind), a foul-mouthed "MENSA-level genius with flexible morality" and a deep love of fire and explosions. She latches onto him as her best chance to survive.</p>
<p>Josh gradually starts to attract other potential allies among his fellow surviving outcasts who haven't pledged fealty to Turbo. They include Wesley Fists (Austin Crute), a former Jock turned pacifist samurai, who hopes to redeem himself for past bad acts via the code of Bushido; Eli Cardashyan (Gregory Kasyan), a bit of a self-serving tool who has holed up alone in the Glendale Mall; and former biology teacher Ms. Crumble (Krysta Rodriguez), who seems to be the only surviving adult who hasn't gone full-on Ghoulie, in that she can form complete sentences and resists the urge to eat the kids.</p>
<p>Like its source material, <em>Daybreak</em> deliberately breaks the fourth wall to address viewers (and sometimes, the writers) directly—a narrative device also used to great effect in Phoebe Waller-Bridge's hit series, <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fleabag">Fleabag</a>.</em> But it cleverly tailors the style to the different main characters, each of whom gets a chance to tell their backstories in <em>Lost</em>-style flashbacks. For instance, Angelica self-identifies as "gangsta" and adopts the <em>Goodfellas</em> voiceover technique for her featured episode. Wesley's story is narrated by the Wu-Tang Clan's RZA and illustrated with kung-fu movie animations. Ms. Crumble finds herself in a cheesy sitcom narration of her backstory (directed by Angelica with a canned laugh track).</p>

<p>It would be so very easy to screw up such an ambitious mix of genres and complicated narrative threads, but Peyton and Coleite pull it off. And that's largely due to the strong writing, terrific cast, and well-developed characters, especially the teens, who reveal themselves to be far more than the stereotypical roles they've adopted because they're frightened and crave some semblance of familiar structure. Deep down, they are still just kids, a dilemma best captured by Angelica, whose tough, sassy exterior hides a lonely, vulnerable pre-teen who desperately wants to belong somewhere. Her deepening relationship with Ms. Crumble, who gradually becomes a demented mother-figure/mentor, is a highlight of the series.</p>
<p>Sure, it's best not to overthink the outrageous premise, and some of the teen soap moments are predictable, but they are also genuinely moving. And more often than not, the writers subvert our expectations in creative, surprising ways. I'd wager there has never been an after-school special as graphically on point as when Angelica gets her very first period and has to figure out how to use a tampon while hiding from Ghoulies in an abandoned cereal factory restroom.</p>
<p>Josh's search for Sam is nominally the broad narrative arc for the season, but it's the makeshift family he finds along the way that gives the series its heart. The teens didn't destroy the world, but they're the ones who have to rebuild a functioning society from the ashes. On the upside, the apocalypse gives the survivors a chance to figure out who they really are and re-invent themselves accordingly—for better or worse, depending on the characters. <em>Daybreak</em> concludes with a final unexpected twist and several unanswered questions that neatly set up a possible second season. Here's hoping Netflix gives the show that chance.</p>
<p><em>Daybreak</em> is currently streaming on Netflix.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1591973&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The best new board games from the world’s biggest board game show</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595229</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ars cardboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595229</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hands-on with top games at Essen 2019.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Crowd-2-800x533.jpg" alt="There were a <em>lot</em> of people at Essen this year."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Crowd-2.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2570" data-width="3855">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> There were a <em>lot</em> of people at Essen this year. </p>  </figure>




      <p><em>Welcome to Ars Cardboard, our weekend look at tabletop games! Check out our complete board gaming coverage at <a href="http://cardboard.arstechnica.com/">cardboard.arstechnica.com</a>.</em></p>
    

<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>For four days each year, the German city of Essen becomes the center of the tabletop gaming universe. The annual Internationale Spieltage fair—better known simply as "Spiel"—sees publishers from around the world unleash their most anticipated new releases.</p>
<p>This year, more than 1,200 exhibitors from 53 countries showed off their games across 86,000 square meters of floor space. With so much to see, it’s impossible to take in more than a tiny fraction of the games on offer. But for the past few years, I’ve been wandering the halls on behalf of Ars readers, hunting for clever, cool, innovative, and entertaining new tabletop titles. So once again I took a deep breath and dove head first into a maelstrom of cards, dice, meeples, and miniatures. And here are my picks from the games I managed to play.</p>
<h3>Obscurio</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Obscurio-5-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Obscurio                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>A growing subcategory of board games challenges players to convey information using cryptic collections of images—think <em>Dixit</em>, <em>Mysterium,</em> or <em>Deception: Murder in Hong Kong</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://amzn.to/2CaJgQ3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Obscurio </em></a>is the latest addition to the bunch. It casts you and your partners as wizards trapped in a maze-like magical library. To escape, you need to open a succession of doors and find your way to freedom. Each door shows a different arcane image, and one player acts as a guide, using picture cards and subtle similarities between different illustrations to point everyone else in the right direction.</p>
<p>It might sound familiar to anyone who has played similar games, but <em>Obscurio</em> makes some tweaks to the well-established blueprint. For one thing, the guide can use a pair of magnetic arrows to highlight particular elements on the image cards, drawing players’ attention to different colors, shapes, and objects. There’s also a limit on how long players can deliberate over their decisions, and taking too long to choose a door incurs penalties which make things tougher in subsequent rounds.</p>
<p>One player also acts as a secret traitor, actively trying to frustrate the group’s effort to escape. In a game with such a pronounced element of ambiguity, there are plenty of opportunities to subtly derail your friends’ progress, and it’s all bound together with a Hogwarts-style aesthetic.</p>
<h3>Pandemic: Rapid Response</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Pandemic-Rapid-Response.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Pandemic-Rapid-Response-980x653.jpg"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Pandemic-Rapid-Response.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> </p></div>
<p>With the lineup of <em>Pandemic</em> games growing at a rate that would make a virulent strain of <em>e. coli</em> jealous, it’s tempting to wonder how far the franchise can expand without running out of creative juice. <em><a href="https://amzn.to/2NDeQLS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rapid Response</a> </em>suggests it has a ways to go yet.</p>
<p>Players control a team of specialists, each with different abilities, rushing to locations around the world to combat epidemics and prevent the fall of civilization. Rather than a map, though, the board now represents a plane, with different sections devoted to producing different types of medicines and resources needed to fight various infectious strains.</p>
<p>You’ll do this by rolling and re-rolling dice, using the results to move around the aircraft and complete tasks while <em>en route</em> to the next global trouble spot. What makes this tricky is the remorseless time limit, forcing you to make quick decisions under pressure and inevitably creating more trouble in the process.</p>
<p>There’s a thematically jarring element where you can lose the game because your plane becomes too full of trash. But, like the original <em>Pandemic</em>, <em>Rapid Response</em> skillfully creates a mounting sense of tension. The game wasn’t the most fun I had with sand timers at Spiel, however…</p>
<h3>House Flippers</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-House-Flippers-2-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>This quick and quirky game sees players become rival property developers aiming to buy and sell a succession of homes, using the profits to retire to a life of luxury and leisure.</p>
<p>You start out with a single card—representing a dilapidated house—and a plastic sand timer. Whenever it runs out, you flip it over and receive a wooden cube representing rental income. Rent money and the proceeds from house sales combine to let you buy more expensive house cards, and along the way you can acquire additional timers and staff who increase your takings, allowing you to develop a prestigious property portfolio.</p>
<p>It’s reminiscent of <em>Splendor</em> and the <em>Century</em> series of spice-trading games, where players aim to string together a succession of judicious deals as efficiently as possible. But what makes <em>House Flippers</em> deliciously different is that you and your opponents all play simultaneously, snatching helpful cards before your rivals and constantly keeping one eye on your growing collection of timers.</p>
<p>At its core, the game is incredibly simple, but it creates a real frenzy at the table as you frantically claw your way towards the high life.</p>
<h3>Marvel Champions: The Card Game</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Marvel-Champions-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>For years, tabletop studio Fantasy Flight Games has produced faithful adaptations of big-name pop-culture franchises. (See the <em>Game of Thrones</em> board and card games, <em>Star Wars X-Wing</em> miniature battle game, and the succession of releases based on J.R.R. Tolkien’s <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> novels.)</p>
<p>Fantasy Flight recently added Marvel Comics to its collection of geek-friendly licenses, and at Spiel the company was showing off a new cooperative card battler in which players become mighty heroes working together to take down an assortment of dastardly villains.</p>
<p>Mechanically, <a href="https://amzn.to/2oM0EYt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Champions</em></a> feels like a slightly streamlined version of Final Fantasy's now-defunct <em>Warhammer Quest Adventure Card Game</em>. Players go head-to-head with an AI adversary. On each round, the antagonist works to fulfill their schemes, attacks the heroes, or dispatches minions to menace them. To save the day, players have to find clever ways to combine their strengths and overcome a constantly evolving set of dangers and obstacles.</p>
<p>Each player controls a single character, and it’s impressive how well their stats and abilities reflect their comic book representations. In our demo game, Spider-Man flipped and dodged to negate attacks, Black Panther deployed an array of advanced gadgets, and Captain Marvel used her powers of leadership to coordinate the heroes’ efforts.</p>
<p>Another nice touch is that heroes’ character cards are double-sided, with one face representing their secret identity and the other showing their spandex-clad alter ego. Each side comes with different powers, and working out which can be of most benefit at different points is an important step towards victory. The game’s pacing also does a great job of recreating an adrenaline-fueled comic book fight scene. Even though I’m not a fan of superheroes, I’d be more than happy to play <em>Champions</em> again.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h3>Trismegistus: The Ultimate Formula</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Trismegistus-2-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Named after the father of alchemy, <a href="https://amzn.to/2pJz8uW" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Trismegistus </em></a>is the latest release from Daniele Tascini, the designer of last year’s thoroughly-enjoyable-if-punishingly-complex <em>Teotihuacan: City of Gods</em>. It casts you and your opponents as aspiring alchemists attempting to conduct mystical experiments and transmute base materials into gold.</p>
<p>Fortunately, that’s far easier in-game than in real life. To pull it off, you’ll draft dice representing various strange substances, acquire arcane artifacts, and publish alchemical tracts to boost your reputation. It’s a head-scratchingly complicated process, but <em>Trismegistus</em> only allows players to take a single action on each of their turns, meaning that while a game can take two hours to complete, the action moves along at a surprisingly consistent pace.</p>
<p>To win, you must chain together a succession of small moves to pull off bigger combined effects, and along the way you’ll pick up some useful new abilities as you expand your knowledge. This is the kind of game you can't hope to master in a single playthrough, and its publisher was only offering one-round taster sessions rather than complete games. But I saw more than enough to make me want to get it to the table again.</p>
<div><a name='page-3'></a></div>
<h3>Megacity: Oceania</h3>
<div class="image shortcode-img center"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Megacity-1.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Megacity-1-980x653.jpg"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Megacity-1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> </p></div>
<p>As a rule, dexterity-based stacking games don’t come with a lot of thought attached. Releases like <em>Jenga</em> and <em>Junk Art</em> might be fun, but they require steady hands rather than mental acuity. But in <em><a href="https://amzn.to/2C8LcZo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Megacity: Oceania</a>, </em>you need both.</p>
<p>The game has players working to build skyscrapers as part of a futuristic floating city off the coast of Australia. Players construct buildings using plastic pieces drawn from a bag, with each structure resting on top of a cardboard hex tile. Different buildings come with different requirements, needing particular pieces in a variety of configurations. Once you’ve built your masterpiece, you have to carefully push it across the table, linking up with your opponents to form a steadily expanding metropolis without sending all your hard work crashing to the table.</p>
<p>Creating and placing buildings to most effectively boost your score takes careful planning, and maneuvering them into place to form a futuristic skyline is genuinely nerve-wracking. It’s a combination of brains and balance you’ll be hard-pushed to find in any other game.</p>
<h3>1987: Channel Tunnel</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Channel-Tunnel-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>A small-box, two-player game from Spanish indie studio Llama Dice, <em>Channel Tunnel</em> hands players control of French and British engineers working to build an undersea rail link between their two countries. Despite its diminutive appearance, the game comes with some impressive depth.</p>
<p>Both players want the prestige of carving out a longer stretch of the tunnel than their opponent. To do that, each will need to survey the sea bed, invest in technological upgrades, and raise money to correct any deviations in drilling.</p>
<p>What’s most impressive, though, is the game’s action selection system, which lets players force their opponent to pay more to carry out particular tasks. It’s a simple idea, but it brings a tight sense of economy to the game, and it throws up a string of tricky and interesting decisions. Hopefully it won’t be long before the game gets wider international distribution.</p>
<h3>5er Finden</h3>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/9075995770910.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/9075995770910-300x214.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/9075995770910.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/9075995770910.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> </p></div>Roll-and-write games have been hot in recent years, with releases like <em>Ganz Shön Clever</em> and <em>Welcome To Your Perfect Home</em> earning high praise from fans. But with a glut of similar titles following in their footsteps, there have been plenty of disappointments as well.</p>
<p><em>5er Finden </em>isn’t one of them. A game of quick wits and perception, it sees players roll a set of five dice, showing a collection of colored symbols. Players then scour their square-grid personal player sheets, hunting for groups of five connected spaces showing matching icons.</p>
<p>The idea is not hard to grasp, but it’s an intense race with everyone trying to spot matching groups before their opponents. There’s also a more challenging “puzzle mode” where players incrementally mark off more of their grids with each passing round, making it harder to find scoring combinations in an ever-decreasing space.</p>
<h3>Undaunted: Normandy</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Undaunted-3-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Historical battle games can be a bit of a niche, with lots of complex simulations catering to hardcore armchair generals. But this two-player World War II game offers a much more accessible approach. At its heart, it uses a deck-building system that will be familiar to anyone who has played games like <em>Star Realms</em> or <em>Dominion</em>. But it also employs a modular battlefield board and tokens representing a variety of units. Playing cards lets you command different squads, and you’ll be able to move them between locations, scout unfamiliar terrain and—of course—engage your enemies in deadly firefights.</p>
<p>What’s really impressive is how elegantly this deck-building approach represents different aspects of battle. When units suffer losses, you remove one of their cards from your deck, making them harder to control. When you advance into new territory, you also acquire some useless fog of war cards, polluting your deck to represent the reduced efficacy of your thinly-spread forces. It’s brilliantly intuitive, and while my demo featured a small-scale clash between basic units, the game comes with a campaign of scenarios to play through as well as more advanced squads with more powerful equipment and abilities.</p>
<p><em>Undaunted</em> seems like a system which could represent any kind of armed struggle. While a follow-up focusing on British troops in North Africa is already in the pipeline, I wouldn’t be surprised to eventually see sci-fi or fantasy releases as well.</p>
<h3><strong>High Rise</strong></h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-High-Rise-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>This upcoming game from designer Gil Hova sees players become property tycoons competing to build lucrative skyscrapers. In the process, though, they’ll have to get their hands dirty. Taking different actions lets you acquire resources and build towering buildings, but in the process you’ll gain corruption points, with the most corrupt players facing consequences at various points in the game.</p>
<p>The result is that you want to be just corrupt enough to get ahead in the construction racket—but not corrupt enough to be punished. It’s a delicate balancing act, and aesthetically the game benefits from the jaw-dropping work of artist Kwanchai Moriya. Even as a prototype at Spiel, it looked enticing, and I’m looking forward to seeing its finished form.</p>
<h3>Paris: Cité de Lumière</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Paris-CDL-1-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
                            </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Another game with stunning visuals, this two-player competitive puzzle transports players to <em>fin-de-siècle</em> Paris as the city installs one of the world’s first electric street lighting systems. Over the course of two rounds, you’ll lay down tiles to determine the layout of the Parisian electric grid, then lay building tiles on top to score points based on the size of conjoined areas you control and the number of streetlamps neighbouring your properties.</p>
<p>Its scoring system feels a little similar to the award-winning family hit <em>Kingdomino</em>, but <a href="https://amzn.to/2NdRCNh" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Paris</em></a> comes with more to think about, including some special abilities that let you tweak the placement of your buildings or gain extra points by having artists wander the streets painting your illuminated constructions. The real standout, though, is the game’s art: stunningly beautiful and powerfully evocative of its setting. I don’t know whether to play with it or frame it.</p>
<h3>Teburu—a hybrid analog/digital gaming platform</h3>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Spiel-19-Teburu-2-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The Teburu system                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>As well as playing games, I had a chance to look at the <em>Teburu</em> app-enhanced digital tabletop system from publisher CMON, which uses a tablet as well as players’ smartphones to display in-game information. The system also records players’ moves using a smart game mat and RFID chips attached to miniatures.</p>
<p>CMON’s game design director Eric Lang (who <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/05/from-xcom-to-golems-cardboard-games-with-digital-brains/">previously spoke to Ars</a> about digital integration in board games) told me the system would also simplify the process of learning games, with interactive tutorials allowing players to pick up the rules while playing rather than working through chunky rulebooks. And he added that players in different locations would be able challenge each other remotely, with the app intelligently coordinating their game.</p>
<p>We'll see how <em>Teburu</em> is received by players and whether CMON will consider licensing access to other publishers, which could massively expand the choice of compatible games.</p>
<h3>Your picks</h3>
<p>Did you go to this year’s Essen Spiel? Or, were you checking out some of the hot new releases from home? Let us know what caught your attention in the comments.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595229&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford is bringing huge screens—and live updates—to its cars</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595227</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 12:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WIRED]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595227</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ford follows lead of Tesla, Volvo, and Subaru with larger, vertically oriented screens.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/edge-three-quarters-800x600.jpg" alt="Edge"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/edge-three-quarters.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1536" data-width="2048">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A 2019 Ford Edge Titanium. (credit: Eric Bangeman)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In the unending war for dominance in the auto industry, the fighting has long focused on questions of performance, reliability, comfort, style, and safety. But in the past decade, a new front has opened up: infotainment.</p>
<p>The newest entrant is Ford. Today, the biggest touchscreen you can get in a Ford is the Explorer’s 10-incher. Most of its cars come with 8-inch offerings. Starting next year, Ford announced Wednesday, some (to be announced) vehicles will come with 12- and 15-inch touchscreens—the latter is larger than any iPad—stuck smack in the middle of the dashboard.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sync4.jpg"><img alt='Sync 4 will run on screens from 8 inches to 15.5 inches, and includes enhanced multitasking.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sync4-300x480.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sync4-640x1024.jpg 2x" alt='Sync 4 will run on screens from 8 inches to 15.5 inches, and includes enhanced multitasking.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sync4.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Sync 4 will run on screens from 8 inches to 15.5 inches, and includes enhanced multitasking.</a> (credit: Ford)</p></div>The trend toward making car owners feel like they’re at a drive-in theater has been going on for years, best exemplified by Tesla, whose Model 3 sedan has a 15-inch center screen that controls many functions that used to require buttons. In the smartphone era, people have been trained to expect <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/goodbye-iphone-se-small-phones/">screens that are not just big</a> but regularly updated and easy to use. (Bringing a bazooka to this knife fight is Chinese electric-car startup Byton, whose <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/byton-tesla-latest-chinese-competitor-takes-screens-to-an-extreme/">M-Byte SUV</a> will come with a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/forget-driving-watch-tv-car/">four-foot screen</a>.)</p>
<p>“We know the benchmark is cellphones,” says Gary Jablonski, the chief engineer who runs Ford’s infotainment efforts. That’s why, along with screens that stretch farther, Ford is also launching Sync 4. The latest generation of its infotainment system will offer the kinds of features you’ve come to expect from the computer in your pocket. The cloud-connected navigation system will liberate users from constrained libraries of points of interest, allowing them to search the map for things like their doctor’s office. Traffic data will be more detailed and up to date.</p>
<p>The bigger screens will allow Ford to show multiple applications (like navigation, phone, and radio) simultaneously, and to automatically configure their arrangement based on which apps the driver uses most frequently. As for the question of screens distracting drivers from the roads, Jablonski says a bigger display can actually help by saving drivers from fiddling with the thing if it’s showing the radio and they need to see directions.</p>
<p>While the system’s female-sounding voice assistant doesn’t have a name, Ford will let drivers summon it with a phrase like “OK, Ford;” Jablonski says his team is still workshopping options. You can still use the old-fashioned button to trigger the voice recognition system, but people have grown accustomed to verbally summoning their digital helpers. “We think that’ll be the expectation in the car as well,” Jablonski says. Ford will continue to support Android Auto and Apple Carplay (now via wireless connection), and models with Amazon’s Alexa will keep her around.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right full"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/wired-logo.png"></div>To go with these upgrades, Ford is introducing over-the-air software updates. It may not use the capability to make its cars drive themselves, as Tesla has, but the ability to update the Sync system or adjust vehicle settings without dragging a customer into a dealership is a good tool to have. People are holding on to their cars for longer than they used to, says John Vangelov, Ford’s embedded modem features lead. “This lets them keep their in-car tech fresh.”</p>
<p>These changes are built on a new electrical architecture that offers twice the processing power of the outgoing system, Jablonski says. And because the screen and tech wars are nowhere near a peace treaty, he made sure to leave some reserve compute to power the features of the future.</p>
<p>Ford hasn’t disclosed which models the screens and systems will debut on or how quickly they’ll make their way across the lineup. But for an automaker that put Sync onto 30 million cars in 10 years, don’t expect it to take too long.</p>
<p><em>This story originally appeared on <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/ford-huge-screens-live-updates-cars/">wired.com</a>.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595227&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forget the habitable exoplanets—here are some of our galaxy’s freaks</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593471</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593471</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of these worlds is darker than coal, with an atmosphere as hot as lava.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/55cancrie-980x599.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          55 Cancri e.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Let's face it, when it comes to the search for planets outside of our Solar System, Earth-like worlds get all of the attention. We want to know where life may exist elsewhere in the galaxy, right? And where better than water-bearing, moderately warm, reasonably sized planets around nice, steady stars?</p>
<p>Even so, what is perhaps more remarkable than the search for habitable worlds is the diversity of planets scientists have found. NASA has now confirmed more than 4,000 exoplanets by two or more discovery methods, and the agency has another 4,600 candidates as potential planets.</p>
<p>All told, NASA has identified more than 3,000 planetary systems, finding planets of all shapes and sizes around all manner of stars. And there are some weird worlds out there. For example, there is the exoplanet TrES-2b, which is larger than Jupiter and orbits a star located 750 light years from our Sun.</p>

<p>This is the darkest planet scientists have discovered, blacker than coal, with an atmosphere as hot as lava. (It makes the planet Mustafar, where Obi Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker fought a fateful duel in the movie <em>Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith</em> look like a garden world).</p>
<p>Anyway, to mark Halloween this year, NASA has put together some splashy websites that show off these worlds and their stars, under the rubric <a href="https://exoplanets.nasa.gov/alien-worlds/galaxy-of-horrors/">Galaxy of Horrors</a> and <a href="https://exoplanets.nasa.gov/alien-worlds/universe-of-monsters/">Universe of Monsters</a>. It's fun stuff, and unlike the movies, these are real worlds in our own galaxy, not so very far, far away.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593471&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Because Internet makes a linguist’s case for l33t speak, other online-text fads</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595099</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emoji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linguistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595099</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Book review: Linguistics in the Internet age charts a path from BBSes to T9 and beyond.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/internet-speak-mag-glass-800x450.jpg" alt="Linguistics in the Internet age <em>can</em> be fun."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/internet-speak-mag-glass.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="563" data-width="1000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Linguistics in the Internet age <em>can</em> be fun. (credit: Aurich Lawson / Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The Internet has done good things to the English language.</p>
<p>That's the most important thing linguist Gretchen McCulloch has to say in her book, <a href="https://gretchenmcculloch.com/book/"><em>Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language</em></a>. Though many prominent opinion-havers rage about the imminent death of the English language at the hands of emoji-wielding teenagers, the Internet has done no more harm to English than television, radio, or dime novels.</p>
<p>In fact, McCulloch makes a compelling argument that Internet language, and emoji in particular, is restoring life to the relatively emotionless medium of text. For hundreds of years, public writing was limited to formal contexts like newspapers and books, written by educated people using very formal language for the edification of other educated people. Even fiction draws a clear line between informal dialogue and formal narration. On the Internet, on the other hand, the lines are much less clear. Private, informal writing (like shopping lists or notes passed between students at the back of a classroom) is now publicly visible, and the conventions developed by individuals or small groups for writing informally can spread and interact on a global scale. To McCulloch, this is more exciting than it is scary, and reading <em>Because Internet</em> might convince you to feel the same.</p>
<h2>Writing like we talk</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/because-internet-listing.png"><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">(credit: Gretchen McCulloch)</p></div>
<p>McCulloch describes a variety of conventions Internet users have developed for informal writing, from emoji, which function like punctuation or gestures, to YELLING IN ALL CAPS, misspelling words in ways that reflect their own accents, or s t r e t c h i n g out words with internal spaces to make a point unmistakably clear. Each of these devices mirrors a spoken one, and their use allows Internet users to write in the same way that they talk, thereby expressing themselves more fully and more creatively.</p>

<p>Even more fascinating, the amount each device is used changes over time in the same way they might in spoken language. It's a common complaint among younger Internet users that parents are all too eager to end sentences in text messages with periods, sounding serious or even angry all the time as a result. This isn't some conspiracy on the part of old people, McCulloch explains; people in different age groups tend to start using the Internet at different times and for different reasons, and those reasons show in how they text and tweet. For example, a person who first sent a text message using a flip phone with T9Word might retain some of the "txtspk" abbreviations that were necessary for saving effort and staying under the character limit in this tricky system. A younger person who's only ever used a smartphone will feel comfortable typing words out in full and considering the emotional weight of every letter and piece of punctuation in a message, including the previously innocuous period.</p>
<p>McCulloch divides Internet users into several generations based on when and why they began using the Internet regularly, from "Old Internet People" who got their start on Usenet and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/04/a-1986-bulletin-board-system-has-brought-the-old-web-back-to-life-in-2017/">BBSes</a> to the "Post Internet People" who have never known a world without the World Wide Web and are currently spending their formative years on Instagram and Snapchat. In the same way that children and teenagers adopt spoken language conventions from their peer groups, Internet users pick up informal writing conventions from the people they interact with most frequently on their social networks of choice.</p>
<p>Her categories are spot-on: not only do I see myself in the "Full Internet People" who began joining Facebook and Tumblr in high school and college, but my friends and relatives of different Internet generations also see their experiences reflected in her categories.</p>
<h2>Linguistics for everyone</h2>
<p>In the introduction to <em>Because Internet</em>, McCulloch describes her goal as "writing for the future." The book was created as not a stodgy treatise written in the English of the past for academics who might see it as some kind of relic. This is a book for anyone who uses English to get excited about, a book that takes advantage of the trends it describes. This doesn't mean the book is full of emoji adding layers of emotional and social interpretation to each sentence, however; it's still written in formal standard American English. It does, though, use some typographical conventions that haven't yet made it into formal style guides, like not capitalizing "Internet." Even if Facebook and Twitter someday collapse, taking all our wonderful correspondence with them, future linguists will be able to pick up this book and say, "Hey, they really did write like that!" Or even "this is when speech-like writing began to catch on," as McCulloch suggested in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/23/opinion/future-english-language-linguistics.html">a <em>New York Times</em> editorial</a>.</p>
<p>McCulloch is on a mission to make linguistics relatable—and, hear me out, she's on a roll in that respect. She does this not only through <em>Because Internet</em>, but also through <a href="https://lingthusiasm.com/">Lingthusiasm</a>, the podcast she co-hosts with fellow linguist Lauren Gawne. As its name suggests, Lingthusiasm shows off the hosts' enthusiasm about linguistics and calls on its listeners to get excited about a wide variety of linguistic topics, such as <a href="https://soundcloud.com/lingthusiasm/17-lingthusiasm-vowels">how vowels work</a>, the ways people from different cultures <a href="https://soundcloud.com/lingthusiasm/15-talking-and-thinking-about-time">talk about time</a>, and why efforts to create <a href="https://soundcloud.com/lingthusiasm/01-the-one-langauge-peace-fallacy">a single world language never catch on</a>. On Lingthusiasm, McCulloch and Gawne dispel myths about language and inspire the kind of excitement that turns curious students into scientists. And in <em>Because Internet</em>, McCulloch continues to demystify and delight.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595099&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Terminator: Dark Fate provides a fitting coda to first two films</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593655</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ah-nold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linda hamilton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terminator: Dark Fate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593655</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But it might be time to finally terminate the franchise and let it go out on a high note.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/darkfateTOP-800x535.jpg" alt="Promotional image for Terminator: Dark Fate."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/darkfateTOP.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="802" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> This one's for the ladies: Natalia Reyes, Mackenzie Davis, and Linda Hamilton star in <em>Terminator: Dark Fate</em>. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.paramount.com/">Paramount Pictures</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>That sentient AI from a dystopian future has returned and is still sending terminating robots back in time to take out pesky humans who might one day defeat it in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator:_Dark_Fate"><em>Terminator: Dark Fate</em></a>. Director Tim Miller's latest installment is great entertainment and a welcome return to form for the Terminator franchise, featuring a great cast, killer special effects, and nonstop action.</p>
<p><strong>(Some spoilers below.)</strong></p>
<p>While technically the sixth film in the series, <em>Dark Fate</em> has actually been conceived as a direct sequel to the hugely successful first two films: <em>The Terminator</em> and <em>Terminator 2: Judgement Day</em>. So <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator:_Dark_Fate"><em>Terminator: Dark Fate</em></a> pretty much ignores all the other Terminator movies as existing in alternate timelines. Best of all, it reunites stars Arnold Schwarzenegger and Linda Hamilton with James Cameron on board as producer. The film takes place two decades after the events of <em><a title="Terminator 2: Judgment Day" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator_2:_Judgment_Day">Terminator 2: Judgment Day</a>.</em> A new, improved Terminator (Gabriel Luna) is sent from the future to take out a young woman named Dani Ramos (Natalia Reyes). A cyborg/human hybrid named Grace (Mackenzie Davis) joins forces with Sarah Connor (Hamilton) and the original Terminator (Schwarzenegger) to protect her.</p>
<p>The film establishes its direct-sequel bona fides right off the bat with a brief but critical scene showing Sarah and her son John relaxing on a Guatemalan beach in 1998, having averted Judgment Day a few years earlier. (Edward Furlong was initially tapped to reprise his role as John Connor, but it ultimately didn't happen. Instead, Miller used CGI to recreate Furlong's youthful face from <em>T2.</em>) Cut to 2020 and the arrival in Mexico City of two new visitors from the future: Grace and the Rev-9 Terminator. Grace manages to save Dani from the Rev-9's initial attack on a factory floor and escape, with the Rev-9 in hot pursuit.</p>
<p>Just when things look dire, Sarah Connor comes to their aid and they hole up off the grid to regroup. Sarah is understandably suspicious of Grace. And Grace comes bearing bad news: "You may have changed the future, but you didn't change our fate." Skynet never came into being in the altered future timeline, but an AI designed for cyberwarfare, dubbed Legion, did. And as before, a human resistance formed. Dani will play a key role in that resistance, so naturally Legion wants her dead.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fate2-980x654.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          On the run: Dani Ramos (Natalia Reyes) and her brother Miguel (Diego Boneta).                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.paramount.com/">YouTube/Paramount Pictures</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p><em>T2</em> is hands-down one of the best film sequels of all time, and Miller clearly set out to recreate the same magic with a clever mix of old and new. A key part of that formula is upping the stakes with an advanced Terminator model that seems well-nigh impossible to destroy. The Rev-9 merges aspects of both the original and <em>T2</em>'s liquid metal T-1000: it has an updated underlying endoskeleton, with a "mimetic polyalloy" (almost ferrofluidic) overlay, like skin, that can split off to make the machine doubly lethal. Luna—best known as Ghost Rider on <em>Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.</em>—brings a ferocious intensity to the role, best exemplified by a scene where he mows through a crowd of Border Patrol agents without ever taking his eyes off his fleeing target, Dani.</p>
<p>Hamilton is better than ever as Sarah Connor, <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/linda-hamilton-terminator-dark-fate-training-regiment-mackie-shilstone-1202765058/">spending nearly a year</a> on a grueling training regimen to get her 60-something body back into fighting shape. Her lean, ripped physique in <em>T2</em> made her a feminist icon on par with Sigourney Weaver's Ripley in the Alien franchise. Yet, here, she's still allowed to look every bit her age. This is a weathered, embittered Sarah who has earned every one of those scars and wrinkles and has only grown tougher over the years. She identifies with Dani because she was first targeted for termination around the same age, destined to give birth to a great hero of the resistance. Sarah assumes Dani, too, is only of value or interest because of her womb. Her expression when she learns that Dani is actually destined to <em>lead</em> the human resistance in this new timeline falls somewhere between wonder and regret.</p>
<p>Reyes and Davis are both terrific in their respective roles, and Schwarzenegger once again brings his trademark deadpan delivery. The special effects are great, the pacing is brisk, and the stunts are appropriately over the top—as always, there are plenty of explosions and property damage. If there's a flaw in this latest film, it's that everything seems just a little too familiar. Some of that can be chalked up to deliberate callbacks to the earlier films, but it's also because it's tough to hew to such a successful formula while still keeping things fresh.</p>
<p><em>Dark Fate</em> provides a fitting coda to <em>The Terminator</em> and <em>T2</em> while introducing fresh characters in a new timeline to tee up a possible next film. Alas, the film seems <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/11/terminator-dark-fate-linda-hamilton-harriet-motherless-brooklyn-weekend-box-office-1202774477/">to be under-performing</a> at the US box office this opening weekend, which is no doubt disappointing to those hoping to reinvigorate the franchise. Personally, while I'd love to see the further adventures of Dani, Grace, and Sarah taking on all the Terminators to come—what, you think Legion will give up that easily?—the tried-and-true formula is starting to show its age, and we already had a great TV spinoff with <em>The Sarah Connor Chronicles</em>. Maybe it really is time to put the franchise to rest. At least it would be going out on a high note with <em>Dark Fate</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1593655&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wildfire chasers are the new tornado chasers</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595193</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WIRED]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A strike team of specially trained researchers drives into the literal line of fire.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wildfire-800x534.jpg" alt="SOMIS, CA - NOVEMBER 01: The Maria Fire burns on a hillside as it expands up to 8,000 acres on its first night on November 1, 2019 near Somis, California. Southern California has been hit by a series of dangerous, fast-moving wildfires this week as Santa Ana Winds ushered in strong gusts up to 80mph and extremely low humidity.  (Photo by David McNew/Getty Images)"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wildfire.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> SOMIS, CA - NOVEMBER 01: The Maria Fire burns on a hillside as it expands up to 8,000 acres on its first night on November 1, 2019 near Somis, California. Southern California has been hit by a series of dangerous, fast-moving wildfires this week as Santa Ana Winds ushered in strong gusts up to 80mph and extremely low humidity.  (Photo by David McNew/Getty Images) (credit: David McNew | Getty)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In the late hours of October 23, Craig Clements was grading papers when a colleague in Oakland texted him about a rapidly growing wildfire just north of San Francisco. He texted a few of his students, who jumped out of bed and rushed his way. Together they loaded a radar-packing Ford F-250 pickup with gear and hit the road, gathering the Oakland colleague <a class="external-link" href="//www.kqed.org/science/1950367/its-hard-to-predict-where-an-ember-hurled-from-a-fire-might-land">on their way to the Kincade Fire</a>, which would quickly become <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/kincade-fire/">California’s biggest blaze of 2019</a>.</p>
<p>Clements, <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/FireWeatherLab">a fire weather researcher</a> at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.fireweather.org/">San Jose State University</a>, and his team arrived around 1am, driving past fire engines and evacuating locals as they steered toward the blaze. Normally they would check in with an incident command post first, where officials could tell them where the wildfire might be heading, but the conflagration was still too young and chaotic for such organization. So they drove on, trying to position themselves near but not too near the growing plume, searching for a spot not surrounded by brush or traffic, away from power lines that could fall on their heads. On their map they found a road leading to a vineyard—lots of vegetation, sure, but chock full of water and therefore <a class="external-link" href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/california-wildfires/article/Yes-vineyards-can-help-stop-fires-as-they-did-14572161.php#">quite resistant to burning</a>—and turned in, landing a kilometer from a ridge line the fire was burning up to.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right full"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/wired-logo.png"></div>It was perfect: good visibility, out of harm’s way, and most of all, well positioned for their equipment. Amid falling ash and fierce winds, they set up their mobile lab. With the press of a button, jacks automatically leveled out the vehicle, bringing online the only mobile radar in the Western US. The sciencing of the Kincade Fire had begun.</p>
<p>A wildfire is a phenomenon of almost impenetrable complexity. Different kinds of brush burn at different rates, and even the same kind of brush can burn differently depending on hydration and humidity, which change hour by hour. Topography affects the trajectory of a fire, as does wind. For Clements, the goal is to better understand how wildfires can create their own weather and how the dynamics of the plumes affect the fire’s spread.</p>
<p>“Everybody on Twitter is an expert on wildfire science, but nobody's actually been to one,” Clements says. “We're the only meteorological team in the United States with this capability, because we're fire-line qualified.” They go through special training and carry special equipment that could save their lives, like fire shelters. “It's like a foil bag that you wrap your body in. And you get down on the ground and you hope to hell that you don't need it.”</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='Scanning the 2014 King Fire with Doppler radar as VLAT drops fire retardant ahead of the fire front.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fire-lab.jpg" alt='Scanning the 2014 King Fire with Doppler radar as VLAT drops fire retardant ahead of the fire front.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Scanning the 2014 King Fire with Doppler radar as VLAT drops fire retardant ahead of the fire front. (credit: Braniff Davis, SJSU Fire Lab)</p></div>
<p>There in the vineyard, though, Clements and his team were insulated in green vegetation, at a distance from the advancing blaze. With their radar now firing its radio signals, they began peering into the Kincade Fire’s plume.</p>
<p>While the doppler radar for your local weather report picks up hail and water droplets, this specialized device operates on a different frequency that can pick up ash particles and other debris. “The plume was sitting about a kilometer above the ground,” Clements says. “As the fire got more vigorous, we couldn't see the fire, but we could see the radar showing the plume punching up to almost three kilometers.”</p>
<p>A glowing leaf landed nearby: it was a firebrand, the lit pieces of debris that winds pick up that can make <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/santa-ana-winds-might-dwindle-but-fire-danger-remains/">California’s wind-driven blazes</a> especially hard to contain. By flying perhaps miles ahead of the main blaze and starting new fires, firebrands can overwhelm crews. Last weekend in Northern California, winds blew firebrands clear across the Carquinez Strait, <a class="external-link" href="https://sanfrancisco.cbslocal.com/2019/10/27/fires-vallejo-carquinez-oct27/">starting a new fire on the other side</a>. In cities they can land on roofs and start a constellation of new fires, as happened in last year’s <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-terrifying-science-behind-californias-massive-camp-fire/">deadly Camp Fire</a>, which obliterated the town of Paradise.</p>
<p>With plenty of green vegetation in the researchers’ vineyard, the smoldering leaf was harmless. But it’s these airborne threats that brought Clements out in the first place. By tracking the firebrands with radar, he can start to better understand how far these things can travel. “We can get the altitude of what we think the embers were,” he says, “and then we can use that information to create a model that actually forecasts spot fires correctly.”</p>
<p>With radar, the team can also better understand the atmospheric eccentricities of the wildfire itself. The conflagrations can grow so massive and intense that they create their own weather: as hot air rises, additional air rushes in at ground level to replace it. If the conditions are right, this kind of atmospheric disturbance can actually create <a href="https://www.wired.com/video/watch/extreme-events-fire-tornado">fire tornadoes</a>—140-mile-per-hour winds of swirling hot gas and debris, much of it aflame. It’s as close as you can get to hell on Earth.</p>
<p>Better understand the dynamics of the plume, and you can better understand the nature of wildfire. “Believe it or not, this is the most neglected phenomenon on the planet,” Clements says. “It's like chasing tornadoes 30 or 40 years ago.” Only in addition to unraveling the atmospheric dynamics, researchers have to consider how fuel burns and how topography influences fire and any number of other complicating factors. But every little bit of data, and every nerve-wracking drive into a firestorm, will help California navigate its <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/californias-wildfires-are-the-doom-of-our-own-making/">epic trial by wildfire</a>.</p>
<p><em>This story originally appeared on <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-chasers/">wired.com</a>.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595193&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waymo let a reporter ride in a fully driverless car</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595215</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Waymo has been touting fully driverless operation for almost two years.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/GettyImages-1008465252-800x533.jpg" alt="Waymo let a reporter ride in a fully driverless car"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/GettyImages-1008465252.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2667" data-width="4000">Enlarge</a> (credit: Caitlin O'Hara/Bloomberg via Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>It's been almost two years since Waymo first <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/11/fully-driverless-cars-are-here/">announced</a> that it was testing fully autonomous vehicles on public roads. Not long afterwards, the company said it planned to offer a fully driverless service to the public by the end of 2018.</p>
<p>The rollout has been a lot slower than expected. Over the course of 2018, most of Waymo's cars continued to have drivers behind the wheel. When Waymo launched its commercial service in December 2018, every car <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/12/waymos-lame-public-driverless-launch-not-driverless-and-barely-public/">had a driver behind the wheel</a>.</p>
<p>But now Waymo seems to be cautiously moving forward with fully driverless technology. Last month, Waymo told people in its closed testing program that they'd start getting rides in driverless vehicles. Now in a new piece for Techcrunch, Ed Niedermeyer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/01/hailing-a-driverless-ride-in-a-waymo/amp/?__twitter_impression=true">reports</a> on his own experience riding in a fully driverless car.</p>

<p>Niedermeyer reports that the trip involved an unprotected left-hand turn, "busy city streets," and speeds as high as 45 miles per hour. Niedermeyer says that his 10-minute ride from a park to a coffee shop was uneventful—which makes sense given how carefully Waymo must have prepared for it.</p>
<p>Still, this represents yet another baby step in Waymo's journey toward full autonomy. And despite Waymo's slow pace of progress relative to expectations it previously set for itself, the company still appears to be the industry leader. No other company is testing fully driverless rides on the scale or at the speeds Waymo is.</p>
<p>Moving forward, the big question remains how soon Waymo can start offering fully driverless rides to the general public at a non-trivial scale. Waymo has been tight-lipped about the scale of its current driverless testing or how soon the technology might become commercially available.</p>
<p>Alphabet, Waymo's parent company, has spent hundreds of millions of dollars developing the driverless car technology. Last quarter alone Alphabet <a href="https://abc.xyz/investor/static/pdf/2019Q3_alphabet_earnings_release.pdf?cache=d41c776">lost $941 million</a> on its "Other Bets," which includes Waymo and other Google "moonshot" projects. Alphabet has vast financial resources, but eventually the company is going to want a return on its investment.</p>
<p><strong>Correction:</strong> The original headline for this story implied that Niedermeyer was the first reporter to ride in a fully driverless Waymo car, but that's <a href="https://www.forbes.com/video/5860372028001/#3090ba237481">not quite true</a>. Niedermeyer does seem to be the first reporter to test the version of Waymo's technology now being made available to passengers in Early Rider Program.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595215&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White House backing off efficiency standard it’s suing over, report says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594875</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 20:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump administration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594875</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Administration may be changing course, leaving its automaker allies hanging.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1164210626-800x533.jpg" alt="Traffic moves through an interchange along Interstate 580 on July 25, 2019 in Oakland, California. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1164210626.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3648" data-width="5472">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Traffic moves through an interchange along Interstate 580 on July 25, 2019 in Oakland, California.  (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/traffic-moves-through-an-interchange-along-interstate-580-news-photo/1164210626">Justin Sullivan | Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The White House is apparently blinking in a contentious lawsuit over fuel efficiency standards, leaving a number of major automakers that had backed the administration in an awkward position.</p>
<p>The administration is considering abandoning a rule that would freeze fuel efficiency requirements at 2020 levels and instead replacing it with a rule that would require fleetwide improvements of about 1.5% per year, The Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/white-house-backing-off-proposed-fuel-efficiency-freeze-11572556860">reports today</a>. </p>
<p>The move is the latest twist in a long and complicated standoff that began basically as soon as the Trump administration did. The man himself promised <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/with-a-shrinking-epa-trump-delivers-on-his-promise-to-cut-government/2018/09/08/6b058f9e-b143-11e8-a20b-5f4f84429666_story.html">on the campaign trail</a> to gut the Environmental Protection Agency and roll back Obama-era fuel efficiency standards for vehicles. The chain of events so far has led to a faceoff among automakers, as Honda, Ford, Volkswagen, and BMW back more stringent guidelines out of California, and General Motors, Toyota, Fiat Chrysler, Hyundai, Mazda, Nissan, and Kia stand with the White House against the rule.</p>
<h2>The story so far...</h2>
<p>In 2012—the middle of the Obama administration—the EPA adopted a fuel economy standard that would gradually increase the average miles-per-gallon rating for most cars to 54.5mpg by 2025 (about 40mpg under real-world conditions). The agency finalized that standard in late 2016.</p>
<p>When the Trump administration began in January 2017, that rule, like so many other policies from the Obama administration, immediately had a target on its back. In April 2018, the EPA officially said the standard was too high and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/04/epa-says-auto-emissions-standards-are-too-high-questions-californias-waiver/">kicked off the process</a> to replace the rule with something weaker.</p>
<p>California, however, threw a wrench in those plans. Most states can't set their own fuel-efficiency guideline, but California is a special case. For several decades, the smog-prone state has had a <a href="https://ww2.arb.ca.gov/resources/fact-sheets/california-waiver-facts">perennially renewed waiver</a> that permits it to enforce stricter standards than the federal rule. The impact of that waiver goes far beyond the Golden State's borders: the other 49 states can choose to adopt California's stricter standards instead of the federal guideline, and at least 16 states have said they will back California's emissions standard rather than support the federal rollback.</p>
<p>In July of this year, four major automakers—Honda, Ford, Volkswagen, and BMW—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/car-makers-california-agree-to-emissions-rules-trump-admin-is-trying-to-kill/">reached an agreement</a> with California. That voluntary framework aims to improve their overall fleet's average fuel efficiency by 3.7% per year, starting with the 2022 model year.</p>
<h2>And then it got messy</h2>
<p>The president did not exactly <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1164311594081247233">greet this new emissions agreement</a> with open arms.</p>
<p>In September, the automakers all <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/trump-admin-threatens-california-automakers-over-emissions-deal/">confirmed</a> they had been contacted by the Department of Justice, which was taking preliminary steps in an antitrust investigation. The probe sought to determine whether the agreement comprised a cartel that unfairly restricted competition, The Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/justice-department-launches-antitrust-probe-into-four-auto-makers-11567778958">first reported</a>.</p>
<p>Separately from the antitrust probe, the EPA and Department of Transportation in September sent a letter (<a href="//cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/EPA-DOT-Puts-California-on-Notice.pdf">PDF</a>) to put California regulators "on notice."</p>
<p>"This framework agreement appears to be inconsistent with federal law," the agencies said. "We urge you to act immediately to disassociate [the California Air Resource Board] from the commitments made by the four automakers. Those commitments may result in legal consequences given the limits placed in Federal law on California's authority." </p>
<p>California Governor Gavin Newsom immediately accused the administration of trying to bully the state, saying, "We remain undeterred. California stands up to bullies and will keep fighting for stronger clean car protections that protect the health and safety of our children and families."</p>
<h2>That escalated quickly...</h2>
<p>Matters escalated from there. Days later, both the House and Senate Judiciary committees <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/the-fight-over-fuel-economy-rules-is-getting-messy/">sought to probe the probe</a>. California Sen. Kamala Harris, a Democrat who is running for the 2020 presidential nomination, said in her <a href="https://www.harris.senate.gov/news/press-releases/harris-calls-for-investigation-of-justice-departments-inquiry-into-automakers-working-with-california-to-reduce-emissions">letter</a> to the DOJ, "This chain of events raises serious questions about whether federal law enforcement is being used to coerce the four automakers to abandon their efforts to make cleaner, less-polluting vehicles. It also raises questions about whether the machinery of the Justice Department is being used for partisan political purposes, or at the behest of special interest groups that oppose even modest efforts to reduce greenhouse gas emissions."</p>
<p>In response, the Trump administration <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/trumps-new-car-emissions-plan-no-new-standards-yet-kneecap-california/">revoked the waiver</a> that allows California to set its own emissions standard. California, as you might expect, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2019/09/20/california-sues-trump-administration-after-revoking-authority-limit-car-pollution/">sued back</a>.</p>
<p>California was joined by 22 other states, as well as several cities, in its lawsuit (<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/65573354-d1b9-4c02-aa2a-d455db01a27d.pdf">PDF</a>) against the administration, arguing that the administration's action, "be declared unlawful and set aside because it exceeds NHTSA's authority, contravenes Congressional intent, and is arbitrary and capricious."</p>
<p>The suit against California gained allies this week when the other major automakers <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/automakers-side-with-trump-in-legal-fight-with-california">joined the fray</a> on the side of the administration.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1594875&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blizzard president gives vague apology for Hong Kong protest response</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595107</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 19:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blitzchung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hearthstone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595107</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Brack accepts "accountability," promises to "do better" without offering details on how.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/meihk-800x382.jpeg" alt="The words Free HK have been photoshopped onto the face of a video game character."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/meihk.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="764" data-width="1600">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Mei from <em>Overwatch</em> has become a grass roots symbol of the Hong Kong protests in the wake of Blizzard's decision. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HongKong/comments/dfdqf8/if_we_are_gonna_do_it_we_are_gonna_do_it_big_mei/">r/hongkong</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Before launching into the weekend-long celebration of Blizzard games that is Blizzcon, company President J. Allen Brack offered a vague on-stage apology for how the company failed to "bring the world together in a tough <em>Hearthstone</em> esports moment about a month ago."</p>
<p>Though Brack didn't delve into the details of that "tough... moment," it's an obvious reference to the company's initial <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/blizzard-bans-pro-hearthstone-gamer-for-statement-supporting-hong-kong/">one-year ban for pro <em>Hearthstone</em> player Ng "Blitzchung" Wai Chung</a> after he shouted a statement of support for <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2019/11/blunt-unplanned-police-tactics-fire-hk-protests-191101070008742.html">ongoing pro-democracy protests in Hong Kong</a> on a post-match stream. While Blitzchung's ban was later <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-reinstates-hong-kong-protestors-prize-says-china-had-no-influence/">reduced to a six-month suspension</a> and his tournament winnings restored, the damage was done among a vocal segment of Blizzard's fan base.</p>
<p>In the wake of the Blitzchung decision, Blizzard was forced to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-calls-off-public-event-to-promote-switch-overwatch-launch/">cancel a public promotional event</a> and belatedly <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-belatedly-punishes-college-hearthstone-team-for-hong-kong-protest/">punish a college <em>Hearthstone</em> team</a> for a similar on-stream protest. The company faced both <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/blizzard-employees-staged-a-walkout-to-protest-banned-pro-hong-kong-gamer">a brief employee walkout</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/us-legislators-urge-blizzard-to-reverse-hong-kong-protest-player-ban/">admonishment from a bipartisan group of US legislators</a>.</p>
<p>"We moved too quickly in our decision-making, and then, to make matters worse, we were too slow to talk with all of you," Brack said from the Blizzcon stage this morning. Adding that the company "didn't live up to the high standards we set for ourselves" and "failed in our purpose," Brack said, "I am sorry and I accept accountability."</p>
<p>How that accountability will manifest, and what if any changes were in store for the company, was less clear from Brack's statement. The executive only offered a vague promise to "do better going forward." Brack asked the audience to notice "as you walk around this weekend, I hope it's clear how committed we are to everyone's right to express themselves in all kinds of ways in all kinds of places. In fact we saw and heard many of you expressing yourself this morning."</p>
<p>That's an apparent reference to <a href="https://www.fightforthefuture.org/news/2019-10-11-internet-freedom-activists-call-for-umbrella/">long-planned protests</a> that are taking place this morning right outside the Anaheim Convention Center where Blizzcon is being held. There, dozens of protesters, who <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/11/1/20943761/hong-kong-protests-blizzcon-2019-blitzchung">reportedly</a> started setting up last night, are <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/blizzcon-2019-protests/">handing out T-shirts</a> featuring <em>Overwatch</em> character (and growing anti-China symbol) Mei and offering support for Hong Kong. A truck carrying pro-democracy and pro-Hong Kong messages has <a href="https://twitter.com/DreamcastGuy/status/1190289041196863488">also been seen</a> circling the convention center.</p>
<p>Brack's stated commitment to let those protesters "express themselves" rings a little hollow, since they are demonstrating on a public sidewalk outside of Blizzard's control. And though Brack said he was committed to fans expressing themselves "in all kinds of places," the company's stance on protest during Blizzard-sponsored esports events seems unchanged <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/blizzard-reinstates-hong-kong-protestors-prize-says-china-had-no-influence/">from a month ago</a>: "The official broadcast needs to be about the tournament and to be a place where all are welcome. In support of that, we want to keep the official channels focused on the game."</p>
<p>Brack's apology was apparently received well inside the convention center, but the lack of specifics or commitments to change any policies seems unlikely to appease those gathering in protest on site and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/boycottblizzard">on the #BoycottBlizzard hashtag</a>. We'll have more reporting on the goings-on at Blizzcon through the coming days.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1595107&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
