<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:51:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Google: You can trust us with the medical data you didn’t know we already had [Updated]</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600915</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ascension]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600915</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google has 50M people's medical records but won't merge them with other Google data.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-google-eye-800x534.jpg" alt="Photo illustration showing the Google logo reflected on the eye of a young man."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-google-eye.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=leon%20neal&amp;assettype=image&amp;family=editorial&amp;sort=best&amp;groupbyevent=true">Getty Images | Leon Neal</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: The Google/Ascension project is now being investigated by the Office for Civil Rights in the Department of Health and Human Services, the Wall Street Journal reported in an <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/behind-googles-project-nightingale-a-health-data-gold-mine-of-50-million-patients-11573571867">update</a> last night. The office said it "will seek to learn more information about this mass collection of individuals' medical records to ensure that HIPAA protections were fully implemented." Google said it is "happy to cooperate with any questions about the project," and that "We believe Google’s work with Ascension adheres to industry-wide regulations (including HIPAA) regarding patient data, and comes with strict guidance on data privacy, security, and usage."</p>
<p><strong>Original story from November 12, 2019 follows</strong>:</p>
<p>Google now has <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/11/would-you-trust-google-with-your-medical-records-it-might-already-have-them/">access to detailed medical records</a> on tens of millions of Americans, but the company promises it won't mix that medical data with any of the other data Google collects on consumers who use its services.</p>
<p>Google provided this statement yesterday shortly after The Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-s-secret-project-nightingale-gathers-personal-health-data-on-millions-of-americans-11573496790?shareToken=st98ed7303aedb45d281bc0bda02eb90b4">reported</a> that Google is partnering with Ascension, the country's <a href="https://ascension.org/News/Social-Media-Hub/Social-Hub-Articles/Ascension-is-nations-second-largest-health-system-by-hospital-count">second-largest health care system</a>, "on a project to collect and crunch the detailed personal-health information of millions of people across 21 states."</p>
<p>"To be clear: under this arrangement, Ascension's data cannot be used for any other purpose than for providing these services we're offering under the agreement, and patient data cannot and will not be combined with any Google consumer data," Google said in a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/inside-google-cloud/our-partnership-with-ascension">blog post</a>. That would mean Google won't use the medical data to target advertisements at users of Google services.</p>
<p>Google also said that its work with Ascension "adheres to industry-wide regulations (including HIPAA) regarding patient data, and come[s] with strict guidance on data privacy, security, and usage."</p>
<p>"We have a <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/covered-entities/sample-business-associate-agreement-provisions/index.html">Business Associate Agreement</a> (BAA) with Ascension, which governs access to Protected Health Information (PHI) for the purpose of helping providers support patient care," Google said. "This is standard practice in health care, as patient data is frequently managed in electronic systems that nurses and doctors widely use to deliver patient care."</p>
<h2>What can Google see? Pretty much everything</h2>
<p>Patient data shared with Google includes names, birth dates, addresses, family members, allergies, immunizations, radiology scans, hospitalization records, lab tests, medications, medical conditions, "and some billing claims and other clinical records," according to a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/behind-googles-project-nightingale-a-health-data-gold-mine-of-50-million-patients-11573571867">followup article in the Journal</a>. The partnership "covers the personal health records of around 50 million patients of Ascension," the Journal wrote.</p>
<p>The Journal said that "Neither doctors nor patients have been formally notified of the arrangement" and that Google and Ascension began the project "in secret last year."</p>
<p>Google seems to be correct that the partnership doesn't violate HIPAA (the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act). As the Journal noted, that law "generally allows hospitals to share data with business partners without telling patients, as long as the information is used 'only to help the covered entity carry out its health care functions.'" An expert quoted by the Journal noted that Google would be at risk of violating the law "if it uses the health data to perform independent research outside the direct scope of patient care."</p>
<p>Ascension is not paying Google for these services, the Journal wrote, but Google's work with Ascension could lead to profitable ventures. Google is using Ascension's patient data "in part to design new software, underpinned by advanced artificial intelligence and machine learning, that zeroes in on individual patients to suggest changes to their care," the Journal wrote. Google could sell this software to other health care institutions. As part of the project, "Staffers across Alphabet Inc., Google's parent, have access to the patient information, internal documents show," the Journal wrote.</p>
<p>The news about Google's work with Ascension comes as Google is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/google-buys-fitbit-for-2-1-billion/">trying to buy Fitbit</a> for $2.1 billion, in a deal that is pending regulatory approval. Fitbit devices are used for health tracking, among other things, and Google wants to use Fitbit to <a href="https://blog.google/products/wear-os/investing-wear-os-ecosystem">bolster its existing Wear OS platform</a>.</p>
<p>But Google's privacy promise should mean that it won't combine any patient data from Ascension with the data it gathers from Fitbit, Wear OS, Google search, Gmail, Google Docs, Chrome, or any of the other consumer services it provides.</p>
<h2>Google’s services for Ascension</h2>
<p>Google said it is providing its standard G Suite productivity tools to Ascension and that it's doing custom work for the company. This includes moving Ascension's "on-premise data warehouse and analytics environments to their own private and secure Google Cloud environment." The arrangement also includes "provid[ing] tools that Ascension could use to support improvements in clinical quality and patient safety," Google said.</p>
<p>Google said its work with Ascension is similar to what it was already doing with "<a href="https://cloud.google.com/solutions/healthcare/#our-customers">dozens of other health care providers</a>."</p>
<p>"These organizations, like Ascension, use Google to securely manage their patient data, under strict privacy and security standards. They are the stewards of the data, and we provide services on their behalf," Google said.</p>
<p>Ascension also released a <a href="https://www.ascension.org/News/News-Articles/2019/11/11/19/51/Ascension-and-Google-working-together-on-healthcare-transformation">statement</a> on its work with Google yesterday. Ascension said it aims to improve the tools used by both patients and caregivers as well as "explor[e] artificial intelligence/machine learning applications that will have the potential to support improvements in clinical quality and effectiveness."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600915&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian man charged with running money-back-guaranteed criminal marketplace</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601205</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment card fraud]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601205</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Cardplanet offered 150,000 cards and defrauded US holders of &#62;$20 million. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/cardplanet-front-page-800x416.jpg" alt="Screenshot of harmless-looking website."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/cardplanet-front-page.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="520" data-width="1000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The front page of cardplanet.cc as it appeared on August 1, 2015. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150801065209/http://cardplanet.cc/">Internet Archive</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A Russian man made his initial appearance in federal court on Tuesday on prosecutors' allegations he operated websites that resulted in more than $20 million in fraudulent purchases made on US credit cards.</p>
<p>Aleksei Burkov, 29, of Tyumen and St. Petersburg, Russia, arrived at Dulles International Airport on Monday night after he was arrested in Israel in late 2015, federal prosecutors <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edva/pr/russian-national-extradited-running-online-criminal-marketplace">said</a>. His extradition came after appeals to the Israeli Supreme Court and the Israeli High Court of Justice were denied. Tuesday's appearance was before the US District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia.</p>
<p>According to an indictment that was unsealed on Tuesday, Burkov ran a website, called Cardplanet, that sold card data for anywhere from $2.50 to $60 apiece, depending on the card type, country of origin, and the availability of the cardholder's name, address, and other identifying information. In all, Cardplanet offered for sale more than 150,000 compromised payment cards, including "at least tens of thousands" of which had been issued to holders located in the US.</p>
<p>In August 2015—four months before Burkov was arrested at Israel's Ben-Gurion Airport near Tel Aviv—the site's front page provided a simple login box along with support contacts and artwork, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150801065209/http://cardplanet.cc/">according to</a> the Internet Archive. Prosecutors said Burkov advertised Cardplanet as "the only service that would refund the price of invalid card data." The site allegedly offered a fee-based service called Checker, which allowed customers to instantly verify if stolen payment cards were still valid.</p>
<p>Burkov allegedly ran a second site that allowed criminal hackers to advertise the sale of personal identity information, malware, and illegal services. The site operated on an invitation-only basis. To be admitted, candidates had to be vouched for by three existing members and pay a $5,000 entrance fee as insurance. The admittance rules were designed to thwart law enforcement investigators and to ensure that members honored any deals they made on the forum.</p>
<p>Burkov is charged with wire fraud, access device fraud, and conspiracy to commit wire fraud, access device fraud, computer intrusions, identity theft, and money laundering. If convicted on all counts, he faces a maximum of 80 years in prison, although actual sentences are typically less than the maximum. Prosecutors are also seeking the forfeiture of more than $21 million in US currency and any other proceeds resulting from the alleged crimes.</p>
<p>It's not clear when an arraignment is scheduled or if Burkov has been assigned an attorney.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601205&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to spot the SpaceX Starlink satellite train overhead this week</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600495</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Trevor Mahlmann]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tutorial]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ars’ resident rocket photographer shares three tools to track Starlink satellites above.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Q15uod5g-980x654.jpeg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          A Falcon 9 rocket launched into space on Monday morning.                      [credit:
                        Trevor Mahlmann                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>At the start of the week, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/11/watch-live-spacex-to-launch-its-second-batch-of-starlink-satellites/">SpaceX launched its first 60 operational Starlink satellites</a>—the company's 50th consecutive successful launch. And as innovative as this <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/11/watch-live-spacex-to-launch-its-second-batch-of-starlink-satellites/">communication network's entire concept</a> might be, many onlookers are curious for a much simpler reason.</p>
<p>You want to view—maybe even photograph—these things in the pre-dawn, post-sunset, or night sky, right? Well, you've come to the right place.</p>
<p>First, you'll want to be quick. Since separating from the upper stage on November 11 at about 11am Eastern Standard Time (Nov. 11, 16:00 UTC) and with each hour that passes, the satellites have been spreading out by individually raising their orbits to the correct height. And after a while, they will be on their own instead of appearing in this initially clustered formation.</p>
<p>At this point in the week, you still have a few options to try to find SpaceX's satellites overhead in the skies. You're only going to be able to see them ~30 minutes or earlier before sunrise, ~30 minutes or later after sunset, or at night when the sky is dark enough or the Sun is below your local horizon yet still illuminating these devices, since they are at a much higher altitude.</p>
<p>To help find the satellites within these limited windows, luckily, there are a few good resources available online.</p>
<h2>Heavens-Above.com (free)</h2>
<p>Heavens-Above's strength lies in its sky charts. If you're intending to only view Starlink's passes (not photograph it), this is the one site you want to use since Heavens-Above is the easiest. The step-by-step process looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Go to <a href="https://heavens-above.com/login.aspx">Heavens-Above.com</a> and make a free account.</li>
<li><a href="https://heavens-above.com/EditConfig.aspx">Set your location</a> to where you would like to view the Starlink satellites.</li>
<li>From the <a href="https://heavens-above.com/">homepage</a>, there is a "Starlink Launch 2" under the "10-day predictions for satellites of special interest" section midway down the left side of the page. Click on that.</li>
<li>The page "Starlink Launch 2" directs you to a list of the upcoming visible passes listed in a 24 hour time format. (So, remember, 21:46 = 9:46pm your local time.)</li>
</ol>
<p>This particular page also shows you things like "start time," "highest point" and "end point." Here's how Heavens-Above defines those:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Start time</strong>: the time and compass direction (north, south, east, west) that the satellites rise above your local horizon or emerge from the Earth's shadow (no longer illuminated by the Sun).</p>
<p><strong>Highest point</strong>: the time and direction the satellites will be highest above your local horizon.</p>
<p><strong>End point</strong>: the time and direction the satellites will enter into the Earth's shadow or set (like a sunset) below your local horizon.</p></blockquote>
<p>One tip if you're using this method: if you do not see any upcoming passes, try selecting "All" instead of "visible only" and see if there are any within 20-30 minutes of your local sunset. For example, if your local sunset is 4:34pm (16:34) and it shows a pass at 4:55pm (16:55), it will be difficult to photograph the satellites because the sky is still so bright, but you should still be able to see them with your naked eye.</p>
<h2>CalSky.com (free)</h2>
<p>A second freely available tool is a website called <a href="https://calsky.com">CalSky.com</a> (account not required, but recommended). CalSky allows you to predict not only upcoming Starlink passes, but it also tracks things like solar/lunar transits and more interstellar points of interest. For instance, CalSky was a big part of the preparation for Destin Sandlin from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lepQoU4oek4">Smarter Every Day,</a> and I used this tool to capture the solar eclipse and ISS transit back in August of 2017:</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/SolarEclipse8-21-17-348-1024x682.jpg"><img alt='The solar eclipse and ISS transit back in August of 2017.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/SolarEclipse8-21-17-348-1024x682-640x426.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/SolarEclipse8-21-17-348-1024x682.jpg 2x" alt='The solar eclipse and ISS transit back in August of 2017.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/SolarEclipse8-21-17-348-1024x682.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The solar eclipse and ISS transit back in August of 2017.</a> (credit: Trevor Mahlmann)</p></div>
<p>If opting for CalSky to help locate Starlink satellites, the process looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li style="list-style-type: none">
<ol>
<li>Go to <a href="https://calsky.com">CalSky.com.</a></li>
<li>Start by <a href="https://www.calsky.com/cs.cgi?obs=82461594361887&amp;Intro=">setting your location</a> here. (You can view Starlink without making an account, but I would recommend it so you can save a location for later use).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.calsky.com/csephem.cgi?&amp;object=Satellite&amp;number=99201">Here is a link</a> to the viewing opportunities for the "Starlink Trail" after you've set your location.</li>
<li>Select your duration at the top of the page for the amount of time you would like to see future fly-by's. (I usually select '3-6 Days.')</li>
<li>Check the following boxes (you can utilize others like transits/close encounters later on, but for the sole purpose of viewing use these) "Show satellite passes" and "Satellite must be illuminated."</li>
<li>Scroll back up to the top and click "GO" again to refresh.</li>
<li>Scrolling down, you'll see a list of the upcoming passes of the Starlink constellation.</li>
<li>If you are confused by the 24-hour time format, it's just like before (say: "21:36:42" for example simply means 9:36:42pm; 12 + 9 = 21). Unlike Heavens-Above, there is an option here to switch to the 12-hour formatting located on the page where you set your location.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right full"><img alt='A CalSky satellite trajectory map | &lt;i&gt;Credit: Trevor Mahlmann and CalSky&lt;/i&gt;'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-25-16.26.25.png" alt='A CalSky satellite trajectory map | &lt;i&gt;Credit: Trevor Mahlmann and CalSky&lt;/i&gt;' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">A CalSky satellite trajectory map | <i>Credit: Trevor Mahlmann and CalSky</i> </p></div>To know where to look, CalSky offers a little map on the right side of each pass. Reading these isn't tricky with a little guidance. The image to the right shows the satellites will be starting from the southwest direction, peaking in the southeast part of the sky ~45 degrees up or so (halfway to straight up), then going toward the northeast, for instance.</p>
<p>To illustrate this with one other example: <a href="//cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-25-16.26.18.png">this one</a> shows the satellites coming from the northwest, going straight over your head, and toward the southeast. Starlink satellites will always be coming from the west and going east. (So NW-&gt;SE &amp; SW-&gt;NE, never from the east.)</p>
<p>If you're not familiar with which way is north/south/east/west, grab a compass app on your phone's App Store/Google Play Store to assist. Otherwise, the details to note in these maps are:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Appears (start point):</strong> where the blue line starts (SW in example two),</p>
<p><b>Culmination (highest point):</b> where the point of the blue arrow is (straight over your head),</p>
<p><strong>Disappears (end point):</strong> where the blue line ends (NE) They are not always directly overhead; some may reach their peak height closer to the horizon, in one area of the sky (like #10, peaking in the SSE sky ~45° up).</p></blockquote>
<h2>FlightClub.io (paid)</h2>
<p>If you are seeking to photograph the trail of satellites or get a bit more advanced with your viewing, the only paid tool I'd recommend is called <a href="https://www.flightclub.io">FlightClub.io</a>. Created by Declan Murphy, this app can be utilized in combination with <a href="https://calsky.com">CalSky</a> to plan out (with a 3D viewer) your photography to a T. It allows you to visualize the Starlink fly-bys in real time on your phone while in the field.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-25-12.39.04-1024x546-980x523.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          A Starlink path as previewed in FlightClub.io.                      [credit:
                        Trevor Mahlmann / FlightClub.io                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>FlightClub is primarily for rocket launch visualizations, simulations, and photography mission planning, but it's useful for planning to view or photograph the Starlink cluster of satellites via what are called TLEs (two-line orbital elements). This tool allows you to enter GPS coordinates and camera/lens information, then pan around to experiment with what millimeter focal length would be the best from your location.</p>
<p>For example, below is a visualization of what a photo would look like of a previous Starlink pass with a full-frame camera and an 11mm lens from Chicago, Illinois (looking SSE).</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-25-15.47.53-1024x679-980x650.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          What a previous Starlink pass would've looked like using a full frame camera and an 11mm lens from Chicago, Illinois (looking SSE).                      [credit:
                        Trevor Mahlmann / FlightClub.io                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>As noted before, this is a paid option, but if you're serious about photographing Starlink or rocket launches in the future, I'd recommend it. You can also <a href="https://www.patreon.com/join/flightclub">become a $10 / Geostationary Transfer Orbit level Patron</a> of Declan Murphy's, and this tier gets you access to the Photog Tools (which produced the 3D Viewer screenshots above).</p>
<p>However you choose to sign up for access, here are the basic steps to utilize Flight Club:</p>
<ol>
<li style="list-style-type: none">
<ol>
<li>Go to <a href="https://www.flightclub.io">FlightClub.io</a> homepage (if the page doesn't automatically redirect you), and in the upper right, click your profile photo.</li>
<li>Find the "Favorite Locations" tab and add a few locations where you might be photographing/viewing at (i.e. home, a nearby dark sky park, etc). Note that it's probably easiest to open Google Maps and find decimal GPS coordinates there by searching for your city and clicking on the map where you want to watch/photograph from.</li>
<li>Click "Visualize Trajectories," then the hamburger menu in the upper left. Here, you will find all the customization options. The ones we will be using today are: <strong>photo equipment, location, </strong>and<strong> Import TLEs.</strong></li>
<li>Set your photo equipment to the camera and lens you plan to use, then click "Set." The field-of-view will snap to that view.</li>
<li>Navigate to "Set your planned location," and in the "Favorite Locations" dropdown, select the one you would like to use that you added earlier. Use an elevation of 25 meters, then click "Set" again. FlightClub will now zoom to your planned location. (Wait a few seconds if it sets you below ground, by the way, as FlightClub will auto snap you up to ground level at those GPS coordinates within a few seconds.)</li>
<li>Now it's time for the TLEs (two-line orbital element sets). <a href="https://www.calsky.com/observer//tle.cgi?satid=19894A&amp;lang=en">Navigate here on CalSky</a> to get the details, then paste the TLE info you've just copied into the "Import TLEs" section of FlightClub. Click "Import" to finalize it. It should look roughly like the screenshot to the right.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>From here, it's time to re-use the CalSky or Heavens-Above portion of the tutorial and determine a good pass for your location.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-27-21.17.01-740x1024.png"><img alt='Importing TLE info from CalSky into FlightClub.io'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-27-21.17.01-740x1024-300x415.png" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-27-21.17.01-740x1024-640x886.png 2x" alt='Importing TLE info from CalSky into FlightClub.io' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot-2019-05-27-21.17.01-740x1024.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Importing TLE info from CalSky into FlightClub.io</a> (credit: Trevor Mahlmann / FlightClub.io)</p></div>To do this, start by using the time scrubber in the lower left of FlightClub's 3D viewer to navigate to your time in UTC and begin planning your photo or viewing session in 3D. Since your camera is 25 meters in the air, you can pan around and use landmarks on the ground to orient yourself, better understand the CalSky map, and determine where the pass will be in the sky in order to point your eyes and the camera.</p>
<p>For one final tip, I'd recommend pulling up <a href="https://celestrak.com/NORAD/elements/starlink.txt">the TLE webpage</a> from before in your mobile Web browser and again copying the entire webpage of data. That way, once you're at your viewing location, you can pull up <a href="https://www.flightclub.io">FlightClub.io</a> and follow the same steps as above if needed. You can click the little "⏰" icon above the time scrubber (whether in mobile or desktop) to jump to the current time and play in real-time on your phone or tablet. Use the same location as before, but in the field for visual (non photographic) aid, select "full frame" for the camera and type "24" in the "focal length (mm)" box this time. When used on your phone or tablet device, these settings aid you in finding the satellites in the sky in real time.</p>
<p>Hopefully, these aids can help any fellow aspiring space photographers locate their satellite specimens this week for practice. After all, this latest launch will be far from the only time you can attempt some Starlink sighting—SpaceX has said it wants to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/09/spacex-says-itll-deploy-satellite-broadband-across-us-faster-than-expected/">deploy a minimum of <em>800 satellites</em> before offering commercial service in 2020 or 2021.</a> And the only thing a few errant photographs of the sky will temporarily cost you is SD card space.</p>
<p><em>An earlier version of this guide appeared on <a href="https://www.tmahlmann.com/2019/05/how-to-watch-or-photograph-starlink/">TMahlmann.com</a>. Good luck with viewing and photographing this week, and feel free to <a href="https://twitter.com/TrevorMahlmann">hit Trevor up on Twitter</a> or in the comments if you still have questions.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600495&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pokémon Sword and Shield review: A big adventure with a small Pokédex</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600607</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon shield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon sword]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A truly console-scale <em>Pokémon</em> RPG, marred by a lack of some legacy Pokémon.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/2019110120532100-B8FAEF4816CAC2B76D11869B05CA7601-980x551.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Making new friends in <em>Pokemon Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em>.                      [credit:
                        Andrew Cunningham                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Finally: a true <em>Pokémon</em> game on a flagship Nintendo console.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2018/11/how-i-neatly-fit-pokemon-lets-go-into-my-grown-up-gaming-life/">Last year’s <em>Pokémon Let’s Go</em> games</a> were technically the Switch’s first Pokémon RPGs, but those remakes of the original <em>Red</em> and <em>Blue</em> were greatly simplified and softened up to cater to newer and younger players who got their start with <em>Pokémon Go</em>. <em>Pokémon Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em>, on the other hand,<em> </em>are "real" mainline <em>Pokémon</em> games, serving as direct sequels to 2016’s <em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em> and continuing the franchise that began with <em>Red</em> and <em>Blue</em> in 1998 (1996 for Japanese players).</p>
<p>That means<em> Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> feature the same basic skeleton that has grown into a <em>Pokémon</em> tradition over the past 20+ years. You pick a starter Pokémon and then travel around the region, catching more monsters and earning eight badges so you can earn the right to challenge the region’s Champion and become the very best, like no one ever was. Along the way, you encounter and vanquish a team of bumbling low-level criminals, repeatedly battle with a rival who helps you hone your skills, and solve a regional mystery that ends with you capturing one or more ancient legendary creatures.</p>

<p>Because <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> throw you into the deep end pretty quickly, they’re not great introductions for newbies; try the <em>Let’s Go</em> games for that, or even <em>Pokémon Go</em>. But for series fans, these are the sequels you've been waiting for... with one substantial caveat.</p>
<h2><em>Pokémon</em> without all the Pokémon</h2>
<p>Any discussion of what <em>has</em> changed in <em>Sword </em>and <em>Shield</em> needs to start with the games’ most controversial subtraction: for the first time in the series’ history, a mainline <em>Pokémon</em> game won’t actually include all the Pokémon.</p>
<p>Every <em>Pokémon </em>game has a “regional” Pokédex that blends the region’s new creatures with a cross-section of monsters from older games. But after you beat the main quest, previous titles opened up a “national” Pokédex, letting you collect all of the Pokémon from every title and (eventually) letting you import Pokémon from previous generations. In <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em>, a mix of 400-odd monsters, old and new, are the only ones available for the entire game—meaning hundreds more are not available at all. Mega Evolutions are gone, as are most of the regional Pokémon forms from <em>Sun </em>and <em>Moon</em>. The <em>Pokémon Home</em> app will still recognize all existing Pokémon when it comes out next year, but you can’t pull them into <em>Sword </em>or <em>Shield</em>, and Game Freak <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/right-as-pokemon-sword-shield-are-about-to-arrive-game-freak-re-iterates-that-there-are-no-plans-to-add-a-full-pokedex-572064.phtml">isn’t planning to add them in later</a>.</p>
<p>The bottleneck is, supposedly, a lack of development time and resources. And before you casually dismiss that rationale, the monsters that <em>are</em> in <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield </em>are clearly more than just refurbished versions of the models used in the 3DS games. Every Pokémon that makes the jump to the Switch needed to be retextured and tweaked and made usable in the mega-sized Dynamax mode (more on that in a moment). It’s clearly a non-trivial amount of work, especially when multiplied across a sprawling history of 800-plus monsters.</p>
<p>When you’re playing the single-player campaign, the amount and variety of Pokémon available actually feels pretty good. For longtime players and monster collectors, though, it’s hard not to feel a bit resentful. Suddenly, a series that has focused on catching ‘em all for more than two decades has decided that hundreds of Pokémon are not actually essential to the <em>Pokémon</em> experience after all. I've been importing certain individual Pokémon from game to game since 2003, and I always appreciated that Game Freak encouraged this kind of sentimental attachment. Not anymore.</p>
<p>With half of all existing Pokémon gone, the “long tail” of <em>Sword </em>and <em>Shield</em>—the stuff that players have always done after the main single-player story has been cleared—has been dramatically reduced in size and scope relative to previous games. The reduced Pokédex also seriously limits the variety of possible monster teams and strategies that make the competitive circuit interesting.</p>
<p>Maybe <em>Pokémon Home</em> will include a battling component, or maybe a re-release of <em>Sword </em>and <em>Shield </em>a couple of years from now will fill in the rest of the monster roster. But despite <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em>'s many improvements, I'd imagine many competitive players will continue to use <em>Sun </em>and <em>Moon</em> just for the larger roster.</p>
<h2>A console-size Pokémon</h2>
<p>Now let’s focus on the good stuff, because there is a lot of it, national 'dex controversy aside.</p>
<p>It starts with some console-scale world-building. In previous <em>Pokémon</em> games, the environments have always looked more or less like our own, And while we’re told that Pokémon vary widely in size and weight, small portable screens have always (by necessity) sort of flattened the monsters out so that a tiny Caterpie looks not all that different from a 21-foot-long Gyarados. Thanks to the extra power of the Switch, <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield </em>can finally show us a world that’s big enough to show us what a Pokémon-centric society would really look like—<em>Sun </em>and <em>Moon</em> attempted this, but they were held back by the aging hardware of the 3DS.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/grO7u1R866o?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The best example of this is the game’s “Wild Area,” a wide-open field between cities with a free-range camera where dozens of Pokémon of different shapes and sizes roam free. Not only does this make an unprecedentedly large and varied roster of Pokémon available from very near the start of the game, but if you’re not careful you can run into high-leveled monsters that will absolutely wipe your fledgling team out if you’re not ready to deal with them.</p>
<p>The game’s cities and battles feel bigger, too; each city is built around a gigantic stadium where battles can happen in front of thousands of spectators. And these cities all have distinct and memorable designs that usually complement the Pokémon type used in the stadium. Sadly, though, there’s not much reason to come back to most of these cities once you clear the stadium challenge and break into everyone’s homes to look for items.</p>
<p>Like most Switch games, <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> deploy some graphical trickery to keep things running smoothly—shadows lose resolution quickly as you move away from objects, for instance, and far-off objects can often pop into existence (the way that Pokémon actually <em>spring up</em> as they pop in makes this graphical artifact more playful and intentional-looking). These aren't the best-looking games on the Switch, or even the best-looking RPGs (<em>Dragon Quest XI</em> running on the Switch manages better draw distance and more detailed environments, for instance, though the resolution is often visibly lower). Still, the monster designs, environments, and big, colorful character models all look good. This is definitely the look that <em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em> were going for but executed more successfully on new hardware.</p>
<p>That said, this does look and feel a bit like a scaled-up portable game in a lot of ways. Text size and the information density of the game’s UI all seem tuned for play on the handheld screen rather than a TV screen. The game seems marginally better-optimized for handheld mode, too—the only times I noticed small framerate dips were exclusively in docked mode. On the other hand, the game retains all of the handy and quick-to-access local multiplayer features from the previous 3DS versions.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>I wish I was big</h2>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/2019111201064600-B8FAEF4816CAC2B76D11869B05CA7601-980x551.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Dynamax Pokémon battles are <em>Sword and Shield</em>'s big gameplay gimmick.                      [credit:
                        Andrew Cunningham                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>One thing that didn’t make the jump from <em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em> to <em>Sword </em>and <em>Shield</em> are the powered up “Z-moves” bestowed by special held items. In their place is something called a Dynamax battle, where Pokémon grow to Godzilla-esque proportions and get stat boosts and more powerful moves for three turns. Some Pokémon get special Dynamax forms, others are just super-sized versions of their regular selves.</p>
<p>In the main game’s story mode, Dynamax battles happen mostly during stadium battles. But there are also certain in-game “dens” dotting the Wild Area where Dynamax Pokémon wait to do battle with you and three other trainers (either other human players or computer-controlled NPCs).</p>
<p>The pacing of Dynamax battles is, frankly, a bit plodding, especially when you’re fighting more powerful monsters who generate protective shields that have to be broken down before you can actually damage them. But it <em>is</em> fun to make one of your Pokémon hulk out to get you out of a tight spot, and battles with wild Dynamax Pokémon can feel tense when they’re close. As <em>Pokémon</em> gameplay gimmicks go, I’d say they're better than Z-Moves but not as fun as <em>X</em> and <em>Y</em>'s Mega Evolved Pokémon.</p>
<h2>Less grinding is good</h2>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/11/review-pokemon-sun-and-moon-are-solid-entries-aimed-at-newbies/">When I reviewed <em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em></a>, I called them good <em>Pokémon </em>games for first-time players because they tried to minimize some of the more frustrating, grind-y aspects of older <em>Pokémon</em> games. <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> aren't quite as welcoming as the 3DS games, but they continue the trend in reducing grinding and repetitive back-and-forth traveling between locations.</p>
<p>The biggest quality-of-life change is probably the ability to access your PC box from the field without going to a Pokémon Center. That feature, first introduced in <em>Let’s Go, </em>makes it a whole lot easier and more convenient to keep more than six Pokémon in your regular rotation. Ditto for fast traveling, which is now accomplished directly from the Town Map without the need for a separate Pokémon or excessive, time-consuming animations.</p>
<p>All Pokémon in your party now earn some experience points for every battle, whether they participate or not. Monsters that do participate in the battle get <em>more </em>experience points, though, encouraging you to keep your entire team in the rotation. Lower-leveled Pokémon continue to earn more experience than higher-leveled Pokémon to help new members of your team catch up to everyone else, too.</p>
<p>For competitive players and collectors, the coolest addition is a class of “mints” you can give to Pokémon to change their natures. This lets you easily customize which of a Pokémon's five basic stats will get a 10% boost and which will get a 10% reduction in exchange. In the past it has been easy to breed Pokémon to get the specific nature you want, but these items let you avoid the gamble of getting an unhelpful nature when catching a rarer Pokémon.</p>
<p>As in <em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em>, <a href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/HM">move-teaching HMs</a> are still a thing of the past, but <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> also cut back on the number of <a href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/TM">unlimited-move-bestowing TMs</a>. In their places are TRs (technical records), earned by battling Dynamax Pokémon, which can only be used once. While you can grind for multiple copies of each TR if you want, it’s no longer quite as easy to teach powerful moves like Surf or Earthquake to every Pokémon on your team.</p>
<h2>A note on multiplayer</h2>
<p>Nintendo’s <em>Pokémon</em> servers weren’t online during the review period, so I haven’t been able to experiment at all with the game’s online features (though I can tell you that they’ll require a Switch Online subscription). But I have been able to experiment a little with the local multiplayer features.</p>
<p>The local multiplayer options you’d expect in a <em>Pokémon</em> game are obviously here—if all you want is a quick battle or trade, it’s easy to set one up. The Wild Area is where the coolest stuff is, though. All players within range will appear in real-ish time in the Wild Area, and when you battle or catch a Pokémon everyone will get a status update notification to let them know what you’re up to. If one player sets up a Pokémon camp, other players can visit your tent and play with members of your team. There’s also a curry cooking minigame that can restore your monsters’ HP and make them more friendly toward you (you can also camp solo or with NPCs throughout the game, if no one else is around).</p>
<h2>Conclusions</h2>
<p>The short version of this review is that <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield</em> are fun, good-looking <em>Pokémon</em> games with a solid story mode and some welcome changes to the game’s mechanics. That probably won't be enough for longtime fans who are upset about the limited roster, though. The missing piece of this is really <em>Pokémon Home</em>, the upcoming cloud storage system for Pokemon from every franchise entry.  It could either render the national 'dex question moot <em>or</em> serve as a depressing mausoleum for unusable Pokémon that can be looked at but not touched.</p>
<p>I do think <em>Sword</em> and <em>Shield </em>are good entries for anyone who got into <em>Pokémon</em> through <em>Go </em>and <em>Let’s Go</em> and is looking for something a bit more difficult and larger in scale. Seasoned players can still enjoy the new monsters and appreciate the game’s story mode while it lasts (I cleared the main story in around 35 hours). It’s just too bad that, for longtime players, what’s missing is probably going to overshadow everything that’s here.</p>
<h3>The good</h3>
<ul>
<li>A good-looking game that finally brings a “real” <em>Pokémon</em> experience to your TV screen.</li>
<li>Tweaked mechanics reduce grinding and make routine tasks more pleasant.</li>
<li>The "Wild Area" gives you access to a varied team right off the bat.</li>
<li>Local multiplayer features are mostly fun.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>The pacing of Dynamax battles can plod a bit.</li>
<li>Probably not great entries for newbies—the Wild Area, in particular, seems like it would be a bit bewildering for a first-time player.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The ugly</h3>
<ul>
<li>The first mainline <em>Pokémon</em> game to shrink the list of usable monsters rather than expanding it.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Verdict</strong>: First-time players should try <em>Let's Go</em> instead, but even without the full Pokédex this is a worthwhile entry for monster-catching veterans.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600607&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>This system from Garmin can land a private plane when your pilot can’t</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601331</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cirrus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garmin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garmin avionics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Piper]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601331</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Unfortunately it’s only available for two GA aircraft, and neither is exactly cheap.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/16A9346r3-980x553.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Garmin Avionics has developed an Autoland system to get a General Aviation plane back on the ground if its pilot becomes incapacitated.                      [credit:
                        Garmin/Piper                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>If you've been around long enough, you've probably heard stories of passengers who successfully landed small planes after their pilots fell ill or died. It happened in Australia just a few months ago (Aug. 31) when a student on his first flight lesson in Perth was forced to land a Cessna 150 after his instructor lost consciousness.</p>
<p>The student had never landed anything previously, but it worked. However, it usually doesn't, and the consequences are disastrous. That's why electronics/avionics maker Garmin is launching Autoland, an emergency autopilot system that can autonomously land a private aircraft and bring it to a stop on the runway.</p>
<h2>Push the red button</h2>
<p>Commercial airliners have long had auto-landing systems as well as the ability to fall back on co-pilots if the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated. Until recently, single-pilot certified general aviation (GA) airplanes haven't had autonomous landing capability. To be clear, they still don't. Garmin's Autoland system is not yet FAA certified, though the company expects certification "soon."</p>
<p>Autoland is a new feature of Garmin's G3000 integrated flight deck, which already comes with 3-axis autopilot, auto-throttles, and automatic stability and descent capabilities. It will debut on two single-engine airplanes: Piper's M600 SLS turboprop and Cirrus Aircraft's Vision Jet. Priced at $2.9 million and $2.3 million, respectively, they admittedly stretch the definition of general aviation aircraft, but each is largely owner-flown.</p>
<p>If you're aboard one, and the owner-pilot succumbs to something, here's what happens:</p>
<p>Upon recognizing the pilot is in distress, a passenger can press the Autoland button. In the Cirrus it's a big red button on the ceiling between the pilot's seats and at top-center on the M600 instrument panel. The G3000 also monitors pilot activity/inactivity and cabin pressure and can automatically engage Autoland or Emergency Descent Mode if no activity is detected. (Recall the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1999_South_Dakota_Learjet_crash">Payne Stewart hypoxia-induced Lear 35 crash</a>.)</p>
<p>The system audibly announces, "Emergency Autoland Activating." The airplane then declares an emergency with air traffic control via automated voice radio messages and sets the transponder to squawk 7700 (mayday signal).</p>
<p>Simultaneously, Autoland analyzes terrain, weather, and nearby airports to determine the optimal airport for landing given the specific aircraft's available fuel and performance characteristics, winds, runway length, and a host of other factors. As the airplane descends, Autoland controls speed, altitude and flight path and manages throttles, flaps, cabin pressurization, and more.</p>
<p>Air traffic controllers are informed of the system's landing destination choice and clear traffic as they would with a human-flown emergency. On final approach, Autoland lowers the gear, flares the airplane, and brings it to a stop with automatic braking. Audible instructions for exiting the airplane then play.</p>
<p>Throughout the evolution, passengers can be in voice contact with ATC, getting reassurance. And if the pilot comes to, they can override Autoland, turning everything off with another press of that button.</p>
<h2>Easy to imagine, hard to do</h2>
<p>"A lot of this was us trying to figure out what would make sense in this class of aircraft," says Garmin's aviation systems team leader, Ben Patel.</p>
<p>Work on the system accelerated four years ago as technology and the business case came together. Garmin's own development of its autopilot, auto-throttles, and other automated systems formed the building blocks for Autoland.</p>
<p>"These systems that we're using to enable it are things that have been in the field for years," Autoland Program Manager Bailey Scheel adds.</p>
<p>Autoland not only employs a sophisticated autopilot, it leverages special routing and destination-selection algorithms. The system is aware of all airports bypassed on a flight as well as those immediately proximate. It actually scores airports for optimal safe landing based on dynamic physical, environmental, and weighted OEM performance parameters.</p>
<p>Senior Software Engineer Eric Tran adds that Autoland routing borrows from Garmin's automotive autonomy side. "It can choose the best, safest airport for autonomous landing faster than any human pilot."</p>
<p>Garmin says that about 70% of airports in the US are suitable Autoland destinations. They simply need a GPS approach with vertical guidance.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Autoland requires an airplane with the latest version of the G3000 flight deck, with auto-throttles, auto-braking, radar altimeter, and more. The population of GA aircraft eligible is very small.</p>
<p>As of this writing, Piper has built about 10 Autoland-enabled M600 SLS. Cirrus has two Autoland-equipped Vision Jets. Fitting the system to your private piston-single or twin could be possible with considerable work but also prohibitively expensive. (Garmin declines to price Autoland.)</p>
<p>That's why Autoland will roll out exclusively on new aircraft for some time to come. Eventually Garmin will broaden the market. In the process, lives will be saved.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601331&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google fires staffer, suspends two others, amid rising workplace tensions</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601115</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Workplace political battles are steadily eroding Google’s open culture.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_0221-copy-800x600.jpg" alt="Exterior of Google office building."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_0221-copy.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3024" data-width="4032">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Google's main headquarters. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://arstechnica.com/author/cyrus-farivar/">Cyrus Farivar</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Google has fired a staffer who allegedly leaked the names of Google employees and their personal details to the news media, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-12/one-google-staffer-fired-two-others-put-on-leave-amid-tensions">Ryan Gallagher reports</a> in a scoop for Bloomberg News. Two other Googlers have been put on leave for violating company policies, Google told Gallagher.</p>
<p>A Google spokeswoman told Gallagher that one of the employees "had searched for and shared confidential documents outside the scope of their job, while the other tracked the individual calendars of staff working in the community platforms, human resources, and communications teams." The tracking made affected staff uncomfortable, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Google's move represents the latest sign of growing tensions between labor and management at Google. Until recently, Google was known for having one of Silicon Valley's most open workplace cultures. Employees could access information about projects they weren't working on. Rank-and-file employees could ask tough questions of senior management at weekly "TGIF" meetings that were broadcast throughout the company.</p>

<p>But that open culture has begun to break down as the polarization of the broader American political culture has seeped into Google's workplace. Two years ago, for example, Google engineer James Damore <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/08/google-fires-engineer-who-crossed-the-line-with-diversity-memo/">wrote a controversial memo</a> suggesting that biological differences could help explain the gender gap among engineers at Google. The memo leaked, and Damore was fired.</p>
<p>Last year, a Googler <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/09/google-cofounder-called-trumps-election-deeply-offensive-in-leaked-video/">leaked a video</a> of a TGIF held shortly after the 2016 election, in which senior Google executives expressed dismay about the election of Donald Trump. Not long after that, thousands of employees around the world <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/11/google-offices-from-mountain-view-to-atlanta-protest-sexual-misconduct/">walked out of their offices</a> to protest Google's handling of sexual harassment issues. Google also faced employee pressure to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/11/google-employees-demand-that-google-stop-work-on-censored-chinese-search/">cancel plans</a> for a censored Chinese search engine and to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/06/google-reportedly-wont-renew-controversial-drone-imaging-program/">stop working</a> on a military contract relating to drones.</p>

<p>Google management has responded by restricting employee access to sensitive documents. And in August, Google <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/08/23/google-bans-political-discussion-on-internal-mailing-lists.html">announced new rules</a> restricting political discussions on internal mailing lists.</p>
<p>On internal discussion forums, some employees expressed dismay at the evolution of Google's corporate culture.</p>
<p>“As a company we’ve prided ourselves on transparency and information-sharing,” wrote an employee in a post leaked to Bloomberg. "One of the big benefits of Google is that you can see what everyone else is working on, and how it all fits together. But I guess we’ve abandoned that now. And that both disappoints and terrifies me.”</p>
<p>But Google's management may not have had a good alternative. Some of the rancor inside Google pits labor against management. But other controversies have pitted workers against one another over hot-button issues like race, gender, and partisan politics. Googlers were not only attacking each other on internal forums, some were leaking the details of these disputes publicly, often embarrassing Google in the process.</p>
<p>And so Google is increasingly becoming like a normal company—one where most employees are given information only on a need-to-know basis, and employees are discouraged from discussing politics on the job.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601115&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple introduces a redesigned, thicker MacBook Pro</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601061</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pro Display XDR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601061</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apple also announced that the Mac Pro and Pro Display XDR are coming in December.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/MacBook_Pro_16_SCREEN_conv-2-980x704.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The 16-inch MacBook Pro with reduced bezels.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.apple.com/">Apple</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Today, Apple begins taking orders <a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/1305166/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmacbook-pro%2F&amp;subid1=ArsMacBook16" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on a new version</a> of its largest MacBook Pro laptop. While its basic design is similar to that of the Touch Bar models the company has made since 2016, it is slightly larger and heavier, the screen is bigger thanks to reduced bezels, and it has new keyboard and speaker designs. The Pro has faster graphics and new upgrade options, such as a 64GB RAM configuration and larger default SSD sizes.</p>
<p>This 16-inch MacBook Pro (the inches here refer to diagonal screen size) replaces the 15-inch in Apple's lineup. Its display has a pixel density of 226 ppi at 3,072 x 1,920 resolution—that's slightly higher than the 2,880 x 1,800 resolution and 220 ppi of the 15-inch MacBook Pro. Apple says that pro video editors will now be able to adjust the refresh rate of the display to match content they're working with. Little else has changed about the screen. It's worth noting, by the way, that the prior model's screen actually measured 15.4 inches, not 15; this new model measures 16 inches.</p>
<p>Dimensions are 0.64 x 14.09 x 9.68 inches—up marginally across the board from its predecessor's 0.61 by 13.75 by 9.48 inches. It weighs 4.3 pounds, compared to 4.02 for the prior model. Chances are it will fit in most existing cases intended for the 15-inch model.</p>
<h2>A big keyboard change</h2>
<p>The new keyboard will likely get more attention than any other change. The butterfly keyboard mechanisms found in recent Mac laptops have been divisive, with many users liking the typing experience but a vocal contingent—and I don't think is an exaggeration, given reader comments here at Ars—<em>despising</em> it. More critically, the keyboard has been prone to failure, with many users having to take advantage of Apple's free repair program to replace their keyboards multiple times. To make matters worse, replacing a single key could require replacing a big chunk of the device.</p>
<p>Several successive iterations have gradually improved the keyboard, but Apple has made the biggest change yet with the 16-inch MacBook Pro.</p>
<p>Apple calls it the Magic Keyboard (whatever that means) and says it drew inspiration from the keyboard that comes with the iMac Pro.</p>
<p>The new keyboard now has a physical Escape key—something developers in particular have been asking for ever since it was replaced with the Touch Bar in 2016. The Touch Bar is still here, but it's slightly smaller to make room for that key and a distinct Touch ID scanner similar to what we saw on the latest <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/apple-updates-entry-level-macbook-air-and-pro-discontinues-macbook/">MacBook Air</a>.</p>
<p>There's also a slightly bigger gap between the physical number keys and the Touch Bar to reduce accidental taps on the bar, and the arrow keys have been redesigned. The keys themselves are raised a little higher above the chassis than in the prior model, and they have a new scissor mechanism and 1mm key travel. Additionally, the keycap now locks at the top of travel, making the keys a little more stable when typing.</p>
<p>We typed on it briefly yesterday and came away with the impression that it felt like a middle ground between the feel of the chiclet keyboard in the 2015 MacBook Pro and the butterfly keyboards in the more recent models.</p>
<p>Time will tell regarding reliability, but Apple says that it expects the Magic Keyboard to be much more reliable. The company also says that this keyboard is not part of its repair program and that it is easier to service individual keys without unnecessarily replacing additional hardware.</p>
<h2>Internals</h2>
<p>As is customary with any hardware refresh, the 16-inch MacBook Pro is faster. Once again, configuration options afford either 6-core or 8-core, Core i7 or Core i9, ninth-generation Intel CPUs. The very top CPU configuration tops out at 5GHz in Turbo Boost—a modest bump over the 4.8Ghz in the prior model, thanks to Intel's Thermal Velocity Boost.</p>
<h3>Graphics</h3>
<p>That's nice but not much to speak of. Meanwhile, the GPU and thermal management system have seen the biggest changes. Apple says the new MacBook Pro can be configured with AMD's new Radeon Pro M5500, made in a 7nm process and paired with 4GB or 8GB of GDDR6 video memory. On the lower end, it comes configured with a Radeon Pro M5300.</p>
<p>The company claims that the M5500 with 4GB will deliver up to 2.1 times faster video performance than the Radeon Pro 560X, and the M5500 with 8GB can achieve up to 80% faster performance than the Radeon Pro Vega 20—both of which were configuration options in the 15-inch MacBook Pro this past year.</p>
<p>The biggest gains will happen for applications that lean on increased video memory capacity, and the GDDR6 video memory has a bandwidth of 189GB/s. Apple is, of course, still including integrated Intel graphics (Intel UHD Graphics 630) and employing automatic graphics switching to maximize battery life.</p>
<h3>Thermal management</h3>
<p>As we've reviewed top-spec MacBook Pros over the past year, we've run into some <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/07/re-testing-the-macbook-pro-apples-firmware-update-led-to-a-big-improvement/">thermal throttling for sustained loads</a> on the top specs, so testing this model will be interesting; Apple says it has significantly overhauled its thermal architecture. Improved fan design affords a 28% improvement in airflow, Apple claims. Between that and a heatsink with 35% more surface area, the new MacBook Pro can manage up to 12 watts of power more than we saw before. Fan noise should be comparable to that of the 15-inch model.</p>
<h3>Other specs and configuration options</h3>
<p>The memory is faster at 2666Mhz (compared to 2400Mhz) and can now be configured up to 64GB. (The company had only recently added a 32GB configuration option; the previous cap was 16GB.) The Pro can now be configured with an 8TB SSD.</p>
<p>Apple has also made significant changes to the speaker system and the microphones. It has a Dolby Atmos-ready, six-speaker system with force-canceling woofers, plus a new 3-microphone system that is intended to compete more directly with entry-level podcast microphones.</p>
<p>In terms of battery life, Apple has upped the battery capacity from 83.6Wh to 100, and it claims 11 hours of wireless Web browsing or Apple TV video playback (one hour more than the 15-inch) and up to 30 days of standby time. Since the 16-inch MacBook Pro draws more power, it now comes with a 96W power adapter.</p>
<p>The ports are unchanged: it has a headphone jack and four Thunderbolt ports. The touchpad, camera, and wireless connectivity options are also unchanged.</p>
<p>Price points for the two base configurations remain the same as before. The $2399 base configuration comes with a 512GB SSD, whereas the $2799 config offers 1TB—double what was previously offered at the same price points in both cases. The laptop is available for order today and will ship to buyers this week.</p>
<p>Ars is testing a unit now and will publish a review in a few days.</p>
<h2>Mac Pro and Pro Display XDR: Now coming in December</h2>
<p>Apple has been saying since its June developers' conference that it would ship the overhauled Mac Pro and the new Pro Display XDR this fall, but it has just announced a new window for those launches: December. The company didn't explain the delay, but it did say that the new MacBook Pro will be able to drive up to two Pro Display XDR monitors.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601061&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How a turf war and a botched contract landed 2 pentesters in Iowa jail</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601265</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penetration testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pentest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white hat]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Despite no evidence of criminal intent, Coalfire employees face charges of criminal trespass.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mug-shots-800x451.jpg" alt="Mug shots of Gary De Mercurio, left, and Justin Wynn."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mug-shots.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="507" data-width="900">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Mug shots of Gary De Mercurio, left, and Justin Wynn. (credit: Dallas County Jail)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In the early hours of September 11, a dispatcher with the sheriff’s department in Dallas County, Iowa, spotted something alarming on a surveillance camera in the county courthouse. Two men who had tripped an alarm after popping open a locked door were wandering through courtrooms on the third floor, she reported over the radio as deputies raced to the scene. The intruders wore backpacks and were crouching down next to judges’ benches. When the first deputy pulled into the parking lot, the men moved to an open area outside the court rooms and concealed themselves.</p>
<p>“They were crouched down like turkeys peeking over the balcony,” Dallas County Sheriff Chad Leonard said in an interview. “Here we are at 12:30 in the morning confronted with this issue—on September 11, no less. We have two unknown people in our courthouse—in a government building—carrying backpacks that remind me and several other deputies of maybe the pressure cooker bombs.”</p>
<p>After more deputies arrived, Justin Wynn, 29 of Naples, Florida, and Gary De Mercurio, 43 of Seattle, slowly proceeded down the stairs with hands raised. They then presented the deputies with a letter that explained the intruders weren’t criminals but rather penetration testers who had been hired by Iowa’s State Court Administration to test the security of its court information system. After calling one or more of the state court officials listed in the letter, the deputies were satisfied the men were authorized to be in the building.</p>
<p>The deputies listened with interest as the pentesters—who work for Westminster, Colorado-based <a href="https://www.coalfire.com/Solutions/Coalfire-Labs">Coalfire Labs</a>—explained how they got in. They said they found a courthouse door unlocked. So they closed it from the outside and let it lock. Then they slipped a plastic cutting board through a crack in the door and manipulated its locking mechanism. (Pentesters frequently use makeshift or self-created tools in their craft to flip latches, trigger motion-detected mechanisms, and test other security systems.) The deputies seemed impressed.</p>
<p>When Leonard arrived on the scene, the mood quickly changed. Leonard read the letter and sized the men up. It said the men were authorized to perform “physical social engineering to attempt to gain access” to courthouse systems. The attempts could include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Impersonating staff, contractors, or other individuals</li>
<li>Providing false pretenses to gain physical access to facilities</li>
<li>“Tailgating” employees into facilities</li>
<li>Accessing restricted areas of facilities</li>
</ul>
<p>The letter also listed tasks that should not be performed, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alarm subversion</li>
<li>Force-open doors</li>
<li>Accessing environments that require personal protective equipment</li>
</ul>
<p>The pentesters had already said they used a tool to open the front door. Leonard took that to mean the men had violated the restriction against forcing doors open. Leonard also said the men attempted to turn off the alarm—something Coalfire officials vehemently deny. In Leonard’s mind that was a second violation. Another reason for doubt: one of the people listed as a contact on the get-out-of-jail-free letter didn’t answer the deputies’ calls, while another said he didn’t believe the men had permission to conduct physical intrusions.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/get-out-of-jail-free-letter.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/get-out-of-jail-free-letter.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/get-out-of-jail-free-letter-640x828.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/get-out-of-jail-free-letter.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/get-out-of-jail-free-letter.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> </p></div></a></p>
<p>The sheriff also said he and his deputies smelled alcohol on the breath of one of the men. (Leonard, who didn't identify which Coalfire employee it was, said a test later showed the pentester had a blood alcohol content of 0.05, the equivalent of one or two drinks. It is below the 0.08 threshold for an <a href="https://iowadot.gov/mvd/driverslicense/suspensions-and-revocations">operating while intoxicated</a> conviction.)</p>
<p>Leonard promptly had the men arrested on felony third-degree burglary charges. They spent the night in jail in separate cells, where one of them was given a bench with a sleeping pad. After being arraigned the following morning, they were shocked when they were once again returned to jail. The pentesters weren’t released until late that afternoon or early that evening on $100,000 bail ($50,000 for each).</p>
<p>The charges have since been reduced to misdemeanor trespassing charges. Trial is scheduled for April. Meanwhile, the sheriff’s department in nearby Polk County is conducting a criminal investigation into a September 10 break-in on its courthouse under the same arrangement with the State Judicial Administration.</p>
<h2>Cause célèbre</h2>
<p>The case has become a cause célèbre that has galvanized a variety of different interests. For Coalfire and professional pentesters around the world, the charges are an affront that threatens their ability to carry out what has long been considered a key practice in ensuring clients’ systems are truly secure. If pentesters can’t be confident that physical assessments won’t result in criminal prosecutions, security professionals say they’ll no longer be able to carry out this core function with the vigor and thoroughness it requires.</p>
<p>“This does affect my job directly,” said a penetration tester who asked to be identified only by his handle <a href="https://twitter.com/TinkerSec">@Tinker</a>. “This affects physical pentesting in general and it really affects government pentesting when the state government can’t provide protection and you can’t trust the state government to stand behind its own laws.”</p>
<p>For Dallas County officials, on the other hand—and possibly officials in nearby Polk County—the case is about their sovereign right to police their tax-payer-owned facilities. Leonard said that Iowa’s State Court Administration, or SCA, didn’t have the legal authority to permit the men to force their way into the county-owned building.</p>
<p>What’s more, the sheriff said the pentesters’ use of lock-picking gear and their alleged tampering with an alarm system—again, Coalfire disputes the latter claim—violated the terms of the get-out-of-jail-free letter. The sheriff also said the midnight assessment was a violation of a term spelled out in one section of the rules of engagement document. It said pentesting was to be conducted between 6AM and 6PM Mountain time. (Curiously, Iowa is in the Central time zone. Another term of the same <a href="//cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/rules-of-engagement.pdf">rules of engagement (pdf)</a> said physical testing “Can be during the day and evening.” Leonard wasn't aware of this last detail until I pointed it out in the interview. The sheriff has declined to release video of the incident.)</p>
<h2>You’re going to jail</h2>
<p>The get-out-of-jail-free letter “said you won’t manipulate doors,” Leonard said. “Well, they picked four doors. It said they won’t manipulate the alarm system. They went right up to the alarm and tried to shut it off. The biggest issue is they were only supposed to work from 6AM to 6PM. They came out in the middle of the night and broke in.”</p>
<p>Equally important, Leonard said, is what he believed to be the overstepping of Iowa officials who retained Coalfire. When the sheriff confronted the men that night, he said: "The State of Iowa has no authority to allow you to break into a county building. You’re going to jail.”</p>
<p>No one has more stake in the controversy than Wynn and De Mercurio, who risk being convicted of criminal charges that among other things could jeopardize government clearances and future job prospects. Coalfire CEO Tom McAndrew <a href="https://www.coalfire.com/News-and-Events/Press-Releases/Coalfire-CEO-Tom-McAndrew-statement">said in a statement</a> last month that Leonard “failed to exercise commonsense and good judgement and turned this engagement into a political battle between the State and the County.” McAndrew also noted that Coalfire conducted an engagement for Iowa’s SCA in 2015 without incident.</p>
<p>Leonard said he has been receiving “hate mail” from as far away as Europe ever since the incident two months ago.</p>
<p>McAndrew told me that Wynn and De Mercurio did everything by the book. The employees, McAndrew said, intentionally tripped the alarm and then proceeded to the third floor to test the response. Crouching on floors or otherwise trying to be covert is standard practice after alarms are tripped to further test authorities’ response and see what surveillance cameras can detect.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>A civil matter</h2>
<p>Matthew Lindholm, the Des Moines defense attorney representing the two pentesters, agreed that his clients are being unfairly swept up in a power struggle between the State of Iowa and the County of Dallas. He said Iowa statutes ensure that the state judicial branch has access to county-owned buildings and that the judicial branch can exercise authority over county court houses when it’s necessary to carry out their administrative purposes.</p>
<p>Whether the state had authority to authorize the pen test is “a civil matter, not a criminal matter,” Lindholm said. “You’re not going to get that answer by filing criminal charges against somebody.” He also noted that a provision in the contract required the SCA to secure all necessary permission for the execution of the contract. Lindholm continued:</p>
<blockquote><p>But you also have political pressures from the county who want to hold somebody criminally responsible because, it’s their opinion, that there clearly was no authority for the judicial branch to do what they did. The problem with that is under the legal analysis it doesn’t matter whether my clients had actual authority or apparent authority. As long as they reasonably believed they could go in and do what they did—which the contract said they could—they are legally obligated and cannot be held criminally responsible for doing what they did.</p></blockquote>
<p>Dallas County Attorney Charles Sinnard, who is prosecuting the case, told me that prosecutors aren’t permitted to say much publicly about cases they bring. He did say that he was familiar with the craft of penetration testing and supported that line of work in ensuring courts are secure.</p>
<p>“I have a relative that is in the industry, so I understand the importance of the work, and I back that type of work,” he said. “Professionals in this area would also agree that there are certain responsibilities and expectations because of the sensitive nature of this work, and if those aren’t followed, then that is a different story. What has been released is only part of the story.” He didn't elaborate.</p>
<h2>A mea culpa of sorts</h2>
<p>In October, Iowa Supreme Court Chief Justice Mark Cady, who oversees the state’s judicial branch including all judicial officers and court employees, apologized for the incident before the state’s Senate Government Oversight Committee, <a href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/crime-and-courts/2019/10/04/iowa-supreme-court-justice-cady-apologizes-courthouse-break-ins-senate-polk-dallas-burglary-ia-cyber/3864938002/">according to</a> the Des Moines Register, which has been closely following developments in the case.</p>
<p>“In our efforts to fulfill our duty to protect confidential information of Iowans from cyberattacks, mistakes were made,” he said, using the passive voice that’s so common in leaders’ admissions of responsibility. “We are doing everything possible to correct those mistakes, be accountable for the mistakes and to make sure they never, ever occur again.” He declined to comment for this story.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='The Dallas County Courthouse in Adel, Iowa.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dallas-county-courthouse.jpeg" alt='The Dallas County Courthouse in Adel, Iowa.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">The Dallas County Courthouse in Adel, Iowa. (credit: Stephen Matthew Milligan)</p></div>
<p>His apology made little or no mention of the two men whose futures have been swept up in the controversy. He has remained silent even after the release early last month of an <a href="https://www.iowacourts.gov/collections/445/files/919/embedDocument/">investigation report</a> the SCA commissioned from lawyers at <a href="link">Faegre Baker Daniels</a>, a global law firm with an office in Des Moines. Attorneys who led the investigation into the matter included Nick Klinefeldt and Paul Luehr, a former US attorney for the Southern District of Iowa and a former federal prosecutor and a national cybersecurity consultant, respectively.</p>
<p>The investigators found that neither Wynn and De Mercurio nor Iowa's SCA acted with deception or ill-intent. The report also made a strong case that the pentesters had good reason to believe that everything they did was within the scope of the agreement between the SCA and Coalfire. The Rules of Engagement, the investigators found, specifically gave the men the authority to pick locks and to “utilize physical penetration testing techniques to gain access to facilities, sensitive information, networks or systems.” (The report did find that Coalfire and the SCA failed to adequately draft the agreement. More about that later.)</p>
<p>The rules of engagement also state that the physical assessments were to be conducted on the Polk County Courthouse and the Judicial building—both in Des Moines—as well as the Dallas County Courthouse in Adel, Iowa. And while one section of the rules of engagement was unclear whether the 6AM to 6PM time frame applied only to systems penetration or physical assessments as well, a Scope of Testing section within that document said physical assessments “can be during the day and evening.” That authorization made no mention of any specific time of day.</p>
<p>The investigators also mentioned that on September 10—one day before Wynn and De Mercurio entered the Dallas County Courthouse after hours—John Hoover, the IT manager for the SCA, found Wynn’s business card on his desk when he arrived at his office at the Judicial Building that morning. Hoover immediately knew the Coalfire pentesters had successfully broken into the building, and entered his office, the night before.</p>
<p>“Well done,” the IT manager wrote to Wynn in an email. “I'll be interested to hear how easy it was.”</p>
<h2>Confusing and contradictory terms</h2>
<p>The investigators went on to criticize both the SCA and Coalfire for stringing the agreement into three separate documents that “contained some confusing and contradictory terms” describing the work to be performed.</p>
<p>“In terms of techniques, the Coalfire agreement often co-mingled descriptions of physical tests with other types of assessments,” investigators wrote. “In its initial Service Order, Coalfire clearly described a plan to conduct ‘Physical Attacks’ against three proposed buildings, but in later forms, Coalfire’s Red Team activities fell under the more abstract label of ‘Social Engineering,’ even though a night-time building break-in would probably not involve social interaction with any other individuals.”</p>
<p>The permitted time for the pentesting is another example of a lack of clarity, with one section of the rules of engagement stating it would be conducted between 6AM and 6PM—again, in Mountain Time—and another section saying it could be during the day and evening. The lack of clarity in the get-out-of-jail-free letter was also a key problem, since that was the document responding Sheriff’s officials would read first.</p>
<p>Making matters worse, the investigators noted that there were differences among various SCA officials about precisely what the assessment involved. The IT director of the SCA, Mark Headlee, said he was unaware that the rules of engagement permitted the same physical assessment on the Dallas and Polk County courthouses that were allowed for the Judicial Building. While Hoover—the IT manager who had congratulated Wynn for accessing the Judicial Building—was more familiar with the scope of the engagement, a serious error prevented him from speaking to deputies the night they caught the pentesters at the Dallas County Courthouse. The report explained:</p>
<blockquote><p>According to Headlee, it was his position that Wynn and Demercurio were not supposed to access courthouse after hours and so he told the Dallas County Sheriff Deputies that Wynn and Demercurio were not working within the scope of what SCA contracted with them to do. In subsequent text messages, Headlee questioned what Wynn and Demercurio were doing in the courthouse after hours. In text messages to Hoover, Headlee pointed out that the Dallas County Sheriff’s office did not believe the Authorization applied because the courthouse was county property. Hoover replied that he was just thinking about that issue. It appears neither law enforcement, Wynn, nor Demercurio contacted Hoover directly that night, because Hoover’s number was incorrect on the Authorization form.</p></blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, the investigators found, it’s unclear if SCA had the authority to authorize the intrusions into the two county courthouses. While there are statutes that require counties to provide “sufficient facilities” for state judicial officers, it’s not clear whether this gives the SCA autonomy when state and county resources are commingled in a single premises.</p>
<h2>Greatest shortcoming</h2>
<p>Ultimately, the investigators said, both the SCA and Coalfire shared responsibility for not anticipating the way the assessment would affect the counties that owned and managed the courthouses and for not alerting law enforcement officers ahead of time.</p>
<p>“Perhaps the greatest shortcoming we found was a failure to take into account the potential impact of the assessment on third parties, specifically the counties,” the investigators wrote. “We did not find that the SCA or Coalfire acted with deception or ill-intent. “However, we believe both the SCA and Coalfire should have foreseen a potential confrontation with law enforcement.”</p>
<p>McAndrew, the Coalfire CEO, said his company is already looking at ways to prevent similar incidents from playing out.</p>
<p>“We could always improve,” he said when I asked him about that part of the report. “Every time we have one of these scenarios, you look at what could we improve in communication and what’s written down. We have looked at that and there are some tweaks to make.”</p>
<h2>A mark on their record</h2>
<p>Meanwhile Dallas County Sheriff Leonard has signaled an openness to recommending more leniency from the county prosecutor. In an interview, he said he had yet to read the investigators’ report that found the SCA had authorized a physical assessment in the evening and had approved the forced entry of doors. When I told him of those findings and asked if he still believed the county should prosecute the case, he said:</p>
<p>“If that is true, if those guys had all that, I don’t want them to have this mark on their record. They were nice guys that night.” Still, he returned to the position that the state of Iowa had no legal authority to grant the pentesters permission to break into a county courthouse. I pressed Leonard further and asked if, in light of the investigators’ findings, he believed the pentesters had any criminal intent. Leonard answered: “I don’t want these guys to have this mark on their record if they truly were supposed to be here.”</p>
<p>He went on to blame McAndrew, the Coalfire CEO, for not being more proactive in defending his employees in the hours following the arrests.</p>
<p>“The CEO could have called and said here’s all the stuff, Sheriff,” Leonard said, referring to the contracts Coalfire signed with the SCA. “Then I would have gone to the county attorney [Charles Sinnard] and said: ‘Listen, Chuck, you need to get rid of this stuff.’ They never did any of that.”</p>
<p>What seems clear from all of this is that for the time being, Wynn and De Mercurio will have these charges—and possibly new ones from Polk County—hanging over their heads, even though there’s no public evidence the pentesters had any criminal intent or bad motives. The ambiguous and sometimes contradictory terms in the agreement—which comprised multiple documents—was problematic. So, too, was the lack of clarity about whether Iowa’s SCA had the legal authority to permit an intrusion on county property.</p>
<p>But it’s hard to see how these defects rise to the level of a criminal offense that threatens not only the future of the two pentesters, but also the increasingly important profession of pentesting itself.</p>
<p>“If what is happening in Iowa begins to happen elsewhere, who will keep those who are supposed to protect citizens honest?” McAndrew wrote in his statement from October. “This is setting a horrible precedent for the millions of information security professionals who are now wondering if they too may find themselves in jail as criminals simply for doing their job.”</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601265&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guidemaster: Ars picks its favorite tech gifts you can buy for under $50</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596209</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 12:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ars Holiday 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gifts under $50]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best tech gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gift guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidemaster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596209</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good tech can get really expensive really quickly—here are some affordable gems.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1-800x534.jpg" alt="Guidemaster: Ars picks its favorite tech gifts you can buy for under $50"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1281" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Finding a gift for your most tech-savvy friends and family can be tough, especially with electronics getting more expensive as the years go by. While it may seem like the only electronics worth getting are those that exist outside of your budget, that's not actually the case. Plenty of tech gifts are available at affordable prices—the struggle is sorting through the junk to find the devices worth shelling out <em>any</em> amount of money for.</p>
<p>This is where we at Ars come in: we spend all year testing electronics, with prices spanning everything from "luxury" to "dirt-cheap." So recently, we poured through our notes to find some of the best tech gifts you can buy that are under $50. All of the devices listed below have been tested and verified for excellence or for personal use on a regular basis. Instead of shooting in the dark or overspending when it comes to tech gifts this year, consider the following devices that we know will make any recipient happy.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Anker PowerLine II Lightning and USB-C cables for $12.99 (and up)</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powerline-ii.jpg"><img alt='Anker&#039;s PowerLine II USB-C to Lightning cable.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powerline-ii-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powerline-ii-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Anker&#039;s PowerLine II USB-C to Lightning cable.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powerline-ii.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Anker's PowerLine II USB-C to Lightning cable.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>Here's a simple one: if your loved one has bought a smartphone in the last couple of years, that phone probably supports some level of fast charging. If they have an iPhone that isn't the iPhone 11 Pro or iPhone 11 Pro Max, they need an external USB-C Power Delivery charger and USB-C to Lightning cable to make that happen. If they have a newer Android phone, the necessary materials probably came in the box, but the thing about good charging gear is that you can never really have too much of it. Either way, this fast-charging can prevent your loved one from spending any number of hours stuck near an outlet.</p>
<p>There are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/07/guidemaster-ars-tested-and-found-the-best-usb-c-accessories-you-can-get-now/#h26" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many chargers</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/features/2019/10/guidemaster-our-favorite-accessories-for-iphones-and-ipads/#h3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">portable batteries</a> that can <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/08/guidemaster-the-best-nintendo-switch-accessories-you-can-buy-in-2019/#h13" target="_blank" rel="noopener">do the job</a> here—for smartphones, just make sure you get at least 18W of power—but for cables, we've found Anker's PowerLine II series to be particularly reliable. Its <a href="https://amzn.to/2NYVSzi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to Lightning cable</a> is MFi certified by Apple to work safely with iOS devices and costs significantly less than Apple's own alternative. Its <a href="https://amzn.to/2NJM5hG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to USB-C 3.1 Gen 2 cable</a> supports up to 5-amp/100W charging and up to 10Gbps data transfer speeds, so it can charge newer USB-C laptops like the 15-inch MacBook Pro as fast as possible (again, with <a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/1305166/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMNF82LL%2FA%2F87w-usb-c-power-adapter%3Fafid%3Dp239%257C1305166%26cid%3Daos-us-aff-ir&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a powerful-enough charger</a>) and move videos and other large files quickly. The more affordable <a href="https://amzn.to/33EpIjb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USB-C to USB-C 2.0 cable</a>, meanwhile, supports up to 60W charging, which is easily fast enough to refill new USB-C phones and tablets at max speeds. Both USB-C cables are certified as compliant by the USB-IF, a <a href="https://www.usb.org/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nonprofit body</a> run by Apple, Microsoft, Intel, and other major tech firms that looks over the USB spec.</p>
<p>In any case, each PowerLine II cable we've tested has performed as it should and shown no serious signs of wear after months of travel and regular use. If something does go wrong, Anker gives each cable a lifetime warranty. It's not the sexiest gift, sure, but bundling a few cables together based on what devices your loved one owns could make their day-to-day a little more convenient.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/51dK6Od0J2L._SL1500_-300x375.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerLine II USB-C to Lightning Cable (6ft) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerLine II USB-C to Lightning Cable (6ft)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_21681431" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2K8lYi3" target="_blank">
                                $16.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Anker PowerWave Stand for $15.99</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpowerwave1.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpowerwave1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpowerwave1-1280x854.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpowerwave1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Wireless chargers are really handy to have on a nightstand or an office desk, and <a href="https://amzn.to/2JQ7tiT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker's PowerWave</a> 10W Qi wireless charging stand is a solid one at a great price of $15.99. It has a simple yet practical design that lets you use your smartphone in an upright position while it's charging, and it can be positioned horizontally or vertically on the stand. It also supports phone cases up to 5mm thick, so most will not have to remove their phone cases to charge up.</p>
<p>Anker's stand supports 10W charging on Galaxy smartphones and others, and up to 5W charging on iPhones. While it's not the fastest fast charger we've ever tested, Anker's stand will power most smartphones at least 30 percent in just one hour. The stand itself doesn't get hot while charging either, nor does it raise the temperature of your smartphone too much. Overall, it's a solid wireless charger for most Qi-enabled smartphones at an excellent price.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ankerpw-300x282.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerWave Stand product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerWave Stand                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_36974775" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2JQ7tiT" target="_blank">
                                $15.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Fiio µBTR for $22.99</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fiio-ubtr.jpg"><img alt='The Fiio uBTR Bluetooth headphone adapter.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fiio-ubtr-640x458.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fiio-ubtr-1280x916.jpg 2x" alt='The Fiio uBTR Bluetooth headphone adapter.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/fiio-ubtr.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Fiio uBTR Bluetooth headphone adapter.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>While it's admittedly a niche product, a Bluetooth headphone adapter like the <a href="https://amzn.to/2CxTB99" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fiio µBTR</a> lets you use any beloved wired headphone with a headphone-jack-less phone. Unlike a wired dongle, though, it still gives you the freedom of leaving your phone in a separate bag, charging it across the room, or just generally using it without having a cable attached.</p>
<p>The µBTR itself is conveniently designed, with a built-in clip that can attach to a pocket and dedicated buttons for volume, pause/play, and activating Siri or Google Assistant (depending on your phone OS). It lasts about eight or nine hours on a charge, which should be enough for a typical workday, and it recharges quickly through a USB-C port. It pairs simply enough and has presented us with no significant connection issues in testing.</p>
<p>Going from a wired connection to Bluetooth almost inherently means a drop in audio quality, but for what it is, the µBTR doesn't degrade things too much. It doesn't support the higher-quality aptX or LDAC audio codecs, but it does support AAC, which is as good as iPhone audio gets. Switching to a Bluetooth headset is still the simplest solution for most people moving to a phone without a headphone jack, but if you know someone who is deeply into audio and has invested a good amount in a decent pair, the µBTR is a nifty compromise.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/41ha-81QiCL._SL1000_-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Fiio µBTR product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Fiio µBTR                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_31553095" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2CxTB99" target="_blank">
                                $21.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>SanDisk MicroSD Card for Nintendo Switch (128GB) for $25.49</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/sandisk-nintendo-switch-microsd-card.jpg"><img alt='SanDisk&#039;s microSD Card for Nintendo Switch.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/sandisk-nintendo-switch-microsd-card-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/sandisk-nintendo-switch-microsd-card-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='SanDisk&#039;s microSD Card for Nintendo Switch.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/sandisk-nintendo-switch-microsd-card.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">SanDisk's microSD Card for Nintendo Switch.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>A good microSD card will spare your loved one some headaches when their Nintendo Switch, Android phone, camera, or whatever else starts to run out of storage space. While it's difficult to say one microSD card is the absolute best choice for everyone, the <a href="https://amzn.to/2K9aYB8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">128GB version of SanDisk's MicroSD Card for Nintendo Switch</a> is a quality blend of speed, reliability, and affordability.</p>
<p>There are <a href="https://amzn.to/2Q2IBZf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">higher-rated cards</a> with noticeably faster speeds, but not every device will actually take advantage of that power (the Switch, for one), and the prices are still too high for all but the heaviest video recording needs. Similarly, while cheaper cards might offer a better price-to-capacity ratio, many of them aren't as future-proof and can be prone to counterfeits online.</p>
<p>The Switch card is more or less a rebranded version of SanDisk's Extreme microSD card: it's a U3, V30-rated card whose sequential and random read/write speeds are fast enough to record 4K video and operate Switch games comfortably; we've tested it for several months without any issues; and at $20-25 for a healthy 128GB of space, its price is modest. Since it's regularly sold directly from retailers like Amazon and Best Buy, you can buy it without fear of receiving a fake. Plus, it's got that cute Toad mushroom on it. Again, there are many other cards that perform similarly—the <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-extreme-plus-128gb-microsdxc-uhs-i-memory-card%2F6282919.p%3FskuId%3D6282919&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SanDisk Extreme Plus</a> and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsamsung-evo-plus-128gb-microsdxc-uhs-i-memory-card%2F5785406.p%3FskuId%3D5785406&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung Evo Plus</a> are two good examples if you see them going for significantly less—but if you don't want to dig into the weeds, we can confirm that SanDisk's Switch card is a safe and speedy way to feed a storage-starved device.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/sandiskswitch-300x218.jpg"
                                    alt="SanDisk MicroSD Card for Nintendo Switch (128GB) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">SanDisk MicroSD Card for Nintendo Switch (128GB)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_88749482" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2K9aYB8" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_88749482">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2K9aYB8">Amazon $25.49</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-128gb-microsdxc-memory-card-for-nintendo-switch%2F6103002.p%3FskuId%3D6103002&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts">Best Buy $34.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2K9aYB8"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsandisk-128gb-microsdxc-memory-card-for-nintendo-switch%2F6103002.p%3FskuId%3D6103002&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2><em>How Things Work: The Inner Life of Everyday Machines</em> by Theodore Gray for $26.99</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/howthingswork_gg.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/howthingswork_gg-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/howthingswork_gg-1280x854.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/howthingswork_gg.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>We take a lot of technology for granted—things like clocks, locks, and scales have become so commonplace that they don't warrant a second glance to most of us. Writer Theodore Gray dives into the world of ordinary things in <a href="https://amzn.to/32lHias" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>How Things Work: The Inner Life of Everyday Machines</em></a>, a stunning coffee-table book with detailed photos by photographer Nick Mann. Gray explores how everyday things work in great detail, going so far as to build some of them himself, and provides a new perspective on these objects that most of us would never have unless we knew them intimately (I don't know about you, but I don't know my alarm clock intimately at all). What Gray did in his previous books about <a href="https://amzn.to/2PR3l60" target="_blank" rel="noopener">elements</a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/2oTPqkI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">molecules</a>, and <a href="https://amzn.to/2qkzBnr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reactions</a>, he has now done for the mechanical systems that run our world, and the result is a beautiful appreciation for systems we all often overlook.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/howthingswork-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="<em>How Things Work</em> product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title"><em>How Things Work</em>                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_38810935" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32lHias" target="_blank">
                                $26.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>LEGO Architecture Sets for $30 to $50</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1-1280x854.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legoarchitecture1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>LEGO sets are fantastic gifts no matter who your recipient is, how old they are, or what their interests may be. While many go gaga for <em>Star Wars</em> or <em>Harry Potter</em> sets—many of which cost hundreds—the modern <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Architecture-New-York-City-21028-Model-Kit-for-Adults-and-Kids-598-pcs%2F47335732&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Architecture line</a> has a number of sets priced $50 and under that make great gifts. The series focuses on landmarks from around the world, making it perfect for those who proudly live in, or who have a soft spot for, cities like New York, London, Las Vegas, Paris, and San Francisco. Thanks to the superb level of detail in each set, you may find yourself seeing the city you love in a new light while building it from scratch.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/legonyc-300x263.jpeg"
                                    alt="LEGO Architecture product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">LEGO Architecture                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_24017375" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Architecture-New-York-City-21028-Model-Kit-for-Adults-and-Kids-598-pcs%2F47335732&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank">
                                $47.99 from Walmart                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Final E2000 for $39</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/final-e2000.jpg"><img alt='Final&#039;s E2000 in-ear headphones.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/final-e2000-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/final-e2000-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Final&#039;s E2000 in-ear headphones.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/final-e2000.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Final's E2000 in-ear headphones.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>For better or worse, the mobile world has wrapped its arms around Bluetooth audio. While the benefits of killing the headphone jack remain debatable, those who care about audio quality first and foremost are still better off with a pair of wired headphones. Provided your loved one is okay putting up with a dongle or adapter (see the Fiio µBTR above), the <a href="https://amzn.to/2CwIHAb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Final E2000</a> is an example of the stellar value you can find by going the old-fashioned way.</p>
<p>The E2000 is a no-frills in-ear headphone: there's no microphone, no noise-cancellation, and, unfortunately, no in-line volume controls. The focus is entirely on comfort and sound quality; thankfully, the E2000 hits both out of the park. The cable could stand to be a touch thicker, but the aluminum earpieces are small and super lightweight, so they should be easy to wear for hours at a time. The snug fit does well to naturally block out external noises, too.</p>
<p>Audio quality, meanwhile, is superb: these aren't "professional" headphones by any means, but for $39, their clean and clear sound is better than many earphones that cost twice as much. (They even surpass something like Apple's AirPods Pro, which admittedly has many more features but still costs $250.) They have a slightly V-shaped signature that gives mild boosts to the bass and treble but remains smooth across genres. The E2000 provides a genuinely surprising amount of width and depth, giving tracks a "3D" feel that's atypical for inexpensive earphones. In all, it's a sound that should be pleasant to most tastes.</p>
<p>All that said, we realize that many people care more about how easy a headphone is to use than how good it sounds. If you can only gift a pair of Bluetooth earphones on the cheap, consider <a href="https://amzn.to/2p8HOLj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker's Soundcore Spirit X</a>. They aren't nearly as balanced sounding, but their bass-heavy profile is fun enough, and their IP68-rated design can withstand daily trips to the gym. They aren't <em>truly</em> wireless—we've yet to find a pair of AirPods-style earbuds under $50 we can comfortably recommend—but they do get around 15 hours of battery life on a charge and won't force you to carry a dongle around. Still, if you know someone who still thinks the point of headphones is to sound good, the E2000 are a somewhat hidden gem.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/51UF2a4jNFL._SL1500_-300x165.jpg"
                                    alt="Final E2000 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Final E2000                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_69713405" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2CwIHAb" target="_blank">
                                $39 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Oral-B White Pro 1000 for $39.94</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/oralbpress.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/oralbpress-640x640.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/oralbpress.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/oralbpress.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Oral B)</p></div>
<p>Electric toothbrushes are electronics that you don't think about often but that get used on a daily basis. <a href="https://amzn.to/2oOt0RJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oral-B's White Pro 1000</a> isn't the fanciest or the most feature-rich electric toothbrush out there (no, it doesn't connect to an app), but it does a much better job of cleaning your teeth than a regular toothbrush does. The built-in timer in the handle pulses every 30 seconds, letting you know when you should move to a different portion of your mouth. It also keeps track of how long you brush, helping you brush at least two minutes each time you use it.</p>
<p>The White Pro 1000 gets about 22 hours of battery life before you need to recharge it using the included charging stand. That means it will last at least one month on a single charge, and it'll charge fully after an overnight stay on the stand. It's also compatible with seven different Oral-B brush heads, so you can change it up when you feel like your teeth need a different type of clean. The $39 Oral-B White Pro 1000 is a great option for anyone who doesn't want to spend close to $100 or more on a solid electric toothbrush.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/orbalb-300x349.jpg"
                                    alt="Oral-B White Pro 1000 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Oral-B White Pro 1000                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_11009043" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2oOt0RJ" target="_blank">
                                $39.94 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-3'></a></div>
<h2>Audible membership (3-month) for $45</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/audible1.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/audible1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/audible1-1280x854.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/audible1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>I get my reading/listening material from a myriad of sources, but the convenience of <a href="https://amzn.to/2WitECw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Audible</a> for audiobooks is unmatched. The Amazon-owned company not only has a huge selection of audiobooks to choose from, but it also has exclusive Audible-only recordings that are a delight, like Thandie Newton's reading of <em>Jane Eyre</em> and Stephen Fry's narration of the complete adventures of Sherlock Holmes.</p>
<p>Audible's membership lets you pick one book each month, plus two Audible originals for free, and it gives you access to daily deals and members-only sales. Giving a 3-month Audible membership as a gift is a win-win situation because, even if your recipient decides to cancel, they get to keep all the books they purchased while they were a member.</p>
<p>I never thought audiobooks were for me until I gave Audible a shot. I still read physical books, but my busy schedule lets me read even when I don't have the time to sit down and pull out a paperback. Any book lover in your life will appreciate how much more they can read on a regular basis with an Audible membership. Plus, new members can sign up for a <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cbn9cv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three-month subscription</a> for just $6.95 per month for a limited time.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/audible-300x186.jpg"
                                    alt="Audible gift subscription (3-month) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Audible gift subscription (3-month)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_80114114" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2WitECw" target="_blank">
                                $45 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K for $49.99</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k.jpg"><img alt='Amazon&#039;s Fire TV Stick 4K media streamer.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Amazon&#039;s Fire TV Stick 4K media streamer.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Amazon's Fire TV Stick 4K media streamer.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>If you know someone who is looking to ditch their cable provider for good, you can get them on their way with a streaming media player. Both <a href="https://amzn.to/2pTlgyC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon's Fire TV Stick 4K</a> and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FRoku-Streaming-Stick-4K-Media-Player%2F300825724&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Roku's Streaming Stick+</a> are worthwhile options: they serve up the 4K and HDR content most streaming apps are increasingly embracing, are fast to navigate and load up content, support the necessary streaming apps, and come in unobtrusive, travel-friendly designs. Both support 802.11ac WiFi. Both devices' remotes can control basic TV functions and neither requires a line of sight with the streamer to work. And with the Streaming Stick+'s recent price cut, both only retail for $50, making them better value for most than pricier boxes like the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-TV-4K-32GB%2F976529747&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple TV 4K</a> (unless your loved one absolutely needs an Ethernet port to stream in 4K.)</p>
<p>Of the two, though, we give a very slight nod to the Fire TV Stick 4K. Whereas the Streaming Stick+ only supports the basic HDR10 format, Amazon's streamer works with HDR10, Dolby Vision, HDR10+, and HLG. This will only matter if your loved one has a TV that supports those standards in the first place—and HDR content in general still isn't the norm—but it gives the Fire TV Stick 4K a greater measure of future-proofing. While its Alexa-aided voice search isn't perfect, Amazon's streamer is also generally more sophisticated and speedier with voice commands than the Streaming Stick+. Having Alexa onboard lets the Fire TV Stick 4K pair with several other smart devices that support the assistant as well.</p>
<p>We found the Fire TV Stick 4K to be smarter about suspending apps at the point you last used them instead of resetting them whenever you return to the home menu. The Fire's ability to display those menus in HDR is a nice touch that makes those menus look consistently colorful on HDR-ready TVs. The recent additions of YouTube TV and Disney+ filled two huge holes in Amazon's otherwise robust app library. If your loved one likes watching game streamers on Twitch, the Fire TV Stick 4K has an official app for that, whereas all Roku streamers do not.</p>
<p>The biggest drawback to the Fire TV Stick 4K—outside of not wanting to contribute to Amazon's ever-widening empire—is that its interface is a bit of a mess. There are ads all over the place, it's not uncommon to find multiple shortcuts to the same app onscreen at the same time, and Amazon still tends to push its own Prime Video shows and services above other content. Ignoring all this is easy enough, and the interface is much flashier-looking than Roku's dated UI, but the Streaming Stick+ is altogether easier to navigate. Still, unless your recipient is a stickler for software design or just wants nothing to do with Alexa, the Fire TV Stick 4K should make cutting the cord more pleasant.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3-Fire-TV-Stick-4K-Right-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_19737813" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2pTlgyC" target="_blank">
                                $49.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Yi Dash cam for $49.99</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/yidashcam8.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/yidashcam8-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/yidashcam8-1280x853.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/yidashcam8.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Dash cams are great gifts in general because most people don't think to buy one for themselves until they realize how useful a dash cam would have been in a bad situation. The <a href="https://amzn.to/34vIut9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yi Dash Cam</a> is one of our favorites because it's just $50 and has all the features most people would need. It has a 165-degree field-of-view and records 1080p video at 60fps, and it's G-sensor will automatically save footage that occurred at a time of impact.</p>
<p>You can view footage and change settings using the buttons on the dash cam itself, or you can use the Yi Dash Cam app. The latter is one of the better dash cam mobile apps out there because it's easy to use and lets you view and download video clips fairly easily. You can even share footage over social media from directly in the app. High-quality video recording, easy access to footage, and a reliable G-sensor are three of the most important features every dash cam should have—and the Yi Dash Cam combines all of them in a compact, affordable device.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/yi-dash-cam-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Yi Dash Cam product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Yi Dash Cam                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_70421751" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/34vIut9" target="_blank">
                                $49.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Echo Dot for $49.99</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/amazonechodot.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/amazonechodot-640x360.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/amazonechodot-1280x720.jpg 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/amazonechodot.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow"></a> (credit: Amazon)</p></div>
<p>Amazon's smallest smart speaker is a gift that does a lot more than just answer your questions. The <a href="https://amzn.to/2WLRLdT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Echo Dot</a> is a home for Amazon's virtual assistant Alexa, but it's also a Bluetooth speaker that will suit small spaces like dorm rooms just fine. It's not the best Bluetooth speaker you can get in terms of sound quality, but the Echo Dot's combination of features is what makes it a great device. In addition to playing music and using Alexa to answer your questions, it can also control smart home devices using your voice commands, call others with Echo devices, set timers and reminders, and use Alexa Skills to do things like read the news, play ambient sounds, and more.</p>
<p>The convenience of a device like the Echo Dot comes from connecting it to your various accounts like Spotify, Apple Music, Philips Hue, and more. Once paired, you can play specific playlists you've created just by asking for them, add items to your shopping list, and trigger a "going to bed" routine with just one command. Alexa can connect to most major services now, but if you're embedded in Google's systems, we recommend getting a <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGoogle-Home-Mini-Chalk%2F159013183&amp;subid1=Under50Gifts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Home Mini</a> instead. It does almost everything an Echo Dot can do and will be easier to set up with your various Google accounts and services.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/6182S7MYC2L._SL1000_-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Echo Dot product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Echo Dot                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_31672918" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2WLRLdT" target="_blank">
                                $49.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>


<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1596209&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Living with range anxiety: Two weeks with the Jaguar I-Pace</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1581535</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 12:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Bangeman]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I-Pace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jaguar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1581535</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We tested the I-Pace in the dead of winter and the heat of summer.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ipace-list-800x533.jpg" alt="Living with range anxiety: Two weeks with the Jaguar I-Pace"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ipace-list.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1365" data-width="2048">Enlarge</a> (credit: Marlowe Bangeman)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The Jaguar I-Pace is a brilliant car. The first battery electric vehicle from Jaguar-Land Rover, the I-Pace starts at about $70,000 and goes up from there.</p>
<p>My colleague, Ars Automotive Editor Jonathan Gitlin, drove the I-Pace when it launched and came away <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/06/forget-about-that-tesla-the-jaguar-i-pace-is-the-most-compelling-ev-yet/">raving about it</a>—and for good reason. Not only did it win the World Green Car award, but it also won <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/04/the-jaguar-i-pace-wins-world-car-of-the-year-world-green-car-awards/">World Car of the Year</a>.</p>
<p>Jonathan covered the I-Pace in great detail, so I won't spend much time talking about the driving experience. Suffice it to say, the I-Pace is blast to drive. It accelerates briskly, it's incredibly comfortable, sight lines are good, handling is impeccable, it's roomy for its size, it has some modest off-road skills, and Jaguar-Land Rover's infotainment system, Touch Duo Pro, is well-thought-out, even if slightly laggy at times. Beyond that, JLR fixed one of the major complaints Jonathan had about the I-Pace as it entered production: the regenerative-braking settings are no longer buried under layers of menus.</p>
<p>In short, there's very little to dislike and much to love where driving the I-Pace is concerned. And at the risk of setting off a storm in the comments, I prefer driving an I-Pace to the Tesla Model S I drove for a few days last year.</p>
<p>But for many people, BEVs are an unknown. One frequent question I get when I talk BEVs is range anxiety—"don't you worry about running out of juice?" Range anxiety is real. Sure, most of us have had the experience of running on fumes as we pulled in to refuel, and even if you run out of gas, you can make the walk of shame to the nearest gas station. It's not the same with a BEV. Charging stations aren't ubiquitous like their fossil fuel counterparts, and you can't trudge back to your Nissan Leaf or Tesla Model S with a can of electrons for your dead vehicle. And even with a full charge, you can see your eventual stall point approaching as you head down the highway.</p>
<p>To see what living with range anxiety is like, we talked Jaguar into letting us drive an I-Pace for two weeks: one in January and one in June. The goal was not only to see what using a BEV as our daily driver was like, but to understand more about how temperature extremes affect range. That's an important consideration for those of us who live where there are four real seasons.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ipace-3617-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The I-Pace is a compact SUV but feels roomier than others in its class due to the longer wheelbase.                      [credit:
                        Marlowe Bangeman                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Our first I-Pace was a preproduction model that had occasional issues charging at some public charging stations, apparently due to a problem with the charging port that has since been corrected on the production models. During that loan, temperatures got as low as 9°F (-13°C). The second I-Pace, fully loaded HSE, saw temperatures ranging from 69-94°F (21-34°C). At both extremes, the car saw almost a 20% drop in range.</p>
<p>For each drive, we recorded the starting and ending range, mileage driven, and outside air temperature. Charging took place primarily in an unattached garage with a 120V hookup, although we did take advantage of public chargers—and DC fast chargers—when available.</p>
<h2>Dead of winter</h2>
<p>Last winter was brutal here in Chicago, with temperatures bottoming out at -23°F (-30˚C) one January morning. It didn't get <em>that</em> cold while I had the I-Pace, but it was chilly enough to see the impact temperature can have on range.</p>
<p>The car I drove was a preproduction model with a charging cable that said "PROTOTYPE" in big, block letters. It unfortunately did not play nicely with every charging station, an issue that I did <strong>not</strong> encounter with the production car I drove this summer.</p>
<h3>January 15: First drive</h3>
<p>The I-Pace arrived on an overcast January day. Upon powering it up for my usual 63-mile (101km) test drive, I noticed that the range was 179 miles, which the car said was 90% of capacity, making the full range around 200 miles (321km). My review route is about 35 miles (56km) of interstate driving combined with all seven miles (11km) of winding, hilly roads in the northwest suburbs of Chicago; the rest is "generic" suburban driving.</p>
<p>I ended up driving 63 miles while using 69 miles (111km) of range on a 34°F (1˚C) day. We're used to seeing higher EPA mileage estimates with highway driving, but the opposite is true for BEVs: the faster you go, the quicker you'll drain the batter.</p>
<h3>January 16: 120V charging</h3>
<p>A 69-mile drive used up just over a third of the available range, leaving me with a nagging feeling that I should plug it in. Production model I-Paces can take advantage of 100kW DC fast chargers. Alas, all I have in my garage is a 120V outlet and the charger that came with the Jaguar. I ended up putting another 12 miles (19km) on the car the first day. Combined with a two-hour mid-afternoon charge, I ended the day with 101 miles (163km) of range.</p>
<p>I left the car plugged in overnight in my unheated garage on a night where temps bottomed out at 31°F (-1˚C), and 12 hours later, I had gained 28 miles (45km) of range—a paltry 2.33 miles (3.7km) of range per hour.</p>
<p>That's an important point when considering a BEV: you'll need regular access to a 240V charger, whether at home or elsewhere, to keep your batteries topped off. Putting 30 or so miles per day on the car and charging at home wasn't going to cut it.</p>
<h3>January 17: 240V charging</h3>
<p>Having more voltage makes a big difference. I headed over to the local Whole Foods to spend my morning working from the in-store café, as there are two parking places reserved for EVs. Power is also free, provided by Volta. You'll notice that I gained 34 miles of range from around four hours of charging on a relatively balmy 34° Chicago day.</p>
<h3>January 21: Imminent polar vortex</h3>
<p>As my time with the I-Pace was coming to an end, the polar vortex was beginning its southward march upon the upper Midwest. On a 9°F (-23˚C) frigid January morning, I was almost startled when I turned on the I-Pace and saw that my range was 100 miles (161km) and that the car was 52% charged. Doing the math results in a number significantly lower than the 234 miles (377km) advertised by Jaguar (max range was 191 miles (307km) at that point), but it highlights an important fact about BEVs: the car's range is heavily influenced by the ambient temperature.</p>
<p>And getting the interior of the car comfortable on a cold morning carries a cost as well. The good thing about the I-Pace is that you can get warm air from the vents very quickly; the flip side is that the heat isn't a byproduct of burning fossil fuels. You need to expend electrons to create heat and still more to blow the heat into the cabin.</p>
<p>Mediterranean climates are the sweet spots for BEVs. The relatively narrow band of temperatures—compared to continental climates—means a BEV should usually be in its sweet spot for maximum range. If you live somewhere with wide annual temperature swings, it's going to affect how far your electric vehicle can go on a full charge.</p>
<h3>January 21: DC fast charging</h3>
<p>I wanted to ensure the I-Pace had enough juice to make it back to the press fleet manager, so I found an EVgo Level 2 fast charging station at a Whole Foods about five miles away. I downloaded the EVgo app, created an account, and headed over for a quick charge. At $1.50 per hour, EVgo is reasonably priced, and I gained almost 40 miles (64km) of range in a little over a half hour.</p>
<h2>Dog days of summer</h2>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ipace-3649-980x653.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          The cockpit of the I-Pace.                      [credit:
                        Marlowe Bangeman                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The second I-Pace arrived at the end of June, where average high temperatures in Chicago reach into the low-to-mid-80s (27-32˚C) and can jump into the 90s (&gt;32˚C) for days at a time. By this time, the I-Pace had been in production and on sale for a few months, and the production version gave me no problems over the week I had it.</p>
<h3>June 26: Where did all of the miles go?</h3>
<p>My first trip was a grocery run. The I-Pace had been sitting in a hot garage, so I was very surprised to see 250 miles (402km) in the center of the instrument cluster—especially for a car that has an advertised range of 234 miles. Once I started driving, the range dropped quickly, and the ending numbers were in line with what I expected from the I-Pace.</p>
<p>This happened a couple of other times: the starting range seemed too optimistic, only to recalibrate itself within a minute or so of starting the car.</p>
<h3>June 29: Sitting in the sun</h3>
<p>The I-Pace had charged overnight for 11 hours, gaining 26 miles of range, before we headed out. It was a hot, humid morning with four people in the car, so the air conditioning and seat ventilation were turned up. Turning the fan up or down resulted in an immediate loss or gain of range on the instrument panel—in some cases as many as seven miles.</p>
<p>We parked the I-Pace in a shade-free lot, and we returned to a car with even more diminished range—we'd lost 21 miles (33km) just by parking for a couple of hours! Once we got going, and the car was able to direct some energy toward cooling the battery pack, things looked normal again. We ended our trip with 126 miles (203km) of range, using 12 miles (19km) of battery while driving twice that.</p>
<p>Key takeaway: park in the shade.</p>
<h3>July 1: Preconditioning</h3>
<p>One nice feature of BEVs is the ability to precondition the car before departure. You can tell the I-Pace what time you want to leave and the car will prepare itself for departure by cooling or heating the battery for optimal range and performance. As a bonus, it will do the same to the cabin so you're not sitting down in a sauna or icebox, depending on the time of year.</p>
<p>With the weather calling for temperatures in the mid-90s and my son having rugby sevens training in the late afternoon, I had the opportunity to see how well it worked. We waded through the humid July air and stifling garage to be greeted by a pleasantly cool interior—no need to max out the AC.</p>
<p>If you look at the starting percentage, you'll note that the max range works out to about 203 miles (327km), which was the lowest I saw during my summer driving. I noticed the range dropping the most when the temperatures got to around 90°, so if you live in a climate were that kind of heat is an infrequent visitor, you shouldn't see much impact with a BEV.</p>
<h3>July 1: 100kW DC fast charging</h3>
<p>Jaguar built in support for 100kW DC fast charging with the I-Pace, so after dropping my son off at practice, I headed over to the nearest ChargePoint station (at a Jaguar-Land Rover dealership) to drink from a 100kW firehose. I'd planned on spending an hour and half there to see how close I'd come to a full charge, but a squall line moved through, forcing an early end to rugby practice.</p>
<p>Still, I was able to charge at a rate of over a mile a minute. And Jaguar claims that at a 100kW charging station, the battery can grab an 80% charge in 40 minutes.</p>
<h2>Takeaways</h2>
<p>I came away from my two weeks driving the I-Pace with a clearer understanding of what's involved with owning a BEV. First, there's no escaping the range indicator. It's always going to be prominently displayed in the instrument cluster. But that doesn't mean you'll always be fretting over how long before the car runs out of juice. With every trip I made, there really was a zero percent chance that I'd do enough driving to bottom out the battery. Once I truly got understood that, I stopped caring so much about that number.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/style.jpg"><img alt='I got a perfect score on accessory usage but didn&#039;t do so hot on speed or braking.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/style-640x261.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/style.jpg 2x" alt='I got a perfect score on accessory usage but didn&#039;t do so hot on speed or braking.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/style.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">I got a perfect score on accessory usage but didn't do so hot on speed or braking.</a> (credit: Eric Bangeman)</p></div>
<p>Second, driving choices matter. The I-Pace keeps a nice running scorecard of your driving efficiency, scoring your braking, speed, and accessory use (heat and air conditioning, mostly), and over time, it adjusts the projected range based on your driving style.</p>
<p>It's also important to remember that the car's range is going to be affected by circumstances outside of your control—most often the weather. Driving on very hot or cold days will take a bite out of your range, and you will see some unexpected—and sometimes alarming—range drops. I didn't have the chance to do a real road trip with the I-Pace, but I would approach a 200-mile trip in the middle of the summer with trepidation. At the very least, I would make sure there was a charger or two on my route. Tesla has done an outstanding job providing a robust charging infrastructure for its customers. But the rest of the world is catching up, and I noticed more stations nearby in July than I did in January.</p>
<p>Like every other buying decision, deciding whether to ditch fossil fuels for electrons comes down to your circumstances. If you can install a 240V outlet in your garage or charge your car at work, you'll have no problem keeping your battery topped off. If you live in a medium-size metropolitan area, there should be no shortage of chargers for when you're out and about. And after decades of grabbing my wallet every time I pull into a gas station, it felt like cheating to charge for free at the Whole Foods. And electricity is cheaper than gas. I pay in the neighborhood of $3.00 per gallon for gas, but my rate for electricity is 6.9¢/kWh. If I had a 240V charger in my garage, I could fully charge an I-Pace with its 90kWh battery for under $7!</p>
<p>Tesla deservedly gets most of the attention when the conversation turns to electric vehicles. But it's not the only game in town. At 234 miles, the I-Pace falls well short of the 370 miles (595km) of the latest Tesla Model S. If that's your sole criteria, the choice is clear, but mileage tradeoffs are necessary with gas burners, as well. With the I-Pace, Jaguar had taken its decades of experience in building fast, beautiful cars and created a zero-emission SUV that is truly a Jaguar and a joy to drive.</p>
<h2>Selected trip data</h2>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Date</th>
<th>Temperature (F)</th>
<th>Starting range (miles)</th>
<th>Ending range (miles)</th>
<th>Miles driven/charge time</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1/15</td>
<td>34°</td>
<td>179</td>
<td>110</td>
<td>63mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1/16</td>
<td>31°</td>
<td>101</td>
<td>129</td>
<td>12 hours</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1/17</td>
<td>34°</td>
<td>143</td>
<td>177</td>
<td>4 hours</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1/21</td>
<td>9°</td>
<td>100</td>
<td>79</td>
<td>15.5mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1/21</td>
<td>16°</td>
<td>63</td>
<td>102</td>
<td>35 minutes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/26</td>
<td>85°</td>
<td>250 (100% charged)</td>
<td>232 (93%)</td>
<td>1.4mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/26</td>
<td>85°</td>
<td>250 (100% charged)</td>
<td>231 (97%)</td>
<td>1.4mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/29</td>
<td>86°</td>
<td>199 (86% charged)</td>
<td>159 (73%)</td>
<td>23.2mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/29</td>
<td>88°</td>
<td>138 (73% charged)</td>
<td>126 (60%)</td>
<td>24.7mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/1</td>
<td>94°</td>
<td>148 (73%)</td>
<td>125 (61%)</td>
<td>19.8mi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/1</td>
<td>94°</td>
<td>125</td>
<td>167</td>
<td>40 minutes</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1581535&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A “mouse-deer,” seen once in the last century, has now been caught on film</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600849</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 11:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathleen O'Grady]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600849</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No sightings of the silver-backed chevrotain for most of the last century.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Camera-trap-photo-of-silver-backed-chevrotain-Tragulus-versicolor-800x600.jpeg" alt="Camera-trap photo of silver-backed chevrotain (Tragulus versicolor)."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Camera-trap-photo-of-silver-backed-chevrotain-Tragulus-versicolor.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3000" data-width="4000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Camera-trap photo of silver-backed chevrotain (Tragulus versicolor). (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41559-019-1027-7">SIE/GWC/Leibniz-IZW/NCNP</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Every time field biologist An Nguyen finds a mammal in the wild that he's never seen before, he adds a line to the <a href="https://www.globalwildlife.org/blog/on-the-case-solving-the-mysteries-of-the-lost-silver-backed-chevrotain/">tally count tattoo</a> on his left wrist.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.onezoom.org/life/@Tragulus_versicolor=3611561#x1511,y292,w1.2525">silver-backed chevrotain</a>, a tiny "mouse-deer" native to Vietnam, is a sighting significant for more than just Nguyen's personal tally. There has been only one confirmed record of the elusive mammal since 1910—a specimen obtained from a hunter in 1990—until Nguyen and his team set camera traps that recorded 280 sightings within nine months.</p>
<p>The news, reported this week in Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution, is more than just confirmation that the silver-backed chevrotain is not yet extinct. It means that researchers can start studying it more comprehensively, trying to get a sense of how many are left and what kinds of protections it needs. And protecting the chevrotain also means protecting the less cute, but equally essential, species that share its habitat.</p>
<h2>Most Wanted</h2>
<p>The silver-backed chevrotain is one of the world's "most wanted" mammals. Along with other elusive species like the Pondicherry shark, Attenborough's long-beaked echidna, and the Wondiwoi tree kangaroo, it hadn't been spotted for decades. Despite the lack of sightings, conservationists have had an inkling that these species might not yet be extinct.</p>
<p>For all of these lost species, there's a huge gap in what conservationists know about them. They're not sure where to find them, how many might be left, what threats they face, and how best to save them. The silver-backed chevrotain is listed by the International Union for the Conservation of Nature as "<a href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/136360/61978789">Data Deficient</a>," meaning that there hasn't been enough field research for anyone to know whether they're extinct, endangered, or doing OK—or whether populations are stable, shrinking, or recovering.</p>
<p>Rediscovering lost species means filling in those knowledge gaps, which will allow conservationists to start figuring out what needs to be done to protect these fragile species and their habitats. The organization Global Wildlife Conservation lists <a href="https://www.globalwildlife.org/lost-species-by-the-numbers/">1,200 lost species</a>, highlighting <a href="https://www.globalwildlife.org/search-for-lost-species/">25 of the most charismatic</a>—including the silver-backed chevrotain—as flagship "most wanted" species that can carry the torch for the efforts to find them all.</p>
<h2>Silent forests</h2>
<p>In eastern Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia, the mountains and forests of the Greater Annamites Ecoregion are home to an incredibly diverse range of mammal species. But many of these animals face severe threats from humans. The threat comes from habitat destruction as well as intensive hunting that supplies the thriving wildlife trade in the region.</p>
<p>This hunting mostly uses wire snares, which indiscriminately catch any unlucky animal that happens to stumble through them. The trapping is so pervasive that it has led to "<a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article-abstract/42/6/412/283862?redirectedFrom=fulltext">empty forest syndrome</a>"—an intact forest, eerily devoid of its inhabitants.</p>
<p>Pervasive snaring is what left conservationists unsure whether there were any silver-backed chevrotains remaining in the region. The beasts have been lost twice. After British zoologist Oldfield Thomas <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00222931008692812?needAccess=true&amp;instName=University+of+Edinburgh&amp;journalCode=tnah14">first described them</a> in 1910 based on four dead specimens, there were no more reports of their existence for 80 years. In 1990, Russian researchers <a href="http://zmmu.msu.ru/rjt/articles/ther3_1_09_13_Kuznez_Borisenko.pdf">obtained a specimen</a> from Vietnamese hunters, confirming that the silver-backed chevrotains did still exist.</p>
<p>Then once again, nothing for nearly 30 years. "Given the considerable increase in hunting pressure that has occurred in Vietnam since the early 1990s, it was unclear whether the species still existed," write Nguyen and his co-authors.</p>
<p>The team started out by interviewing villagers and rangers in regions where the silver-backed chevrotain might still be found. A few people described seeing animals that sounded like they fit the bill, and everyone the researchers interviewed pointed out that all chevrotain species were becoming increasingly rare thanks to intensive snaring. Based on the interviews, the researchers set three camera traps in November 2017 and went to retrieve them in April 2018.</p>
<h2>Rediscovered</h2>
<p>The silver-backed chevrotain had shown up at all three camera trap stations—the first pictures of silver-backed chevrotains in the wild. To avoid inflating the numbers, the team counted photos taken within an hour to be a single "event"; the three camera traps had recorded 72 events.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_kl1r93SYHQ?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Video of the elusive mammal. </p></div>
<p>Following up on this success, the researchers set up plenty more camera traps, and captured 208 events between April and July 2018. It's impossible to say how many individual animals this represented, but the new information does mean that the researchers could start sketching out some notes about the species' behavior: it seems to move around during the day, either alone or in pairs.</p>
<p>But there's a huge amount of information still missing. It's essential, the researchers write, to work out how this newly recorded population is doing, search for other populations, and figure out how to combat the threats that the animals are facing: "Together, this information can provide the foundation for an evidence-based conservation plan for the silver-backed chevrotain."</p>
<p>A crucial question is whether this information could put the remaining silver-backed chevrotains in further danger, although there is no specific location information about the sightings. "We carefully weighed the risk of increased hunting owing to an increase in attention to the species," the researchers write.</p>
<p>But that risk needed to be weighed against the benefit of building support for more research and new conservation measures, they point out. "In an age of mass extinctions, confirming the survival of lost species provides rare second chances for biodiversity conservation."</p>
<p>Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution, 2018. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41559-019-1027-7">10.1038/s41559-019-1027-7</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600849&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EPA still moving to limit science used to support regulations</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600865</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 01:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott K. Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lamar smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scott pruitt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600865</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Draft published by New York Times expands on version started under Scott Pruitt.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1175711697-800x561.jpg" alt="Image of a human."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1175711697.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="718" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Andrew Wheeler. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=Win%20McNamee&amp;assettype=image&amp;family=editorial&amp;sort=best&amp;groupbyevent=true#license">Win McNamee / Getty</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Former Texas Congressman Lamar Smith may have retired in January, but his ideas still stalk the halls of the US Environmental Protection Agency. The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/11/climate/epa-science-trump.html">reported Monday</a> that the latest incarnation of Smith's quest to change the science the EPA can use for its rule making is moving forward.</p>

<p>Smith had unsuccessfully pushed a bill called the "<a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/1030">Secret Science Reform Act</a>," which would have required the EPA to consider only those studies with data that is "publicly available in a manner sufficient for independent analysis and substantial reproduction of research results." He claimed that opponents of regulations were often unable to audit the science underlying the regulations—although those opponents could, of course, have done their own science.</p>
<h2>Limiting science</h2>
<p>The scientific community noted that this requirement would have the effect of excluding quite a lot of relevant science published in peer-reviewed journals. In particular, research on the public health impacts of pollutants is only possible through the use of confidential health data. There are systems in place to give researchers controlled access to that data, but releasing it to the public is simply not an option, and doing so very well might violate other federal rules.</p>
<p>Smith couldn't get his bill through Congress, but he worked with former EPA Administrator Scott Pruitt to get it rolling as an internal agency rule change. A 2018 E&amp;E News story <a href="https://www.eenews.net/stories/1060079655">reported that</a> this collaboration ran into an unlikely opponent: the pesticide industry. Those companies must provide safety studies when registering a new pesticide, so they were concerned about the cost of making all their data publicly available, and they were unclear on what form that would take.</p>
<p>The rule change was not finalized before Pruitt's resignation, and current EPA Administrator Andrew Wheeler appeared to take it back to the drawing board. But in a surprising twist, a new draft has appeared that The New York Times described as "headed for White House review." The twist is that the new draft doesn't do much to refocus the rule in a more narrow way that minimizes industry objections. Instead, it has been made broader in some ways.</p>
<p>The first version of the rule only covered the research that quantifies toxicity of things like pollutants and pesticides. This draft removes that limitation. "EPA is modifying the regulatory text initially proposed in the 2018 proposed Rule[…]" it reads, "so that these provisions would apply to all data and models, not only dose-response data and dose-response models."</p>
<h2>Retroactive</h2>
<p>What's more, the rule isn't just for new studies—it could end up applying retroactively. The draft contains multiple options on a couple points, one of which is setting a date <em>after</em> which research would have to comply with these requirements. But if that isn't the option chosen, it would mean that all past research for which data has not been made publicly available would be found to fail the test. If a regulation comes up for renewal or updating, the science on which it was based could then plausibly be excluded from consideration.</p>
<p>Options are also listed for the issue at the heart of the rule—what to do with data that isn't sufficiently public. There are two alternatives to simply dropping that data in the trash bin. One would be to make availability part of the <em>weighting</em> of a study's value. This might not immediately disqualify a study if other characteristics of the work are seen as redeeming. However, the draft reads, "EPA would reserve the right to place less weight on the studies, to the point of entirely disregarding them, if the data and models underlying pivotal regulatory science are not made available in full to EPA."</p>
<p>The other alternative would recognize several tiers of data, from publicly available to "confidential business information" to "personally identifiable information that cannot be anonymized." Access would be different for each tier, with proprietary or personal information only required to be available to "authorized officials and researchers" rather than the general public. It's not clear how many privacy problems that would solve, although it would be easier for companies to navigate, as they would only have to respond to requests rather than publishing their data somewhere permanent.</p>
<p>Assuming this draft goes forward, it will once again be opened to public comment. When Pruitt's version went to public comment last year, more than <a href="https://www.epa.gov/osa/strengthening-transparency-regulatory-science">590,000 such comments</a> were submitted.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600865&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The world finally has an approved vaccine against Ebola</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601141</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Democratic Republic of the Congo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug approval]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infectious disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viral disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WHO]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The WHO wasted no time to "prequalifying" the newly approved vaccine.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/GettyImages-1155783283-800x533.jpg" alt="A nurse in PPE administers a shot to a man in an outdoor clinic."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/GettyImages-1155783283.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3774" data-width="5661">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A man receives a vaccine against Ebola from a nurse outside the Afia Himbi Health Center on July 15, 2019, in Goma.  (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/man-receives-a-vaccine-against-ebola-from-a-nurse-outside-news-photo/1155783283?adppopup=true">Getty | PAMELA TULIZO </a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Regulators in Europe have granted the world's first approval of a vaccine against Ebola—and health officials are wasting no time in rolling it out.</p>
<p>The European Commission announced at the start of the week that it had granted a landmark marketing authorization of Merck's Ebola vaccine Ervebo. The vaccine has been in the works since the 2014 West African Ebola outbreak. It is now being used in the ongoing outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo based on a "compassionate use" protocol.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/03/ebola-cases-surpass-1000-in-drc-outbreak-the-second-largest-of-all-time/">The current outbreak</a> in the DRC <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/ebola/drc-2019">has killed nearly 2,200 since August 2018</a>, causing nearly 3,300 cases. The outbreak is the second-largest recorded, surpassed only by the 2014 West African outbreak that caused more than 11,000 deaths and 28,000 cases.</p>
<p>Preliminary vaccine data from the current DRC outbreak suggested that Ervebo is 97.5% effective at preventing the devastating viral disease. It protected well over 90,000 people in the outbreak.</p>
<p>The vaccine protects against <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vhf/ebola/about.html">one of four species of Ebola known to infect humans</a>—the Zaire ebolavirus species. Zaire is responsible for the current outbreak in the DRC, as well as the 2014 West African outbreak, and <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/ebola-virus-disease">nearly all other outbreaks recorded</a> since Ebola was first discovered in 1976.</p>
<p>"Finding a vaccine as soon as possible against this terrible virus has been a priority for the international community ever since Ebola hit West Africa five years ago," European Commissioner Vytenis Andriukaitis said in a statement Sunday, November 10. "Today's decision is therefore a major step forward in saving lives in Africa and beyond."</p>
<p>The vaccine was initially developed by researchers at the Public Health Agency of Canada's National Microbiology Laboratory, which subsequently licensed it to NewLink Genetics Corporation. Merck obtained the license in 2014 amid the West African outbreak and developed it further.</p>
<p>The company celebrated the vaccine's approval Monday.</p>
<p>"It is a historic milestone and a testament to the power of science, innovation and public-private partnership," Merck <a href="https://www.mrknewsroom.com/news-release/ebola/mercks-ervebo-ebola-zaire-vaccine-rvsvdg-zebov-gp-live-granted-conditional-approv">CEO Kenneth Frazier said in a statement</a>. "After recognizing the need and urgency for an Ebola Zaire vaccine, many came together across sectors to answer the global call for outbreak preparedness. We at Merck are honored to play a part in Ebola outbreak response efforts and we remain committed to our partners and the people we serve."</p>
<p>The US Food and Drug Administration is expected to make an approval decision on the vaccine in March 2020.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the World Health Organization announced Tuesday, November 12 that it has "<a href="https://www.who.int/immunization_standards/vaccine_quality/pq_system/en/">prequalified</a>" Ervebo, signaling to member countries that the vaccine meets WHO standards for safety, quality, and effectiveness. In an announcement, the WHO noted that it was "the fastest vaccine prequalification process ever conducted by WHO" and came less than 48 hours after the European Commission approved the vaccine. The organization said it is also working to facilitate licensing in countries at risk of Ebola outbreaks.</p>
<p>"[Prequalification] is a historic step towards ensuring the people who most need it are able to access this life-saving vaccine," WHO Director-General Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said in the announcement. "Five years ago, we had no vaccine and no therapeutics for Ebola. With a prequalified vaccine and experimental therapeutics, Ebola is now preventable and treatable."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601141&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US violated Constitution by searching phones for no good reason, judge rules</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601063</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACLU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suspicionless searches]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601063</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ICE and Customs violated 4th Amendment with suspicionless searches, ruling says.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-border-patrol-800x534.jpg" alt="US Customs and Border Protection agents participate in a training exercise at the border with Mexico."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-border-patrol.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> US Customs and Border Protection agents participate in a training exercise at a vehicle entry point along the border with Mexico on November 5, 2018, in Hidalgo, Texas. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=andrew%20cullen&amp;assettype=image&amp;mediatype=photography&amp;sort=best">Getty Images | Andrew Cullen</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The United States government violated the Fourth Amendment with its suspicionless searches of international travelers' phones and laptops, a federal court <a href="https://www.aclu.org/sites/default/files/field_document/alasaad_opinion_summary_judgment.pdf">ruled today</a>.</p>
<p>The ruling came in a case filed "on behalf of 11 travelers whose smartphones and laptops were searched without individualized suspicion at US ports of entry," the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) <a href="https://www.aclu.org/press-releases/federal-court-rules-suspicionless-searches-travelers-phones-and-laptops">said today</a>. The ACLU teamed up with the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) to fight the government on behalf of plaintiffs including 10 US citizens and one lawful permanent resident.</p>
<p>The order from a US District Court in Massachusetts limits what searches can be made by US Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE).</p>
<p>"The district court order puts an end to CBP and ICE's <a href="https://www.aclu.org/legal-document/alasaad-v-nielsen-motion-summary-judgement">asserted authority</a> to search and seize travelers' devices for purposes far afield from the enforcement of immigration and customs laws," the ACLU announcement said. "Border officers must now demonstrate individualized suspicion of contraband before they can search a traveler's device."</p>
<p>Because of the ruling, travelers will be able to "cross the international border without fear that the government will, in the absence of any suspicion, ransack the extraordinarily sensitive information we all carry in our electronic devices," EFF Senior Staff Attorney Sophia Cope said.</p>
<p>The US government could appeal the ruling.</p>
<h2>Judge: Searches require reasonable suspicion</h2>
<p>US District Judge Denise Casper's ruling granted the plaintiffs' request for a declaration that the government violated their constitutional rights by conducting searches and seizures "of electronic devices absent a warrant supported by probable cause."</p>
<p>The ruling said:</p>
<blockquote><p>[T]he Court declares that the CBP and ICE policies for "basic" and "advanced" searches, as presently defined, violate the Fourth Amendment to the extent that the policies do not require reasonable suspicion that the devices contain contraband for both such classes of non-cursory searches and/or seizure of electronic devices; and that the non-cursory searches and/or seizures of plaintiffs' electronic devices, without such reasonable suspicion, violated the Fourth Amendment.</p></blockquote>
<p>CBP defines "advanced" searches as those "in which an officer connects external equipment, through a wired or wireless connection, to an electronic device, not merely to gain access to the device, but to review, copy and/or analyze its contents." Anything short of that is a "basic" search.</p>
<p>The court ruling said that CBP's policy was "to require reasonable suspicion or a national security concern for any advanced search, but no showing of cause for a basic search." The judge ruled that both types of searches require reasonable suspicion.</p>
<p>"Although governmental interests are paramount at the border, where such non-cursory searches—even 'basic' searches as broadly defined under CBP and ICE policies as well as the 'advanced' searches of plaintiffs' electronic devices—amount to non-routine searches, they require reasonable suspicion that the devices contain contraband," Casper wrote.</p>
<p>It wasn't all good news for plaintiffs though: Judge Casper's ruling denied their request for an injunction that would have more strictly limited the government's ability to search and seize devices. But the ruling denied the request for injunctive relief <em>without prejudice</em>, so it can be raised again in future proceedings. To apply a nationwide injunction, the court would need "further briefing from the parties" involved in the case, Casper wrote.</p>
<p>Despite that, the ACLU said the ruling should lead to real change in government policy.</p>
<p>"This ruling significantly advances Fourth Amendment protections for the millions of international travelers who enter the United States every year," ACLU staff attorney Esha Bhandari said. "By putting an end to the government's ability to conduct suspicionless fishing expeditions, the court reaffirms that the border is not a lawless place and that we don't lose our privacy rights when we travel."</p>
<h2>Some plaintiffs’ phones were searched repeatedly</h2>
<p>Casper's ruling contains some details of the contested searches and seizures. Nadia Alasaad, one of the 11 plaintiffs, "has twice had her iPhones searched at the border over her religious objections to having CBP officers, especially male officers, view photos of her and her daughters without their headscarves as required in public by their religious beliefs," the ruling said.</p>
<p>One plaintiff "observed a CBP officer viewing communications between her and her lawyer," another plaintiff's "phone contained information from his work as a journalist," and another plaintiff's "phone was a work phone officially owned by NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory," the ruling said. Federal officials did not dispute that they retained information that they got from these searches of electronic devices.</p>
<p>Multiple plaintiffs had their electronic devices seized during the border searches, although they were later returned.</p>
<p>The ruling noted that the harm to plaintiffs from the searches is ongoing, as "agents have the potential to access information on a traveler's past searches and... such information may be used to inform decisions on future searches."</p>
<p>The ruling includes this example:</p>
<blockquote><p>The recent additional search of [plaintiff Suhaib] Allababidi's devices on July 6, 2019, furthers plaintiffs' argument as to the risk of future harm. Allababidi had previously been subject to a border search on January 24, 2017. When he declined to provide the password to his locked phone, CBP seized it to conduct an examination. On July 6, 2019, Allababidi arrived at the Toronto airport for a flight to Dallas, traveling with a smartphone and a laptop. CBP officers searched both devices. That such search of electronic devices continues for plaintiffs, even in the midst of their ongoing legal challenges to same, serves as further, undisputed indication of the sufficient likelihood that, unremedied, such alleged harm will continue in the future, particularly given the plaintiffs' future plans for international travel.</p></blockquote>
<p>The government told the court that electronic-device searches were conducted on .007% of the hundreds of millions of international travelers processed by CBP in 2017. But the judge wrote that "the number of reported electronic devices likely is underestimated" because of apparent shortcomings in how CBP calculates its data and because "ICE does not maintain records of the number of basic searches that it conducts." The judge concluded that "the likelihood of plaintiffs having their electronic devices searched without cause is not a remote risk."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1601063&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How does Plume get all these ISP partnerships? Open source software</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600881</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 22:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Salter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600881</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Simplified device management might be more attractive than Wi-Fi mesh itself.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/opensync-cloud-diagram-1.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          This is the most basic overview of what OpenSync is and where it fits in a network diagram—it's a bridge from Wi-Fi devices to a cloud-based management and control system.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.plume.com/">Plume</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Yesterday, Charter Communications*—the second-largest ISP in the United States—<a href="https://newsroom.charter.com/press-releases/charter-adopts-opensync-the-fastest-growing-open-sourced-framework-for-spectrums-advanced-in-home-wifi/">announced</a> its adoption of the OpenSync software platform for Spectrum's advanced in-home Wi-Fi. This raises a few questions, first of which is "what's OpenSync?"</p>
<p>The short answer is "Plume," which in turn means that Plume now has partnerships with the first- and second-largest ISPs in the United States, as well as the first- and second-largest in Canada—and also with the National Cable Television Collective (<a href="https://www.nctconline.org/index.php/about-nctc">NCTC</a>), a membership organization comprising several hundred independent US cable companies.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, we <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/plume-takes-another-step-toward-fixing-isps-crappy-wi-fi-worldwide/">covered</a> the announcement of a Plume partnership with J:COM, Japan's largest ISP. In that coverage, we referenced tighter integration into ISPs' existing infrastructure than better-known mesh alternatives such as Eero, Google (now <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/ars-puts-googles-new-nest-wi-fi-to-the-test/">Nest</a>) Wi-Fi, or Orbi can provide. OpenSync is where that tighter integration comes from.</p>
<h2>It’s all about the cloud</h2>
<p>From its infancy, Plume has insisted that its cloud optimizer is the magic sauce that makes its little pods great. The cloud optimizer uses machine-learning techniques to analyze telemetry from customer-deployed pod and superpod networks. The optimizer determines which topologies and which uses of Wi-Fi channels are optimal to support each customer's client devices in that customer's specific environment.</p>
<p>The cloud optimizer can route around congestion from neighboring networks as well as minimize its own congestive problems. The cloud optimizer—and its massive ingestion of client telemetry—also gives Plume information about broad classes of device, identifiable by BSSID or MAC address, that have consistent problems of their own. This has enabled the company to create proprietary, device-specific rulesets for devices such as iPhones and iPads that tend to have particular problems with common Wi-Fi issues such as roaming or use of DFS spectrum.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/plume-superpods-NOC-postDFS-cropped.png"><img alt='Plume&#039;s cloud optimizer makes predictions about near-future service needs based on telemetry taken from its Wi-Fi pods, and it changes the pods&#039; configuration accordingly.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/plume-superpods-NOC-postDFS-cropped-640x625.png" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/plume-superpods-NOC-postDFS-cropped.png 2x" alt='Plume&#039;s cloud optimizer makes predictions about near-future service needs based on telemetry taken from its Wi-Fi pods, and it changes the pods&#039; configuration accordingly.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/plume-superpods-NOC-postDFS-cropped.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Plume's cloud optimizer makes predictions about near-future service needs based on telemetry taken from its Wi-Fi pods, and it changes the pods' configuration accordingly.</a> (credit: Plume)</p></div>
<p>This does help make your Wi-Fi better, but from an ISP's perspective, that's just a bonus. The real value proposition for ISPs is better support, with faster and cheaper ISP development pipelines. Plume's virtual NOC makes it easy for a support technician to see just what's going on in a customer's network and, therefore, make helpful and accurate assessments about problems. If a customer calls in to complain that their Apple TV, Fire Stick, or Roku keeps buffering, a technician can see at a glance whether the problem is low signal strength or congestion, and they can offer advice accordingly.</p>
<h2>Connecting all the things</h2>
<p>Fitting existing cable modems and routers into this kind of enhanced support infrastructure is a big challenge for an ISP. It's one thing to offer pods (or Eero routers and beacons) to customers, but it's another thing entirely to blend that infrastructure in seamlessly with the existing Wi-Fi capabilities of the hundreds of thousands—or millions—of existing cable or DSL modem/router gateways the company has already deployed.</p>
<p>ISPs don't want to have to support two different infrastructures—a "basic" one for "just the modem" customers and an "advanced" one for customers who paid a little extra for mesh. ISPs also don't want to leave money on the table by disabling perfectly capable Wi-Fi APs built into their gateway devices and plugging in a separate "router" device where the modem/gateway already is. That's where OpenSync comes in.</p>
<p>Plume has always envisioned its cloud infrastructure being largely hardware-independent and able to use non-Plume hardware as additional access points in a Plume network. In its earlier days of building ISP partnerships, the company offered to do the software integration—building its front end into the firmware on ISPs' modems and gateway devices—directly. This created a significant pain point, as there were intellectual property concerns involved on both sides.</p>
<p>In response, Plume re-developed OpenSync as a more generic front-end framework, and it offered the entire codebase directly to its partners. This allowed ISPs to do their own integration into firmware, solving two problems—the ISPs no longer needed to develop and maintain massive cloud infrastructure to manage and support their customers' Wi-Fi effectively, and they no longer needed to do anywhere near as much firmware customization on each new model of gateway device.</p>
<h2>Hedging bets and increasing adoption with OSS</h2>
<p>Releasing Plume's front end as open source software (OSS) does more than accelerate the development pipeline for ISPs. It also overcomes a potential objection to adoption—vendor lock-in.</p>
<p>Plume's tentacles aren't just spreading into major ISPs—they're even reaching Wi-Fi chipset vendors themselves. OpenSync is being adopted into <a href="https://wiki.rdkcentral.com/display/RDK/RDK-B+Overview">RDK-B</a>, the Reference Design Kit for Broadband. RBK-B is itself a collaborative open source initiative designed to standardize software functionality in modem and gateway devices, spearheaded by Arris and Cisco. OpenSync is also finding its way into Wi-Fi SoCs themselves, such as Quantenna's <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2019/02/25/1741250/0/en/Quantenna-and-Plume-Showcase-World-s-First-OpenSync-Wi-Fi-6-Integration-at-MWC.html">QSR5GU-AX Plus</a>, a Wi-Fi 6 SoC released earlier this year.</p>
<p>This wouldn't likely be possible without the assurances against vendor lock-in that open source software provides. Plume CEO Fahri Diner told Ars on a call that "Plume wants to be friends with everybody," meaning in part that the company envisions itself as providing Wi-Fi support infrastructure for as many organizations as possible. Opening up the software and APIs necessary for both the front end and back end of the cloud infrastructure connection makes this considerably more feasible.</p>
<p>Although Plume is currently the only big cloud infrastructure you can connect an OpenSync-enabled client to, that won't be the case forever. In the call, Diner alluded to at least one organization that's currently building out a back-end infrastructure that can be connected to with the OpenSync front end. Diner doesn't see this as a threat—or at least, not enough of a threat to offset the obvious advantages of reference software frameworks and even Wi-Fi SoCs that can be connected to Plume's cloud just by dropping in a couple of lines in a config file.</p>
<h2>Is it really open source?</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/opensync-license.png"><img alt='OpenSync is released under the BSD 3-clause license. Effectively, this license makes the software itself available while protecting the project&#039;s branding.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/opensync-license-640x422.png" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/opensync-license.png 2x" alt='OpenSync is released under the BSD 3-clause license. Effectively, this license makes the software itself available while protecting the project&#039;s branding.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/opensync-license.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">OpenSync is released under the BSD 3-clause license. Effectively, this license makes the software itself available while protecting the project's branding.</a> (credit: Jim Salter)</p></div>
<p>OpenSync is <a href="https://github.com/plume-design/opensync/">available</a> under the BSD <a href="https://choosealicense.com/licenses/bsd-3-clause/">3-Clause</a> license. This is an Open Source Initiative-<a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/BSD-3-Clause">approved</a> open source license which falls into the general category of "weak" OSS licenses. That means, in effect, that modifications made to the original project are not required to be open source themselves. A weakly licensed project can even be redistributed as fully proprietary software, with no distribution of or access to the source code required.</p>
<p>Unlike the more-popular MIT <a href="https://choosealicense.com/licenses/mit/">license</a>, the BSD 3-clause license specifically protects the original project's branding. Redistribution of the original project requires the retention of the original copyright notice, in both source code and documentation, while also restricting redistributors from promoting derived products without explicit written consent from the project owners.</p>
<p><em>* The Advance/Newhouse Partnership, which owns 13 percent of Charter, is part of Advance Publications. Advance Publications owns Condé Nast, which owns Ars Technica.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600881&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla announces its next car factory will be near Berlin</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600991</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gigafactory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA["Everyone knows that German engineering is outstanding," Musk said.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1035243680-800x534.jpg" alt="Elon Musk."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1035243680.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Elon Musk. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=david%20mcnew&amp;sort=mostpopular#license">DAVID MCNEW/AFP/Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Tesla's next "Gigafactory" will be in the Berlin area, Elon Musk announced at an event in Germany on Tuesday evening. Techcrunch's <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/elon-musk-picks-berlin-for-teslas-europe-gigafactory/">Kirsten Korosec reports</a> that Musk made the comments during an on-stage conversation with Volkswagen CEO Herbert Diess at the Golden Steering Wheel awards show.</p>
<p>The original Gigafactory was Tesla's massive battery factory in Nevada. Musk dubbed it a "Gigafactory" because it was designed to produce batteries with gigawatt-hours of storage capacity. Batteries are made in Nevada and then shipped to Tesla's car factory in Fremont, California, for final assembly.</p>
<p>When Tesla built a car manufacturing facility in Shanghai, China, the company dubbed that "Gigafactory 3." (Tesla's <a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/tesla-gigafactory-2-new-york-write-down-value/">beleaguered</a> solar panel factory in Buffalo, NY, is <a href="https://www.tesla.com/gigafactory2">Gigafactory 2</a>.) Tesla took a more integrated approach in China, building batteries and cars in the same facility.</p>

<p>It's a reasonable guess that Tesla will take the same integrated approach for its Berlin Gigafactory, which will likely be called Gigafactory 4. Musk said Tuesday that the new facility would be "near the new airport," Korosec reports.</p>
<p>The effort has been a long time coming. "We are accelerating our European Gigafactory efforts and are hoping to finalize a location choice in the coming quarters," Tesla wrote in its <a href="https://ir.tesla.com/static-files/1e70a30c-20a7-48b3-a1f6-696a7c517959">quarterly letter</a> to shareholders in July.</p>
<p>It makes sense for Tesla to build a manufacturing facility in Europe. Tesla sells a lot of cars in Europe, and the logistics of shipping cars from California to Europe are complex.</p>
<p>Tesla is also planning to create an engineering and design center in Berlin, Musk added.</p>
<p>"Everyone knows that German engineering is outstanding, and that’s part of the reason we’re locating our Gigafactory Europe in Germany," Musk said.</p>
<p>Tesla has almost completed construction of its Shanghai Gigafactory and is aiming to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/11/tesla-shows-off-chinese-made-model-3s-ahead-of-shanghai-factory-start/">begin volume manufacturing</a> there before the end of the year. The company says it's waiting for regulatory approval from local officials there.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600991&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon gains unfair edge by making sellers use its shipping, complaint says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600799</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chinese knockoffs and Amazon's shipping carrot/stick hurt vendors, reports say.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1157406884-800x533.jpg" alt="The Amazon logo at the entrance of a logistics center in France, July 2019."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1157406884.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1959" data-width="2939">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The Amazon logo at the entrance of a logistics center in France, July 2019. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/picture-shows-the-amazon-logo-at-the-entrance-of-the-amazon-news-photo/1157406884">Denis Charlet | AFP | Getty </a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Amazon has come quite a way from when it was just an online bookstore, but it still operates a booming retail business among all its other ventures. A majority of the retail products sold on Amazon aren't actually sold <em>by</em> Amazon at all but rather by its sprawling network of third-party "marketplace" vendors. The company's relationships with those vendors, foreign and domestic, are at the center of a web of investigations and criticism.</p>
<p>Third-party retailers accounted for about 58% of Amazon's retail activity in 2018, company CEO Jeff Bezos said earlier this year, and they sold a cumulative $160 billion worth of goods. But those goods are sold in a "flea market" environment with minimal quality control, leading to ubiquitous counterfeits or <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/report-finds-more-than-4100-unsafe-or-recalled-listings-on-amazon/">recalled goods</a> available for sale from fly-by-night merchants. If something goes wrong with your sale, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/amazon-on-the-hook-for-third-party-goods-that-cause-injury-federal-court-says/">getting recourse from these sellers is impossible</a>.</p>
<h2>Risky imports</h2>
<p>All those kinda shady Amazon listings from companies in China you never heard of? They're not a bug, The Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazons-heavy-recruitment-of-chinese-sellers-puts-consumers-at-risk-11573489075">reports today</a>. They're a feature, present by design.</p>
<p>Amazon began a deliberate campaign in 2013 urging businesses in China to use its platform to sell directly to international customers, the WSJ writes. In 2017, an Amazon sales director based in China told business leaders in that country, "We help factories directly open accounts on Amazon and sell to US customers directly. This is our value."</p>
<p>The company made its website fully available in Mandarin in 2015, and by 2016, its team for recruiting and helping Chinese vendors was up to 150 employees, a former Amazon employee told the WSJ.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the Journal found <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/report-finds-more-than-4100-unsafe-or-recalled-listings-on-amazon/">thousands</a> of defective, recalled, or banned items for sale on Amazon. Those goods were sold by thousands of different merchants. Of the nearly 2,000 the WSJ could identify addresses for, 54% were based in China.</p>
<p>As of October, about 38% of the 10,000 most-reviewed merchant accounts on Amazon were based in China, analysts found; that number was around 25% in 2016. The WSJ and analytics firm Marketplace Pulse had to discern the business locations from their merchant pages on Amazon's Mexico site, as vendors are not required to disclose their locations on the US site.</p>
<p>Amazon disputed the WSJ's number, calling it "a significant exaggeration of the real percentage of the top 10 thousand." Amazon, however, did not provide a different number.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, new product listings appear on Amazon from China every 1/50th of a second, according to the WSJ, and that comes with some headaches. "Concerns at Amazon about Chinese listings arose several years ago in its China team, which noticed that, as local sellers flocked to the platform, it saw increasing patterns of fraud, counterfeits, and unsafe products," former Amazon employees based in China told the WSJ.</p>
<p>"Bad actors make up a tiny fraction of activity in our store and, like honest sellers, can come from every corner of the world," Amazon told the WSJ in response. "Regardless of where they are based, we work hard to stop bad actors before they can impact the shopping or selling experience in our store."</p>
<h2>When Amazon’s the bad actor</h2>
<p>Amazon's handling of its US marketplace vendors, meanwhile, is under deep scrutiny by federal regulators. Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-08/amazon-merchant-lays-out-antitrust-case-in-letter-to-congress">recently obtained</a> a letter one Amazon merchant sent to the House Antitrust Subcommittee, which is investigating Amazon, accusing the company of anticompetitive acts. </p>
<p>The letter "accuses Amazon of tying its marketplace and logistics services together," Bloomberg reports—using dominance in one business market to gain leverage in another, in a way that violates competition law.</p>
<p>Amazon has focused intensely on increasing its own in-house shipping business in recent years, and it now contracts with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/amazon-delivery-contractors-operates-with-little-oversight-report-finds/">hundreds of third-party last-mile firms</a> to get products from its warehouses to your door. That Prime-branded delivery service has continued to grow as competitors <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/fedex-leaves-amazon-on-the-doorstep-as-the-store-becomes-a-competitor/">such as FedEx</a> have stopped working with Amazon.</p>
<p>The merchant alleges that fees for using Amazon logistics have increased by 20% over the past four years and now cost as much as 35% more than competing services. But vendors are forced into paying the higher fees and using Amazon anyway, the complaint says, because Amazon promotes discovery for products it can mark as "fulfilled by Amazon" and demotes those that are not.</p>
<p>"The sticks Amazon uses to coerce merchants to use its logistics services are strict penalties, including getting kicked off the platform, for merchants who handle their own logistics," Bloomberg reports. "Merchants using Amazon logistics services aren't penalized when customer orders arrive late, even though they frequently do, since that’s Amazon’s responsibility. Those who handle their own logistics face stiff penalties for even minor delivery mishaps, including being suspended from selling on the platform," the vendor alleges.</p>
<p>The claims come as Amazon faces antitrust probes <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/antitrust-101-why-everyone-is-probing-amazon-apple-facebook-and-google/">in both the US and EU</a> investigating its marketplace. Critics say that the company collects data from third-party marketplace sales to choose what it should produce and promote in its own house brands.</p>
<p>"When providing a marketplace for independent sellers, Amazon continuously collects data about the activity on its platform," the European Commission's competition bureau <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_19_4291">said in July</a>. "Based on the Commission's preliminary fact-finding, Amazon appears to use competitively sensitive information—about marketplace sellers, their products and transactions on the marketplace," to boost its own sales.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600799&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dealmaster: Get a year of Disney+ for free if you’re a Verizon Wireless user</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600779</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealmaster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600779</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Or a new Fios or 5G user. Plus deals on Kindle Unlimited, AMD CPUs, and more.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111219-800x444.png" alt="Dealmaster: Get a year of Disney+ for free if you’re a Verizon Wireless user"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111219.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1200" data-width="2160">Enlarge</a> (credit: Ars Technica)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Greetings, Arsians! The Dealmaster is back once again with a new round of deals and price drops. Today's list is headlined by a quick PSA for those who subscribe to a Verizon unlimited data plan or plan to subscribe to a Fios home Internet plan: if you're at all interested the new <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/we-now-know-what-disney-will-look-like-plus-a-few-new-exclusive-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disney+ streaming service</a>, you can get a <a href="https://www.verizonwireless.com/solutions-and-services/disneyplus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12-month subscription at no extra cost</a>. As a refresher, Disney's Netflix competitor launched on Tuesday and <a href="http://disneyplus.bn5x.net/4YV4G" target="_blank" rel="noopener">normally costs $7 a month or $70 a year</a>.</p>
<p>Now, as is often the case with mobile carrier promos, there's some <a href="https://www.verizonwireless.com/support/disney-faqs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fine print to sort through</a>. To get the free year of service, you need to subscribe to one of the carrier's Verizon Unlimited, Go Unlimited, Beyond Unlimited, Above Unlimited, Get More Unlimited, Do More Unlimited, Pay More Unlimited, or Start Unlimited plans. (If you're marveling at the fact that Verizon has had this many unlimited plans, many of which <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/06/verizons-new-95-unlimited-plan-offers-at-least-75gb-of-high-speed-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">aren't actually unlimited</a>, you're not alone.) Both new and existing subscribers are eligible; Verizon has options on its promo page for existing subscribers who wish to switch to an unlimited plan and those who wish to move over from another carrier.</p>
<p>The offer is <a href="https://www.verizon.com/support/residential/account/manage-service/disney-redemption-faqs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">also available</a> to Verizon Fios home Internet users and the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/09/verizon-plans-5g-home-internet-in-every-city-where-it-deploys-mobile-5g/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">handful of people</a> who can access its 5G Home plan, but only if you're a new subscriber, not if you have currently pay for one of those services. For Fios users, you'll need a standalone Internet plan of at least 50/50 Mbps service, a two-year "Triple Play" bundle, or a 2-year Internet + TV "Double Play" bundle. Either way, all of this has you signing up for Disney+ through Verizon, not Disney.</p>
<p>Some items worth noting: it's possible to redeem the offer through the Web or the <a href="https://twitter.com/glkcreative/status/1194253110400692225" target="_blank" rel="noopener">carrier's mobile app</a>, and Verizon says the offer is not available to prepaid or business plan customers of any sort. The email address you use to register for the promo with Verizon can't already be in use by an active Disney+ account, either. If you're eligible for the free 12 months but already bought a Disney+ subscription ahead of time, though, the carrier says its promo will not replace your existing purchase; instead, that purchase will simply be paused and you can use it once the 12 months from this promotional offer have been used. (That said, we'd still advise you to keep an eye on your account and registered email address to make sure everything is managed correctly.)</p>
<p>If you're both a Verizon Wireless <em>and</em> a new Fios user, you can technically redeem the promo twice with separate email addresses and get two years of Disney+, since Verizon treats the two services as different accounts. If you didn't purchase an annual or multi-year Disney+ subscription before you redeem the offer, Verizon will automatically renew your Disney+ service at $7 a month once the promo period expires. And the carrier says the whole promo will be available until June 1, 2020.</p>
<p>Got all that? If you're not interested in Verizon, or you'd rather just wait until Disney+ sorts through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/high-demand-causes-login-problems-on-disney-launch-day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the myriad technical problems</a> it's having at launch, we also have deals on Kindle Unlimited subscriptions, robot vacuums, USB-C chargers, gaming laptops, and more. Have a look at the full list below.</p>
<div class="ars-component-layout ars-newsletter-callbox full" data-list-id="248915">
    <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-container">
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-header">    
            <h5 class="ars-newsletter-callbox-title">
                Dealmaster: An Ars newsletter
            </h5>
            <span class="ars-dotted-pattern"></span>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-content">    
            <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-description">The Dealmaster is launching its very own newsletter! Sign up to receive a shorter, tightly curated list of the very best tech deals on the Web—no nonsense, direct to your inbox, and often before they make it to the Ars homepage.</div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-button-container">
            <a class="button button-orange ars-newsletter-callbox-button" href="https://arstechnica.com/newsletters?subscribe=248915">Sign Me Up!</a>  
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Top 10 deals of the day</h2>
<ul>
<li>Verizon Wireless unlimited plan customers, new Verizon Fios Home Internet customers, and new Verizon 5G customers only: <a href="https://www.verizonwireless.com/solutions-and-services/disneyplus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disney Plus 12-month membership</a> for <strong>free</strong> at Verizon (normally $69.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2phf3w4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort Strip PD 2 Mini</a> power strip - 18W USB-C PD, 2x USB-A, 2x AC for <strong>$24.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $33.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KdTZxN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribit XSound Go</a> portable Bluetooth speaker for <strong>$23.39</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon </strong>and use code: <strong>KBPYCM7E </strong>- normally $32.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Joy-Con-Charging-Grip-Simultaneous-Play-and-Charge-45496590178%2F55449979&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch Joy-Con Charging Grip</a> for <strong>$18.46</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/32GBGY8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $25.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34VO1ti" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eufy RoboVac 30C</a> robot vacuum for <strong>$191.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $100 coupon</strong> - normally $299.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32FZVpB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link Kasa HS200</a> smart WiFi light switch for <strong>$19.49</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon</strong> - normally $26.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZkHBV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FiiO μBTR</a> portable Bluetooth headphone adapter for <strong>$22.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $27.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Ideas-LEGO-NASA-Apollo-Saturn-V-21309%2F55231379&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Ideas NASA Apollo Saturn V 21309</a> building kit (1,900 pieces) for <strong>$89.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2q5GUQ8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMD Ryzen 7 3700X</a> 8-core 16-thread desktop processor + Xbox Game Pass for PC 3-month membership + <em>Borderlands 3 </em>(PC) or <em>The Outer Worlds </em>(PC) for <strong>$309.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $329).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33T5bHC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a> 6-month membership for <strong>$29.97</strong> at Amazon (normally $59.94).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Laptop and desktop PC deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNVIDIA-G-Strix-1660-FHD-GTX-IPS-Intel-GeForce-8GB-DDR4-II-includes-NVMe-120Hz-ROG-i5-9300H-SSD-Asus-512GB-Laptop-Gladius-Mouse-Ti-GL531GU-WB53-B-Gami%2F359426903&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Asus ROG Strix G</a> gaming laptop - Intel Core i5-9300H, 15.6-inch 1080p 120Hz, 8GB RAM, 512GB SSD, GTX 1660 Ti 6GB + Asus ROG Gladius II gaming mouse for <strong>$899</strong> at Walmart (normally $1,299).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32tfmRO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple MacBook Pro</a> (latest model) laptop - 1.4GHz Intel Core i5-8257U, 13.3-inch 2560x1600, 8GB RAM, 256GB SSD for <strong>$1,299.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $1,429).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2q5GUQ8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMD Ryzen 7 3700X</a> 8-core 16-thread desktop processor + Xbox Game Pass for PC 3-month membership + <em>Borderlands 3 </em>(PC) or <em>The Outer Worlds </em>(PC) for <strong>$309.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $329).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33HSHlZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24-inch Dell UltraSharp U2415</a> monitor - 1920x1200, IPS, 60Hz for <strong>$199.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $214.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Gaming deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Joy-Con-Charging-Grip-Simultaneous-Play-and-Charge-45496590178%2F55449979&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch Joy-Con Charging Grip</a> for <strong>$18.46</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/32GBGY8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $25.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-wireless-controller-for-xbox-one-and-windows-10-black%2F5621843.p%3FskuId%3D5621843&amp;subid1=dealmaster102219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Xbox Wireless Controller</a> for Xbox One and Windows 10 - compatible with iOS 13 for <strong>$39.99</strong> at Best Buy and <a href="https://amzn.to/32EdFSw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $49.99).</li>
<li><a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster102219&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerA-Wireless-Controller-for-Nintendo-Switch-GameCube-Style-Purple-1507452-01%2F436100675" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PowerA Wireless GameCube-Style Controller</a> for Nintendo Switch for <strong>$33.99 </strong>at Walmart (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Q3r575" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HyperX Pulsefire Surge</a> wired gaming mouse for <strong>$32.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $46.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g920-driving-force-racing-wheel-for-xbox-one-and-windows-black%2F4223402.p%3FskuId%3D4223402&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G920 Driving Force</a> racing wheel controller for Xbox One and PC for <strong>$199.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $219.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-G203-Prodigy-Wired-Gaming-Mouse-Optical-6-Buttons%2F342327342&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G203 Prodigy</a> wired RGB gaming mouse for <strong>$20.99</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g203-prodigy-wired-optical-gaming-mouse-with-rgb-lighting-black%2F5799700.p%3FskuId%3D5799700&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://amzn.to/33gIcWV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $26.49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36PuDjd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corsair K95 RGB Platinum</a> wired mechanical gaming keyboard - Cherry MX Speed for <strong>$129.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fcorsair-k95-rgb-platinum-mechanical-gaming-keyboard-cherry-mx-speed-rgb-led-backlit-black%2F5713210.p%3FskuId%3D5713210&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $164.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2JQOxQY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Catan</a> </em>board game for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $39.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F7-Wonders-Strategy-Board-Game%2F30655387&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>7 Wonders</em></a> board game for <strong>$29.92 </strong>at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/31PwEs4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $36.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHitman-2-Warner-Bros-PlayStation-4-883929639571%2F755532848&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Hitman 2</em></a> (PS4, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHitman-2-Warner-Bros-Xbox-One-883929639564%2F817700036&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XB1</a>) for <strong>$17.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2qJcCTg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $24.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2q62TGD" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Collection of Mana</a> </em>(Switch) - includes <em>Final Fantasy Adventure</em>, <em>Secret of Mana</em>, <em>Trials of Mana </em>for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fcollection-of-mana-standard-edition-nintendo-switch%2F6352162.p%3FskuId%3D6352162&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $39.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2CDvp58" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Final Fantasy XV Royal Edition</a> </em>(PS4) for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMario-Tennis-Aces-Nintendo-Nintendo-Switch-045496592639%2F398355044&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Mario Tennis Aces</em></a> (Switch) for <strong>$38.94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/370LjnU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $49.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Worlds-Warner-Bros-PlayStation-4-883929561803%2F234060369&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Worlds</a> </em>(PS4) for <strong>$12 </strong>at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2reXFsx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $15.99).</li>
<li>Pre-order: <em><a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Brothers-PlayStation-4-883929689613%2F786104378" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cyberpunk 2077</a></em> (PS4, <a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Bros-Xbox-One-883929689620%2F973645137" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XB1</a>) for <strong>$49.94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2LwLwXn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $59.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Electronics deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Qczm91" target="_blank" rel="noopener">55-inch Vizio M558-G1 M-Series Quantum</a> (2019 model) 4K HDR LED TV for <strong>$473.17</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FVIZIO-55-Class-M-Series-Quantum-4k-Ultra-HD-2160p-HDR-Smart-TV-M558-G1-2019-Model%2F239027548&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Walmart</a> (<strong>clip $4.83</strong> <strong>coupon </strong>- normally $548).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGarmin-Vivoactive-3%2F280563492%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Garmin Vivoactive 3</a> GPS smartwatch for <strong>$149.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2pWQy7P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $179.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KdTZxN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribit XSound Go</a> portable Bluetooth speaker for <strong>$23.39</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon </strong>and use code: <strong>KBPYCM7E </strong>- normally $32.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32FZVpB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link Kasa HS200</a> smart WiFi light switch for <strong>$19.49</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon</strong> - normally $26.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34VO1ti" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eufy RoboVac 30C</a> robot vacuum for <strong>$191.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $100 coupon</strong> - normally $299.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZkHBV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FiiO μBTR</a> portable Bluetooth headphone adapter for <strong>$22.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $27.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/321a2oK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chamberlain MyQ Smart Garage Hub</a> smart garage door opener for <strong>$29.98</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fchamberlain-myq-smart-garage-hub-black%2F5900972.p%3FskuId%3D5900972&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ygq8D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WD Elements</a> (8TB) desktop hard drive for <strong>$124.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $139.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FWD-My-Passport-4TB%2F692843877&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WD My Passport</a> (4TB) portable external hard drive for <strong>$94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/34dn43E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $109.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2oTcz6S" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 970 Evo Plus</a> (500GB) internal NVMe M.2 SSD for <strong>$99.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $114.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Accessories and miscellaneous deals</h2>
<ul>
<li>Verizon Wireless unlimited plan customers, new Verizon Fios Home Internet customers, and new Verizon 5G customers only: <a href="https://www.verizonwireless.com/solutions-and-services/disneyplus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disney Plus 12-month membership</a> for <strong>free</strong> at Verizon (normally $69.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33T5bHC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a> 6-month membership for <strong>$29.97</strong> at Amazon (normally $59.94).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cbn9cv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Audible</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$6.95/month</strong> at Amazon (normally $14.95/month).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36xYgpm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung Evo Select</a> (512GB) microSDXC card for <strong>$77.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $89.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2phf3w4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort Strip PD 2 Mini</a> power strip - 18W USB-C PD, 2x USB-A, 2x AC for <strong>$24.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $33.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34YD36n" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort III Nano</a> USB-C wall charger - 18W USB-C PD for <strong>$15.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2r8Hmgz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Alkaline</a> AAA batteries (24-pack) for <strong>$6.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon</strong> - normally $11.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32BRHP7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Keyboard</a> for 10.5-inch iPad Pro, 10.2-inch iPad, and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$99.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-smart-keyboard-for-apple-ipad10-2-7th-generation-2019-10-5-ipad-pro-and-ipad-air%2F5822276.p%3FskuId%3D5822276&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2X9sf2v" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Battery Case</a> for iPhone XR for <strong>$69</strong> at Amazon (normally $109.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2POBeV6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro for <strong>$30</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34yVMFo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro Max for <strong>$30</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2plGAfJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brydge 10.5</a> Bluetooth keyboard for 10.5-inch iPad Pro and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$69.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $87).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Ideas-LEGO-NASA-Apollo-Saturn-V-21309%2F55231379&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Ideas NASA Apollo Saturn V 21309</a> building kit (1,900 pieces) for <strong>$89.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $119.99).</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600779&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>High demand causes login problems on Disney+ launch day</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600775</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BAMTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600775</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Demand “has exceeded our high expectations,” Disney says.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/EJK681uW4AIZQCF-800x832.jpg" alt="High demand causes login problems on Disney+ launch day"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/EJK681uW4AIZQCF.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1149" data-width="1105">Enlarge</a> </p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Disney's new streaming service is straining under the load as users rush to log in to the highly anticipated service on its US launch day. Frustrated users took to social media to complain about seeing "unable to connect" error screens instead of the Star Wars, Marvel, and Pixar movies they were hoping for.</p>
<p>"The consumer demand for Disney+ has exceeded our high expectations," <a href="https://twitter.com/DisneyPlusHelp/status/1194268462283018241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1194268462283018241&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2019%2F11%2F12%2Funable-to-connect-to-disney%2F">Disney tweeted</a> on Tuesday morning. "We are working to quickly resolve the current user issue."</p>
<p>Disney is aiming to reshape the paid video streaming landscape with its Disney+ offering. Until now, a lot of online streaming has been done on independent services like Netflix and Amazon Prime Video.</p>

<p>With Disney+, Disney is seeking to cut out the middleman and stream its content directly to customers. The company's vast library of movies and television shows, bolstered by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/06/trump-administration-approves-potential-disneyfox-merger/">last year's acquisition</a> of 21st Century Fox, will make the service immediately attractive to millions of potential customers.</p>
<p>But of course the product will only be attractive if it works reliably. Disney is building its streaming service using technology developed by BAMTech, a company formed by Major League Baseball teams to stream baseball games. In recent years, the company has expanded to support everything from professional wrestling to HBO Now (though HBO recently <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90373706/hbos-tech-is-prepping-att-for-the-streaming-wars">cut BAMTech loose</a>).</p>
<p>Disney acquired a majority stake in the company in 2016 and started to use it for the streaming service of Disney-owned ESPN. Now it serves as the foundation for Disney+.</p>
<p>The outages come despite extensive preparations by the BAMTech team—now known as Disney Streaming Services.</p>

<p>"We’re thinking very much about" overloaded servers, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/26/20831284/disney-plus-overload-crash-hbo-now-espn-launch-day">said Michael Paull</a>, the head of Disney's streaming efforts, in an August interview with the Verge. Paull has been the head of BAMTech since 2017 and before that was a vice president at Amazon's digital video team.</p>
<p>"Fortunately, we’ve had the experience with <em>Game of Thrones, </em>we’ve had the experience of ESPN+ with the big pay-per-view events that we’re doing with UFC exclusively on our platform," Paull told the Verge in August. “We are ready. We’re spending a lot of time planning for this launch.”</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600775&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two years later, Apple’s AR/VR headset plans reportedly pushed back two years</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600805</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 16:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600805</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Combined VR/AR headset for 2022 to be followed by “lightweight” AR glasses in 2023.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/applevr2-800x370.jpg" alt="An image <a href='http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PALL&amp;p=1&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=8,605,008.PN.&amp;OS=PN/8,605,008&amp;RS=PN/8,605,008'>from a patent Apple filed back in 2008</a> shows exactly what Apple's VR/AR headset will look like, 100%, with no changes if/when it launches over 15 years later."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/applevr2.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="740" data-width="1600">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> An image <a href='http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PALL&amp;p=1&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=8,605,008.PN.&amp;OS=PN/8,605,008&amp;RS=PN/8,605,008'>from a patent Apple filed back in 2008</a> shows exactly what Apple's VR/AR headset will look like, 100%, with no changes if/when it launches over 15 years later. </p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Right around this date in 2017, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/apple-is-working-on-an-ar-headset-with-a-new-os-report-says/">Bloomberg reported</a> that Apple was working on a pair of augmented reality glasses for a planned 2020 launch. Now that it's late 2019, <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-eyes-2022-release-for-ar-headset-2023-for-glasses">The Information is reporting</a> (and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-11/apple-s-ar-push-will-start-with-ipad-and-culminate-with-glasses">Bloomberg is largely confirming</a>) that Apple is now planning to launch a combined VR/AR headset in 2022, following up with a lightweight pair of AR glasses in 2023.</p>
<p>Apple's perpetually three-or-more-years-away headset plans have "a focus on gaming, watching video and virtual meetings," Bloomberg reports, and now include a new 3D sensor that builds off of Apple's existing FaceID sensor. A 1,000-person team inside the company—reportedly led by former Dolby Labs engineer Mike Rockwell and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/01/apple-hires-top-virtual-and-augmented-reality-expert-ft-reports/">involving former Virginia Tech professor Doug Bowman</a>—is still reportedly working on a completely new operating system for the headset dubbed rOS (reality operating system).</p>
<p>The market for VR and AR headsets looks very different today than it did back in 2016, when reports <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/01/apple-hires-top-virtual-and-augmented-reality-expert-ft-reports/">first started leaking out</a> regarding Apple's plans in the space. Back then, expensive PC-tethered VR headsets like the Oculus Rift and HTC Vive were launching to a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/03/the-ars-review-oculus-rift-expands-pc-gaming-past-the-monitors-edge/">lot</a> of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/04/htc-vive-review-you-can-now-buy-your-own-holodeck-simulator-v-1-0/">fanfare</a> but <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2017/11/more-than-a-fad-vr-headset-sales-are-slowly-creeping-higher/">generally disappointing sales</a>. Today, improvements in technology have moved the focus to cheaper "all-in-one" untethered headsets like the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/oculus-quest-review-2019s-best-new-gaming-system-is-wireless-affordable-vr/">$400 Oculus Quest</a>, which has <a href="https://qz.com/1739575/strong-oculus-quest-sales-boost-facebooks-non-advertising-revenue/">reportedly sold a decent-but-uninspiring 400,000 units</a> since its launch in May (a relatively poor showing when compared to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2017/12/putting-nintendo-switchs-10-million-sales-in-context/">other recent portable gaming-focused hardware</a>).</p>
<p>On the AR side, Apple's Tim Cook was largely correct <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/10/tim-cook-believes-ar-will-be-huge-but-dont-expect-apple-glasses-yet/">when he said back in 2017</a> that "the technology itself doesn't exist to do that in a quality way." Since then, AR has remained a pricey <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/microsofts-hololens-2-tracks-your-eyeballs-to-see-what-youre-looking-at/">enterprise-focused market</a>. Bulky headsets from Microsoft and Magic Leap run for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2018/08/magic-leap-opens-orders-for-2300-creator-edition-ar-headset/">thousands</a> of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/microsofts-hololens-2-tracks-your-eyeballs-to-see-what-youre-looking-at/">dollars</a> and still have important limitations in field-of-view and image solidity. And while <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/06/arkit-2-why-apple-keeps-pushing-ar-and-how-it-works-in-ios-12/">Apple's ARKit API</a> has helped integrate augmented reality into many iOS apps, using such technology on a headset is very different from doing so by holding a phone or tablet as a "magic window" in front of your face.</p>
<p>An additional three or four years of technological advancement could bring more significant changes to the space, especially with Apple's considerable R&amp;D muscle involved. But the market for both VR and AR headsets seems unlikely to mature much past the niche stage without some major advances in both software appeal, hardware form factor, and total price. We look forward to hearing more in two years, when Apple will probably be pushing its headset launch plans back to 2024, if current patterns hold.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600805&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
