<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 16:37:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Did Neanderthals make eagle talon necklaces 120,000 years ago?</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 16:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neanderthals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleoarchaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleolithic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleolithic europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolic thought]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The evidence is indirect, but a recent find suggests the answer may be "yes."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Aguila_Imperial_Entrando_Al_Posadero_125891767-800x532-800x532.jpg" alt="Did Neanderthals make eagle talon necklaces 120,000 years ago?"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Aguila_Imperial_Entrando_Al_Posadero_125891767-800x532.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="532" data-width="800">Enlarge</a> (credit: José Antonio Lagier Martin)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>At Foradada Cave in northeast Spain, Neanderthal fossils lie mingled with stone tools and animal bones. Here, archaeologists recently unearthed the tip of a 39,000-year-old eagle toe with its claw missing. The phalanx (toe bone) came from the end of a Spanish imperial eagle’s big toe (the left one, to be exact), and cut marks along the length of the bone suggest that someone had cut off the large, curved talon at the end of the toe.</p>
<p>Archaeologist Antonio Rodriguez, of the Institute of Evolution in Africa, and his colleagues suggest that the missing talon ended up on a Neanderthal necklace.</p>
<h2>The case of the missing jewelry</h2>
<p>Along the top side of the toe (a proximal phalanx, if you’re an anatomy fan), 11 deep cut marks run diagonally across the bone; a shallower twelfth cut crosses the others, parallel with the bone’s length. Under the microscope, the cuts have v-shaped cross-sections, leaning to one side—the signature shape of tool-made cuts rather than predator teeth or damage from scraping against rocks or other bone. In fact, the cuts look almost exactly like the marks archaeologists left behind when they used stone tools to separate a raptor’s claw from its toe (because of course they did, for science).</p>
<p>Twenty-two other raptor toes found across southern Europe bear similar cut marks: an eagle-owl, a vulture, and 20 other eagles. But (with one exception), the talons all seem to have been taken somewhere else. Smaller birds seem not to have been given the talon-removal treatment, although their bones often show up at Neanderthal sites. Collectively, these objects offer a tantalizing hint that Neanderthals used eagle talons for <em>something</em>, and it probably wasn’t strictly practical—which makes it pretty interesting.</p>
<p>Rodriguez and his colleagues suggest that the missing talons and the cut-marked toes are evidence that Neanderthals in southern Europe were making jewelry out of eagle talons. That sounds like a pretty big leap, considering the complete lack of eagle-talon necklaces in the archaeological record. The whole case hangs on the argument that the talons were obviously being collected, but they probably weren’t being used as food or tools.</p>
<h2>If you can’t eat it, what’s it for?</h2>
<p>Bird feet aren’t terribly nutritious—some cultures have tasty recipes involving the cartilage and tendons, but it still wouldn’t make much sense to remove the talons as part of meal prep. And there’s not much evidence that they ate the rest of the eagle, either. Neanderthals, especially those living close to the Mediterranean Sea, ate birds pretty often, but large raptors do not seem to have been regular items on the menu. Modern hunter-gatherers also occasionally eat large birds of prey, but only rarely.</p>
<p>And based on the things they left behind, Neanderthals don’t seem to have used many bone tools. There’s no evidence of smaller bird talons being used as awls or needles, and Rodriguez and his colleagues say it’s unlikely the Neanderthals would use only eagle talons for those purposes, when a range of sizes would make sense. The possibility of eagle talons as tools can’t be totally ruled out, but it doesn’t look very likely, either.</p>
<p>The explanation that's left, according to Rodriguez and his colleagues, is that the use was artistic—another piece of evidence that Neanderthals were as intelligent and sophisticated as we are. They argue that Neanderthals at Foradada Cave and elsewhere across southern Europe used eagle talons the same way that others at sites like Cueva de los Aviones in Spain used seashell beads and ocher: as talismans or as visible markers of social standing, group membership, or some other aspect of a person’s identity. The talons may have been pendants, earrings, or just something people carried; without the talons themselves, there’s no way to know.</p>
<h2> A glimpse into the Neanderthal mind</h2>
<p>If the talons really were being removed to make jewelry, that brings Neanderthals in line with a lot of other groups of people around the world. Many cultures have viewed large raptors as symbols to represent power, nature, nobility, or military prowess, so it’s not that surprising that Neanderthals would, too.</p>
<p>“To know, or try to imagine, the significance for Neanderthals is out of science,” Rodriguez told Ars. “Unfortunately we don't have a Rosetta Stone to decode the meaning of Middle Paleolithic talons.” But he plans to study eagle-talon ornaments from indigenous Australian and North American cultures to compare patterns of cut marks and wear, as well as how each culture used those objects and what they meant to the people who wore them.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, what do the missing talons and the incriminating cut marks tell us about Neanderthal culture? Well, for starters, it suggests that Neanderthals weren’t a cultural monolith; for tens of thousands of years, they lived in small groups scattered across almost the whole of Eurasia, but the missing eagle talons only show up in a relatively small area of southern Europe. Isotopic studies have already shown us that Neanderthals in different areas ate distinct foods, and we know that tool types varied from place to place (and over time). The talons suggest that groups living in different areas also used different types of symbols—and therefore, perhaps, had different ideas and beliefs. (That’s not surprising, of course, but it’s interesting to see that pattern in the archaeological record.)</p>
<p>If Rodriguez and his colleagues are right, the talons may also suggest that Neanderthal culture is older than some similar aspects of human culture. The earliest eagle toes with cut marks date to sometime between 120,000 and 130,000 years ago, which makes them slightly older than the perforated seashells at Homo sapiens sites in North Africa. Of course, that doesn’t mean that humans living in parts of Africa <em>didn’t</em> have symbolism and jewelry long before Neanderthals; it just means that these are the earliest examples we’ve found.</p>
<p>Critically, the timing means that Neanderthals probably developed symbolism on their own, instead of learning it from <em>Homo sapiens</em> as some archaeologists have suggested (it’s possible and even likely that the two species swapped ideas and symbols once they met).</p>
<p>And it suggests that Neanderthal culture had some serious staying power. The Foradada Cave bones date to around 42,000 years ago—roughly 80,000 years later than the earliest examples, and around the time the last Neanderthals were losing their world to upstart newcomers, <em>Homo sapiens</em>. In fact, if the missing eagle talon from Foradada Cave did become a necklace or other ornament, it may have been among the last ones the Neanderthals ever made, a final remnant of an ancient tradition, “surviving on [as] one of the last expressions of their material culture and probably extinguishing with them forever.”</p>
<p><em>Science Advances</em>, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/ https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aax1984">10.1126/sciadv.aax1984</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researchers see spike in “out of season” IRS-impersonating phishing attacks</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 15:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax scam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researchers track surge in IRS phishing sites as filing extension deadline arrived.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/irs-800x382.png" alt="A fake IRS site used in a set of phishing campaigns observed by Akamai from August to October."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/irs.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="652" data-width="1365">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A fake IRS site used in a set of phishing campaigns observed by Akamai from August to October. (credit: Akamai)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Tax return scammers usually strike early in the year, when they can turn the personal information of victims into fraudulent tax refund claims. But members of Akamai's threat research team <a href="https://blogs.akamai.com/sitr/2019/11/out-of-season-irs-phishing-campaigns.html">found a recent surge in "off-season" phishing attacks</a> masquerading as notices from the Internal Revenue Service, targeting over 100,000 individuals. The attackers used at least 289 different domains hosting fake IRS websites—the majority of them legitimate sites that had been compromised. This wave of attacks came as the October 15 deadline for people who had filed for extensions approached.</p>
<p>According to a post by Akamai's Or Katz, the phishing campaigns kicked off in the second half of August, with the majority of victims targeted between August 22 and September 5. But the campaigns continued to be launched into early October. Each of the fake websites used visually identical HTML pages, but used randomly generated style tags and other content in an attempt to throw off signature detection by security software.</p>
<p>Most of the domains were active for under 20 days. However, a significant number of them remained active after a month—undetected by the owners of the sites. "The lack of maintenance on legacy websites, as well as the challenges of patching and removing injected content, explains the duration over which phishing pages can remain active," Katz wrote.</p>
<p>This is consistent with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/08/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-lose-the-war-on-phishing-enlist-machine-learning/">research into phishing infrastructure done by Ars</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.akamai.com/us/en/multimedia/documents/state-of-the-internet/soti-security-phishing-baiting-the-hook-report-2019.pdf">other research by Akamai</a>. Because of their age—and the lack of attention paid to them by their owners, who often pay someone to set them up and then forget about maintaining them—older sites based on "legacy" versions of WordPress and other content management systems are a prime target for phishing operators, as they have a higher reputation score than freshly minted domains. Depending on the degree to which the site is compromised, they can even create subdomains and register their own certificates for the phishing site.</p>
<p>With these sorts of scams propagating all year, it's worth reminding friends and family that the IRS will not e-mail you or call you about overdue taxes or any other matter—those notices will only come by paper postal mail, usually by certified mail. So just don't click.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volkswagen is putting this cool electric station wagon into production</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 14:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LA Auto Show 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MEB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volkswagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volkswagen ID Space Vizzion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is the latest concept to show off the VW's modular electric platform.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/VW-Space-Vizzion-4-980x735.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          We've seen buses and buggies, hatches, sedans, and crossovers. And now there's a VW ID station wagon concept.                      [credit:
                        Jonathan Gitlin                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  


<p>LOS ANGELES—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/01/the-best-of-the-2017-north-american-international-auto-show/">Buzz</a>. Crozz. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/weve-driven-vws-bright-green-smile-machine-the-electric-id-buggy/">Buggy</a>. Vizzion. And now Space Vizzion. No, I haven't overdosed on the letter Z; those are the slightly wacky names for a series of not-at-all-wacky electric ID concept cars from Volkswagen, the newest of which was just unveiled on Tuesday night in Los Angeles. The ID Space Vizzion is the latest installment in an electrification push from one of the world's largest automakers, one aiming to sell 20 million electric cars worldwide over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>Volkswagen Group had little choice but to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/09/volkswagen-group-will-electrify-all-12-brands-by-2030-needs-gigafactories/">embrace electric powertrains</a> in the aftermath of dieselgate—the alternative would be failing to meet 2021's European CO2 rules, which would result in billions of dollars in fines. Audi and Porsche, the two big premium brands within the group, got their battery EVs to market first. The first of these—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/12/weve-driven-audis-first-proper-electric-car-the-2019-e-tron-suv/">the Audi e-tron</a>—is mainly a stop-gap, a Q8 with batteries and two electric motors in place of the normal internal combustion engine stuff. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/09/the-porsche-taycan-every-bit-as-good-as-a-200000-porsche-should-be/">The Porsche Taycan</a> had an extra year to gestate, and is all the better for it, a mostly clean-sheet design that's wowed everyone who's driven it.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, over at VW (the brand, not the group) the engineers were working on MEB (<em>Modularer E-Antriebs-Baukasten</em>, or Modular Electrification Toolkit), which it will use to build millions of BEVs over the next decade. VW has long embraced the use of modular architectures; its current MQB (<em>Modularer Querbaukasten</em>, or Modular Transverse Toolkit) gives rise to such diverse cars as the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/04/the-volkswagen-atlas-reviewed-a-peoples-wagon-for-the-american-people/">VW Atlas</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/09/audi-sports-rs3-and-tt-rs-the-same-engine-but-very-different-cars/">Audi TT-RS</a>. And MEB should be even more flexible, as the various ID concept cars have shown.</p>
<p>Ignore the ID Space Vizzion's Z-overdose name and think of it instead as an electric Passat station wagon. It's a five-door, more practical evolution of 2018's ID Vizzion, itself VW's take on a Passat-sized electric sedan. But this one looks better because as we all know, wagons &gt; sedans. I'm also impressed with how aerodynamic it is—VW told me that the Space Vizzion's drag coefficient is just 0.24, and that's with conventional side mirrors, too.</p>
<p>Between the axles there's an 77kWh battery pack. Add that to the low-drag body, and the result is at least 300 miles on the EPA test cycle or 590km on the WLTP test, VW says. The rear wheels are driven by a 205kW (275hp), 550Nm (406lb-ft) motor, although there will be an option for all-wheel drive with a total power output of 250kW (335hp).</p>
<p>The fact that VW is talking about options on a concept car should give you the idea that this is one of those thinly disguised production car concepts rather than a "it's made entirely out of clay and half the stuff in it hasn't been invented yet" kind of concept car. In 2022 the Space Vizzion will go on sale, probably with a slightly more boring nose, almost certainly with a more boring interior, and definitely with a less Z-filled name.</p>
<p>If you don't want to wait that long for an electric VW, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/09/this-is-volkswagens-new-e30000-electric-car-the-id-3/">ID.3 hatchback</a> is on sale in Europe, and next year here in the US we get the ID.4 crossover (which will also be built in Chattanooga, Tennessee, starting in 2022).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guidemaster: The most useful gadgets to have in your bag while traveling</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ars Holiday 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidemaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tech gifts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here are some stellar gadgets that will make your future trips better.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-638533994-800x533.jpg" alt="Not all of us frequently travel with camping/hiking backpacks like these joyful stock photo travelers—luckily, we have some recommendations on tech tailored for on-the-go life. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-638533994.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3667" data-width="5500">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Not all of us frequently travel with camping/hiking backpacks like these joyful stock photo travelers—luckily, we have some recommendations on tech tailored for on-the-go life.  (credit:  Hinterhaus Productions / Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Traveling <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/03/hold-onto-your-butts-a-tour-through-kualoa-ranch-aka-real-world-jurassic-park/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">can be a fun,</a> illuminating experience, but packing for your travels is often stressful. Everything you choose to bring with you on your excursions must have a purpose, because unnecessary items do not belong in anyone's cramped suitcase. Whether you're traveling for business or pleasure, it can be difficult to decide which pieces of tech deserve to come with you and which you only <em>think</em> would be useful.</p>
<p>It can also be hard to find gadgets that are suitable for travel—devices that work even more efficiently when you're not in your normal environment. To combat this, Ars has picked out some of the best travel tech gifts that will be solid additions to anyone's travel bag. All of the items below we've personally tested or reviewed, so we're confident saying that none of these devices will end up languishing, abandoned, at the bottom of your suitcase.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Dell XPS 13</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15.jpg"><img alt='Dell&#039;s XPS 13 laptop.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Dell&#039;s XPS 13 laptop.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Dell's XPS 13 laptop.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Dell has crafted and re-crafted the <a href="http://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8984087-12578053?sid=TravelGifts2019&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Flaptops%2Fnew-13%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-7390-laptop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XPS 13</a> to be one of the most travel-friendly laptops you can get. Weighing 2.7 pounds and measuring 11.6mm thick, it's impressively thin considering how much power it has built inside the chassis. The 2019 model with 9th-gen Intel processors is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/03/guidemaster-the-best-windows-ultrabooks-you-can-buy-right-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our current favorite Windows ultrabook</a>, and Dell recently updated the machine to include 10th-gen Intel processors. Regardless of the model you get, you're getting a Windows laptop that doesn't compromise performance while being slim and attractive.</p>

<p>That said, the newest XPS 13 does offer a lot of improvements over last year's model. First and foremost, the webcam has been moved to the top of the screen rather than sitting on the bottom like it has for so many years. This makes the webcam much more functional, and Dell didn't sacrifice screen space in order to make it happen. You can get the display in a 1080p panel, but there's a 4K panel option as well now. In terms of ports, you get three USB-C ports (two of which are Thunderbolt 3) in addition to a headphone jack, a microSD card slot, and a lock slot.</p>
<p>While we wish the XPS 13 had an IR camera for facial recognition, it does have a fingerprint reader embedded into the power button, so you'll get speedy biometric login from that. We also appreciate that the 4K model can last 13 hours on a single charge (according to our testing), and you could configure the XPS 13 to get up to 21 hours of battery life.</p>
<p>Dell gives you a lot of configuration options on the XPS 13, making it a good choice for anyone who wants to truly customize their laptop. The only bad part is that the base model starts with 4GB of RAM (the next step up has 8GB of RAM, and we would recommend most people have that amount of memory in their primary machine). Regardless of how you configure it, the XPS 13 is a solid laptop that will be a workhorse no matter where you find yourself working.</p>
<p>For those who want a machine that's a bit more flexible (plus a tad thinner and lighter), consider the Microsoft Surface Pro. Last year's <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-surface-pro-6-12-3-touch-screen-intel-core-i5-8gb-memory-128gb-solid-state-drive-platinum%2F6298148.p%3FskuId%3D6298148&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Surface Pro 6</a> is our current favorite Windows detachable, and you can still find powerful configurations of this device at a good price. Those who want the latest and greatest (plus a newly added USB-C port) should consider the <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-surface-pro-7-12-3-touch-screen-intel-core-i3-4gb-memory-128gb-ssd-with-black-type-cover-latest-model-platinum%2F6374985.p%3FskuId%3D6374985&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Surface Pro 7</a>.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/xps132in1-300x124.png"
                                    alt="Dell XPS 13 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Dell XPS 13                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_47369981" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="http://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8984087-12578053?sid=TravelGifts2019&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Flaptops%2Fnew-13%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-7390-laptop" target="_blank">
                                Starting at $949 from Dell                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s.jpg"><img alt='Logitech&#039;s MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Logitech&#039;s MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Logitech's MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Travel-friendly mice are a dime a dozen, but <a href="https://amzn.to/2NDodMM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech's MX Master Anywhere 2s</a> puts some of the best features found in a stationary mouse into a travel-sized device. This mouse is noticeably smaller than other Logitech mice, and while it may take some getting used to, it's the perfect sized mouse to live in your backpack, work, or travel bag.</p>
<p>Its 4000 dpi Darkfield sensor helps it track on nearly any surface, even glass, so you can use it no matter where you find yourself working. It has a rechargeable battery that should last up to 70 days on a single charge, and it recharges using a microUSB port. It works with macOS and Windows devices, as well as iPadOS and Linux, and you can pair this mouse with up to three devices at once and switch between them with just the press of a button. Like most Logitech accessories, the MX Master Anywhere 2s connects to a PC via Bluetooth or a USB receiver.</p>
<p>In addition to customizable pointer and scroll speeds, you can also customize the five buttons on the MX Master Anywhere 2s. This is one of the features I love in Logitech's main mice, and I'm glad the company made a travel mouse that works almost exactly like the one you may use every day at your main desk. The MX Master Anywhere 2s could end up being your main mouse if you prefer smaller mice, but it's truly hard to beat as a travel mouse—especially at the good price of $54.99.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anywhere2s-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_94844339" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NDodMM" target="_blank">
                                $49.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux.jpg"><img alt='Anker&#039;s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux-640x398.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux-1280x796.jpg 2x" alt='Anker&#039;s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Anker's PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>There are countless power banks that can effectively keep devices charged on the go, but for an explicitly portable option, we like <a href="https://amzn.to/2NZBf7u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker’s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a>. The main reason for that is size: at seven ounces and 106×52.3×25.5mm, the PowerCore is particularly small and light enough to fit into many pants pockets, let alone a handbag or suitcase, without being too obtrusive. The whole thing is sturdily put together, with rounded edges that subtly make the battery more comfortable to hold and stash on your person.</p>
<p>Besides that, it includes a USB-C Power Delivery (PD) port that charges at 18W, which is powerful enough to refill most new smartphones at maximum speeds. (It’s not quite fast enough to recharge higher-end tablets like the iPad Pro at maximum speeds, but it’ll still speed up the process to an extent.) There’s a 12W USB-A port as well, which is handy if you have multiple devices low on power. Because the battery maxes out at 18W of output, it’s best suited for smartphone charging above all else, though.</p>
<p>The PowerCore has a capacity of 10,000mAh (36Wh), which is enough to charge an iPhone 11 roughly twice. A quartet of LED lights lets you know how much of that capacity is left at any given time, and the battery itself can recharge at 18W with a USB-C PD wall charger, so it doesn’t take long to fully restore. We’ve had no hints of reliability issues after months of use, and Anker generally has a strong reputation in this market, but the device is covered by an 18-month warranty if something goes wrong. At $46, it’s not the cheapest power bank in its class, but it does come with a USB-C to USB-C cable in the box, and we think its blend of good-enough power and genuine portability is worth it.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerpd-300x375.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_31490341" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NZBf7u" target="_blank">
                                $45.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Garmin Dash Cam Mini</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1.jpg"><img alt='Garmin&#039;s Dash Cam Mini.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Garmin&#039;s Dash Cam Mini.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Garmin's Dash Cam Mini.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Protecting your car with the watchful eye of a dash cam can be useful if you're on the road a lot, and <a href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Garmin's Dash Cam Mini</a> is certainly one of the most compact dash cams you can get. Measuring 1.23×2.1×1.15 inches, it's about the size of a house key and almost as lightweight as one. Its camera records 1080p video @ 30fps of the road ahead of you, and its 140-degree field of view will capture almost everything going on in the area in front of your car.</p>
<p>It's also one of the most convenient dash cams to use. Just stick the Dash Cam Mini onto your windshield, plug it into your car's charger, and forget about it—it will start when the car starts, record continuously, and stop when the car stops. Garmin's companion mobile app makes it easy to view and access footage relatively quickly, too. While other dash cams force you to remove the microSD card and use it to view footage on a computer, you can see new clips immediately in the Garmin Drive app and download them to your smartphone. There are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/06/guidemaster-the-best-dash-cams-to-guard-your-every-drive/">plenty of dash cams</a> out there to choose from—some more affordable, some more expensive—but Garmin's Dash Cam Mini will appeal to those who want an unobtrusive device that also doesn't get in the way of them accessing their driving footage whenever necessary.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/garmindashcammini-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Garmin Dash Cam Mini product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Garmin Dash Cam Mini                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_59907213" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_59907213">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ">Amazon $129.98</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgarmin-mini-dash-cam%2F6351243.p%3FskuId%3D6351243&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $129.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgarmin-mini-dash-cam%2F6351243.p%3FskuId%3D6351243&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Sony WH-1000XM3</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1.jpg"><img alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Sony's WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>While more than a year old now, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony’s WH-1000XM3</a> remains our favorite wireless noise-cancelling headphone. It has the most powerful and consistent active noise cancellation (ANC) of any model we’ve tested: some sharper sounds may sneak through during quieter tracks, but that’s the case with every ANC headphone, and the XM3 is still outstanding at shutting out the low- and mid-range noises that are most disturbing on a long flight or subway ride.</p>
<p>While the XM3 is not the best-sounding $350 headphone we’ve used by any means, sound quality in consumer headphones as a whole has taken a bit of a backseat as Bluetooth has become the norm. Sony’s profile here is tailored toward bass lovers more than purists, but that’s not exactly an unpopular sound these days, and the XM3 is well-measured given the warmer sound it’s going for. Those who are willing to sacrifice a little treble and vocal clarity for more oomph in the low-end will find plenty to like. That said, Sony’s companion app lets you customize the XM3’s sound in meaningful ways, so if your loved one doesn’t like the default sound (or wants even more bass), it’s not hard to address that.</p>
<p>The XM3 is primarily made of plastic, which might be disappointing for the price, but the upshot is that it keeps the whole thing relatively light. Combined with the cushy, not-overly-tight earpads and a headband, this keeps the XM3 comfortable to wear for hours at a time. The headphone got a solid 21 hours of battery life during our testing, and it can fully recharge in about two hours through its USB-C port. It also supports a nifty “ambient sound” mode that can let you hear outside noises without stopping whatever’s playing.</p>
<p>The XM3 is not without flaws. Unlike the <a href="https://amzn.to/2O0bm7x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose Noise Cancelling Headphones 700</a>, there’s no way to manually adjust the strength of the XM3’s noise cancellation. The Bose 700 also has a more premium-feeling design, with a stainless steel headband. <a href="https://amzn.to/2qZZbhT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose’s QuietComfort 35 II</a>, meanwhile, has physical volume and playback buttons that are generally more reliable than the XM3’s touch-based controls—though we find the XM3’s setup to work fine for what it is—an even lighter design, and a sound profile that’ll appeal more to those who don’t want as much bass. But the Bose 700 are too reliant on a finicky app for crucial functions, the QC 35 II’s sound is less customizable and impressive on the whole, and the XM3 has stronger ANC than both of them. It’s possible Sony will release a follow-up in the next few months, but either way, the XM3 should be a treat for anyone who is frequently stuck on long commutes.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/51IdLe-6kL._AC_SL1500_-300x436.jpg"
                                    alt="Sony WH-1000XM3 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Sony WH-1000XM3                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_32503850" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_32503850">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $348</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2qgiZOd">Amazon $348</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-wh-1000xm3-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-with-google-assistant-black%2F6280544.p%3FskuId%3D6280544&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $349.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2qgiZOd"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-wh-1000xm3-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-with-google-assistant-black%2F6280544.p%3FskuId%3D6280544&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Beats Powerbeats Pro<br />
Apple AirPods Pro</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro.jpg"><img alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>If over-ear headphones like the WH-1000XM3 are too bulky for your loved one’s liking, consider gifting them a pair of “true wireless” earphones. Easily the trendiest item in consumer audio nowadays, these are Bluetooth earphones with absolutely no wires between them. Almost none of them are well-suited to critical listening at this point, but their small size and total lack of cables make them feel particularly freeing for someone who is frequently on the move.</p>
<p>A handful of worthwhile options have launched in the past year, but we think the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beats Powerbeats Pro</a> will make the widest swath of people happy. As you might expect from a Beats product, the Powerbeats Pro’s sound is heavy on the bass and far from neutral, but it doesn’t totally muddle up detail in the mids. Given the context, it sounds more “fun” than bloated.</p>
<p>It’s the other fundamentals that really make the Powerbeats Pro a winner, though: the earhook design balances its weight well and stays nice and secure throughout intense workouts, the physical volume and playback controls mirrored on each earbud are always convenient to access, and the semi-sealing eartips block out enough outside noise with music playing without putting too much stress on the ear canals or totally shutting off access to your surroundings. For iPhone users, they use Apple’s H1 wireless chip for a particularly stable connection and easier pairing, but even on Android they connect quickly to a remembered device and don’t lose any major features.</p>
<p>Best of all, the Powerbeats Pro are <em>by far</em> the current battery life champ among true wireless earbuds, getting more than 11 hours of continuous use in our testing. By contrast, most of the major competitors we’ve tested have averaged somewhere between 4-6 hours on a charge. It’s a shame that their case is enormous—you’ll likely need to keep it in a jacket pocket, bag, or purse on the road—and the fact that the case charges over Lightning instead of USB-C might be an annoyance. At $250, they aren’t cheap, either. Still, the Powerbeats Pro live up to the promise of being genuinely wire-free better than most of their peers.</p>
<p>If your loved one likes the true wireless idea but doesn’t want to give up active noise cancellation, however, we can also give <a href="https://amzn.to/3416Cns" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple’s AirPods Pro</a> our blessing. We’re wrapping up an in-depth review of these earphones now, but the short version is that they’re an improvement over the standard AirPods in both comfort and sound quality—as they should be, considering they cost $100 more—and they offer more effective active noise cancellation than other true wireless earbuds like <a href="https://amzn.to/2CX5u8y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon’s Echo Buds</a> or <a href="https://amzn.to/32Yk0Yf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony’s WF-1000XM3</a>. (Yes, Sony’s naming conventions are bad.) The “transparency” mode that artificially lets in outside noise works well, and their case can actually fit in most pants pockets.</p>
<p>But you should only consider the AirPods Pro if you must have that blend of ANC and true wireless design. Their battery life, at roughly five hours a charge, isn’t enough to last through a cross-country flight. The touch-sensor-based controls are less intuitive than Beats’ physical buttons, and they don’t offer any way to adjust volume without using your phone or talking to Siri (which few people want to do in public). Many of their customization settings are simply inaccessible if you don’t have an iOS device on you. And that ANC, while good, is still inferior in a vacuum to what you get from full-size headphones like the Sony and Bose models above. All that said, they do a better job of justifying their inevitable popularity than the ordinary AirPods do.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bpb-300x210.jpg"
                                    alt="Beats Powerbeats Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Beats Powerbeats Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_81775022" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_81775022">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $249.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/3407IA4">Amazon $249.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds%26irclickid%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26irgwc%3D1%26ref%3D198%26loc%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26acampID%3D614286&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $249.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/3407IA4"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds%26irclickid%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26irgwc%3D1%26ref%3D198%26loc%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26acampID%3D614286&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71zny7BTRlL._AC_SL1500_-300x256.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple AirPods Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple AirPods Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_43747406" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_43747406">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93">Amazon $234.98</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $249</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-airpods-pro-white%2F5706659.p%3FskuId%3D5706659&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $249.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-airpods-pro-white%2F5706659.p%3FskuId%3D5706659&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>UE Wonderboom 2</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"><img alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The UE Wonderboom 2.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>For those times when the music needs to be shared, <a href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UE’s Wonderboom 2</a> is a cute, effective, and supremely portable Bluetooth speaker. It measures 104mm high and 95.3mm wide, with a squat design that looks like a small candle holder, so it shouldn’t be tough to toss into a backpack or carry-on. It’s IP67-rated—meaning it’s dustproof and waterproof—and its rugged design can withstand five-foot drops and float in water. An elastic loop built into the speaker allows it to hang from a carabiner (or towel hook), and its huge volume buttons and playback buttons make it largely straightforward to operate.</p>
<p>This is still a small Bluetooth speaker, so it doesn’t sound <em>amazing</em>, but it plays loud for its size, produces some semblance of bass, and does particularly well at keeping vocals and other mids clear. Don’t expect it to totally avoid distortion at maximum volume, but it sounds cleaner than most sub-$100 speakers. Its nine or so hours of battery life isn’t spectacular, and we’d prefer it charge over USB-C instead of microUSB, but it shouldn’t die out so quickly that it becomes an annoyance.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ue-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="UE Wonderboom 2 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">UE Wonderboom 2                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_23026773" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_23026773">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s">Amazon $79.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $79.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-3'></a></div>
<h2>DJI Osmo Mobile 3</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"><img alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">DJI's Osmo Mobile 3.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>DJI's newest gimbal is a great gift for that person in your life who's forever the photographer of your group, the person who's always first to whip out their smartphone to document events in photos or videos. Much of what has made DJI gimbals great remains in the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Osmo Mobile 3</a>, but the company made this device more compact and more affordable at $119.</p>
<p>The Osmo Mobile 3 folds into itself with one swift motion, reducing it to a size that can easily be stored in a purse or backpack. Although you must rebalance your smartphone each time before using the device, the stabilization is solid, and the accompanying mobile app gives you a ton of ways to shoot video. We particularly like DJI's object tracking, which smoothly tracks the object you tap on in the frame even while you're moving your smartphone camera. You can even charge your smartphone while using it in the Osmo Mobile 3 via the newly included USB port—and with 15 hours of estimated battery life, the Osmo Mobile 3 will likely have some juice to share even while working hard for you.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dji-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="DJI Osmo Mobile 3 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">DJI Osmo Mobile 3                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_82599952" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_82599952">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2qLYjx3">Amazon $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $139.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2qLYjx3"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18.jpg"><img alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Amazon's Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Readers who want to take their libraries with them while they travel will get a lot of use out of <a href="https://amzn.to/2KaQp7u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon's Kindle Paperwhite</a>. The paperback-sized e-reader can hold thousands of e-books, and the newest model also holds Audible audiobooks, allowing you to listen to books with a pair of Bluetooth headphones.</p>
<p>The Paperwhite may not provide the tactile satisfaction that reading a physical book does, but it's at least as comfortable if not more. Not only is it lighter than most hardbacks, but its E-Ink display with multiple front lights makes digital reading easy on the eyes (and as close as you'll get to real paper on an electronic device). At $129, it's a gift that won't break the bank and will keep on giving for years to come. But if that's more than your budget will allow, the new $89 Kindle provides the same reading experience, just with a less pixel-dense display and no Audible integration.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/paperwhite-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Amazon Kindle Paperwhite product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Amazon Kindle Paperwhite                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_46418814" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2KaQp7u" target="_blank">
                                $129.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Nintendo Switch Lite</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1.jpg"><img alt='The Nintendo Switch Lite.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='The Nintendo Switch Lite.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Nintendo Switch Lite.</a> </p></div>
<p>While the original Nintendo Switch was (and still is) a convenient portable console, the new <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch Lite</a> is just a bit better-suited for gaming on the go. It's slightly smaller and lighter than the original Switch, and it can play nearly all of the games that the original console can. We say "nearly" mostly because the lack of TV docking in the Switch Lite will make some games a bit more difficult to play—though it is possible.</p>

<p>But all the major titles like <a href="https://amzn.to/2KjRwBM" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em></a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/2pFiuNi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em></a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/37s2jEb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Luigi's Mansion 3</em></a>, and others for the Switch can be played on the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/09/nintendo-switch-lite-is-the-best-portable-system-nintendo-has-ever-made/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch Lite</a>, and the enhanced portability of the latter lets you bring that gameplay wherever you go. Gameplay isn't hindered by the smaller, 5.5-inch, 1280 x 720p display on the Switch Lite, and the newly added d-pad on the left side is a huge improvement over the small directional buttons that sit in its place on the original Switch.</p>
<p>Most sacrifices made in the Switch Lite do not detrimentally affect portable gameplay. The joycons cannot be removed, nor do they have HD rumble or IR sensors, but those features become less important when you're playing on your own and on the go. The biggest downside is that you can't dock the Switch Lite to a TV for larger-screen gameplay. But if you're wanting primarily to play Nintendo titles while on the road, during your commute, or while generally out and about, the Switch Lite is the better option and costs $100 less than the original Switch.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/switchlite-300x249.jpg"
                                    alt="Nintendo Switch Lite product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Nintendo Switch Lite                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_89905897" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_89905897">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $199.96</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2CAIPia">Amazon $199.96</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-gray%2F6257135.p%3FskuId%3D6257135&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $199.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2CAIPia"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-gray%2F6257135.p%3FskuId%3D6257135&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Apple iPad Air (3rd gen)</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629.jpeg"><img alt='The front of the 2019 iPad Air.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629-640x427.jpeg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629-1280x855.jpeg 2x" alt='The front of the 2019 iPad Air.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629.jpeg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The front of the 2019 iPad Air.</a> (credit: Samuel Axon)</p></div>An iPad is an iPad. You don’t need us to tell you that it remains an ideal computing device for watching movies, reading e-books, browsing the Web, and getting light work done on the go. But with Apple refreshing much of its tablet lineup over the past year, the question of <em>which</em> iPad is best for most people has gotten murkier.</p>
<p>As it stands now, we’re going with <a href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the iPad Air</a>. At $499, it costs a fair bit more than the <a href="https://amzn.to/2r2c5fk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new 10.2-inch iPad</a>—which starts at $329, though both tablets can often be found discounted online—but that premium gets you a number of meaningful quality of life improvements.</p>
<p>The big one is processing power. While the 10.2-inch iPad comes with the same A10 Fusion chip that was introduced with the iPhone 7 in 2016, the iPad Air runs on an A12 Bionic chip that’s two generations newer and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/mini-review-the-2019-ipad-has-a-new-skin-but-its-mostly-the-same-tablet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performs significantly better in benchmarks</a>. To be clear, the 10.2-inch iPad is still powerful enough to do most of the things you’d expect an iPad to do without immediate issue, and it pairs its processor with the same 3GB of RAM as the iPad Air. But the Air is quicker with games and more intensive tasks, and it’s better equipped to handle iPadOS updates as the years roll along. Since an iPad is designed to last several years, that last bit is what’s most important.</p>
<p>Beyond that, the iPad Air’s display is a noticeable step up. It’s laminated, for one, so it doesn’t have the air gap that makes the 10.2-inch iPad’s screen look recessed behind the glass that covers it. It has an anti-reflective coating that makes it more convenient to use in sunlight, support for Apple’s TrueTone display tech—which automatically adjusts colors onscreen to better suit the lighting of your surroundings—and a wider P3 color gamut. The iPad Air’s display is also marginally larger, at 10.5 inches, despite having a smaller overall footprint. (It’s 6.1mm thin, compared to the 7.5mm chassis of the 10.2-inch iPad.) Both tablets have LCD panels with virtually the same resolution, and again, your loved one will likely be perfectly content with the standard model’s display if they never see the two slates side by side. But a tablet is nothing if not a big display, and the iPad Air’s is just more pleasant to look at.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the iPad Air comes with 64GB of storage by default, double the amount of the entry-level iPad. Its front-facing camera is significantly sharper and supports 1080p video, whereas the 10.2-inch iPad’s selfie cam maxes out at 720p. It’s slightly lighter, at 456g compared to the iPad’s 483g, and it’s no worse with battery life.</p>
<p>If you simply want to save cash, the standard iPad is still a fine tablet, with the same support for <a href="https://amzn.to/2OnVhaK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple’s first-gen Pencil stylus</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/37knaZF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Keyboard attachment</a>. The <a href="https://amzn.to/37eVwxk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPad Mini</a> is basically a smaller iPad Air for the niche that still prefers a 7.9-inch tablet, and if you can find the discontinued 10.5-inch iPad Pro for a decent price from a reputable retailer, it’s a better piece of hardware than any current midrange model. (The <a href="https://amzn.to/330Gh7K" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPad Pro</a>, meanwhile, is still too expensive for most use cases and positioned more as a Windows laptop alternative.) But for most would-be iPad owners, the iPad Air is the best blend of performance, size, and build quality. If nothing else, it’ll be a smoother ride than almost any Android tablet in this price range.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/61z85f1XsgL._AC_SL1500_-300x351.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple iPad Air (3rd gen) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple iPad Air (3rd gen)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_87149974" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_87149974">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb">Amazon $469</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F10-5-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Silver%2F426123983%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $499.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-ipad-air-latest-model-with-wi-fi-64gb-space-gray%2F5985600.p%3FskuId%3D5985600&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $499.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F10-5-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Silver%2F426123983%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-ipad-air-latest-model-with-wi-fi-64gb-space-gray%2F5985600.p%3FskuId%3D5985600&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>


<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>400-year-old warships in Swedish channel may be sisters of doomed Vasa</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nautical archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipwrecks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwater archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vasa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The pair of warships were sunk to block enemy naval access to Stockholm.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/knees-vrak-1-800x534.png" alt="Photo of shipwreck timbers underwater"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/knees-vrak-1.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1474" data-width="2208">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> These curved timbers, called knees, help support deck beams. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.vrakmuseum.se/">Jim Hansson, Vrak Museum of Wrecks</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Two 17th-century shipwrecks on the bottom of a busy Swedish shipping channel may be the sister ships of the ill-fated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasa_(ship)"><em>Vasa</em></a>. Archaeologists with Sweden's Vrak—Museum of Wrecks discovered the vessels in a 35-meter-deep channel near Stockholm during a recent survey. Neither wreck is as well-preserved as <em>Vasa</em> (to be fair, there are probably ships actually sailing today that aren't as well-preserved as <em>Vasa</em>), but they're in remarkably good shape for several centuries on the bottom.</p>
<p>Studying the wrecks could reveal more details about how early naval engineers revised their designs to avoid another disaster like <em>Vasa</em>.</p>
<h2>Hiding in plain sight</h2>
<p>The wrecks may be the remains of two of the four large warships Sweden's King Gustav II Adolf built in the 1620s and 1630s. The earliest of the four ships, <em>Vasa</em>, had a first trip out of port in 1628 that ended in disaster; the top-heavy vessel caught a gust of wind and leaned over far enough to let water rush in through open gun ports. King Gustav's prized warship sank just a few dozen meters offshore in front of hundreds of spectators, killing half the crew onboard.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the three later ships—<em>Äpplet</em>, <em>Kronan</em>, and <em>Scepter</em>—had longer careers. <em>Äpplet</em> sailed with the Swedish fleet to invade Germany in 1630, and <em>Kronan</em> and <em>Scepter</em> sailed against a combined Danish-Norwegian fleet in the 1644 battle of Kolberger Heide.</p>
<p>In the late 1600s, the Swedish navy scuttled the three aging warships to help control access to a narrow sea channel approaching Stockholm. A complex network of channels and straits weaves among the islands of western Sweden, but only two routes offer access to Stockholm by sea. The channel where the wrecked warships now lie is the larger of those two routes, and it's still in use today.</p>
<p>Ferries and cargo ships now unwittingly pass within a few dozen meters of the 17th-century wrecks. "All heavy traffic to Stockholm passes through this narrow sound, so it's always quite strong currents and heavy noise from the ships," Vrak Museum archaeologist Jim Hansson (who coincidentally shares a surname with <em>Vasa</em>'s captain) told Ars.</p>
<p>And beneath all that modern traffic lie the battered but recognizable remains of two 400-year-old warships, sitting upright on the bottom. "The massive hull is standing right on the seabed," Hansson told Ars, describing the better-preserved of the two wrecks, which has a bow that still juts proudly 5m above the sand. Swimming along the first gun deck, where cannon once thundered, Hansson and his colleagues saw deck beams and curved timbers called knees, which supported the heavy beams where they met the sides of the hull.</p>
<p>Those timbers suggested that the two wrecks might be Gustav II Adolf's retired warships. "We took a lot of measurements to understand what kind of ship it was. We needed to have some measurements from some specific ship timbers to compare with <em>Vasa</em>, just to see if it could be one of her sisters," Hansson told Ars. "The measurements were similar to <em>Vasa</em>'s so that's why we think it might be one of them." Each wreck is about 40m long.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Jim-prepare-for-diving-980x653.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Archaeologist Jim Hansson prepares to dive.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.vrakmuseum.se/">Jim Hansson, Vrak Museum of Wrecks</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The area has seen almost constant construction since the 1500s to maintain the busy shipping channel and control access to the capital. In the years after the warships were scuttled, harbor defenses took the form of "stone coffins," which are enormous boxes built out of several whole logs and filled with large rocks. One of those coffins landed on the stern of the first wreck, smashing the timbers beneath it. And at some point, dynamite blasting farther out in the channel destroyed the port side of the second wreck—but the starboard side of her hull still looms about 5m high, to the level of the deck beams.</p>
<p>There has never been a sonar survey of the area, so archaeologists had no idea what was down there—and knowing how many blockades had been built, dynamited out of the way, and rebuilt over the years, Hansson and his colleagues weren't too optimistic about the survey. "We wanted to see if there were wrecks there, but we had no hope to find any well-preserved [because] there has been a lot of constructions built and blown away by the navy during 500 years," he told Ars.</p>
<p>But the divers braved the frigid water and the strong currents anyway. On one dive, the broad curves of a wooden hull suddenly emerged from the gloom before them, stretching much further than the 3m to 4m they could see underwater. The next day, diving further out in the channel, they found a second wreck lying about 5m away from the first, end-to-end across the channel.</p>
<h2>Long-lost sisters?</h2>
<p><em>Äpplet</em> was scuttled in 1659, and at least a few people in Sweden's navy probably watched the ship vanish beneath the waves with a sense of relief. They'd been trying to get rid of her for years.</p>
<p>"We know that the navy tried to sell her three times," Hansson told Ars. "She was a slow sailer and wasn't used often for more than transportation."</p>
<p>He suggests that shipbuilder Hein Jacobsson built <em>Äpplet</em> wider than <em>Vasa</em>, in an attempt to correct the top-heaviness that doomed the earlier ship. But he may have actually built her too wide, making her sluggish and unwieldy in the water.</p>
<p>"We don't know that yet," Hansson told Ars. "That sort of question, we will hopefully answer after more dives and surveys."</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/374280453?color=ff9933" width="980" height="550" frameborder="0"></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Video taken as divers explored the wrecks. </p></div>
<p><em>Kronan</em> and <em>Scepter</em> had more successful careers, but in the end, they also ended up as sunken blockades in the harbor. Historic documents describe <em>Kronan</em>'s hold being filled with iron bars before other warships aimed their cannons at her waterline to scuttle her. "The ships had sailed and survived several battles, and after 30-40 years in duty, there was no meaning to repair them anymore," Hansson told Ars. "It's a kind of old [form of] recycling."</p>
<p>At the moment, Hansson and his colleagues don't know which two of the three ships they're dealing with—assuming that the wrecks really are <em>Vasa</em>'s sisters. The divers collected wood samples from both wrecks and will radiocarbon date them to confirm when the ships were built. All three of <em>Vasa</em>'s sisters hail from the early 1630s, so if the dates match up, that will be a strong hint.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the archaeologists plan to continue diving on the wrecks, measuring timbers and documenting details of how the ships are put together. Wooden sailing ships were the high-tech military vehicles of their day, and <em>Vasa</em> and her sisters were among the earliest to carry large numbers of heavy cannon. "We didn't have time to do a proper survey but will come back," Hansson told Ars. "It's quite hard to get a grip of such a big wreck in such a short time."</p>
<p>Nearby Djurgården Island is the site of the museum where <em>Vasa</em> now resides in a carefully prepared facility. Her presence is a reminder of what a large, complex, and very expensive undertaking raising these two wrecks could be—so far there are no similar plans for these ships. It's also not clear what sorts of artifacts might turn up; most things of value and most personal effects would have been removed before the scuttling. But the wrecks may help fill in some details about exactly why Vasa sank and how shipbuilders modified their designs in response to the disaster.</p>
<p>"We hope to learn how the construction developed and to see actually why <em>Vasa</em> sank," Hansson told Ars. "This is a tremendous opportunity for us and the <em>Vasa</em> museum. It's not very common we find wrecks with this potential and long, exciting history!"</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Official Monero website is hacked to deliver currency-stealing malware</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 02:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website hack]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GetMonero.com delivers Linux and Windows binaries that steal users' funds.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/hacked-640x438.jpg" alt="Image of ones and zeros with the word "Hacked" superimposed."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">(credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://pixabay.com/p-823336/">Pixabay</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The official site for the Monero digital coin was hacked to deliver currency-stealing malware to users who were downloading wallet software, officials with GetMonero.com said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The supply-chain attack came to light on Monday when a site user reported that the <a href="https://github.com/monero-project/monero/issues/6151">cryptographic hash for a command-line interface wallet downloaded from the site didn't match the hash listed on the page</a>. Over the next several hours, users discovered that the miss-matching hash wasn't the result of an error. Instead, it was an attack designed to infect GetMonero users with malware. Site officials later confirmed that finding.</p>
<p>"It's strongly recommended to anyone who downloaded the CLI wallet from this website between Monday 18th 2:30 AM UTC and 4:30 PM UTC, to check the hashes of their binaries," GetMonero officials <a href="https://web.getmonero.org/2019/11/19/warning-compromised-binaries.html">wrote</a>. "If they don't match the official ones, delete the files and download them again. <strong>Do not run the compromised binaries for any reason.</strong>"</p>
<p>An <a href="https://bartblaze.blogspot.com/2019/11/monero-project-compromised.html">analysis of the malicious Linux binary</a> found that it added a few new functions to the legitimate one. One of the functions was called after a user opened or created a new wallet. It sent the wallet seed—which is the cryptographic secret used to access wallet funds—to a server located at node.hashmonero[.]com. The malware then sent wallet funds to the servers located at node.xmrsupport[.]co and 45.9.148[.]65.</p>
<p>A malicious Windows version of the CLI wallet carried out an almost identical attack sequence.</p>
<p>At least one person participating in a Reddit forum claimed to have <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/moneromanz/">lost digital coins after installing the malicious Linux binary</a>.</p>
<p>"Roughly 9 hours after I ran the binary a single transaction drained my wallet of all $7000," the person wrote. "I downloaded the build yesterday around 6pm Pacific time."</p>
<p>The user said at the time that it wasn't clear if the malware carried out other nefarious actions on the computer itself. The person made a copy of the malware <a href="https://anonfile.com/bbq8h9Bdn7/monero-wallet-cli">available for download</a> so that researchers can analyze the code. Under no circumstances should people run this binary on anything other than a test machine that has no access to cryptocurrency wallets.</p>
<p>GetMonero's advisory didn't say the site was compromised or if the vulnerabilities that led to the hack had been fixed. Users should stay apprised of this breach in the coming days.</p>
<p>In the meantime, people who want to verify the authenticity of their Monero CLI software can <a href="https://getmonero.org/resources/user-guides/verification-windows-beginner.html">check here for Windows</a> or <a href="https://getmonero.org/resources/user-guides/verification-allos-advanced.html">here</a> for more advanced users of Windows, Linux, or macOS.</p>
<p>The incident is a graphic reminder of why it's crucial to check summaries before installing software. The links in the paragraph above this one explain how to do that.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google outlines plans for mainline Linux kernel support in Android</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Amadeo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google wants less forking, more modularization for Android's Linux kernel. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Solving_issues_associated_with_modules_and_supplie-980x513.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Google's eventual plan for Android, one kernel for every device, instead of the device-specific kernels that exist now.                       [credit:
                        <a href="https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/sessions/67/#20190910.detailed">Saravana Kannan</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>It seems like Google is working hard to update and upstream the Linux kernel that sits at the heart of every Android phone. The company was a big participant in this year's <a href="https://www.linuxplumbersconf.org/">Linux Plumbers Conference</a>, a yearly meeting of the top Linux developers, and Google <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f2C-gA8jEyY">spent a lot of time</a> talking about getting Android to work with a generic Linux kernel instead of the highly customized version it uses now. It even showed an Android phone running a mainline Linux kernel.</p>
<p>But first, some background on Android's current kernel mess.Currently, three major forks happen in between the "mainline" Linux kernel and a shipping Android device (note that "mainline" here has no relation to Google's own "<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/09/android-10-the-ars-technica-review/#h8">Project Mainline</a>"). First, Google takes the LTS (Long Term Support) Linux kernel and turns it into the "Android Common kernel"—the Linux kernel with all the Android OS-specific patches applied. Android Common is shipped to the SoC vendor (usually Qualcomm) where it gets its first round of hardware-specific additions, first focusing on a particular model of SoC. This "SoC Kernel" then gets sent to a device manufacturer for even more hardware-specific code that supports every other piece of hardware, like the display, camera, speakers, usb ports, and any extra hardware. This is the "Device Kernel," and it's what actually ships on a device.</p>
<p>This is an extremely long journey that results in every device shipping millions of lines of out-of-tree kernel code. Every shipping device kernel is different and device specific—basically no device kernel from one phone will work on another phone. The mainline kernel version for a device is locked in at the beginning of an SoC's initial development, so it's typical for a brand-new device to ship with a Linux kernel that is two years old. Even Google's latest <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/google-pixel-4-review-overpriced-uncompetitive-and-out-of-touch/">and, uh, greatest device</a>, the Pixel 4, shipped in October 2019 with Linux kernel 4.14, an LTS release from November 2017. It will be stuck on kernel 4.14 forever, too. Android devices do not get kernel updates, probably thanks to the incredible amount of work needed to produce just a single device kernel and the chain of companies that would need to cooperate to do it. Thanks to kernel updates never happening, this means every new release of Android usually has to support the last three years of LTS kernel releases (the minimum for Android 10 is 4.9, a 2016 release). Google's commitments to support older versions of Android with security patches means the company is still supporting kernel 3.18, which is five years old now. Google's band-aid solution for this so far has been to team up with the Linux community and support mainline Linux LTS releases for longer, and they're now up to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/android-users-rejoice-linux-kernel-lts-releases-are-now-good-for-6-years/">six years of support</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, at Linux Plumbers Conference 2018, <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/771974/">Google announced</a> its initial investigation into bringing the Android kernel closer to mainline Linux. This year it shared a bit more detail on its progress so far, but it's definitely still a work in progress. "Today, we don't know what it takes to be added to the kernel to run on a [specific] Android device," Android Kernel Team lead Sandeep Patil told the group at LPC 2019. "We know what it takes to run <em>Android</em> but not necessarily on any given hardware. So our goal is to basically find all of that out, then upstream it and try to be as close to mainline as possible."</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='Google says that &quot;compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018).&quot; Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kernel_lts_diff.png" alt='Google says that &quot;compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018).&quot; Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Google says that "compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018)." Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://source.android.com/devices/architecture/kernel/android-common">Google </a>)</p></div>
<p>While there is still work to be done for getting the wider Android ecosystem and myriad device configurations on board, for specific models of device, things seem to be progressing well. Tom Gall, the director of the Linaro Consumer Group, showed off a Xiaomi Poco F1 <em>actually running</em> the mainline Linux kernel under the usual Android OS. Gall told the audience, "There are major, major props to be given to the Google Kernel Team in particular for getting their code upstream so that we can boot devices with a mainline kernel."</p>
<p>Along with the plan to upstream as much kernel code as possible, Google is also aiming to replicate its earlier work at modularizing Android, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/android-8-0-oreo-thoroughly-reviewed/#h1">Project Treble</a>. Just as Treble created a stable interface between the Android OS and the device HALs (Hardware Abstraction Layers), Google's proposal for bringing Android closer to mainline Linux (How is there not a silly "project" name for this yet?) involves stabilizing Linux's in-kernel ABI and having a stable interface for the Linux kernel and hardware vendors to write to. Google wants to decouple the Linux kernel from its hardware support.</p>
<p>The Linux community <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/process/stable-api-nonsense.rst">has been against</a> the idea of a stable interface for some time, with the suggestion that if you want the ability to quickly update a kernel, open source your drivers and get them in the main kernel tree, where any changes will be taken care of for you. Open sourcing drivers is an absolute deal breaker for many hardware companies, though, and no amount of advocacy or product degradation is going to change that. The fact that Google is stuck supporting five-year-old versions of Linux shows this model isn't working.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome.png"><img alt='Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome-980x537.png" alt='Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/sessions/67/#20190910.detailed">Matthias Männich</a>)</p></div>
<p>Matthias Männich, a senior software engineer at Google, displayed a diagram labeled "Android Next Generation" that showed what this proposed kernel architecture would look like. Google would ship a "Generic Kernel Image (GKI)" along with several "GKI Modules" that would expose this stable API/ABI in the kernel. The hardware-specific drivers (probably closed source drivers) would be loaded as kernel modules. So instead of forks on top of forks, everything gets modularized into additive packages.</p>
<p>For now, Google is only proposing that the in-kernel ABI be stable for a single LTS version. So this wouldn't allow devices to upgrade from one version of the Linux kernel to another—it would just allow for a single generalized kernel image to work across multiple devices, instead of the device-specific kernel forks we have today. It would definitely allow for easier security updates, and hopefully it would get new LTS releases to market faster.</p>
<p>We would be premature if we said this is a change that is <em>definitely</em> coming to Android and the Linux kernel. There are still tons of problems to solve (both technically and politically, I would imagine), and some of these talks were more like public brainstorming sessions between the Google presenters and the Linux engineers (many of which were also Googlers!) in the audience. This is the second year in a row Google has showed up to LPC and pitched the idea of using the mainline Linux kernel in Android, though, and with Android being one of the biggest Linux sort-of-distros on Earth, it makes sense for everyone to work together, right?</p>
<p>"We have miles to go, and we know that, but we've come along from where we started," Patil told the crowd. "Last year, I talked it into existence. This time, we actually have problems to discuss."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>As DirecTV tanks, AT&#038;T says it will “re-bundle” TV with HBO Max</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 23:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hbo max]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[HBO Max will include non-AT&#38;T shows as AT&#38;T aims to rebuild the bundle. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-john-stankey-att-hbo-max-800x525.jpg" alt="AT&T executive John Stankey speaking in front of a backdrop that says "HBO Max.""/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-john-stankey-att-hbo-max.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="672" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> AT&amp;T executive John Stankey at a presentation for investors at Warner Bros. Studios on October 29, 2019, in Burbank, California. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=presley%20ann&amp;assettype=image&amp;sort=newest">Getty Images | Presley Ann</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>AT&amp;T's traditional TV business is tanking, with the company having lost <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/10/att-loses-another-1-3-million-tv-customers-as-directv-freefall-continues/">nearly 5 million</a> satellite and wireline TV customers since the end of 2016.</p>
<p>But AT&amp;T President John Stankey sees a path forward in recreating the traditional cable-TV bundle on the Internet. AT&amp;T's HBO Max is slated to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/hbo-max-will-bring-up-the-streaming-v">launch in May 2020</a> for $14.99 a month, and AT&amp;T has set an ambitious goal of <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/hbo-max-will-reach-50m-u-s-subscribers-by-2024-att-projects-1202770351/">50 million US subscribers</a> within five years.</p>
<p>A subscriber number like that would make HBO Max far bigger than AT&amp;T's DirecTV satellite division and its U-verse wireline TV service. But ultimately, the service customers get could end up looking pretty similar to DirecTV, U-verse, or cable TV.</p>
<p>"Stankey said the vision for HBO Max is to create a bundle of content that includes movies and shows not owned by WarnerMedia in addition to those it creates and licenses on its own," <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/11/18/20970066/hbo-max-netflix-streaming-cable-bundle-john-stankey-warnermedia-cord-cutting">Vox wrote yesterday</a> in a report titled "HBO Max wants to be the next cable bundle instead of the next Netflix." The report summarizes an interview Stankey gave at Recode's Code Media conference.</p>
<p>HBO Max will "at some point in time" be "a platform that we allow others to bring content into," Stankey said. "I don't think, from my point of view, we're ever going to have a lock or a monopoly on creativity."</p>
<h2>“Re-aggregate and re-bundle”</h2>
<p>Stankey, a 34-year AT&amp;T employee who is president and chief operating officer, is second-in-command to AT&amp;T CEO Randall Stephenson and may be in line to become CEO when Stephenson retires. He is also CEO of WarnerMedia, the AT&amp;T division that includes HBO.</p>
<p>Stankey noted that the proliferation of online video services has caused the traditional cable bundle to "fragment" into multiple platforms. Customers are frustrated about "the fragmentation of the bundle," but AT&amp;T can bring the bundle back together, Stankey said.</p>
<p>"We're basically unbundling to re-bundle," Stankey said. "At some point, there will be platforms that re-aggregate and re-bundle, and we'd like the [HBO Max] platform ultimately to be a place where re-aggregation occurs. And that doesn't just mean our content."</p>
<p>You can see the whole Stankey interview in the video below. The bundling discussion starts at 29:10:</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k-gUi8Oju90?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">AT&amp;T's John Stankey and Recode Senior Media Correspondent Peter Kafka onstage at Code Media 2019 in Los Angeles. </p></div>
<h2>With AT&amp;T, expect price increases</h2>
<p>If AT&amp;T fully recreated the cable bundle and still charged $14.99 a month for all of it, that'd be a good deal. But that isn't likely, as AT&amp;T has already developed a history of raising online streaming prices to amounts far greater than the introductory prices.</p>
<p>DirecTV Now, AT&amp;T's online alternative to DirecTV satellite service, was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/11/atts-35-directv-streaming-will-cost-60-unless-you-sign-up-right-away/">initially pitched in 2016</a> as a $35-per-month plan with more than 100 channels. But AT&amp;T has raised prices multiple times and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/03/att-raises-directv-now-price-again-after-promising-lower-post-merger-bills/">lowered the number of channels</a> by removing ones that aren't part of the AT&amp;T-owned Time Warner Inc.</p>
<p>The service, since renamed "AT&amp;T TV Now," today <a href="https://www.atttvnow.com/">costs</a> $65 a month for 45 channels including HBO. Packages with more than 100 channels cost at least $124 a month, while the "Ultimate" package costs $135 a month for 125 channels.</p>
<p>At $14.99 a month, HBO Max's price would be similar to Netflix's standard and premium offerings that cost $12.99 and $15.99, respectively. HBO Max's price would also be identical to the current price of HBO Now, even though HBO Max would have all the HBO content plus other stuff. But as we noted with the DirecTV Now example, it wouldn't be surprising to see AT&amp;T raise HBO Max prices significantly in the years after it launches.</p>
<h2>AT&amp;T scoffs at net neutrality concerns</h2>
<p>AT&amp;T becoming a bigger player in online video would raise net neutrality concerns, because AT&amp;T could use its control over home and mobile broadband networks to steer customers away from rival online services and toward AT&amp;T's.</p>
<p>In yesterday's Recode interview, Stankey claimed that it would be ridiculous for anyone to worry at all about AT&amp;T or other ISPs acting in anti-competitive ways with online streaming.</p>
<p>"You'd be hard-pressed to point to an instance of anybody's behavior that would suggest that there is any kind of discrimination, favoritism, or anything else going on in how people get to content on the Internet over a broadband connection," Stankey said. "It's a problem that's non-existent. There's absolutely nothing that's occurring."</p>
<p>Stankey would prefer that consumers direct their ire elsewhere. "I'd be far more concerned over the scale of what's occurring in terms of distribution platforms on mobile OSes, in terms and conditions associated with new product development on that and what that does to squash innovation, than anything to do with how traffic over the Internet is being treated today," he said.</p>
<p>But Stankey is wrong that AT&amp;T hasn't shown "favoritism" in its treatment of video services. The Federal Communications Commission in January 2017 accused AT&amp;T and Verizon of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/01/tom-wheeler-accuses-att-and-verizon-of-violating-net-neutrality/">violating net neutrality rules</a> by allowing their own video services (including AT&amp;T's DirecTV) to stream on their mobile networks without counting against customers' data caps, while charging other video providers for the same data cap exemptions.</p>
<p>FCC Chairman Ajit Pai <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/02/fcc-rescinds-claim-that-att-and-verizon-violated-net-neutrality/">rescinded that finding</a> shortly after taking over, but that doesn't change the fact that AT&amp;T gave its own video content favorable treatment under the data caps imposed on its mobile service.</p>
<p>Currently, AT&amp;T imposes data caps ranging from <a href="https://www.att.com/esupport/article.html#!/u-verse-high-speed-internet/KM1010099">150GB</a> to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/07/att-boosts-u-verse-data-cap-to-1tb-keeps-dsl-users-at-150gb/">1TB</a> on most of its home broadband plans, which can make it hard for TV watchers to get rid of cable or satellite and use online streaming exclusively. But AT&amp;T gives customers an <a href="https://www.att.com/esupport/article.html#!/u-verse-high-speed-internet/KM1242860/faq/who-is-eligible-unlimited-home-internet-data-usage">upgrade to unlimited data</a> if they pay an extra $30 a month or subscribe to DirecTV or U-verse TV. That means customers who prefer online streaming to AT&amp;T's own TV services could have to pay $30 a month extra to get enough data or pay $10 for each additional 50GB.</p>
<p>Under these schemes, AT&amp;T hasn't intentionally harmed the streaming performance of Netflix and other third-party services. But AT&amp;T has made it more expensive for customers on AT&amp;T broadband connections to make extensive use of those third-party services. The company has also used the unlimited-data perk to push customers toward AT&amp;T's own TV services.</p>
<p>The old net neutrality rules didn't include a ban on data caps or zero-rating schemes that exempt content from data caps, but the FCC evaluated individual implementations to determine whether they were anti-competitive or anti-consumer. Since the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/12/goodbye-net-neutrality-ajit-pais-fcc-votes-to-allow-blocking-and-throttling/">Trump administration's repeal</a>, the FCC hasn't enforced any net neutrality rules or scrutinized data-cap practices. But Washington state is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/net-neutrality-is-still-the-law-in-washington-state/">enforcing a net neutrality law</a>, and states including <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/10/california-delays-net-neutrality-laws-enforcement-until-after-court-case/">California</a> intend to do so in the future after all appeals are exhausted in a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/why-ajit-pais-unhinged-net-neutrality-repeal-was-upheld-by-judges/">lawsuit over the FCC's repeal of net neutrality rules</a>.</p>
<p>Stankey says that AT&amp;T won't abuse its control over broadband networks regardless of whether net neutrality rules are enforced in the future. "There was nothing [in terms of ISPs discriminating]. It's not happened," he said yesterday. "We all want a good broadband connection that people can use to get wherever they want to get."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ayahuasca alters brain waves to produce waking dream-like state, study finds</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 23:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ayahuasca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroscience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scientists at Imperial College London took EEG readings of subjects under the influence.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua1-800x535.jpg" alt="A highly stylized drawing of kneeling people waving their hands."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="803" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A sketch drawn by study participant of visuals during their experience. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/">Imperial College London/Chris Timmermann</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>People under the influence of a psychedelic brew known as ayahuasca frequently experience vivid visual and aural hallucinations and also report feeling as if they are in a dream. Now <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-51974-4">a new study</a> published in Scientific Reports has shown that the drug alters the user's waking brain-wave patterns to produce a mental state that the researchers describe as "dreaming while awake."</p>
<p>Ayahuasca is a bitter tea made from the Brazilian vine <em>banisteriopsis caapi</em>, colloquially known as the "spirit vine," used in shaman-led spiritual ceremonies among native people in the Amazon basin. Its primary active ingredient is dimethyltryptamine (DMT). That's the secret to ayahuasca's powerful psychedelic effects, which can also produce feelings of elation and fear or a sense of epiphany or psychological breakthrough. Those mind-altering properties come at a price, however. Participants in the ceremonies are often advised to bring a bucket, since nausea and vomiting (and sometimes diarrhea) are common reactions to the tea.</p>
<p>The brain controls perception and communication throughout the body via chemical neurotransmitters. Each neurotransmitter attaches to matching areas on nerve cells known as receptors. LSD, for example, targets the brain's serotonin receptors. Ayahuasca contains a compound (banisterine) that latches onto dopamine receptors in the brain. (That's why banisterine holds potential as a treatment for Parkinson's disease, which destroys dopamine receptors.)</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg"><img alt='A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg 2x" alt='A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.</a> (credit: Eitan Abramovich/AFP/Getty Images)</p></div>
<p>Several prior brain-imaging studies involving humans have shown that psychedelics disrupt normal brain activity and boost the random firing of neurons in the visual cortex. For instance, a <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3277566/">2012 study</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Nutt">David Nutt</a> and colleagues at the Imperial College London's Center for Psychedelic Research (CPR) scanned the brains of 30 subjects (all experienced users of psychedelics) while under the influence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psilocybin">psilocybin</a>—aka magic mushrooms. The lab then compared those scans to scans taken after the subjects ingested a saltwater placebo. The overall brain activity dropped in the so-called "default mode," a collection of highly interconnected neuronal networks that typically fire together when the brain is at rest. Psilocybin disrupted that synchronization, which could cause the dissociative aspects—the oft-reported disintegrating sense of self or ego—of hallucinogenic drugs.</p>

<p>In 2016, Nutt <em>et al</em>. <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2016/04/05/1518377113.abstract">published the results</a> of a second fMRI study, this time with subjects under the influence of LSD, compared with a placebo. Once again, there was less synchronization (overall brain activity) among neurons in the default mode. But the researchers also found that certain disparate regions of the brain that normally didn't communicate with each other did so under the influence of LSD, particularly the visual cortex. This could explain the vividly intricate hallucinations experienced by people tripping on acid. The effect <a href="https://www.nature.com/news/brain-scans-reveal-how-lsd-affects-consciousness-1.19727" rel="nofollow">appears to be separate</a> from that of ego dissolution, however; it's possible to experience one without the other.</p>
<p>Yet <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/srep46421" rel="nofollow">another study</a> the following year in Scientific Reports found a sudden increase in randomness in brain activity in subjects under the influence of psychedelic drugs. This is possible evidence for a heightened state of consciousness commonly associated with psychedelics. And earlier this year, a team of Swiss researchers used MRI imaging to follow the brain under the influence of acid. The results <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/116/7/2743">support the idea</a> that hallucinogens cause the breakdown of the system that helps the brain keep track of which information is coming from the real world and which is generated by the brain itself.</p>
<p>As Ars' John Timmer <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/02/watching-brains-on-acid-using-an-mri/">reported in February</a>, "Instead of a general flooding of the cortex, they found that a limited number of specific regions saw increased activity. This suggests the states induced by hallucinogens are distinct from states like anesthesia and sleep, which lead to widespread changes in the cortex."</p>
<p>The current paper is the most recent study out of the Imperial's CPR. The study involved 13 subjects fitted with EEG caps and electrodes to monitor their brain activity while being given an IV infusion of DMT. The team found that the DMT caused a marked drop in alpha waves, a mark of wakefulness, along with a corresponding brief increase in theta brain waves, indicative of a dream state.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua-placebo-980x808.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          These are brainwaves measured by EEG under control conditions.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/">Imperial College London/Chris Timmermann</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Furthermore, while brain activity has been shown to decrease in subjects under the influence of psilocybin and LSD, the Imperial College researchers found more chaotic brain activity in subjects while under the influence of DMT. That might be why ayahuasca users report more vivid visual effects and a greater sense of immersion than is typically experienced with other psychedelics.</p>
<p>"We saw an emergent rhythm that was present during the most intense part of the experience, suggesting an emerging order amidst the otherwise chaotic patterns of brain activity," <a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/news/193993/ayahuasca-compound-changes-brainwaves-vivid-waking-dream/">said lead author Christopher Timmermann</a>. "From the altered brainwaves and participants' reports, it's clear these people are completely immersed in their experience—it's like daydreaming only far more vivid and immersive, it's like dreaming but with your eyes open."</p>
<p>Future studies could involve extending the time subjects spend on DMT to gather even more brain wave data, or subjecting participants to fMRI imaging while on DMT, as has been done already with psilocybin and LSD.</p>
<p>"It's hard to capture and communicate what it is like for people experiencing DMT, but likening it to dreaming while awake or a near-death experience is useful," said co-author and CPR head Robin Carhart-Harris. "Our sense is that research with DMT may yield important insights into the relationship between brain activity and consciousness, and this small study is a first step along that road."</p>
<p>DOI: Scientific Reports, 2019. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-51974-4">10.1038/s41598-019-51974-4</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bonkers pricing of “free” flu shots shows what’s wrong with US healthcare</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 22:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aetna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cigna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare costs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influenze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In broken US health system, a flu shot can cost triple what it should.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-111874254-800x533.jpg" alt="A chain pharmacy uses it sign to advertise flu shots."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-111874254.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2000" data-width="3000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Regardless of the crazy pricing, you should get your flu shot. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/flu-shot-availability-is-advertised-below-cvs-caremark-corp-news-photo/111874254?adppopup=true">Getty | Bloomberg</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The annual flu shots that are free to those with health insurance are not immune from the convoluted and contemptible price-gouging that plague the US healthcare system.</p>
<p>Health insurance companies pay wildly different amounts for the same vaccines depending on how negotiations go with individual medical providers across the country. In some cases, providers have forced insurers to pay upward of three times the price they would pay to other providers, according to <a href="https://khn.org/news/the-startlingly-high-cost-of-the-free-flu-shot/?utm_campaign=KHN%3A%20First%20Edition&amp;utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=79594026&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9j3CgVWTbdvIGCuGfMrRsbldj15PAtJawit8jUwTgslJpMtRcxjew9LY2sLO6SgJt6wGTe3RWUEJSGuhTTcgckztQYMA&amp;_hsmi=79594026">an investigation by Kaiser Health News</a>.</p>
<p>The outlet noted that one Sacramento, California, doctors’ office got an insurer to pay $85 for a flu shot that it offered to uninsured patients for $25.</p>
<p>Though $85 might seem like a trifling amount in the bloated scheme of the US healthcare system, such prices quickly add up as tens of millions of people receive a flu shot each year. And while the Affordable Care Act requires insurers to cover the full costs of all federally recommended vaccines, including the flu vaccine, any extra costs to insurers get passed on to patients through higher insurance premiums, economists told KHN.</p>
<p>Looking further at what insurers paid for flu vaccines, KHN found that costs spanned the whole range from $25 to $85. A doctor in Long Beach, California, got insurer Cigna to pay $47.53 for a shot, while a CVS in downtown Washington, DC, got $32 from Cigna for the same shot. A CVS just 10 miles away in Maryland got $40.</p>
<p>My insurance did a little bit better than those. My doctor’s office in the District of Columbia initially charged my insurer, Aetna, $35 for my flu shot, and Aetna paid them the negotiated rate of $24.50.</p>
<p>But that’s still significantly above federally negotiated rates. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/programs/vfc/awardees/vaccine-management/price-list/index.html">negotiated a price just under $14</a> for the same shot. The agency reported a private-sector cost of around $18. Likewise, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Medicare-Fee-for-Service-Part-B-Drugs/McrPartBDrugAvgSalesPrice/VaccinesPricing">the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services pays out $18</a> for the vaccine.</p>
<p>Aetna paid around 35% more than that for my identical shot—and there was no way for me to know that before I got the shot. Hidden negotiated rates make it impossible for patients to shop around. And this isn’t just a problem for flu shots. Wild price variances occur for everything from diagnostic scans to surgeries.</p>
<p>“We don’t have a functioning health care market because of all this lack of transparency and opportunities for price discrimination,” Glenn Melnick, a health economist at the University of Southern California, told KHN. “Prices are inconsistent and confusing for consumers,” he added. “The system is not working to provide efficient care, and the flu shot is one example of how these problems persist.”</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Password data for ~2.2 million users of currency and gaming sites dumped online</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal information]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researcher confirms data belongs to users of Gatehub and EpicBot services.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dumping-800x600.jpg" alt="A dump truck is on the verge of emptying its contents."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dumping.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="768" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/blmalaska/33923188986">Bureau of Land Management Alaska Follow</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Password data and other personal information belonging to as many as 2.2 million users of two websites—one a cryptocurrency wallet service and the other a gaming bot provider—have been posted online, according to Troy Hunt, the security researcher behind the Have I Been Pwned breach notification service.</p>
<p>One haul includes personal information for as many as 1.4 million accounts from the <a href="https://gatehub.net/">GateHub cryptocurrency wallet service</a>. The other contains data for about 800,000 accounts on <a href="https://epicbot.com/">RuneScape bot provider EpicBot</a>. The databases include registered email addresses and passwords that were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_hash_function">cryptographically hashed</a> with bcrypt, a function that's among the hardest to crack.</p>
<p>The person posting the 3.72GB Gatehub database said it also includes two-factor authentication keys, mnemonic phrases, and wallet hashes, although GateHub officials said an investigation suggested wallet hashes were not accessed. The EpicBot database, meanwhile, purportedly included usernames and IP addresses. Hunt said he selected a representative sample of accounts from both databases to verify the authenticity of the data. All of the email addresses he checked were registered to accounts of the two sites.</p>
<p>Another indication that the data in the file belongs to GateHub account holders: <a href="https://twitter.com/aashishkoirala/status/1195001331657957377">this Twitter post</a>. It came from Aashish Koirala, a self-described software developer who said he recently received a notification from the identity protection arm of consumer credit reporting service Experian. The advisory, Koirala said, notified him that "my credentials for @GateHub were found compromised on the Dark Web."</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/troyhunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@troyhunt</a> Just got word from Experian's IDNotify that my credentials for <a href="https://twitter.com/GateHub?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GateHub</a> were found compromised on the dark web. FYI in case you were getting any news about a GateHub breach or hack.</p>
<p>— Aashish Koirala (@aashishkoirala) <a href="https://twitter.com/aashishkoirala/status/1195001331657957377?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p>While there were 2.2 million unique addresses in the two dumps, it's possible that corresponding password hashes or other data isn't included with each one.</p>
<h2>Unauthorized access</h2>
<p>The Gatehub account data, which was posted to a widely visited hacker site in late August, came three months after the cryptocurrency service <a href="https://gatehub.net/blog/gatehub-investigation-final-statement/">reported that it had been hacked</a>. The attackers, GateHub said, had stolen—or at least tried to steal—a wealth of sensitive information for more than 18,000 user accounts. The wording of the post left unclear exactly what data beyond access tokens was successfully obtained.</p>
<p>GateHub officials wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>As previously suggested in our investigation update, we believe the perpetrator gained unauthorized access to a database holding valid access tokens of our customers. Using these tokens the perpetrator accessed 18,473 encrypted customer accounts, a very small fraction of our total user base. On affected accounts, the following data was being targeted: email addresses, hashed passwords, hashed recovery keys, encrypted XRP ledger wallets secret keys (non-deleted wallets only), first names (if provided), last names (if provided).</p></blockquote>
<p>GateHub's disclosure went on to say that site officials notified users whose accounts were accessed and generated new encryption keys and re-encrypted sensitive information, such as ledger wallet secret keys.</p>
<p>The posting of the database means the breach that the wallet service disclosed in July was much bigger than previously thought. Rather than obtaining only access tokens, the attackers also took 2FA keys, email addresses, password hashes, mnemonic phrases, and possibly wallet hashes. What's more, the breach affected as many as 1.4 million GateHub users, not just the 18,473 mentioned in the disclosure. In an email, an unnamed member of the GateHub security team wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>We are aware of a database posted on RaidForums whose author claims that it belongs to GateHub. The alleged GateHub database is being thoroughly examined by our team, therefore, we are unable to confirm its authenticity at this time. We will make sure to keep you posted of any updates.</p>
<p>From what we have gathered so far, it does not contain wallet hashes. As mentioned before, we are still verifying its authenticity.</p>
<p>One of our initial responses to the cyber attack was to introduce re-encryption to all GateHub accounts. With the new re-encryption, all GateHub accounts were re-encrypted and all of our customers had to change their passwords. This was introduced in July 2019.</p></blockquote>
<p>The statement didn't explain why the investigation has been unable to verify the authenticity of the data 25 days after it was posted and four months after it was first accessed. It was also unclear precisely what officials meant by "re-encrypted."</p>
<p>"There are references to PGP [in the database]," Hunt told me. "There are what appear to be PGP encrypted strings. I'm not sure if that's what they rotated. Are they talking about rotating cryptographic hashes, or are they talking about this section of PGP which is wallet related?"</p>
<h2>Change passwords, mnemonic phrases, etc.</h2>
<p>The EpicBot leak, meanwhile, was posted to the same hacker forum on October 25, the same day as the GateHub dump. Hunt said it contains roughly 800,000 unique email addresses, along with usernames, IP addresses, and bcrypt-hashed passwords. EpicBot officials didn't respond to requests to comment for this post. I couldn't find any mention of a breach on the EpicBot website.</p>
<p>Both sites' use of the bcrypt hashing function, assuming it was implemented correctly, is encouraging. Bcrypt is so compute-intensive that it would require years for even powerful graphic-card equipped clusters to crack all of the passwords. Of course, deploying bcrypt insecurely is easy. Programming errors made by the Ashley Madison cheaters' website, for instance, made it trivial to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/09/once-seen-as-bulletproof-11-million-ashley-madison-passwords-already-cracked/">crack more than 11 million of the 36 million bcrypt hashes</a> leaked in the 2015 hack of the site.</p>
<p>The leaking of other types of personal information for what could be as many as 2.2 million accounts is less admirable, especially since there's little evidence all affected users were notified in a timely fashion. EpicBot users should change their passwords as soon as possible. For GateHub users, a password reset isn't required given the mandatory change done in July. But mnemonic phrases should be replaced, assuming they weren't already.</p>
<p>To ward off the growing threat of credential stuffing attacks, users of both sites should also change passwords for any other sites that used the compromised credentials. Users should also be on the alert for spear phishing and other forms of attack that make use of their personal information.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Where the Wi-Fi sucks” is where a new wireless protocol does its magic</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604007</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 21:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Salter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WiFi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604007</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ONPC won't help you browse the Internet, but it's a good way to monitor devices.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/lundrigan-800x535.jpeg" alt="A man operates an elaborate computer interface."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/lundrigan.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="562" data-width="840">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> BYU assistant professor of computer engineering Phil Lundrigan is looking at an ONPC heartbeat on an RF signal analyzer. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.byu.edu/">Brigham Young University</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Researchers at Brigham Young University have created a new RF protocol that runs on top of existing consumer Wi-Fi at significantly greater range. But before you get too excited, the protocol's bandwidth is extremely low—so much so that it makes <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/lostik-usb-lora-radios/">LoRa</a> look like an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_Carrier_transmission_rates#OC-24">OC-24</a>. The protocol, called <a href="https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3345436">ONPC</a>—short for On-Off Noise Power Communication—currently only specifies a single bit per second.</p>
<p>Although ONPC only conveys one bit per second of data, its range is 60m or more beyond Wi-Fi—and it runs in software alone, on unmodified Wi-Fi hardware. An ONPC device can connect to standard Wi-Fi when range permits, fall back to ONPC mode if the connection drops, and then re-connect to the Wi-Fi when it becomes available again.</p>
<h2>Disconnected versus unpowered</h2>
<p>BYU Associate Professor of Computer Engineering Phil Lundrigan told Ars that ONPC was inspired by problems in an otherwise unrelated health care research project he'd worked on. The project required placing IoT sensors in the homes of study participants so that BYU's control over the environment was minimal to nonexistent. The project also required the sensors to report back to the researchers over the Internet, using whatever Wi-Fi the study participants had in place.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, participants' home Wi-Fi tended to have problems. The sensors didn't need much of a connection, since they only needed to report small amounts of data over a time series—so placing them at the dubious edges of coverage was basically OK. The problem the researchers ran into was that at the edge of coverage, their sensors would frequently drop off the Wi-Fi for hours or even days at a time.</p>
<p>Dropping off the Wi-Fi wasn't necessarily a big problem. The sensors were perfectly capable of continuing to store data locally, and they would send all the collected data in a batch whenever they managed to reconnect to the Wi-Fi again. But if the sensor was truly powered off or broken—and thus not collecting data—this posed real problems for the study.</p>
<p>This left researchers balancing the need to make sure sensors worked against the likelihood of annoying participants badly enough that they might drop out of the study. In one memorable case, a basket of laundry in front of a sensor was all that kept it from transmitting its data to the researchers. When the laundry basket was moved, the device almost immediately reconnected to the house's Wi-Fi and began transmitting its stored data.</p>
<h2>Shave and a haircut, two bits</h2>
<p>The desire to know whether their sensors were <em>working</em>, even if they weren't connected, led the researchers to the idea of ONPC. 802.11 Wi-Fi requires a bi-directional signal strong and clean enough to establish a 1Mbps PHY rate, and if such a signal can't be established, the client device and Wi-Fi infrastructure are effectively invisible to one another.</p>
<p>Although a Wi-Fi AP (Access Point) can't actually receive <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/802.11_Frame_Types">frames</a> sent by a STA (Station, or Wi-Fi client device) outside its range, it's still possible for it to detect them by looking for changes in the RF noise floor. When a STA outside the AP's range transmits a frame, the noise floor increases. When the STA stops transmitting, the noise floor decreases.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ONPC-overview.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          This is an overview of an ONPC-capable Wi-Fi network. Whenever possible, the devices just use normal Wi-Fi. When the network isn't available, they transmit ONPC frames instead.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.byu.edu/">Brigham Young University</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>ONPC isn't looking for data inside Wi-Fi frames at all—it deduces its data from the presence or absence of the frames themselves, much like plugging and unplugging a device into a switch. ONPC also looks for Morse Code in the pattern the link-light blinks in.</p>
<p>A Wi-Fi AP configured as an ONPC receiver has pre-configured and shared pseudo-random patterns which associate it with STAs configured as ONPC transmitters. When the AP detects a matching pattern in the RF noise floor—like Roger Rabbit hearing a famous ditty <a href="https://youtu.be/xWdCQqAJxS0?t=70">knocked</a> on the wall of his hideout—it knows it's receiving a communication from one of its ONPC partners.</p>
<p>In the BYU researcher's testing, ONPC transmissions had minimal effect on the Wi-Fi network they rode. Test laptops near the edge of the Wi-Fi network saw no distinguishable drop in speed, as the lost-frame overhead was greater than the impact of the ONPC transmitter. Test laptops very near the AP, with near-flawless signal, might see throughput drop by 20% due to CSMA interruptions caused by ONPC transmission.</p>
<p>The 20% decrease BYU measured is as compared to no transmission at all—not compared to a Wi-Fi device connected to the same AP and moving data at extreme range. It's not unreasonable to suspect that the ONPC transmission still consumes no more airtime (and therefore impacts performance no worse than) an actual Wi-Fi connection would have.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/onpc-locations.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Even the closest of these ONPC test locations is well over a football field away.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.byu.edu/">Brigham Young University</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<h2>Stayin’ Alive</h2>
<p>Since ONPC is designed to supplement standard 802.11 Wi-Fi, not replace it, there's one more piece to the puzzle—a controller that decides when to fall back from Wi-Fi to ONPC. The BYU team named that controller "Stayin' Alive."</p>
<p>When an ONPC-capable STA gets disconnected from the Wi-Fi network, it begins transmitting its ONPC identifying symbol. Similarly, when a controller realizes that it hasn't received data from that STA for a longer than normal interval, it turns on the ONPC receiver functionality and looks for that missing device's symbol on the noise floor. If the missing device's symbol is present, the controller knows the sensor is OK; if the symbol is missing, the controller can set an alarm condition to notify a human to investigate.</p>
<h2>Why ONPC?</h2>
<p>Numerous alternatives are competing for low-rate, long-range RF data transmission, including but not limited to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/lostik-usb-lora-radios/">LoRa</a>, cellular broadband, <a href="https://www.wi-fi.org/discover-wi-fi/wi-fi-halow">HaLow</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.11af">White-Fi</a>. However, these protocols achieve their long range in large part by operating at lower frequencies than consumer Wi-Fi, and they require an entirely separate infrastructure to operate.</p>
<p>ONPC allows for much greater economy through the use of existing, widely mass-marketed consumer Wi-Fi gear. Ars spent $46 apiece on a pair of <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B07NL2Y6LL/?tag=arstech20-20">LoStik</a> LoRa radios; the ONPC project used <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B076F52NQD/?tag=arstech20-20">Wemos D1 mini</a> WLAN boards, which cost about $3 apiece.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604007&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Company claims breakthrough in concentrating the Sun’s rays</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604265</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heliogen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar thermal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Company's tech could allow sunlight to power industrial processes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Heliogen_Lancaster_Facility_1_compressed-1080x675-800x500.jpg" alt="Image of a solar thermal tower and its associated mirrors."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Heliogen_Lancaster_Facility_1_compressed-1080x675.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="675" data-width="1080">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Heliogen's demonstration facility. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://heliogen.com/press-release-heliogen-achieves-breakthrough-temperatures-from-concentrated-sunlight-for-industrial-processes-with-momentum-toward-commercial-hydrogen-fuel-creation/">Heliogen</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The explosion of solar energy capacity has been driven almost entirely by the plunging cost of photovoltaic hardware. That has made the situation difficult for an alternate technology known as solar thermal. Thermal uses mirrors to focus incoming sunlight onto a location that reaches high temperatures, which can then be used to generate electricity by driving a steam turbine. Since heat is relatively easy to store, these plants can continue to produce power long after the Sun has set. In some cases, these plants are able to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2017/03/plans-for-a-24-hour-solar-thermal-plant-earn-environmental-approval-in-chile/">operate around the clock</a>.</p>
<p>Today, a company backed by tech investors is announcing that it has <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20191119005374/en/">developed an enhanced form of solar thermal</a> generation that can push the temperatures at the point of focus much higher. That's significant, because the promised temperatures reach heat needed for industrial processes like concrete production, metallurgy, and hydrogen production. While there are clear advantages when it comes to generating electricity, the key to this technology may be how readily it can be integrated into these industrial processes.</p>
<h2>A hot startup</h2>
<p>The company in question is a <a href="https://heliogen.com">startup called Heliogen</a>, which has received backing from several Silicon Valley investors and Bill Gates. But the technology Heliogen has developed does have a rather heavy tech component.</p>
<p>The tech comes in the form of the control of the mirrors involved. These have to track the Sun's motion and keep its incoming rays focused on a target, often held on a tower. That target contains some material, typically either molten salt or a fluid that transfers heat readily, in order to heat it. Typically, that fluid is heated to about 600°C, which is more than sufficient to generate electricity. But it falls well short of the 1,000°C-plus reached by the new system.</p>
<p>Heliogen's announcement is that its system has now cleared 1,000°C, and the company expects its system can go even higher. Heliogen claims to do so via finer mirror control. While details of Heliogen's system are sparse, it appears to use cameras to register the pointing of the mirrors and constantly adjust their location to keep the sunlight highly focused. This would be able to produce higher temperatures if either of the following is true: the system can focus more sunlight, or it can focus the same amount of sunlight on a smaller area than competing systems.</p>
<p>What are the advantages of higher temperatures? There are some for electrical generation. One of them is that it's simpler to generate electricity from a large temperature difference than it is from a smaller one. A high temperature would also allow the same amount of heat to be stored in a smaller volume, which could also simplify solar thermal systems and would cut down on the total materials needed for the system. So, there's some potential to lower the costs of solar thermal and make them somewhat more competitive with photovoltaic hardware.</p>
<h2>Industrial uses</h2>
<p>But Heliogen's key difference is that the temperature brings it into play for direct involvement of industrial processes. The company's press focuses on three industrial processes: production of steel, cement, and hydrogen.</p>
<p>The two former production processes require high temperatures; while these can be met by electrical heating elements, they're often reached by the direct burning of fossil fuels. Obviously, industrial facilities need to run as frequently as possible to recoup the large investments involved in building them, and a Heliogen system is not going to store enough heat for round-the-clock operation. The company realizes that but calculates that its system could prevent over half the cost of fossil fuels, as well as the associated carbon emissions.</p>
<p>An additional option is to use this temperature for hydrogen production. This can be done at environmental temperatures by the electricity-powered splitting of water. But the process is not especially efficient. Sufficiently high solar thermal temperatures can be used to directly split water, releasing hydrogen and oxygen, although those processes are <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/fuelcells/hydrogen-production-thermochemical-water-splitting">currently in the research stage</a>. But it can also be used for the <a href="https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlelanding/2019/se/c8se00565f#!divAbstract">decomposition of biomass</a>, releasing a syngas in the process. The hydrogen produced through these processes could either be used directly or converted into liquid fossil fuel replacement.</p>
<p>Solar thermal has some distinct advantages for electricity production, notably a built-in storage capability, and its relative lack of success makes shifting to full renewable energy more difficult. Having thermal produce transportation-ready fuels would allow it to tick off another item in our list of needs for getting to a fully renewable energy economy. So, even if Heliogen isn't ultimately successful as a company, it could at least provide a useful reconsideration of the technology it relies on.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604265&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senators ask if Facebook really lets users opt out of location tracking</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603987</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 19:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Facebook says you can turn off location tracking; two senators have their doubts]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1173369843-800x521.jpg" alt="The Facebook logo is displayed on a TV screen on September 9, 2019 in Paris, France."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1173369843.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3321" data-width="5104">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The Facebook logo is displayed on a TV screen on September 9, 2019 in Paris, France. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/in-this-photo-illustration-the-facebook-logo-is-displayed-news-photo/1173369843">Chesnot | Getty</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Back in September, Facebook updated its location privacy settings for users. "Facebook is better with location," the company stressed, but users were free to turn off location tracking, and the company would be happy to tell them how. That setting, however, comes with an enormous loophole, and two US senators want the company to explain itself.</p>
<p>Senators Chris Coons (D-Del.) and Josh Hawley (R-Mo.) today sent a letter (<a href="https://www.hawley.senate.gov/sites/default/files/2019-11/Hawley-Coons-Letter-Facebook-WiFi-Location-Data-Track.pdf">PDF</a>) to Facebook asking the company how, exactly, it tracks users' locations—even when location access and location history are disabled.</p>
<p>"We appreciate Facebook's attempt to proactively inform users about their privacy options," the senators wrote. "However, we are concerned that Facebook may not in fact be offering users the level of control that the company suggests these settings provide."</p>
<p>That choice of language is diplomatic indeed, given how often in the past Facebook has been <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-data-sharing-privacy-investigation/">accused</a> of <a href="https://fortune.com/2018/06/27/google-facebook-dark-patterns-privacy/">misleading users</a> when it comes to users' privacy, drawing attention from both <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/ftc-fines-facebook-5-billion-imposes-new-privacy-oversight/">US</a> and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/07/facebook-twitter-investigations-in-ireland-reach-conclusion.html">EU</a> regulators. </p>
<p>"If a user has decided to limit Facebook's access to his or her location, Facebook should respect these privacy choices," Sens. Coons and Hawley stress, expressing concerns that Facebook does not respect those choices at all.</p>
<h2>What Facebook does</h2>
<p>Facebook in September published a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2019/09/understanding-updates-to-your-devices-location-settings/">blog post</a> clarifying the way it gathers user location data from its mobile apps. Fall updates in both Android (to Android 10) and iOS (to iOS 13) spurred the changes, Facebook said at the time, with both operating systems allowing for more granular location sharing control.</p>
<p>For Android users, Facebook said it will "continue to respect your most restrictive settings choice." The social media giant also explained, "if your device location setting is set to 'all of the time' but your Facebook background location setting is off, we won't collect your precise location information when you're not using the Facebook app."</p>
<p>Facebook also explained the changes for iOS users. In addition to the three existing location settings—always, never, or only when in use—iOS users gained an "allow once" option for location data. That's in addition to additional notifications about when an app is using your precise location, as well as how many times the app accesses that information.</p>
<h2>What Facebook left out</h2>
<p>In one line near the end of the blog post, Facebook writes, "We may still understand your location using things like check-ins, events, and information about your Internet connection." That's the element Sens. Coons and Hawley zero in on.</p>
<p>GPS is great for super-precise pinpointing, but it's not wholly necessary for tracking your movements in a more general sense. You can get a less specific but still pretty accurate read on a device's location by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/11/where-have-you-been-your-smartphones-wi-fi-is-telling-everyone/">examining information about the Wi-Fi network</a> or cellular data network it's connected to. Facebook is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/12/10/business/location-data-privacy-apps.html">far from the only app</a> to take advantage of this kind of data, but its sheer size and history of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/ftc-fines-facebook-5-billion-imposes-new-privacy-oversight/">repeated bad behavior</a> have landed it in Congress's crosshairs. </p>
<p>Disabling Facebook's granular location settings has very little effect on what ads are targeted to you based on your location, as researcher Aleksandra Korolova <a href="https://medium.com/@korolova/facebooks-illusion-of-control-over-location-related-ad-targeting-de7f865aee78">explained in 2018</a>. Data relating to IP address, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth connections are enough for the platform to target you for location-based ads.</p>
<p>"Given that most mobile devices are connected to the Internet nearly all the time, whether through a cellular network or a Wi-Fi connection, this practice would allow Facebook to collect user location data almost constantly, irrespective of the user's privacy preferences," the senators note. They add that users who turn location services off "could reasonably be under the misimpression that their selection limits all of Facebook's efforts to extract location information."</p>
<p>"How frequently does Facebook collect location data based on information about a user's Internet connection when a user has turned off or limited location services?" the senators ask. They also seek information about how "precise" location information differs from all that other location information. And, importantly, they include: "Is it possible for a user to configure his or her privacy settings such that Facebook never monetizes any location information about that user?"</p>
<p>Sens. Coons and Hawley give Facebook until December 12 to respond to the request for information.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603987&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dealmaster: The OnePlus 7 Pro for $549 may be the smartphone deal of the year</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603859</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 18:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Staff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealmaster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For 256GB of storage, too. Plus tons more early Black Friday deals. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111919-800x444.png" alt="Dealmaster: The OnePlus 7 Pro for $549 may be the smartphone deal of the year"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dealmaster111919.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1200" data-width="2160">Enlarge</a> (credit: Ars Technica)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Greetings, Arsians! The Dealmaster is back with another round of deals to share. Today's deal is headlined by a <a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-7pro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$150 discount on the OnePlus 7 Pro</a>, a device we called the "<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/05/oneplus-7-pro-review-the-fastest-best-designed-best-value-android-phone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fastest, best-designed, best-value Android phone</a>" on the market earlier this year.</p>
<p>The deal applies to unlocked models—which <a href="https://www.verizonwireless.com/unlocked-smartphones/oneplus-7-pro-unlocked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">work on Verizon</a> and GSM networks like AT&amp;T and T-Mobile—and brings the phone down to $549. OnePlus says this is their official Black Friday discount for the holiday season, and our own Android guru <a href="https://arstechnica.com/author/ronamadeo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ron Amadeo</a> told the Dealmaster it will likely go down as the "smartphone deal of the year."</p>
<p>You can read Ron's review from this past May for the full details, but the short take is that the OnePlus 7 Pro was already a good value at its standard going rate of $699. Despite being a large phone, it's been efficiently designed, with no notches or overly large borders blocking the the 6.67-inch 3120x1440 display. The in-display fingerprint reader and pop-up selfie camera only add to that efficiency, and both work well. That display supports a 90Hz refresh rate, too, which makes operating the device feel noticeably smoother across the board. The Snapdragon 855 processor, 8GB of RAM, and UFS 3.0 storage keep general performance as snappy as a top-of-the-line phone should. The triple-camera system on the back isn't the absolute best on the market, but it's still a great value for the price. And the "Oxygen OS" software remains a uniquely clean and useful take on Android.</p>
<p>OnePlus does make a few trade-offs to reach its relatively low price: there's no microSD slot, headphone jack, wireless charging, or always-on display support, and you won't get security updates as quickly as something like a Google Pixel phone. It's also worth noting that OnePlus recently launched a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/oneplus-7t-review-not-very-new-but-still-one-of-the-best-phones-you-can-buy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new phone called the OnePlus 7T</a>, which adds a marginally faster chipset and flatter display than the 7 Pro's slightly curved panel but includes a notch and a more pronounced camera module on the back. The 7T typically starts at $599 outright, but with the deal here, there's little reason to get it over the 7 Pro, which remains a genuine flagship phone at a mid-tier price.</p>
<p>If $549 is still too much, OnePlus is also offering last year's <a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-6t?from=6t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus 6T for $449</a>, which is another $150 discount. Either way, OnePlus says these offers will last through December 2.</p>
<p>If you have no need for a new phone, though, we also have plenty more early Black Friday deals in today's roundup, including a ton of discounts on Anker charging gear, a Nintendo Switch bundle, holiday pricing for Sony's DualShock 4 controller, and much more. Have a look at the full rundown below.</p>
<div class="ars-component-layout ars-newsletter-callbox full" data-list-id="248915">
    <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-container">
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-header">    
            <h5 class="ars-newsletter-callbox-title">
                Dealmaster: An Ars newsletter
            </h5>
            <span class="ars-dotted-pattern"></span>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-content">    
            <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-description">The Dealmaster is launching its very own newsletter! Sign up to receive a shorter, tightly curated list of the very best tech deals on the Web—no nonsense, direct to your inbox, and often before they make it to the Ars homepage.</div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-newsletter-callbox-button-container">
            <a class="button button-orange ars-newsletter-callbox-button" href="https://arstechnica.com/newsletters?subscribe=248915">Sign Me Up!</a>  
        </div>
    </div>
</div>

<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Top 10 deals of the day</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-7pro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus 7 Pro</a> (256GB) unlocked smartphone for <strong>$549</strong> at OnePlus (normally $699).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-6t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus 6T</a> (256GB) unlocked smartphone for <strong>$449</strong> at OnePlus (normally $549).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Wireless-Controller-Crystal%2F228382645&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony DualShock 4</a> (Crystal) controller for PlayStation 4 for <strong>$39.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/37iFimP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $46.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fco%2FNintendo-Switch-Console-with-Minecraft-Game%2F842043295&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch</a> (latest model) + <em>Minecraft</em> (Switch) for <strong>$298.47</strong> at Walmart (normally $329.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-watch-series-4-gps-cellular-40mm-stainless-steel-case-with-white-sport-band-stainless-steel%2F6139670.p%3FskuId%3D6139670&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Watch Series 4</a> (40mm, GPS + Cellular) for <strong>$399</strong> at Best Buy (normally $649).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FFitbit-Versa-2-Smartwatch%2F172573076%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fitbit Versa 2</a> smartwatch for <strong>$149</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://amzn.to/332oJZ3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>, and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ffitbit-versa-2-smartwatch-40mm-aluminum-black-carbon-with-silicone-band%2F6364307.p%3FskuId%3D6364307&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $199.95).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2Fecobee3-Lite-Smart-Thermostat-2-0-No-Hub-Required%2F264743623&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ecobee3 Lite</a> (2nd gen) smart thermostat for <strong>$139</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://amzn.to/2KAmm9u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>, and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fecobee-ecobee3-lite-smart-thermostat-black%2F5823200.p%3FskuId%3D5823200&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $169).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XthFDt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a> portable battery - 18W USB-C PD for <strong>$31.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $45.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2D0bJZe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerLine</a> (3ft, 3-pack) USB-A to USB-C cable for <strong>$11.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $15.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OhjRK6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple AirPods Pro</a> true wireless noise-cancelling headphones for <strong>$234.98</strong> at Amazon (shipping in 1-4 weeks - normally $249).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Laptop and desktop PC deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/hp-envy-13-aq0011ms-laptop/93tjc4252km8/?activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HP Envy 13</a> laptop - Intel Core i5-8265U, 13.3-inch 1080p, 8GB RAM, 256GB SSD for <strong>$499</strong> at Microsoft (normally $849).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1488640-REG/msi_gl75_9sdk_007_gl75_i7_9750h_16gb_512gb.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MSI GL75</a> gaming laptop - Intel Core i7-9750H, 17.3-inch 1080p 144Hz, 16GB RAM, 512GB SSD, GeForce GTX 1660 Ti for <strong>$1,099</strong> at B&amp;H (normally $1,299).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdell-inspiron-2-in-1-13-3-4k-ultra-hd-touch-screen-laptop-intel-core-i7-16gb-memory-512gb-ssd-optane-black%2F6339272.p%3FskuId%3D6339272&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dell Inspiron 13</a> laptop - Intel Core i7-8565U, 13.3-inch 3840x2160, 16GB RAM, 512GB SSD + Optane for <strong>$979.99 </strong>at Best Buy (normally $1,399.99).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8984087-12578053?sid=dealmaster111919&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeals.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fproductdetail%2F331q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27-inch Dell UltraSharp U2717D</a> monitor - 1440p, IPS, 60Hz for <strong>$269.99</strong> at Dell (normally $399.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33HSHlZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24-inch Dell UltraSharp U2415</a> monitor - 1920x1200, IPS, 60Hz for <strong>$199.90</strong> at Amazon (normally $214.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Video game deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FRed-Dead-Redemption-Game-of-the-Year-Edition-Rockstar-Games-Xbox-One-360-710425490071%2F17491140&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Red Dead Redemption: Game of the Year Edition</em></a> (XB1) for <strong>$8.99</strong> at Walmart (normally $14.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/hellblade-senuas-sacrifice-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hellblade: Senua's Sacrifice</a> </em>(Switch) for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Nintendo eShop (normally $29.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2CDvp58" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Final Fantasy XV Royal Edition</a> </em>(PS4) for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li>Pre-order: <em><a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Brothers-PlayStation-4-883929689613%2F786104378" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cyberpunk 2077</a></em> (PS4, <a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?subId1=dealmaster091719&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FCyberpunk-2077-Warner-Bros-Xbox-One-883929689620%2F973645137" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XB1</a>) for <strong>$49.94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/2LwLwXn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $59.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Gaming deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fco%2FNintendo-Switch-Console-with-Minecraft-Game%2F842043295&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch</a> (latest model) + <em>Minecraft</em> (Switch) for <strong>$298.47</strong> at Walmart (normally $329.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-Playstation-4-DualShock-4-Wireless-Controller-Crystal%2F228382645&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony DualShock 4</a> (Crystal) controller for PlayStation 4 for <strong>$39.99</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/37iFimP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $46.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-wireless-controller-for-xbox-one-and-windows-10-black%2F5621843.p%3FskuId%3D5621843&amp;subid1=dealmaster102219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Xbox Wireless Controller</a> for Xbox One and Windows 10 - compatible with iOS 13 for <strong>$39.99</strong> at Best Buy and <a href="https://amzn.to/32EdFSw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $49.99).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-game-pass-ultimate/CFQ7TTC0KHS0/?activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$1</strong> at Microsoft (normally $44.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/121345728193" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony PlayStation Plus</a> 12-month membership card for <strong>$39.99</strong> at eBay (normally $59.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Finsignia-dock-kit-with-hdmi-and-usb-for-nintendo-switch-black%2F6065700.p%3FskuId%3D6065700&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Insignia Dock Kit</a> for Nintendo Switch - HDMI, USB 2.0 for <strong>$29.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $49.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34a1Y73" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HyperX Cloud II</a> wired gaming headset for <strong>$69.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $89.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g920-driving-force-racing-wheel-for-xbox-one-and-windows-black%2F4223402.p%3FskuId%3D4223402&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G920 Driving Force</a> racing wheel controller for Xbox One and PC for <strong>$199.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $219.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-G203-Prodigy-Wired-Gaming-Mouse-Optical-6-Buttons%2F342327342&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech G203 Prodigy</a> wired RGB gaming mouse for <strong>$20.99</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flogitech-g203-prodigy-wired-optical-gaming-mouse-with-rgb-lighting-black%2F5799700.p%3FskuId%3D5799700&amp;subid1=dealmaster110519" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://amzn.to/33gIcWV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $26.49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36PuDjd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corsair K95 RGB Platinum</a> wired mechanical gaming keyboard - Cherry MX Speed for <strong>$129.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fcorsair-k95-rgb-platinum-mechanical-gaming-keyboard-cherry-mx-speed-rgb-led-backlit-black%2F5713210.p%3FskuId%3D5713210&amp;subid1=dealmaster110919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $164.99).</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2QhtN9e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pandemic</a> </em>board game for <strong>$23.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $35.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F7-Wonders-Strategy-Board-Game%2F30655387&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>7 Wonders</em></a> board game for <strong>$29.92 </strong>at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/31PwEs4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $36.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>TV and home entertainment deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Famazon-fire-tv-stick-with-all-new-alexa-voice-remote-streaming-media-player-black%2F6321069.p%3FskuId%3D6321069&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Fire TV Stick</a> 1080p media streamer + <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Famazon-echo-dot-3rd-gen-smart-speaker-with-alexa-charcoal%2F6287974.p%3FskuId%3D6287974&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Echo Dot</a> (3rd gen) smart speaker + TP-Link Kasa Mini smart WiFi plug for <strong>$41.99</strong> at Best Buy (<strong>add both to cart</strong> - normally $88.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Qczm91" target="_blank" rel="noopener">55-inch Vizio M558-G1 M-Series Quantum</a> (2019 model) 4K LED TV for <strong>$479.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $548).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fvizio-65-class-m-series-quantum-led-smart-4k-uhd-2160p-tv-with-hdr%2F6345460.p%3FskuId%3D6345460&amp;subid1=dealmaster111419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">65-inch Vizio M658-G1 M-Series Quantum</a> (2019 model) 4K LED TV for <strong>$649.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $748).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZnGKO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polk Audio Command Bar</a> smart soundbar for <strong>$199</strong> at Amazon (normally $239.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Electronics deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-7pro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus 7 Pro</a> (256GB) unlocked smartphone for <strong>$549</strong> at OnePlus (normally $699).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.oneplus.com/oneplus-6t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus 6T</a> (256GB) unlocked smartphone for <strong>$449</strong> at OnePlus (normally $549).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OhjRK6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple AirPods Pro</a> true wireless noise-cancelling headphones for <strong>$234.98</strong> at Amazon (shipping in 1-4 weeks - normally $249).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FFitbit-Versa-2-Smartwatch%2F172573076%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fitbit Versa 2</a> smartwatch for <strong>$149</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://amzn.to/332oJZ3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>, and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ffitbit-versa-2-smartwatch-40mm-aluminum-black-carbon-with-silicone-band%2F6364307.p%3FskuId%3D6364307&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $199.95).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-watch-series-4-gps-cellular-40mm-stainless-steel-case-with-white-sport-band-stainless-steel%2F6139670.p%3FskuId%3D6139670&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Watch Series 4</a> (40mm, GPS + Cellular) for <strong>$399</strong> at Best Buy (normally $649).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XAhPcw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Watch Series 4</a> (44mm) for <strong>$329</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-apple-watch-series-4-gps-44mm-space-gray-aluminum-case-with-black-sport-band-space-gray-aluminum%2F5543300.p%3FskuId%3D5543300&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $379).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2Fecobee3-Lite-Smart-Thermostat-2-0-No-Hub-Required%2F264743623&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ecobee3 Lite</a> (2nd gen) smart thermostat for <strong>$139</strong> at Walmart, <a href="https://amzn.to/2KAmm9u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>, and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fecobee-ecobee3-lite-smart-thermostat-black%2F5823200.p%3FskuId%3D5823200&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $169).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2CWROKM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eufy Video Doorbell</a> - 2560x1920 for <strong>$107.99</strong> at Amazon (use code: <strong>D2EUFYSD</strong> - normally $159.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2O8SguG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TP-Link RE220</a> AC750 Wi-Fi range extender for <strong>$21.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $8 coupon</strong><span class="postCouponContainer"><span class="code"><strong> </strong>- normally $29.99).</span></span></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KdTZxN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribit XSound Go</a> portable Bluetooth speaker for <strong>$23.39</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon </strong>and use code: <strong>KBPYCM7E </strong>- normally $32.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34ZkHBV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FiiO μBTR</a> portable Bluetooth headphone adapter for <strong>$21.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $27.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34VO1ti" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eufy RoboVac 30C</a> robot vacuum for <strong>$191.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $100 coupon</strong> - normally $299.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/321a2oK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chamberlain MyQ Smart Garage Hub</a> smart garage door opener for <strong>$29.98</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fchamberlain-myq-smart-garage-hub-black%2F5900972.p%3FskuId%3D5900972&amp;subid1=dealmaster103119" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $44.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Storage deals</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XodvNm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung T5</a> (2TB) portable SSD for <strong>$247.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $284.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Xvnuk6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 860 EVO</a> (2TB) SATA III internal SSD for <strong>$229.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $299.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KCaT9h" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung 970 Evo Plus</a> (2TB) internal NVMe M.2 SSD for <strong>$329.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $479.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32XO0nk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SanDisk Extreme</a> (1TB) microSDXC card - U3, V30 for <strong>$299.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $439.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fwd-easystore-5tb-external-usb-3-0-portable-hard-drive-black%2F6356880.p%3FskuId%3D6356880&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WD Easystore</a> (5TB) external portable hard drive for <strong>$89.99</strong> at Best Buy (normally $169.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FWD-My-Passport-4TB%2F692843877&amp;subid1=dealmaster102919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WD My Passport</a> (4TB) portable external hard drive for <strong>$94</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/34dn43E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $109.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/36xYgpm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsung Evo Select</a> (512GB) microSDXC card for <strong>$77.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $89.99).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Accessories and miscellaneous deals</h2>
<ul>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/33Pssu3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Music Unlimited</a> 4-month membership for <strong>$0.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $39.96).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/33T5bHC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a> 6-month membership for <strong>$29.97</strong> at Amazon (normally $59.94).</li>
<li>New users only: <a href="https://amzn.to/2Cbn9cv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Audible</a> 3-month membership for <strong>$6.95/month</strong> at Amazon (normally $14.95/month).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XthFDt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a> portable battery - 18W USB-C PD for <strong>$31.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $45.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2D0bJZe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerLine</a> (3ft, 3-pack) USB-A to USB-C cable for <strong>$11.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $15.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XvoqVE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerLine II</a> (6ft) USB-C to Lightning cable - MFi-certified for <strong>$11.99</strong> at Amazon (use code: <strong>AKPL6FT2</strong> - normally $16.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XtWD7L" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerLine+ II</a> (3ft) braided nylon UB-C to Lightning cable - MFi-certified for <strong>$14.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $21.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KCUKAF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerLine</a> (6ft, 2-pack) USB-A to Lightning cable - MFi-certified for <strong>$13.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $19.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2qir9FP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerWave Pad</a> wireless charger - 10W Galaxy phones, 7.5W iPhones for <strong>$8.49</strong> at Amazon (use code: <strong>SDSR45HP </strong>- normally $13.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2KC16A4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerWave Pad</a> wireless charger + Anker PowerWave Stand wireless charging stand - 10W Galaxy phones, 7.5W iPhones for <strong>$25.89</strong> at Amazon (normally $36.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XrYcDn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker PowerPort Cube</a> power strip - 3x USB-A, 18W USB, 3x AC for <strong>$19.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $28.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2r8Hmgz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker Alkaline</a> AAA batteries (24-pack) for <strong>$6.99</strong> at Amazon (<strong>clip $3 coupon</strong> - normally $11.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/32BRHP7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Smart Keyboard</a> for 10.5-inch iPad Pro, 10.2-inch iPad, and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$99.99</strong> at Amazon and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-smart-keyboard-for-apple-ipad10-2-7th-generation-2019-10-5-ipad-pro-and-ipad-air%2F5822276.p%3FskuId%3D5822276&amp;subid1=dealmaster111219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> (normally $119.99).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2POBeV6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro for <strong>$30</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/34yVMFo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Leather Case</a> for iPhone 11 Pro Max for <strong>$30.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $49).</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2plGAfJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brydge 10.5</a> Bluetooth keyboard for 10.5-inch iPad Pro and iPad Air (3rd gen) for <strong>$69.99</strong> at Amazon (normally $87).</li>
<li><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Star-Wars-20th-Anniversary-Edition-Snowspeeder-75259%2F511638569&amp;subid1=dealmaster111919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Star Wars: The Empire Strikes Back Snowspeeder - 20th Anniversary Edition 75259</a> (309 pieces) building kit for <strong>$20.97</strong> at Walmart and <a href="https://amzn.to/37kkYRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> (normally $31.99).</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603859&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Esports gamers experience same stressors as pro athletes, study finds</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603089</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603089</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researchers interviewed seven elite players of <em>Counter-Strike Global Offensive</em>.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esportsTOP-800x533.jpg" alt="A new study by researchers at the University of Chichester in England found that esports players who compete in major tournaments face the same level of stress as pro-athletes."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esportsTOP.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="800" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A new study by researchers at the University of Chichester in England found that esports players who compete in major tournaments face the same level of stress as pro-athletes. (credit: ESL/University of Chichester)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Professional athletes at the highest level regularly contend not only with fierce competition from opposing teams or individual athletes but also intense psychological pressures, ranging from performance anxiety, fear of failure, and tensions resulting from miscommunication, particularly in team sports. Professional gamers competing in major esports competitions experience the same kinds of stressors, according to <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/336080393_Identifying_Stressors_and_Coping_Strategies_of_Elite_Esports_Competitors">a new psychology study</a> published in the International Journal of Gaming and Computer-Mediated Simulations.</p>
<p>Sports psychology has long been an active field, but applying it to esports is a relatively new area of research, one that the University of Chichester in the UK is embracing with its newly launched BA (Hons) esports degree. The program focuses on the scientific study of the physical and psychological impact of esports, including nutrition, coaching, and strategy in an immersive gaming environment, according to co-author Philip Birch, who specializes in sports and exercise performance psychology.</p>
<p>This is the <a href="https://www.chi.ac.uk/news/elite-esports-gamers-face-equivalent-psychological-pressure-pro-athletes-study-reveals">first study</a> of its kind, per Birch. The objective was to gain a clearer understanding not just of the stresses esports players face but also the coping strategies they use to deal with those stressors. Birch and his colleagues decided to focus on <em>Counter-Strike: Global Offensive</em> (<em>CSGO</em>) because it is similar to physical team sports like football or rugby. It's a multiplayer first-person shooter game that pits two teams against each other: Terrorists and Counter-Terrorists. The Terrorists try to plant bombs or take hostages, for example, while the Counter-Terrorists strive to defuse those bombs and rescue any hostages, as both sides try to eliminate the other. Players who do well are rewarded after each round with in-game currency; those who screw up can incur penalties.</p>
<p>The winning team takes home the prize pool. Prize pools for <em>CSGO</em> competitions range from $75,000 to as much as $1 million. More than 380 million people watched esports competitions in 2018 alone, according to the authors, and it's becoming increasingly professionalized, including the formation of a trade union for players in 2015. As esports has grown into a nearly $1 billion enterprise, so has interest in exploring the psychological factors affecting game play.</p>
<p>In fact, in 2016, one <em>CSGO</em> elite team, Astralis, actually hired a sports psychologist to help its members cope with the psychological pressures of competing in such a high-stakes environment. Astralis went on to win the ELEAGUE Major in January 2017, and members credited the team psychologist with improving their ability to cope with the competitive pressures. The use of sports psychologists by esport teams is likely to become more common, and that means more research like that conducted at Chichester is needed to provide an evidence-based foundation.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports3.jpg"><img alt='Gamers compete in a Valve Corp. &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt; esports tournament at the Gaming Stadium in Vancouver, British Columbia, on July 14, 2019. '  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports3-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports3.jpg 2x" alt='Gamers compete in a Valve Corp. &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt; esports tournament at the Gaming Stadium in Vancouver, British Columbia, on July 14, 2019. ' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports3.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Gamers compete in a Valve Corp. <em>Counter-Strike: Global Offensive</em> esports tournament at the Gaming Stadium in Vancouver, British Columbia, on July 14, 2019. </a> (credit:  James MacDonald/Bloomberg/Getty Images)</p></div>
<p>"We thought [the study] was a good opportunity to see how esports players cope in front of live audiences and how they get along as a team," Birch told Ars. Many elite teams are more like families, often rooming together as well as training and competing in <em>CSGO</em> together. "Sometimes families get along really well, and sometimes they don't," he said. And unresolved tensions can potentially affect overall team performance.</p>
<p>Since this was the first study, laying the groundwork for future research, the researchers adopted more of a qualitative, rather than quantitative, approach. According to Birch, the qualitative nature of the study was better suited to an initial exploration of the various stress factors and coping mechanisms common to esports players. Future studies might opt for a more quantitative approach, although that would require many more participants.</p>
<p>The sample size is admittedly small, involving seven elite male players competing at the ESP Premiership <em>CSGO</em> Spring finals. The players had between two and six years' experience in competitive esports. Lead researcher Matt Smith attended an esports competition to better understand both the gameplay and the competitive environment, and he used that knowledge to develop the interview guide used in the study. Interviews were conducted by Skype within three weeks of the competition and were transcribed verbatim for later analysis.</p>
<p>Birch <em>et al</em>. concluded that esports players faced 51 different stress factors, most notably team communication problems and anxiety about competing in front of live audiences, akin to stage fright. Those are the same stressors typically experienced by professional sports athletes competing at the highest levels. Communication issues included players not listening, or not following instructions, or aggressively negative (often profane) verbal criticism from the in-game leader (IGL) during gameplay.</p>
<p>"His way of motivating players is to destroy them," one study participant said of an IGL in one of the milder examples. "He said to me, 'You are so stupid, and so dumb, and so incapable of doing anything that once you go into the real world you'll find it too difficult.'"</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports1.jpg"><img alt='Researchers found esports players faced 51 different stress factors—including worries about competing in front of live audiences.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports1.jpg 2x" alt='Researchers found esports players faced 51 different stress factors—including worries about competing in front of live audiences.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/esports1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Researchers found esports players faced 51 different stress factors—including worries about competing in front of live audiences.</a> (credit: ESL/University of Chichester)</p></div>
<p>Other internal team issues included lack of confidence in one's teammates—especially in terms of maintaining emotional control under pressure—and being overly risk averse for fear of failing and letting down the team. Some players are more focused on besting their individual scores rather than increasing the team's performance as a whole, and tensions arose when some team members didn't take practice sessions seriously.</p>
<p>External stressors included trash talk from opposing teams, social media attacks, and the anxiety associated with playing a fast-paced, high-pressure game in front of a large live audience. "Like, you have whiffed, and you have no idea if the camera's on you, but in your head, they've just watched and it just makes you feel so much worse," one study participant admitted. Some participants reported feeling stressed over having to do media interviews—particularly players who speak English as a second language.</p>
<p>Birch <em>et al</em>. also identified several common coping strategies employed by esports athletes. These include techniques for managing emotional distress, like taking a break between maps, mentally blocking out the cameras, and trying to get into "the zone" so that one's sole focus is on the game. Other coping strategies were more oriented to solving problems, such as boosting a flagging teammate's confidence or having a group discussion after a competition to review what worked and what went wrong. Players may also practice so-called "avoidance coping," declining media interviews if they are press-shy, for instance, or staying off social media.</p>

<p>In addition to the study's small sample size, Birch <em>et al</em>. acknowledged another shortcoming: there were no female study participants. This was largely because the competition was heavily male dominated; the only women were on the hospitality and production teams. Female gamers are likely to face additional stressors; prior studies have shown that female gamers experience more sexual harassment, for example. The authors hope future research will remedy that omission.</p>
<p>The team would also like to look more closely at extra psychological stressors affecting in-game leaders. Additional studies might also explore how personality traits—like neuroticism, narcissism, and extraversion—can affect gamers' ability to cope in high-stress competitive environments. "We may be able to infer some predictions from their personality about how they're likely to respond to certain situations," said Birch. "And we'd love to get esports athletes to do some kind of training scenario where we try to improve their performance with things like breathing and relaxation techniques."</p>
<p>"As an industry, we've known for a long time that stressors on top-level players can negatively affect their performance," said ESL's chief operating officer, Rob Black, <a href="https://www.chi.ac.uk/news/elite-esports-gamers-face-equivalent-psychological-pressure-pro-athletes-study-reveals">in a statement</a>. “This study proves this and reinforces what we have been saying for years. Further developments are needed in this area, and that will be key in ensuring the number of professional players continues to grow worldwide.”</p>
<p>DOI: <em>International Journal of Gaming and Computer-Mediated Simulations</em>, 2019. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4018/IJGCMS.2019040102">10.4018/IJGCMS.2019040102</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603089&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sweden drops Julian Assange rape investigation after nine years</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604085</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julian Assange]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604085</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Assange is in prison for skipping bail, and he faces hacking-conspiracy charge.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-julian-assange-800x537.jpg" alt="Julian Assange speaks to the media from the balcony of the Embassy Of Ecuador on May 19, 2017 in London, England."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-julian-assange.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="687" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Julian Assange speaks to the media from the balcony of the Embassy Of Ecuador on May 19, 2017 in London, England.   (credit: Getty Images | Jack Taylor)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Swedish prosecutors have dropped a nine-year-old rape investigation into Julian Assange, saying that "the evidence has weakened considerably due to the long period of time that has elapsed since the events in question."</p>
<p>"I would like to emphasize that the injured party has submitted a credible and reliable version of events," Deputy Director of Public Prosecution Eva-Marie Persson said, according to a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-50473792">BBC report today</a>. "Her statements have been coherent, extensive and detailed; however, my overall assessment is that the evidential situation has been weakened to such an extent that there is no longer any reason to continue the investigation."</p>
<p>Prosecutors said they interviewed seven witnesses before deciding to stop the investigation, according to the BBC.</p>
<p>"Memories fade for natural reasons," Persson also said, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/19/world/europe/sweden-julian-assange.html">according to The New York Times</a>.</p>
<p>The large amount of media coverage of the case over the past nine years apparently also affected the decision. "You have to consider how much the witnesses will have read and heard from the media," Persson said.</p>
<h2>Assange in prison, faces other charges</h2>
<p>Two women made sexual-assault accusations against Assange, including a rape allegation, in August 2010. He was <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-19281492">granted asylum</a> in the Ecuadorian embassy in London in 2012, allowing him to avoid extradition.</p>
<p>In April 2019, British police <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/04/british-police-arrest-julian-assange-on-behalf-of-the-us-government/">arrested Assange</a> after the Ecuadorian government invited the Metropolitan Police Service into the embassy to remove him. A British court later <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/05/julian-assange-gets-50-weeks-for-jumping-bail/">sentenced</a> Assange to 50 weeks in prison for fleeing to the Ecuadorian embassy in London while on bail in 2012.</p>
<p>Assange also faces an indictment in the US that charges him with conspiring with Chelsea Manning to crack a hashed password belonging to a Pentagon computer in 2010. If convicted, he could spend <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edva/pr/wikileaks-founder-charged-computer-hacking-conspiracy">up to five years in a US prison</a>. </p>
<p>The statute of limitations on sexual-assault allegations against Assange <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/08/clock-runs-out-on-some-sexual-assault-allegations-against-assange/">expired in 2015</a>, but the rape charge's statute of limitations doesn't expire until August 2020.</p>
<p>Sweden dropped the rape investigation once before, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/05/sweden-drops-rape-allegation-against-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange/">in 2017</a>, but didn't rule out the possibility of reopening the case. Swedish prosecutors reopened the rape investigation <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/05/swedish-authorities-re-open-rape-investigation-against-julian-assange/">in May 2019</a> and conducted interviews over the past few months before announcing today that there isn't enough evidence to pursue it further.</p>
<p>WikiLeaks, the document-publishing group that Assange founded, issued a statement after the Swedish prosecutor's announcement today.</p>
<p>"Let us now focus on the threat Mr. Assange has been warning about for years: the belligerent prosecution of the United States and the threat it poses to the First Amendment," WikiLeaks Editor-in-Chief Kristinn Hrafnsson said, according to the BBC.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604085&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft says yes to future encrypted DNS requests in Windows</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604097</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNS over HTTPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604097</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In highly hedged post, Microsoft pledges support for DoH and other schemes, eventually.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1027924112-800x463.jpg" alt="Microsoft will (eventually) support secure DNS requests over the DoH protocol, and maybe over some others at some point."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1027924112.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1317" data-width="2275">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Microsoft will (eventually) support secure DNS requests over the DoH protocol, and maybe over some others at some point. (credit:  Yuichiro Chino via Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/Networking-Blog/Windows-will-improve-user-privacy-with-DNS-over-HTTPS/ba-p/1014229">a post yesterday </a>to the Microsoft Tech Community blog, Microsoft Windows Core Networking team members Tommy Jensen, Ivan Pashov, and Gabriel Montenegro announced that Microsoft is planning to adopt support for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/">encrypted Domain Name System queries</a> in order to "close one of the last remaining plain-text domain name transmissions in common web traffic."</p>
<p>That support will first take the form of integration with DNS over HTTPS (DoH), a standard proposed by the <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8484">Internet Engineering Task Force</a> and supported by Mozilla, Google, and Cloudflare, among others. "As a platform, Windows Core Networking seeks to enable users to use whatever protocols they need, so we’re open to having other options such as DNS over TLS (DoT) in the future," wrote Jensen, Pashov, and Montenegro. "For now, we're prioritizing DoH support as the most likely to provide immediate value to everyone. For example, DoH allows us to reuse our existing HTTPS infrastructure."</p>
<p>But Microsoft is being careful about how it deploys this compatibility given the current political fight over DoH being waged by Internet service providers concerned that they'll lose a lucrative source of customer behavior data.</p>
<p>ISPs give a number of reasons for their opposition to DoH. Since it prevents them from viewing plain-text DNS requests, it prevents filtering and blocking of some content—including, in the United Kingdom, the enforcement of content-filtering requirements placed on them by UK law. Because of its adoption of DoH as part of the Firefox Web browser, the UK's Internet Services Providers Association named Mozilla an "Internet Villain."</p>
<p>In the US, ISP lobbyists <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/isps-lied-to-congress-to-spread-confusion-about-encrypted-dns-mozilla-says/">have pressed Congress to prevent Google from deploying DoH</a> on Chrome on antitrust grounds. Part of that lobbying is based on claims that Google would, as a letter from Comcast to members of Congress put it, "centraliz[e] a majority of worldwide DNS data with Google" and "give one provider control of Internet traffic routing and vast amounts of new data about consumers and competitors."</p>
<h2>Administrator’s choice</h2>
<p>According to the authors of the Microsoft post, the Windows implementation of DoH support will not change the status quo for corporate users or many ISP customers. "We will not be making any changes to which DNS server Windows was configured to use by the user or network," Jensen et al wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>…[W]e will look for opportunities to encrypt Windows DNS traffic without changing the configured DNS resolvers set by users and system administrators.</p>
<p>Today, users and admins decide what DNS server to use by picking the network they join or specifying the server directly; this milestone won’t change anything about that. Many people use ISP or public DNS content filtering to do things like block offensive websites. Silently changing the DNS servers trusted to do Windows resolutions could inadvertently bypass these controls and frustrate our users. We believe device administrators have the right to control where their DNS traffic goes.</p></blockquote>
<p>However, Microsoft's implementation will also not "get in the way" of applications that use DoH or other encrypted DNS requests themselves. And it will have to provide for fallbacks when DoH requests fail. "DoH use will be enforced so that a server confirmed by Windows to support DoH will not be consulted via classic DNS," the Core Networking team members wrote. "If this preference for privacy over functionality causes any disruption in common Web scenarios, we’ll find out early."</p>
<p>All of this is for the future, however. Microsoft is announcing its intent now before making early versions of the capability available to Windows Insiders, because, as the three wrote, "With encrypted DNS gaining more attention, we felt it was important to make our intentions clear as early as possible. We don’t want our customers wondering if their trusted platform will adopt modern privacy standards or not."</p>
<p>It also seems that Microsoft is staking out a position friendly to ISPs—and to enterprises as well, where what might be hiding in encrypted DNS traffic from individual computers might be a security concern.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604097&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sony controller patent points to potential PS5 permutations</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604013</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 16:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[controller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playstation 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ps5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604013</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Images show missing light bar, potential microphone opening.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ps5controlfixed1-980x462.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Patent images showing a potential PlayStation 5 controller design. Perspective view.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.j-platpat.inpit.go.jp/d0200">Sony / Japanese patent office</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>New images from a Japanese Sony patent, first filed in March and <a href="https://www.j-platpat.inpit.go.jp/d0200">recently published by the Japanese patent office</a>, seem to show a new version of Sony's DualShock controller. The patent images display some potential changes to the hardware for next year's planned release of the PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>Sony system architect Mark Cerny previously discussed the PlayStation 5's new controller <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/sony-confirms-the-playstation-5-is-coming-in-2020-reveals-new-hardware-details/">in an interview with Wired last month</a>. That interview mentioned that the new system's controller would sport a USB-C connector for charging and a potential wired data connection. And while the newly published patent images resemble the PS4's existing DualShock 4 in many ways, the port at the top appears to be USB-C rather than the USB-B micro connector on the DualShock 4.</p>
<p>There are a few other changes in the patent images that do not reflect potential controller changes Sony has publicly discussed. Chief among them is the apparent omission of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/02/sony-unveils-new-dualshock-3d-camera-for-playstation-4/">the DualShock 4's lightbar</a>. That lightbar's ability to glow in different colors was often used as a gimmick by game developers to indicate health or other in-game status effects, but it was also positioned in a way that was hard for players to use it or see it effectively. More importantly, many PlayStation VR games used that lightbar in conjunction with the PlayStation Eye camera <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/07/standard-dualshock-controller-will-work-with-all-playstation-vr-games/">to track the controller's position in space</a>, a function that would not be possible in the same form on the patented controller.</p>
<p>The patent images also show a small strip running along the bottom center of the controller, below the apparent location of the PlayStation button, including small holes in the front and rear of the controller. Wired's October story made specific mention of "a little hole" on the PS5 controller prototype being tested and raised the possibility that the hole could be an opening for a built-in microphone that might integrate with <a href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2019183343&amp;tab=PCTBIBLIO">a recently patented "voice help system using artificial intelligence."</a></p>
<p><a href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2019183343&amp;tab=PCTBIBLIO">The recently launched Stadia controller</a> has a similar built-in microphone for integration with the Google Assistant.</p>
<p>Cerny would only tell Wired "we'll talk more about it another time" regarding the microphone, with a Sony spokesperson adding, "We file patents on a regular basis, and like many companies, some of those patents end up in our products, and some don’t."</p>
<p>Sony has previously discussed other new features in the PS5 controller, including "adaptive triggers" that provide variable resistance based on in-game situations and more fine-grained haptic feedback that can provide distinct "rumble" profiles when walking across different in-game surfaces, for instance. That last feature was reportedly being considered for inclusion in the PS4 Pro controller but was delayed to avoid creating a "split experience" for PS4 users.</p>
<p>Sony first discussed the successor to the PS4 <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/sonys-ps4-successor-sports-3d-audio-tech-faster-ssd-storage/">back in April</a>. That announcement stressed plans for high-speed SSD storage that will allow for faster loading times, a GPU capable of hardware-accelerated ray-tracing, and a "custom unit for 3D audio."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604013&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Nintendo designer reviews your Super Mario Maker 2 levels</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603625</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 16:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mario maker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Video: "You don't need to make a course difficult to make it fun!"]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6YFhORwXdA?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Video shot and edited by Justin Wolfson. <a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mario_script.txt">Click here for transcript</a>. </p></div>
<p>There are over 7 million courses available in <em>Super Mario Maker 2</em>. And at least seven of them are pretty fun.</p>
<p>Seriously, though, making a good Mario level is one of those tasks that's harder than it looks. So what differentiates a satisfying level from a frustrating one?</p>
<p>To find out, we reached out to both the <em>Mario Maker</em> and Nintendo Switch subreddits and asked readers to submit their favorite homemade levels for review. After sifting through pages and pages of submissions, we picked out a handful of interesting examples for a fuller evaluation by Corey Olcsvary of <a href="https://nintendo.fandom.com/wiki/Nintendo_Treehouse">Nintendo's storied Treehouse product development division</a>.</p>
<p>In the above video, Olcsvary plays through the levels and gives his real-time assessments of what they did well or badly. It's a good sign, for example, when he says things like "when I've been failing I feel like it's my fault." A strong theme can make a level stand out—as with one example here that looks like the inside of a computer. Another course offers players a "sneak preview of... impending doom" via a quick trip through a clear pipe, a touch Olcsvary appreciated. Then there's the largely enemy-free, theme-park-inspired level that proves "you don't need to make a course difficult to make it fun."</p>
<p>Olcsvary also took us behind the scenes a bit, showing how the designers at Nintendo Treehouse used playtesting and feedback to refine a level that ended up <a href="//www.youtube.com/watch?v=PwQh6oYH7mk">used in this year's Nintendo's World Championships</a>. That led to what might be his most important piece of advice: "Get someone to playtest [your level]. You might change it up based on their feedback."</p>
<p>Here are the course IDs for the levels shown in this video, if you want to try them out on your own copy of <em>Super Mario Maker 2</em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Overgrown Grotto, by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/newkyd">/u/newkyd</a>: 4RS-WWV-3MF</li>
<li>Explosive Temper, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/Vann_Accessible">/u/Vann_Accessible</a>: 9L9-1QD-YGG</li>
<li>Antivirus: MAR10, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/IHaeTypos">/u/IHaeTypos</a>: M3Y-S8G-SGG</li>
<li>Skipsqueak's Switching Spire, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/ElectroX44">/u/ElectroX44</a>: 653-35J-DKF</li>
<li>The Mushroom Kingdom Theme Park, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/CDV_Solrac">/u/CDV_Solrac</a>: HP3-V0C-Q4G</li>
<li>Mount Kiliman-Dry-Bones, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/DonkeyMintInc">/u/DonkeyMintInc</a>: DDK-HS3-2YF</li>
<li>Plateau Platforms, by <a href="https://reddit.com/user/ThirdStrongestBunny">/u/ThirdStrongestBunny</a>: 2GC-LG0-5MG</li>
<li>Invitational 2019: Round 1, by Nintendo: 641-9CJ-J9G</li>
</ul>
<p>Big thanks to the members of <a href="https://reddit.com/r/MarioMaker/">/r/MarioMaker</a> and <a href="https://reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/">/r/NintendoSwitch</a> for letting us showcase some of their work!</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603625&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>