<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 13:58:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.11</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>No, Apple isn’t opening a new manufacturing plant in Texas</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605137</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 05:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tariffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605137</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“I opened a major Apple manufacturing plant in Texas,” Trump wrote Wednesday.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183652419-800x534.jpg" alt="Donald Trump speaks at Apple's Mac Pro manufacturing facility in Austin, Texas."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1183652419.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3416" data-width="5120">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Donald Trump speaks at Apple's Mac Pro manufacturing facility in Austin, Texas. (credit: MANDEL NGAN / Getty)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>President Donald Trump toured Apple's Mac Pro manufacturing facility in Austin, Texas, with CEO Tim Cook on Wednesday.</p>
<p>"We're seeing the beginning of a very powerful and important plant," Trump said during the visit. "I want to see Apple building plants in the United States. That's what's happening."</p>
<p>Trump echoed that theme in a <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1197293250115014656">tweet</a> after the tour. "Today I opened a major Apple manufacturing plant in Texas that will bring high paying jobs back to America," he wrote.</p>
<p>Trump neglected to mention a couple of key facts about the facility. First, it's technically owned by Apple contractor Flex, not Apple itself. More important, it's not new. Apple has been building the Mac Pro at the same location since 2013.</p>
<p>Apple <em>is</em> opening a new facility in Austin—a 3 million-square-foot office complex where <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2018/12/apple-to-build-new-campus-in-austin-and-add-jobs-across-the-us/">Apple says</a> its employees will perform a variety of functions, including "engineering, R&amp;D, operations, finance, sales and customer support." In remarks at the Mac Pro plant Wednesday, Cook touted it as a $1 billion investment that will create Apple's second-biggest site after Apple's home base in Cupertino.</p>
<p>But that new facility isn't a manufacturing plant. It will create some high-paying jobs, but they'll mostly be white-collar jobs in areas like engineering, finance, and sales.</p>
<h2>Tariff relief helped Apple stay in the US</h2>
<p>Apple's decision to keep Mac Pro manufacturing in the United States follows contentious negotiations with the Trump administration. Back in June, a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/06/apple-moves-mac-pro-production-from-texas-to-china/">Wall Street Journal story</a> suggested that Apple was preparing to move Mac Pro manufacturing to China.</p>
<p>The Journal story included remarks from an Apple spokesman that didn't dispute plans to move to China. Instead, the spokesman emphasized that "final assembly is only one part of the manufacturing process."</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, Apple was seeking tariff concessions that would make it more affordable to assemble the Mac Pro in the United States. Several key components of the Mac Pro were made in China, and Apple would incur tariffs if it shipped those parts to the US for assembly.</p>
<p>Donald Trump <a href="https://twitter.com/realdonaldtrump/status/1154774656861257732">took a hard line</a> on the issue in a July tweet. "Apple will not be given Tariff waiver, or relief, for Mac Pro parts that are made in China," he wrote. "Make them in the USA, no Tariffs!"</p>
<p>But then in September, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/apple-says-itll-make-the-new-mac-pro-in-texas/">Apple announced</a> that it would continue making the Mac Pro in Austin after all—and the company credited the Trump administration for the shift.</p>
<p>"The US manufacturing of Mac Pro is made possible following a federal product exclusion Apple is receiving for certain necessary components," Apple wrote in its September announcement. Despite Trump's threats, his administration <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-19/apple-s-chinese-tariff-requests-advance-despite-trump-opposition">granted 10 out of 15 Apple requests</a> for relief from Trump's 25% tariff on Chinese imports.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605137&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report: Sacklers using fake doctors, false marketing to sell OxyContin in China</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605115</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 02:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opioids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oxycontin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prudue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacklers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As Purdue files for bankruptcy, business in China is ramping up.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-598733690-800x463.jpg" alt="Consumer-sized bottles of prescription drugs sit on a shelf."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-598733690.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2575" data-width="4448">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Bottles of Purdue Pharma L.P. OxyContin medication sit on a pharmacy shelf in Provo, Utah, on Wednesday, Aug. 31, 2016. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/license/598733690">Getty | Bloomberg</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The mega-rich family behind the OxyContin-maker Purdue Pharma is back to selling its highly addictive pain-killer with underhanded tactics and deceptive advertising—this time in China, via its international company, Mundipharma. That’s all according to a searing <a href="https://apnews.com/3ff1dfa05dac46ebb2615f729d947c0f">new investigation by the Associated Press</a>.</p>
<p>The Sackler family, which owns both Purdue and Mundipharma, is embroiled in litigation in the United States over its alleged role in sparking the country’s epidemic of opioid abuse and overdoses. Thousands of plaintiffs—many state and local governments—claim that Purdue and the Sacklers misled patients, doctors, and regulators on the addictiveness of their drugs, aggressively marketed them, and wooed doctors into over-prescribing them.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/09/purdue-files-for-bankruptcy-as-states-claim-sacklers-are-hiding-money/">Purdue has since declared bankruptcy</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2018/02/purdue-will-stop-forcefully-pushing-oxycontin-focus-on-constipation-instead/">stopped promoting OxyContin in the US</a>, the Sacklers seem to be employing the same practices in China.</p>
<p>Based on documents and interviews with multiple Mundipharma representatives in China, the AP investigation found that reps were at times posing as doctors, providing debunked information that its long-acting opioids are safe and less addictive, and even illegally copying private medical records of patients to inform sales tactics.</p>
<p>When an AP reporter informed one of the Mundipharma reps that some of the marketing information was incorrect, she replied: “I’m shocked... Why after more than 10 years would they still do the same thing and go against the laws and regulations of society?”</p>
<p>In a response to the AP, Mundipharma said it promotes ethical behavior and legal compliance. It added: “We have detailed policies covering interactions with healthcare professionals, grants and donations, and sponsorships and incentives.”</p>
<p>The AP reported that China’s National Health Commission, National Medical Products Administration, State Administration for Market Regulation, and National Development and Reform Commission declined to comment. The Sackler family representatives did not respond to a request for comments.</p>
<p>Mundipharma, meanwhile, is still hiring in China.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1605115&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubiquiti’s new “Amplifi Alien” is a mesh-capable Wi-Fi 6 router</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604879</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 22:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Salter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604879</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Amplifi Alien’s specs look pretty good, but $380 is a lot to ask for a router.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FB-1200x628static-800x419.png" alt="We were also provided an animated version of this image, in which the Alien router bobs up and down gently while levitating. We elected not to use that one."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FB-1200x628static.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="628" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> We were also provided an animated version of this image, in which the Alien router bobs up and down gently while levitating. We elected not to use that one. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://amplifi.com/">Amplifi</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Ubiquiti's consumer brand Amplifi has launched a new Wi-Fi 6 product line called "AmpliFi Alien." The original Amplifi products were typically sold as three-piece Wi-Fi mesh kits, so we got a little excited when we saw a price tag of $380 for <a href="https://amplifi.com/alien">Alien</a>.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, that price is for a single router, not a kit—which means that Amplifi Alien, like <a href="https://amzn.to/2QAETX2">Orbi AX6000</a>, is still in stratospheric "you probably don't want this yet" territory where price is concerned. We have a sneaking suspicion both these price points are a bit of a gouge, since TP-Link's Broadcom <a href="https://www.broadcom.com/products/wireless/wireless-lan-infrastructure/bcm6750">BCM6750</a>-based <a href="https://amzn.to/2XDbkpd">AX1500</a> Wi-Fi 6 router is already available for under $100.</p>
<p>Like Amplifi's earlier products, Alien features a small touchscreen on the router which can display the time, speed-test results, and offer some simple direct network control. Its power and WAN ports are recessed inside the base of the unit with a cable-management tunnel, but the four LAN ports are arranged along the back side of the barrel, opposite the touchscreen.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/AFi-ALN-R_Front_Top_Angle-980x980.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          In this front/top shot of Alien, we can see the 274x1268 color touchscreen—and, of course, the glowing green ring at the bottom, which can be disabled if you don't like the look.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://amplifi.com/">Amplifi</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Under the hood, Alien offers 5GHz 8x8 and 2.4GHz 4x4 radios, and—curiously—a Wi-Fi 5-only 5GHz 4x4 radio. Given the marketing copy, we expect that Alien will use the Wi-Fi 6 radio for backhaul in a multiple-router mesh setup. We think it's an odd choice to include a Wi-Fi 5-only radio instead of sticking with Wi-Fi 6 on all three bands, though.</p>
<p>Amplifi describes these radios as delivering 7685Mbps total capacity and Alien as covering "twice the square footage" of Amplifi's previous mesh Wi-Fi efforts, complete with a bar chart demonstrating the difference between 2 and 1. However, as we have exhaustively covered in the past, Wi-Fi marketing numbers are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/03/802-eleventy-what-a-deep-dive-into-why-wi-fi-kind-of-sucks/">useless</a>. We won't really have any idea of how good Alien is until we've gotten a unit or two to test.</p>
<p>Alien hasn't shown up on Amazon yet, but it's available directly at the Amplifi <a href="https://amplifi.com/alien">website</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604879&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ars talks fighting games with Guilty Gear creator Daisuke Ishiwatari</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604559</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 22:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurich Lawson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604559</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Daisuke talks netcode, game development, and the future of the franchise]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/daisuke-arcrevo-800x450.jpg" alt="Daisuke Ishiwatari takes the stage at ArcRevo 2019 in Irvine, CA"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/daisuke-arcrevo.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="563" data-width="1000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Daisuke Ishiwatari takes the stage at ArcRevo 2019 in Irvine, CA (credit: Arc System Works / Aurich Lawson)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A little over 20 years ago, when Daisuke Ishiwatari created <em>Guilty Gear</em>, popular fighting games like <em>Street Fighter</em> or <em>King of Fighters</em> tended to have a similar premise: gather the strongest warriors in the world and pit them against each other in a test of skill. Daisuke wanted a fighting game that was less grounded in the real world and reflected the wilder possibilities of manga and anime. (<em>Guilty Gear</em> was less grounded in a literal sense, too: characters could practically fly about the screen with mid-air moves, later leading to people referring to this style of anime-based fighters as "air dashers.") His vision was a war-torn future, full of magic, man-made bioweapons that turned on their creators (the eponymous Gears), and a diverse cast of heavy-metal-inspired characters players could choose from.</p>
<p><em>Guilty Gear</em> games are both very difficult to master and also very rewarding for those who put in the hours of study. If fighting games are music, <em>Guilty Gear</em> is jazz, free form and technical, allowing players to improvise and develop their own styles and personalities. It's beautiful in motion but difficult for outsiders to follow, and the hardcore reputation has led to many feeling intimidated about learning or following the games.</p>
<p>In summer 2019, a new <em>Guilty Gear</em> game was announced, and Daisuke began hinting that this time around, the game would be simpler and more accessible. He wanted more players to pick up the game, more people to be able to follow along with tournaments and play. That perhaps comes as welcome news for those curious about the game but put off by the effort required to learn. The long-time player base, however, expressed consternation. Was the game they know and love going to be dumbed down? Was the freedom of expression they adore going to be removed?</p>
<p>Last weekend's <a href="https://www.arcsystemworks.com/awt2019/en/">ArcRevo World Tour</a> in Irvine, California, was the final stop of a world tour for <em>Guilty Gear</em> and other Arc System Works games. There, the public got a first hands-on with a beta the new game, titled <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>. I played a few sets but not enough to give detailed impressions (look for that in a later article when I get more time with it). I did get to sit down with Daisuke and talk about where he sees the series going, how to balance making the game accessible for new players while still keeping the hardcore happy, and what he thought about the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/explaining-how-fighting-games-use-delay-based-and-rollback-netcode/">state of fighting-game netcode</a>.</p>
<p>You can watch the announcement trailer below, featuring the first six characters revealed for the game, and get a sense for how the game looks in motion (in a word, gorgeous) before reading Daisuke's thoughts.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DQSC4w_zMWQ?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p><em>(This interview was conducted through a Japanese translato and has been lightly edited for clarity).</em></p>
<p><strong><em>You've been working on </em>Guilty Gear<em> for over 20 years. As the original creator, can you talk about what the game means to you now? What keeps it fresh and interesting to you as a creator?</em></strong></p>
<p>For me—and this is gonna be kind of fighting games in general, and I think <em>Guilty Gear</em> is definitely part of that—in the PlayStation One era it was really kind of an extension of action games. And in fact, internally, we would call games like fighting games, what we know of them as now, more of like a "battle tool." It's like a tool, a programming tool, specifically for the battle portion of something. But nowadays, I really feel fighting games have turned into a tool to connect people and to make friends. So like here, the reason I am able to come to the US right now, we have people from around the world gathered here trying to make friends and building a community. I think it's a tool to connect people, especially with the Internet and networks evolving the way they have. So that's kind of what I think keeps it fresh for me.</p>
<p><strong><div class="image shortcode-img right full transbkg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sol-idle.gif"></div><em>As the arcades becoming less relevant in Japan and the home audience becomes the primary focus for fighting games, does that affect how you think about developing </em>Guilty Gear<em>?</em></strong></p>
<p>I wouldn't necessarily say what I'm doing is related to the arcade's performance. Really what it was for me was when I went to a lot of overseas events because of <em>Guilty Gear's</em> rising popularity. I saw a lot of fans who were, of course, not Japanese. And then these fans would then come to Japanese events and meet other people. And the way they were making friends to me was really kind of the purpose and the big motivator of how I felt this was a tool to connect people, not necessarily what was happening with the arcade.</p>
<p><strong><em>When designing a new </em>Guilty Gear<em>, how do you think about the balance of bringing back old characters versus making new ones?</em></strong></p>
<p>Especially for the existing characters, when we consider the balance, like with Sol or Ky, I think people have a way they imagine they're supposed to be played, a way that they feel that they're designed to be played. And when we make a completely new <em>Guilty Gear</em> like this one, I think we need to both shift and kind of reset that mindset. So it kind of opens up the possibility of, well, maybe Sol could be played like this, or maybe he's more of a character that would do those type of things. With a new game, it's a reexamination of all the existing characters and then adding other ways to play the game in addition. So that's how we maintain overall balance.</p>
<p><strong><em>Was it tempting to throw the old characters out, like Capcom did with </em><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/street-fighter/">Street Fighter</a> III<em>, when it was Ken and Ryu returning and everyone else was new?</em></strong></p>
<p>Incidentally, <em>Street Fighter III</em> is one of my favorite fighting games. And I wouldn't necessarily say we're going to that extent. Kind of the approach for this is—let's say you take Ryu, the protagonist of the story, something we imagine a lot of the players are going to pick. And he was kind of really based around his shoryuken [Ryu's dragon-punch uppercut]. So the idea is, well, what if we take that away from his toolkit? And I'm sure most of the conversation would be "No, it's impossible, etc." But at least posing those questions and seeing what they might lead to is kind of the process we're going through.</p>
<p><strong>Guilty Gear<em> players are very passionate about the game, and some have been playing for 20 years. What do you think keeps them playing it?</em></strong></p>
<p>That might frankly go a little bit beyond my understanding of human psychology [laughs]. What we are creating is a very honed and a very fine-tuned game, stuff for the true mania of the world. I think the people who are able to follow that development and evolution are the ones who are naturally attracted to it.</p>

<p><em><strong>If I was a long-time player who was worried that the game is changing too much, what would you say to me?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think in a lot of interviews and when we speak with the public, the words "simple" or "simplified" or "accessibility" have been tossed around a lot. That's not necessarily the intent of the development team. I think that's just, in the limited language and vocabulary that exists, the only way that we were able to describe what's actually going on. That's certainly not the dev team's intent or my intent. I think it's very important to kind of understand the difference which feel we like we really do, in terms of what makes our games different from other company's games. So the high-level concept is to make it look easy, make it easier to spectate. But by no means does that mean that we're shaving away level of depth. That's not our solution to make it easier to watch. That's a big topic of discussion for the development team.</p>
<p><strong><em>To follow that up, if I'm a new player, not a </em>Guilty Gear<em> player, what's your pitch to me? Why should I play your game?</em></strong></p>
<p>Because we're dealing with a video game, I believe that it's impossible to convince someone or pitch someone strictly verbally to bring them onto the side of playing <em>Guilty Gear</em>. I don't think there's any amount of explanation or pitches that's going to work. My suggestion would be, as they walk past, they see the game play. And they'll want to play it. I think that the old style of Arc System Works games and how we made them would fail in that department. Especially because it's overly complex, the HUD is overwhelming, you can't tell what is happening on the screen. A large part of our current development philosophy is simplifying it for the spectator. Making it look really fun, and that's the thing I think that's going to attract players.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='&lt;em&gt;Guilty Gear Strive&lt;/em&gt;&#039;s name is a bit of a visual pun; being the fourth game in the series, the IV in the logo is highlighted.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/guilty-gear-strive-logo.jpg" alt='&lt;em&gt;Guilty Gear Strive&lt;/em&gt;&#039;s name is a bit of a visual pun; being the fourth game in the series, the IV in the logo is highlighted.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>'s name is a bit of a visual pun; being the fourth game in the series, the IV in the logo is highlighted. </p></div>
<p><strong><em>Not just </em>Guilty Gear—<em>you've been thinking about fighting games for 20 years. ArcSys is also making games like </em>GranBlue Fantasy Versus<em> and </em>Dragon Ball Fighterz<em>. How do you get more people to not be scared of trying fighting games?</em></strong></p>
<p>I think there are a lot of people who just by looking at a game, with it being a fighting game, will say, "Nah, I don't do fighting games." You really can't explain it to someone and expect them to want to play something. It's kind of related to the previous question as well. My job is, I feel, is to show people that it's accessible. It's like, "Oh, well, I think I could do what that guy just did on the screen." So while they're spectating, give them the perception that "Oh, this is more possible than I thought it was."</p>
<p><strong><em>You said in a <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/daisuke-ishiwatari-creator-of-guilty-gear-opens-up-about-arc-s-legacy-his-crazy-inspirations-and-the-switch-487855.phtml">2018 interview with Destructoid</a> that "</em>Dragon Ball Fighterz<em> was developed based on the lessons learned through previous </em>Guilty Gear<em> and </em>BlazBlue<em> titles." Were there lessons from those games that informed the new </em>Guilty Gear<em>?</em></strong></p>
<p>I would probably say "no," at least with respect to the gameplay aspects. Each director and person overseeing their project has their own policy, if you will, on how they want to sculpt the game and shape the experience. So in terms of that infusing itself back into <em>Guilty Gear</em>, I would say there isn't much. If anything, it's more the experience of the game itself, like lobbies for example, or match-making. We'll share that type of information, the stuff that isn't related to once you enter the game, the overall experience. And that is something that they'll say, "hey, you know I tried this kind of style and it worked" or "this wasn't very effective." And that kind of information we share.</p>

<p><em><strong>The big hot topic in the fighting-game community now is rollback netcode. I interviewed French Bread battle director Kamone Serizawa earlier this year at Evo, and he said that adding rollback netcode to his company's game would require a "super programmer." What is the ArcSys response to the demand for rollback netcode?</strong></em></p>
<p>Where we are right now at ArcSys, in terms of rollback netcode, is we haven't really arrived at the conclusion that we'll need a super programmer as much, as the engineering team is kind of divided, actually. There are some that say this would be really good and others that say, you know, implementing this wouldn't really work with the <em>Guilty Gear</em> system. And it makes sense for a game like <em>Street Fighter</em>, but how <em>Guilty Gear</em> is designed—this wouldn't really fit the bill. So we're actually right in the middle of investigating on the engineering team how that might look.</p>
<p>[The current game, <em>Guilty Gear Xrd</em>, used delay-based netcode, which creates generally inferior results to rollback netcode. For more on the differences, and how rollback works, you can <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/explaining-how-fighting-games-use-delay-based-and-rollback-netcode/">check out our deep dive</a>. Here's a video clip from that article showing how the frame delay can fluctuate.]</p>
<figure class="video ars-wp-video">
    <div class="wrapper" style="padding-bottom: 56.333333333333%;">
        <div style="width: 600px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-1604559-1" width="600" height="338" autoplay="1" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UnripeCheapIbisbill.mp4?_=1" /><em>Guilty Gear Xrd</em> changes the input delay on the fly to hopefully avoid needing to pause the game and wait for inputs. Sometimes the fluctuations are small, and sometimes they can get out of control.<a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UnripeCheapIbisbill.mp4">https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UnripeCheapIbisbill.mp4</a></video></div>    </div>
        <figcaption class="caption">
        <div class="caption-text"><em>Guilty Gear Xrd</em> changes the input delay on the fly to hopefully avoid needing to pause the game and wait for inputs. Sometimes the fluctuations are small, and sometimes they can get out of control. </div>
    </figcaption>
    </figure>
<p><strong><em>Another big conversation in the fighting game community right now, partially because of the new </em>Guilty Gear<em>, is the topic of chip kill [dying when you have no health left and are hit by a special move even when you are blocking] and how chip kill has been taken out of this build of </em>Guilty Gear<em>, even though there are defensive tools to mitigate it, and it feels too simple. You are a </em>Street Fighter: Third Strike<em> fan, and the big famous moment in that game, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JzS96auqau0">Evo Moment 37</a>—the Daigo parry versus Justin Wong—only occurred because of the threat of chip kill. What's the thinking behind removing it?</em></strong></p>
<p>Again, nothing you see in this game is completely locked in. So to your point, it's still in a very experimental stage, and really, we're kind of testing a lot of different angles. If you ask me personally, I'm the guy who definitely errs on the side of hardcore. So I love these complex mechanics and systems, and you know, with everything kind of going into a lot of network-based fighting and communities, we accept the input queue, like pre-inputs [referring to modern fighting games having a larger input buffer, making button timing less strict] which you didn't need in the arcades. And that's something that I personally kind of like. So I think there's definitely two schools of thought with regard to this. But you know, we're always trying to balance the hardcore experience versus the easy-to-spectate side of things. We're experimenting—we're taking surveys and seeing where the consensus is going to be. It's just one experiment for now.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='The beta build of &lt;em&gt;Guilty Gear Strive&lt;/em&gt;&#039;s UI is not &quot;close to being final whatsoever,&quot; and it shows.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/guilty-gear-strive-ui.jpg" alt='The beta build of &lt;em&gt;Guilty Gear Strive&lt;/em&gt;&#039;s UI is not &quot;close to being final whatsoever,&quot; and it shows.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">The beta build of <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>'s UI is not "close to being final whatsoever," and it shows. </p></div>
<p><em><strong>How final is the user interface right now? Is it very, very early? Is it too early to talk about? Are there things that are being tried that might stay?</strong></em></p>
<p>With respect to the thought process behind the interface, what I had told our UI design team was that I want something that, again, goes back to the very high-level philosophy and concept of being easy to spectate and watch. It's kind of become <em>Guilty Gear's</em> identity, but the very complex HUD, you know, it's very intricate and very detailed. We're trying to deviate from that a bit and see what a different approach might be. With respect to the version you see right now, I don't think that's close to being final whatsoever. But to kind of explain the thought process or the inception of that, it is to make it easier to watch for the viewer.</p>
<p><em><strong>The one question I will ask, then, and then we can leave the UI topic since it's unfinished: what is the thinking behind having the character portrait move with the life bar?</strong></em></p>
<p>With the <em>Guilty Gear</em> interface, especially with <em>Guilty Gear</em> players—I don't know where this was done, but I read an article or a survey that found that <em>Guilty Gear</em> players compared to other fighting games have a tendency to look all around the screen at any given time. They have the most eye movement of any other fighting game. We thought this was because there is a lot of vital information scattered across screen. So one thing we're trying to do—and to their credit, this is probably what makes <em>Guilty Gear</em> players <em>Guilty Gear</em> players, they're able to look around and absorb all the information and make decisions—but with that said, we're trying to reduce the number of focal points on the screen at any given time. So this is, again, another experiment to bring everything toward a more single focal point.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right full transbkg"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kykiske-xrd-stance.gif"></div><strong><em>Last question, and then I think I've probably taken enough of your time. When </em>Guilty Gear Xrd<em> first game out, it was very cutting-edge with regards to doing 3D graphics that looked like hand-drawn sprites. That was taken a little further with </em>Dragon Ball Fighterz<em>, which almost looks better than the source anime. With the new </em>Guilty Gear<em>, the engine is obviously being taken a step further. What sort of things are you exploring visually that you couldn't do before?</em></strong></p>
<p>That's a very interesting and good point that you bring up because I agree with you that <em>Dragon Ball Fighterz</em> and even <em>Granblue Versus</em> are kind of evolution of what we've done with <em>Xrd</em>. So if you take that expression and then crank it up to 11, that's what you're going to get. With that said, you know, it's already been done. So there's no point in <em>Guilty Gear</em> going back to that point, and we needed to find a new form of expression, something else that we could do. Unlike <em>Xrd</em>, where we relied heavily on anime-type expressions, the big reference point has been live-action movies. We're really trying to push the seamless experience really hard. So we won't suddenly cut to the character's face; [instead] we're trying to make all the camera movement dynamic and seamless. That I think is a huge step in our visual expression and experimentation.</p>
<p><em><strong>Thank you very much for your time!</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Guilty Gear Strive</em> is currently expected for release in late 2020.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604559&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It’s the user’s fault if a Ring camera violates your privacy, Amazon says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604635</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Cox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon ring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ring]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The company’s answers to congressional questioning only earned it more questions]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Ring_doorbell-800x415.jpg" alt="Your local police might like to interest you in this product."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Ring_doorbell.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="779" data-width="1500">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Your local police might like to interest you in this product. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00N2ZDXW2/?tag=arstech20-20">Amazon</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Amazon subsidiary Ring, which makes home surveillance equipment and cameras, has "partnerships" with more than 600 law enforcement agencies nationwide, allowing those police access to users' footage. And while Ring says it sets terms around how and when it will share that footage with police, anything the police do with it afterward is entirely out of its hands, the company says.</p>
<p>The partnerships between Ring and police, and the terms of the agreements, have not been transparent to the general public. Instead, they've come out in bits and pieces in media reports throughout the year. Sen. Ed Markey (D-Mass.) in September <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/09/senator-pushes-amazon-for-details-about-ring-partnerships-with-police/">demanded clearer answers</a> from Amazon about Ring and published the company's responses this week.</p>
<p>In the pair of replies (<a href="https://www.markey.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Response%20Letter_Ring_Senator%20Markey%209.26.19.pdf">PDF 1</a>, <a href="https://www.markey.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Response%20Letter_Ring_Senator%20Markey%2011.01.2019.pdf">PDF 2</a>), Ring repeatedly deflects responsibility for the contents of captured footage to the consumers who capture it and the police departments that acquire it.</p>
<h2>Who <em>else</em> watches the watchers?</h2>
<p>Amazon in the last week of August agreed to share publicly a list of where it has police partnerships. At that time, there were <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/08/ring-has-more-than-400-police-partnerships-company-finally-says/">405 such agreements</a>. As of November 15, however, that map now boasts <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=1eYVDPh5itXq5acDT9b0BVeQwmESBa4cB&amp;usp=sharing">630 police partnerships</a>, a greater than 50% increase.</p>
<p>Customers who buy Ring systems for their homes can connect to an app called Neighbors. Police who work in partnerships with Ring have a companion app to Neighbors that allows them to request footage from users in a given geographic area when it's pertinent to an investigation.</p>
<p>What police do after that, however, is a mystery in which Ring says it has no part.</p>
<p>"Ring does not require law enforcement to delete materials shared through a video request after a certain period of time," the company said. Law enforcement departments set their own terms for record retention in accordance with the laws of their jurisdiction and can keep it as long as they see fit.</p>
<p>Amazon and Ring also do not have any minimum security requirements for the use of user footage. Partners use their own "requirements, protocols, and security measures" for protecting any Ring data they acquire. And they can share it with whomever they like: "If videos are downloaded by law enforcement, Ring does not require police departments to agree to additional restrictions," the company said, citing potential public records law and police investigative procedures.</p>
<p>"Ring is constantly seeking ways to maximize transparency and user control, including adding additional information on how video footage may be used when a customer consents," the company added.</p>
<h2>“Volunteered” data and privacy</h2>
<p>Amazon has repeatedly said throughout the year that Ring users must volunteer to share their footage in response to a police request. In August, the company told Ars that participating law enforcement agencies must go through Ring to request footage, adding, "Customers can choose to opt out or decline any request, and law enforcement agencies have no visibility into which customers have received a request and which have opted out or declined."</p>
<p>The minimum region for requesting footage is 0.025 square miles, Ring told Sen. Markey, in order to prevent police from targeting specific individuals. The maximum region is 0.5 square miles, in order to prevent broad blanketing. The maximum time frame of data police can ask for is 12 hours, and they can only get footage less than 45 days old.</p>
<p>In some neighborhoods, housing may be dense enough to effectively mask the identity of someone in a radius of a few blocks. But in lower-density neighborhoods zoned for single-family homes, it could be trivial for police to figure out which residence in a 0.025-square-mile radius is using a camera, regardless of if it shares footage willingly, and which residents they may wish to talk to.</p>
<p>All that said, however, Ring said it believes that "state and federal procedures, regulations, and statutes serve to ensure that police departments do not open investigations or seek information for improper purposes."</p>
<p>Respecting users and non-users' privacy is also the camera owner's problem, Amazon said.</p>
<p>"Ring's Terms of Service state that users are responsible for their use of our products and services, including use in accordance with any applicable privacy laws," the company said in response to a question about cameras pointed at public space such as municipal sidewalks that aren't part of a homeowner's property. "Ring includes a door/window sticker in the box with each device that is equipped with audiovisual recording capabilities" so that homeowners can prominently notify anyone in the neighborhood that they may be recorded, Amazon added. It has no oversight or compliance program in place for owners, however.</p>
<p>"Amazon Ring’s policies are an open door for privacy and civil liberty violations," Markey said in a statement following Amazon's response. "If you're an adult walking your dog or a child playing on the sidewalk, you shouldn't have to worry that Ring's products are amassing footage of you and that law enforcement may hold that footage indefinitely or share that footage with any third parties."</p>
<h2>Especially the kids</h2>
<p>Ring's privacy policy says it does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13. But the cameras, of course, collect footage of whoever happens to be nearby. "Ring has no way to know or verify that a child has come within range of a device," Amazon wrote. "Customers own and control their video recordings."</p>
<p>And yet Ring itself seems to have no compunction about showing children under 13 in footage if it's good for their marketing. For example: 15.8 million Ring doorbells rang in the 24 hours of Halloween, the company said in <a href="https://blog.ring.com/2019/11/04/ring-video-doorbells-get-15-million-dings-this-halloween-and-capture-cute-costumes-and-fun-pranks/">a blog post</a>.</p>
<p>The company shared some harmless data about all those trick-or-treaters. (Peak time on the East Coast was around 6:30pm, while West Coast kids peaked about 20 minutes later, apparently.) But the company also released a <a href="https://twitter.com/ring/status/1190058611738841090">promotional video</a> using captured Halloween footage, including several very clear images of children both with and without their parents present.</p>
<p>Website Mashable <a href="https://mashable.com/article/ring-halloween-surveillance/">asked Ring</a> whether parents consented to their children's appearance in the advertisement video, but the company did not respond.</p>
<p>Ring's terms of service allow for it, BuzzFeed <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/daveyalba/amazon-ring-doorbell-company-using-security-footage-for-ads">pointed out</a> earlier this year:</p>
<blockquote><p>You hereby grant Ring and its licensees an unlimited, irrevocable, fully paid and royalty-free, perpetual, worldwide right to re-use, distribute, store, delete, translate, copy, modify, display, sell, create derivative works from and otherwise exploit such Shared Content for any purpose and in any media formats in any media channels without compensation to you.</p></blockquote>
<h2>All your face are belong to us</h2>
<p>Markey also pressed Ring several times about the use of facial-recognition technology. The company responded that it does not use any facial recognition yet but may do so in the future.</p>

<p>A sentence in its privacy policy to the effect that Ring may "obtain certain facial feature information about the visitors you ask your Ring product to recognize" refers to "a contemplated, but unreleased feature," the company said. "If our customers want these features in Ring security cameras," it added, "we will only release these features with thoughtful design including privacy, security, and user control; and we will clearly communicate with our customers as we offer new features."</p>
<p>What Ring users choose, however, affects not just homeowners who buy the systems but also anyone who gets close enough to their house for any reason.</p>
<p>"Connected doorbells are well on their way to becoming a mainstay of American households, and the lack of privacy and civil rights protections for innocent residents is nothing short of chilling," Markey said in his statement—a sentiment echoed by civil liberties organizations and advocates.</p>
<p>"Through consumer products like Ring, Amazon is collecting footage and all the data needed to build a nationwide surveillance network," Fight for the Future deputy director Evan Greer said in a statement.</p>
<p>"They leverage government relationships to promote their own products, gain consumer trust, and secure their position in the market. This is an unprecedented assault on our security, constitutionally protected rights, and communities," Greer added, calling on Congress to launch an investigation.</p>
<p>The American Civil Liberties Union and Electronic Frontier Foundation have also both repeatedly expressed concerns about Ring, about facial recognition, and about both of them together.</p>
<p>Staff attorney Mohammad Tajsar of the ACLU of Southern California told the <a href="https://apnews.com/651059b843294fd28ad959b33804d46f">Associated Press</a> that the potential for facial recognition in Ring products raised significant concerns. "Even if you don't sell data or provide data to law enforcement, you're creating a mechanism whereby people can express latent biases and racism and classism in a portal that encourages it," he said.</p>
<h2>We’re not through</h2>
<p>A group of senators, including Markey, found Amazon's response insufficient. Senators Ron Wyden (D-Ore.), Chris Van Hollen (D-Md.), Chris Coons (D-Del.), and Gary Peters (D-Mich.) joined Markey in a new letter (<a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/112019%20Wyden%20Markey%20Can%20Hollen%20Coons%20Peters%20Ring%20Letter%20to%20Amazon.pdf">PDF</a>) dated today asking pointed follow-up questions, particularly about Amazon's handling of consumer data.</p>
<p>"Ring's emphasis on safety and security has not always extended to the massive amount of data it amasses, retains, and shares," the senators wrote, referring to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/11/ring-patches-total-lack-of-password-security-during-setup/">a vulnerability</a> that sent WiFi network passwords in plaintext. </p>
<p>Additionally, the senators wrote, Amazon has reportedly <a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/01/10/amazon-ring-security-camera/">sent footage to contractors in Ukraine</a> and apparently is still doing so. "Please describe the process by which Americans' data is accessed by employees or contractors in Ukraine or any other country" outside the United States, the letter asks.</p>
<p>Amazon is also told to provide data on how many consumers own Ring devices; what kind of encryption Ring uses for the data; what data retention or deletion policy is used on the data; what employees, and where, have access to what content, and why; what consumer-identifying data might be included in that content; and what the company plans to do about facial recognition in the future.</p>
<p>Amazon has until January 6 to respond to the latest round of questions.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604635&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EverQuest lead producer and designer Brad McQuaid has passed away</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604819</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 20:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brad McQuaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EverQuest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MMO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obituary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pantheon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanguard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604819</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Developers and industry figures publicly shared feelings of loss and mourning.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screen-Shot-2019-11-20-at-11.49.11-AM-800x448.png" alt="Promotional image for fantasy adventure video game."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screen-Shot-2019-11-20-at-11.49.11-AM.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="659" data-width="1176">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The original promotional art for <em>EverQuest</em>. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.everquest.com/news/eq-anniversary-producers-letter-january-2019">Daybreak Games</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Brad McQuaid, the lead developer for the groundbreaking massively multiplayer online (MMO) game <em>EverQuest</em>, has died, according to an update from his development team. He was 51.</p>
<p>Details about the circumstances of his death have not been shared publicly, other than a mention that he passed away in his home. The Twitter account for <em>Pantheon</em>, McQuaid's project at the time of his death, and Visionary Realms, the company behind it, <a href="https://twitter.com/PantheonMMO/status/1196943965028802561">tweeted</a> out the following announcement:</p>
<blockquote><p>It is with deep regret we share that Brad McQuaid passed away last night. He will be deeply missed and forever remembered by gamers worldwide.</p>
<p>Thank you for bringing us together through your worlds. Rest in peace <a class="PrettyLink profile customisable h-card" href="https://twitter.com/Aradune"><span class="PrettyLink-prefix">@</span><span class="PrettyLink-value">Aradune</span></a>.</p>
<p>VR offers our deepest condolences to Brad’s family.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.mobygames.com/developer/sheet/view/developerId,13586/">McQuaid</a> worked as a game programmer and designer starting back in the late 1980s, but he is most well-known for his role as lead programmer, producer, and designer (at various times) on <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/06/everquests-long-strange-20-year-trip-still-has-no-end-in-sight/"><em>EverQuest</em></a>, the 1999 massively multiplayer online role-playing game (MMORPG) that defined the genre to this day. <em>EQ</em>, which adapted the DikuMUD formula from text games for a 3D persistent graphical virtual world, was a breakthrough moment for MMORPGs. Its success codified that model for the genre as other, different ideas of what MMORPGs might look like (such as those posited by <em>Meridian 59</em>, <em>Underlight</em>, or <em>Ultima Online</em>) largely faded into memory.</p>
<p>McQuaid was involved in designing some of the very first raids as we know them today, and his work had significant influence on later games like <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/world-of-warcraft/"><em>World of Warcraft</em></a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/final-fantasy/"><em>Final Fantasy XIV</em></a>, <em>The <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/elder-scrolls/">Elder Scrolls</a> Online</em>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/destiny/"><em>Destiny</em></a>, and many more.</p>
<p>He later went on to co-found Sigil Games, which developed and launched the hardcore MMO <em>Vanguard: Saga of Heroes</em>. The game found a niche audience seeking demanding, group-oriented content—a focus of McQuaid's work over the years—amidst a market of increasingly casual and solo-friendly MMOs. Most recently, McQuaid was working at Visionary Realms on the above-mentioned <em>Pantheon</em>, which marries that model to some newer game-design ideas. <em>Pantheon</em> is still in development.</p>
<p>Visionary Realms communications chief BenD shared these notes <a href="https://www.pantheonmmo.com/content/forums/topic/11315/with-deepest-regrets-aradune-has-passed-away/view/post_id/219996">on the <em>Pantheon</em> forums</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Brad was a visionary, a mentor, an artist, a trailblazer, a friend, a husband, a father. He touched thousands of lives with his dreams and concepts. He changed the landscape of video games forever. He will be deeply missed and forever remembered in life and in Pantheon.</p>
<p>Thank you, Brad, for bringing us together through your worlds. Rest in peace, Aradune.</p>
<p>All of us at Visionary Realms offer our deepest condolences to Brad’s family and during this most difficult time, we kindly ask that you respect the privacy of Brad’s family.</p></blockquote>
<p>McQuaid's passing resulted in an outpouring of mourning and memories from other notable online game developers such as <a href="https://twitter.com/raphkoster/status/1196952262616088576">Raph Koster</a> (<em>Ultima Online, Star Wars: Galaxies</em>), <a href="https://twitter.com/ZenOfDesign/status/1196969230157135872">Damion Schubert</a> (<em>Meridian 59</em>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tag/star-wars-the-old-republic/"><em>Star Wars: The Old Republic</em></a>), <a href="https://twitter.com/EveOnline/status/1197104476689195014">the <em>EVE Online</em> team</a>, and former Sony Online and <em>EverQuest</em> boss <a href="https://twitter.com/j_smedley/status/1196945326583607297">John Smedley.</a></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604819&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nikki Haley lost her password, so she sent confidential info over unclassified system</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604835</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classified]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operational security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opsec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US State Department]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604835</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Former US Ambassador to the UN was responding to North Korea nuke testing.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nikki-haley-800x529.jpg" alt="A serious woman listens intently to an earpiece."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/nikki-haley.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="677" data-width="1023">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Ambassador Nikki Haley listens at the United Nations. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/us-mission/35043214691">United States Mission Geneva / Eric Bridiers / Flickr</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Former US Ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley sent confidential material over a network reserved only for unclassified material because she forgot her password for classified communications, <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/nikki-haley-used-system-for-unclassified-material-to-send-confidential-information">The Daily Beast reported</a>.</p>
<p>The event happened on July 4 and July 5, 2017, after North Korea had tested an intercontinental ballistic missile capable of hitting Alaska. As she and her staff scrambled to draft a statement responding to the test, Haley reportedly used her BlackBerry 10 to trade comments over the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classified_United_States_website#OpenNet">OpenNet</a>, a State Department network for communicating sensitive, but not classified, information.</p>
<p>“Can’t find my password,” she wrote on July 5. Other messages instructed staff to make changes to the preliminary statement versions they had drafted.</p>
<p>The revelation was disclosed in emails watchdog organization American Oversight obtained under the Freedom of Information Act. The incident comes after Haley’s boss, President Donald Trump, castigated his campaign rival Hillary Clinton for sending classified material over her private email server. His chant to “lock her up” became a constant refrain for him and his supporters.</p>
<p>It’s arguable that the OpenNet is more secure than a private email address. Still, there’s a reason the State Department system isn’t suitable for transmitting classified material. Last year, <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2018/09/17/state-department-email-personal-information-792665">Politico reported</a> that the State Department’s unclassified email system suffered a breach that exposed the personal information of a small number of employees.</p>
<p>Watchdog groups have repeatedly criticized the State Department for what they say is insufficient network security. By the time the 2018 breach came to light, a bipartisan group of senators had already asked Secretary of State Mike Pompeo what the department was doing to improve things.</p>
<p>Given the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/07/microsoft-warns-10000-customers-theyre-targeted-by-nation-sponsored-hackers/">growing determination and skill of hackers</a> sponsored by the governments of North Korea, Iran, Russia, and China, unclassified systems are increasingly vulnerable to espionage. Staff members for Haley, who resigned her ambassador post in October of last year, didn’t provide a comment to Politico.</p>
<p><em>Post updated on 11/20/2019, 6:49 PM to change "sensitive" to "confidential" per original article.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604835&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New antibiotic found in bacteria inside a worm inside an insect egg</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604435</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 18:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Gitig]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antibiotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gram-negative bacteria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microbiome]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It comes from the microbiome of parasitic worms.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-925864520-800x534.jpg" alt="False color microscope image of bacteria."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-925864520.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: BSIP/Universal Images Group)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The last antibiotics generated against Gram-negative bacteria—which tend to be the more dangerous type—were developed in the 1960s. Thanks to the rise of antibiotic resistance, we need more. But rather than going through the trouble of trying to make our own, scientists have looked to other species that might need to kill the same bacteria that we do—we can just swipe theirs. </span><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/10/new-antibiotic-mined-from-human-gut-reverses-drug-resistance-in-superbugs/"><span style="font-weight: 400">Our own guts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> and </span><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2015/01/a-new-kind-of-antibiotic-that-kills-many-drug-resistant-bacteria/"><span style="font-weight: 400">soil bacteria</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> have yielded a few recent hits.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The latest organisms that researchers have looked to are bacteria in the microbiomes of roundworms that parasitize insects (technically termed enteropathogenic nematodes). They were considered promising candidates because the worms invade insect larvae and release bacteria. Those bacteria then have to fend off the ones already living in the insect larva, as well as all the other bacteria the nematodes just spewed out. Conveniently for us, those species include common pathogens in our own guts, like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">E. coli</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Usually, when microorganisms are being screened to see if they make effective antibiotics, they are grown on a plate along with the pathogenic bacteria to see if the ones being screened thwart the growth of the ones being targeted. The species taken from the nematodes’ guts did not stop the growth of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">E. coli </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">in this traditional assay. But the scientists speculated that maybe they still made antibiotics, just not at high enough levels. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">And they were right. Concentrated extracts of the nematode gut cultures <em>did</em> stop </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">E. coli</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> from growing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The active compound in the extracts was a seven-amino-acid-long peptide chain, a shorter version of a protein. The peptide chain isn't typically made when the bacteria are grown under laboratory conditions and is made only slowly and at low levels in other contexts. The discoverers named it darobactin. It is made by a number of different bacterial species, including </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Yersinia pestis</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, the Gram-negative bacteria that causes plague.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Darobactin is too big to get across the outer membrane of the Gram-negative bacteria it targets. To figure out how it worked, the researchers generated mutant </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">E. coli</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> that were resistant to it by growing the</span><span style="font-weight: 400">m </span><span style="font-weight: 400">in its presence. Generating resistance took all of a week. The resistant strains all had mutations in a protein called BamA, which encodes a chaperone protein. This chaperone's job is to shepherd proteins that belong in the bacterial outer membrane to their proper spot and, once there, help them fold into the correct three-dimensional orientations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Darobactin binds to BamA after it's stuck to one of these outer membrane proteins locking it in place and thereby preventing the formation of a functional outer membrane. BamA is one of only two essential proteins expressed on the outer surface of Gram-negative bacteria. If these nematode commensals make a molecule that targets it that we can exploit, perhaps other microorganisms do, too.</span></p>
<p><em>Nature</em>, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1791-1">10.1038/s41586-019-1791-1</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/ science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604435&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Earth gets content creation tools for geography-focused presentations</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604733</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 17:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Amadeo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Build a presentation with text, images, videos, and terabytes of Google Earth imagery.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/18-1-800x450.jpg" alt="A Google Earth presentation in action. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/18-1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1080" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A Google Earth presentation in action.  (credit: Google)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Google Earth is getting a <a href="https://blog.google/products/earth/new-google-earth-creation-tools/">new content creation feature set</a>. You'll now be able to make presentations using Google's vast 3D Earth imagery and point-of-interest information. It's sort of like a geography-focused Powerpoint.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/04/google-earth-adds-guided-video-tours-from-bbcs-planet-earth-and-others/">Back in 2017</a>, Google Earth was completely rebuilt from a desktop application to a WebGL-based browser app at <a href="https://earth.google.com/web/">earth.google.com/web</a>. Starting today, on the left side of the website, you'll see a new "Projects" button, which will let you create a presentation. Just like a Google Doc or Sheet or Slide, these Google Earth Projects get saved as files on your Google Drive.</p>
<p>And like a normal presentation, you can create slides and attach text, images, and videos. Since this is Google Earth, though, all the text and images get overlaid on top of Google's terabytes of Earth imagery. You can pick from Google Earth's 3D views or Street View, set the camera just right, and capture a view. As you click through slides in your presentation, Google Earth will smoothly fly from point to point as your slides pop up.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5KtwMRedAbc?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Just like with any other Google Drive product, you can collaborate with others in real time. The Google Earth apps for Android and iOS support viewing these presentations, too.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604733&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Did Neanderthals make eagle talon necklaces 120,000 years ago?</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 16:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neanderthals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleoarchaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleolithic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleolithic europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolic thought]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The evidence is indirect, but a recent find suggests the answer may be "yes."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Aguila_Imperial_Entrando_Al_Posadero_125891767-800x532-800x532.jpg" alt="Did Neanderthals make eagle talon necklaces 120,000 years ago?"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Aguila_Imperial_Entrando_Al_Posadero_125891767-800x532.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="532" data-width="800">Enlarge</a> (credit: José Antonio Lagier Martin)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>At Foradada Cave in northeast Spain, Neanderthal fossils lie mingled with stone tools and animal bones. Here, archaeologists recently unearthed the tip of a 39,000-year-old eagle toe with its claw missing. The phalanx (toe bone) came from the end of a Spanish imperial eagle’s big toe (the left one, to be exact), and cut marks along the length of the bone suggest that someone had cut off the large, curved talon at the end of the toe.</p>
<p>Archaeologist Antonio Rodriguez, of the Institute of Evolution in Africa, and his colleagues suggest that the missing talon ended up on a Neanderthal necklace.</p>
<h2>The case of the missing jewelry</h2>
<p>Along the top side of the toe (a proximal phalanx, if you’re an anatomy fan), 11 deep cut marks run diagonally across the bone; a shallower twelfth cut crosses the others, parallel with the bone’s length. Under the microscope, the cuts have v-shaped cross-sections, leaning to one side—the signature shape of tool-made cuts rather than predator teeth or damage from scraping against rocks or other bone. In fact, the cuts look almost exactly like the marks archaeologists left behind when they used stone tools to separate a raptor’s claw from its toe (because of course they did, for science).</p>
<p>Twenty-two other raptor toes found across southern Europe bear similar cut marks: an eagle-owl, a vulture, and 20 other eagles. But (with one exception), the talons all seem to have been taken somewhere else. Smaller birds seem not to have been given the talon-removal treatment, although their bones often show up at Neanderthal sites. Collectively, these objects offer a tantalizing hint that Neanderthals used eagle talons for <em>something</em>, and it probably wasn’t strictly practical—which makes it pretty interesting.</p>
<p>Rodriguez and his colleagues suggest that the missing talons and the cut-marked toes are evidence that Neanderthals in southern Europe were making jewelry out of eagle talons. That sounds like a pretty big leap, considering the complete lack of eagle-talon necklaces in the archaeological record. The whole case hangs on the argument that the talons were obviously being collected, but they probably weren’t being used as food or tools.</p>
<h2>If you can’t eat it, what’s it for?</h2>
<p>Bird feet aren’t terribly nutritious—some cultures have tasty recipes involving the cartilage and tendons, but it still wouldn’t make much sense to remove the talons as part of meal prep. And there’s not much evidence that they ate the rest of the eagle, either. Neanderthals, especially those living close to the Mediterranean Sea, ate birds pretty often, but large raptors do not seem to have been regular items on the menu. Modern hunter-gatherers also occasionally eat large birds of prey, but only rarely.</p>
<p>And based on the things they left behind, Neanderthals don’t seem to have used many bone tools. There’s no evidence of smaller bird talons being used as awls or needles, and Rodriguez and his colleagues say it’s unlikely the Neanderthals would use only eagle talons for those purposes, when a range of sizes would make sense. The possibility of eagle talons as tools can’t be totally ruled out, but it doesn’t look very likely, either.</p>
<p>The explanation that's left, according to Rodriguez and his colleagues, is that the use was artistic—another piece of evidence that Neanderthals were as intelligent and sophisticated as we are. They argue that Neanderthals at Foradada Cave and elsewhere across southern Europe used eagle talons the same way that others at sites like Cueva de los Aviones in Spain used seashell beads and ocher: as talismans or as visible markers of social standing, group membership, or some other aspect of a person’s identity. The talons may have been pendants, earrings, or just something people carried; without the talons themselves, there’s no way to know.</p>
<h2> A glimpse into the Neanderthal mind</h2>
<p>If the talons really were being removed to make jewelry, that brings Neanderthals in line with a lot of other groups of people around the world. Many cultures have viewed large raptors as symbols to represent power, nature, nobility, or military prowess, so it’s not that surprising that Neanderthals would, too.</p>
<p>“To know, or try to imagine, the significance for Neanderthals is out of science,” Rodriguez told Ars. “Unfortunately we don't have a Rosetta Stone to decode the meaning of Middle Paleolithic talons.” But he plans to study eagle-talon ornaments from indigenous Australian and North American cultures to compare patterns of cut marks and wear, as well as how each culture used those objects and what they meant to the people who wore them.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, what do the missing talons and the incriminating cut marks tell us about Neanderthal culture? Well, for starters, it suggests that Neanderthals weren’t a cultural monolith; for tens of thousands of years, they lived in small groups scattered across almost the whole of Eurasia, but the missing eagle talons only show up in a relatively small area of southern Europe. Isotopic studies have already shown us that Neanderthals in different areas ate distinct foods, and we know that tool types varied from place to place (and over time). The talons suggest that groups living in different areas also used different types of symbols—and therefore, perhaps, had different ideas and beliefs. (That’s not surprising, of course, but it’s interesting to see that pattern in the archaeological record.)</p>
<p>If Rodriguez and his colleagues are right, the talons may also suggest that Neanderthal culture is older than some similar aspects of human culture. The earliest eagle toes with cut marks date to sometime between 120,000 and 130,000 years ago, which makes them slightly older than the perforated seashells at Homo sapiens sites in North Africa. Of course, that doesn’t mean that humans living in parts of Africa <em>didn’t</em> have symbolism and jewelry long before Neanderthals; it just means that these are the earliest examples we’ve found.</p>
<p>Critically, the timing means that Neanderthals probably developed symbolism on their own, instead of learning it from <em>Homo sapiens</em> as some archaeologists have suggested (it’s possible and even likely that the two species swapped ideas and symbols once they met).</p>
<p>And it suggests that Neanderthal culture had some serious staying power. The Foradada Cave bones date to around 42,000 years ago—roughly 80,000 years later than the earliest examples, and around the time the last Neanderthals were losing their world to upstart newcomers, <em>Homo sapiens</em>. In fact, if the missing eagle talon from Foradada Cave did become a necklace or other ornament, it may have been among the last ones the Neanderthals ever made, a final remnant of an ancient tradition, “surviving on [as] one of the last expressions of their material culture and probably extinguishing with them forever.”</p>
<p><em>Science Advances</em>, 2019. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/ https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aax1984">10.1126/sciadv.aax1984</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604577&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researchers see spike in “out of season” IRS-impersonating phishing attacks</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 15:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Gallagher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax scam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researchers track surge in IRS phishing sites as filing extension deadline arrived.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/irs-800x382.png" alt="A fake IRS site used in a set of phishing campaigns observed by Akamai from August to October."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/irs.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="652" data-width="1365">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A fake IRS site used in a set of phishing campaigns observed by Akamai from August to October. (credit: Akamai)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Tax return scammers usually strike early in the year, when they can turn the personal information of victims into fraudulent tax refund claims. But members of Akamai's threat research team <a href="https://blogs.akamai.com/sitr/2019/11/out-of-season-irs-phishing-campaigns.html">found a recent surge in "off-season" phishing attacks</a> masquerading as notices from the Internal Revenue Service, targeting over 100,000 individuals. The attackers used at least 289 different domains hosting fake IRS websites—the majority of them legitimate sites that had been compromised. This wave of attacks came as the October 15 deadline for people who had filed for extensions approached.</p>
<p>According to a post by Akamai's Or Katz, the phishing campaigns kicked off in the second half of August, with the majority of victims targeted between August 22 and September 5. But the campaigns continued to be launched into early October. Each of the fake websites used visually identical HTML pages, with randomly generated style tags and other content, in an attempt to throw off signature detection by security software.</p>
<p>Most of the domains were active for fewer than 20 days. However, a significant number of them remained active after a month—undetected by the owners of the sites. "The lack of maintenance on legacy websites, as well as the challenges of patching and removing injected content, explains the duration over which phishing pages can remain active," Katz wrote.</p>
<p>This is consistent with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/08/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-lose-the-war-on-phishing-enlist-machine-learning/">research into phishing infrastructure done by Ars</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.akamai.com/us/en/multimedia/documents/state-of-the-internet/soti-security-phishing-baiting-the-hook-report-2019.pdf">other research by Akamai</a>. Because of their age—and the lack of attention paid to them by their owners, who often pay someone to set them up and then forget about maintaining them—older sites based on "legacy" versions of WordPress and other content management systems are a prime target for phishing operators, as they have a higher reputation score than freshly minted domains. Depending on the degree to which the site is compromised, they can even create subdomains and register their own certificates for the phishing site.</p>
<p>With these sorts of scams propagating all year, it's worth reminding friends and family that the IRS will not email you or call you about overdue taxes or any other matter—those notices will only come by paper postal mail, usually by certified mail. So just don't click.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604679&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volkswagen is putting this cool electric station wagon into production</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 14:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LA Auto Show 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MEB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volkswagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volkswagen ID Space Vizzion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is the latest concept to show off the VW's modular electric platform.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/VW-Space-Vizzion-4-980x735.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          We've seen buses and buggies, hatches, sedans, and crossovers. And now there's a VW ID station wagon concept.                      [credit:
                        Jonathan Gitlin                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  


<p>LOS ANGELES—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/01/the-best-of-the-2017-north-american-international-auto-show/">Buzz</a>. Crozz. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/08/weve-driven-vws-bright-green-smile-machine-the-electric-id-buggy/">Buggy</a>. Vizzion. And now Space Vizzion. No, I haven't overdosed on the letter Z; those are the slightly wacky names for a series of not-at-all-wacky electric ID concept cars from Volkswagen, the newest of which was just unveiled on Tuesday night in Los Angeles. The ID Space Vizzion is the latest installment in an electrification push from one of the world's largest automakers, one aiming to sell 20 million electric cars worldwide over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>Volkswagen Group had little choice but to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/09/volkswagen-group-will-electrify-all-12-brands-by-2030-needs-gigafactories/">embrace electric powertrains</a> in the aftermath of dieselgate—the alternative would be failing to meet 2021's European CO2 rules, which would result in billions of dollars in fines. Audi and Porsche, the two big premium brands within the group, got their battery EVs to market first. The first of these—<a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/12/weve-driven-audis-first-proper-electric-car-the-2019-e-tron-suv/">the Audi e-tron</a>—is mainly a stop-gap, a Q8 with batteries and two electric motors in place of the normal internal combustion engine stuff. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/09/the-porsche-taycan-every-bit-as-good-as-a-200000-porsche-should-be/">The Porsche Taycan</a> had an extra year to gestate, and is all the better for it, a mostly clean-sheet design that's wowed everyone who's driven it.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, over at VW (the brand, not the group) the engineers were working on MEB (<em>Modularer E-Antriebs-Baukasten</em>, or Modular Electrification Toolkit), which it will use to build millions of BEVs over the next decade. VW has long embraced the use of modular architectures; its current MQB (<em>Modularer Querbaukasten</em>, or Modular Transverse Toolkit) gives rise to such diverse cars as the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/04/the-volkswagen-atlas-reviewed-a-peoples-wagon-for-the-american-people/">VW Atlas</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/09/audi-sports-rs3-and-tt-rs-the-same-engine-but-very-different-cars/">Audi TT-RS</a>. And MEB should be even more flexible, as the various ID concept cars have shown.</p>
<p>Ignore the ID Space Vizzion's Z-overdose name and think of it instead as an electric Passat station wagon. It's a five-door, more practical evolution of 2018's ID Vizzion, itself VW's take on a Passat-sized electric sedan. But this one looks better because as we all know, wagons &gt; sedans. I'm also impressed with how aerodynamic it is—VW told me that the Space Vizzion's drag coefficient is just 0.24, and that's with conventional side mirrors, too.</p>
<p>Between the axles there's an 77kWh battery pack. Add that to the low-drag body, and the result is at least 300 miles on the EPA test cycle or 590km on the WLTP test, VW says. The rear wheels are driven by a 205kW (275hp), 550Nm (406lb-ft) motor, although there will be an option for all-wheel drive with a total power output of 250kW (335hp).</p>
<p>The fact that VW is talking about options on a concept car should give you the idea that this is one of those thinly disguised production car concepts rather than a "it's made entirely out of clay and half the stuff in it hasn't been invented yet" kind of concept car. In 2022 the Space Vizzion will go on sale, probably with a slightly more boring nose, almost certainly with a more boring interior, and definitely with a less Z-filled name.</p>
<p>If you don't want to wait that long for an electric VW, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/09/this-is-volkswagens-new-e30000-electric-car-the-id-3/">ID.3 hatchback</a> is on sale in Europe, and next year here in the US we get the ID.4 crossover (which will also be built in Chattanooga, Tennessee, starting in 2022).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604607&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guidemaster: The most useful gadgets to have in your bag while traveling</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ars Holiday 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidemaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tech gifts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here are some stellar gadgets that will make your future trips better.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-638533994-800x533.jpg" alt="Not all of us frequently travel with camping/hiking backpacks like these joyful stock photo travelers—luckily, we have some recommendations on tech tailored for on-the-go life. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-638533994.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="3667" data-width="5500">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Not all of us frequently travel with camping/hiking backpacks like these joyful stock photo travelers—luckily, we have some recommendations on tech tailored for on-the-go life.  (credit:  Hinterhaus Productions / Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Traveling <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/03/hold-onto-your-butts-a-tour-through-kualoa-ranch-aka-real-world-jurassic-park/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">can be a fun,</a> illuminating experience, but packing for your travels is often stressful. Everything you choose to bring with you on your excursions must have a purpose, because unnecessary items do not belong in anyone's cramped suitcase. Whether you're traveling for business or pleasure, it can be difficult to decide which pieces of tech deserve to come with you and which you only <em>think</em> would be useful.</p>
<p>It can also be hard to find gadgets that are suitable for travel—devices that work even more efficiently when you're not in your normal environment. To combat this, Ars has picked out some of the best travel tech gifts that will be solid additions to anyone's travel bag. All of the items below we've personally tested or reviewed, so we're confident saying that none of these devices will end up languishing, abandoned, at the bottom of your suitcase.</p>
<p><em>Note: Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Dell XPS 13</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15.jpg"><img alt='Dell&#039;s XPS 13 laptop.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Dell&#039;s XPS 13 laptop.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/xps132019_15.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Dell's XPS 13 laptop.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Dell has crafted and re-crafted the <a href="http://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8984087-12578053?sid=TravelGifts2019&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Flaptops%2Fnew-13%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-7390-laptop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XPS 13</a> to be one of the most travel-friendly laptops you can get. Weighing 2.7 pounds and measuring 11.6mm thick, it's impressively thin considering how much power it has built inside the chassis. The 2019 model with 9th-gen Intel processors is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/03/guidemaster-the-best-windows-ultrabooks-you-can-buy-right-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our current favorite Windows ultrabook</a>, and Dell recently updated the machine to include 10th-gen Intel processors. Regardless of the model you get, you're getting a Windows laptop that doesn't compromise performance while being slim and attractive.</p>

<p>That said, the newest XPS 13 does offer a lot of improvements over last year's model. First and foremost, the webcam has been moved to the top of the screen rather than sitting on the bottom like it has for so many years. This makes the webcam much more functional, and Dell didn't sacrifice screen space in order to make it happen. You can get the display in a 1080p panel, but there's a 4K panel option as well now. In terms of ports, you get three USB-C ports (two of which are Thunderbolt 3) in addition to a headphone jack, a microSD card slot, and a lock slot.</p>
<p>While we wish the XPS 13 had an IR camera for facial recognition, it does have a fingerprint reader embedded into the power button, so you'll get speedy biometric login from that. We also appreciate that the 4K model can last 13 hours on a single charge (according to our testing), and you could configure the XPS 13 to get up to 21 hours of battery life.</p>
<p>Dell gives you a lot of configuration options on the XPS 13, making it a good choice for anyone who wants to truly customize their laptop. The only bad part is that the base model starts with 4GB of RAM (the next step up has 8GB of RAM, and we would recommend most people have that amount of memory in their primary machine). Regardless of how you configure it, the XPS 13 is a solid laptop that will be a workhorse no matter where you find yourself working.</p>
<p>For those who want a machine that's a bit more flexible (plus a tad thinner and lighter), consider the Microsoft Surface Pro. Last year's <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-surface-pro-6-12-3-touch-screen-intel-core-i5-8gb-memory-128gb-solid-state-drive-platinum%2F6298148.p%3FskuId%3D6298148&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Surface Pro 6</a> is our current favorite Windows detachable, and you can still find powerful configurations of this device at a good price. Those who want the latest and greatest (plus a newly added USB-C port) should consider the <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-surface-pro-7-12-3-touch-screen-intel-core-i3-4gb-memory-128gb-ssd-with-black-type-cover-latest-model-platinum%2F6374985.p%3FskuId%3D6374985&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Surface Pro 7</a>.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/xps132in1-300x124.png"
                                    alt="Dell XPS 13 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Dell XPS 13                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_42427093" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="http://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8984087-12578053?sid=TravelGifts2019&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Flaptops%2Fnew-13%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-7390-laptop" target="_blank">
                                Starting at $949 from Dell                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s.jpg"><img alt='Logitech&#039;s MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Logitech&#039;s MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/logimxmasteranywhere2s.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Logitech's MX Master Anywhere 2s mouse.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Travel-friendly mice are a dime a dozen, but <a href="https://amzn.to/2NDodMM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Logitech's MX Master Anywhere 2s</a> puts some of the best features found in a stationary mouse into a travel-sized device. This mouse is noticeably smaller than other Logitech mice, and while it may take some getting used to, it's the perfect sized mouse to live in your backpack, work, or travel bag.</p>
<p>Its 4000 dpi Darkfield sensor helps it track on nearly any surface, even glass, so you can use it no matter where you find yourself working. It has a rechargeable battery that should last up to 70 days on a single charge, and it recharges using a microUSB port. It works with macOS and Windows devices, as well as iPadOS and Linux, and you can pair this mouse with up to three devices at once and switch between them with just the press of a button. Like most Logitech accessories, the MX Master Anywhere 2s connects to a PC via Bluetooth or a USB receiver.</p>
<p>In addition to customizable pointer and scroll speeds, you can also customize the five buttons on the MX Master Anywhere 2s. This is one of the features I love in Logitech's main mice, and I'm glad the company made a travel mouse that works almost exactly like the one you may use every day at your main desk. The MX Master Anywhere 2s could end up being your main mouse if you prefer smaller mice, but it's truly hard to beat as a travel mouse—especially at the good price of $54.99.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anywhere2s-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Logitech MX Master Anywhere 2s                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_79110873" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NDodMM" target="_blank">
                                $49.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux.jpg"><img alt='Anker&#039;s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux-640x398.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux-1280x796.jpg 2x" alt='Anker&#039;s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/anker-powercore-10000-pd-redux.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Anker's PowerCore 10000 PD Redux portable battery next to a Google Pixel 3a.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>There are countless power banks that can effectively keep devices charged on the go, but for an explicitly portable option, we like <a href="https://amzn.to/2NZBf7u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anker’s PowerCore 10000 PD Redux</a>. The main reason for that is size: at seven ounces and 106×52.3×25.5mm, the PowerCore is particularly small and light enough to fit into many pants pockets, let alone a handbag or suitcase, without being too obtrusive. The whole thing is sturdily put together, with rounded edges that subtly make the battery more comfortable to hold and stash on your person.</p>
<p>Besides that, it includes a USB-C Power Delivery (PD) port that charges at 18W, which is powerful enough to refill most new smartphones at maximum speeds. (It’s not quite fast enough to recharge higher-end tablets like the iPad Pro at maximum speeds, but it’ll still speed up the process to an extent.) There’s a 12W USB-A port as well, which is handy if you have multiple devices low on power. Because the battery maxes out at 18W of output, it’s best suited for smartphone charging above all else, though.</p>
<p>The PowerCore has a capacity of 10,000mAh (36Wh), which is enough to charge an iPhone 11 roughly twice. A quartet of LED lights lets you know how much of that capacity is left at any given time, and the battery itself can recharge at 18W with a USB-C PD wall charger, so it doesn’t take long to fully restore. We’ve had no hints of reliability issues after months of use, and Anker generally has a strong reputation in this market, but the device is covered by an 18-month warranty if something goes wrong. At $46, it’s not the cheapest power bank in its class, but it does come with a USB-C to USB-C cable in the box, and we think its blend of good-enough power and genuine portability is worth it.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ankerpd-300x375.jpg"
                                    alt="Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Anker PowerCore 10000 PD Redux                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_59464693" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2NZBf7u" target="_blank">
                                $45.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Garmin Dash Cam Mini</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1.jpg"><img alt='Garmin&#039;s Dash Cam Mini.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Garmin&#039;s Dash Cam Mini.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/garmindashcammini_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Garmin's Dash Cam Mini.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Protecting your car with the watchful eye of a dash cam can be useful if you're on the road a lot, and <a href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Garmin's Dash Cam Mini</a> is certainly one of the most compact dash cams you can get. Measuring 1.23×2.1×1.15 inches, it's about the size of a house key and almost as lightweight as one. Its camera records 1080p video @ 30fps of the road ahead of you, and its 140-degree field of view will capture almost everything going on in the area in front of your car.</p>
<p>It's also one of the most convenient dash cams to use. Just stick the Dash Cam Mini onto your windshield, plug it into your car's charger, and forget about it—it will start when the car starts, record continuously, and stop when the car stops. Garmin's companion mobile app makes it easy to view and access footage relatively quickly, too. While other dash cams force you to remove the microSD card and use it to view footage on a computer, you can see new clips immediately in the Garmin Drive app and download them to your smartphone. There are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/06/guidemaster-the-best-dash-cams-to-guard-your-every-drive/">plenty of dash cams</a> out there to choose from—some more affordable, some more expensive—but Garmin's Dash Cam Mini will appeal to those who want an unobtrusive device that also doesn't get in the way of them accessing their driving footage whenever necessary.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/garmindashcammini-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Garmin Dash Cam Mini product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Garmin Dash Cam Mini                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_65890100" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_65890100">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ">Amazon $129.98</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgarmin-mini-dash-cam%2F6351243.p%3FskuId%3D6351243&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $129.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/32EjdeQ"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgarmin-mini-dash-cam%2F6351243.p%3FskuId%3D6351243&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Sony WH-1000XM3</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1.jpg"><img alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Sony's WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>While more than a year old now, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony’s WH-1000XM3</a> remains our favorite wireless noise-cancelling headphone. It has the most powerful and consistent active noise cancellation (ANC) of any model we’ve tested: some sharper sounds may sneak through during quieter tracks, but that’s the case with every ANC headphone, and the XM3 is still outstanding at shutting out the low- and mid-range noises that are most disturbing on a long flight or subway ride.</p>
<p>While the XM3 is not the best-sounding $350 headphone we’ve used by any means, sound quality in consumer headphones as a whole has taken a bit of a backseat as Bluetooth has become the norm. Sony’s profile here is tailored toward bass lovers more than purists, but that’s not exactly an unpopular sound these days, and the XM3 is well-measured given the warmer sound it’s going for. Those who are willing to sacrifice a little treble and vocal clarity for more oomph in the low-end will find plenty to like. That said, Sony’s companion app lets you customize the XM3’s sound in meaningful ways, so if your loved one doesn’t like the default sound (or wants even more bass), it’s not hard to address that.</p>
<p>The XM3 is primarily made of plastic, which might be disappointing for the price, but the upshot is that it keeps the whole thing relatively light. Combined with the cushy, not-overly-tight earpads and a headband, this keeps the XM3 comfortable to wear for hours at a time. The headphone got a solid 21 hours of battery life during our testing, and it can fully recharge in about two hours through its USB-C port. It also supports a nifty “ambient sound” mode that can let you hear outside noises without stopping whatever’s playing.</p>
<p>The XM3 is not without flaws. Unlike the <a href="https://amzn.to/2O0bm7x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose Noise Cancelling Headphones 700</a>, there’s no way to manually adjust the strength of the XM3’s noise cancellation. The Bose 700 also has a more premium-feeling design, with a stainless steel headband. <a href="https://amzn.to/2qZZbhT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bose’s QuietComfort 35 II</a>, meanwhile, has physical volume and playback buttons that are generally more reliable than the XM3’s touch-based controls—though we find the XM3’s setup to work fine for what it is—an even lighter design, and a sound profile that’ll appeal more to those who don’t want as much bass. But the Bose 700 are too reliant on a finicky app for crucial functions, the QC 35 II’s sound is less customizable and impressive on the whole, and the XM3 has stronger ANC than both of them. It’s possible Sony will release a follow-up in the next few months, but either way, the XM3 should be a treat for anyone who is frequently stuck on long commutes.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/51IdLe-6kL._AC_SL1500_-300x436.jpg"
                                    alt="Sony WH-1000XM3 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Sony WH-1000XM3                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_28716967" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_28716967">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $348</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2qgiZOd">Amazon $348</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-wh-1000xm3-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-with-google-assistant-black%2F6280544.p%3FskuId%3D6280544&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $349.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-WH1000XM3-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-with-Google-Assistant%2F931234733&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2qgiZOd"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsony-wh-1000xm3-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-with-google-assistant-black%2F6280544.p%3FskuId%3D6280544&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Beats Powerbeats Pro<br />
Apple AirPods Pro</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro.jpg"><img alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beats-powerbeats-pro-and-apple-airpods-pro.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Beats Powerbeats Pro (left) and Apple AirPods Pro.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>If over-ear headphones like the WH-1000XM3 are too bulky for your loved one’s liking, consider gifting them a pair of “true wireless” earphones. Easily the trendiest item in consumer audio nowadays, these are Bluetooth earphones with absolutely no wires between them. Almost none of them are well-suited to critical listening at this point, but their small size and total lack of cables make them feel particularly freeing for someone who is frequently on the move.</p>
<p>A handful of worthwhile options have launched in the past year, but we think the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beats Powerbeats Pro</a> will make the widest swath of people happy. As you might expect from a Beats product, the Powerbeats Pro’s sound is heavy on the bass and far from neutral, but it doesn’t totally muddle up detail in the mids. Given the context, it sounds more “fun” than bloated.</p>
<p>It’s the other fundamentals that really make the Powerbeats Pro a winner, though: the earhook design balances its weight well and stays nice and secure throughout intense workouts, the physical volume and playback controls mirrored on each earbud are always convenient to access, and the semi-sealing eartips block out enough outside noise with music playing without putting too much stress on the ear canals or totally shutting off access to your surroundings. For iPhone users, they use Apple’s H1 wireless chip for a particularly stable connection and easier pairing, but even on Android they connect quickly to a remembered device and don’t lose any major features.</p>
<p>Best of all, the Powerbeats Pro are <em>by far</em> the current battery life champ among true wireless earbuds, getting more than 11 hours of continuous use in our testing. By contrast, most of the major competitors we’ve tested have averaged somewhere between 4-6 hours on a charge. It’s a shame that their case is enormous—you’ll likely need to keep it in a jacket pocket, bag, or purse on the road—and the fact that the case charges over Lightning instead of USB-C might be an annoyance. At $250, they aren’t cheap, either. Still, the Powerbeats Pro live up to the promise of being genuinely wire-free better than most of their peers.</p>
<p>If your loved one likes the true wireless idea but doesn’t want to give up active noise cancellation, however, we can also give <a href="https://amzn.to/3416Cns" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple’s AirPods Pro</a> our blessing. We’re wrapping up an in-depth review of these earphones now, but the short version is that they’re an improvement over the standard AirPods in both comfort and sound quality—as they should be, considering they cost $100 more—and they offer more effective active noise cancellation than other true wireless earbuds like <a href="https://amzn.to/2CX5u8y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon’s Echo Buds</a> or <a href="https://amzn.to/32Yk0Yf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sony’s WF-1000XM3</a>. (Yes, Sony’s naming conventions are bad.) The “transparency” mode that artificially lets in outside noise works well, and their case can actually fit in most pants pockets.</p>
<p>But you should only consider the AirPods Pro if you must have that blend of ANC and true wireless design. Their battery life, at roughly five hours a charge, isn’t enough to last through a cross-country flight. The touch-sensor-based controls are less intuitive than Beats’ physical buttons, and they don’t offer any way to adjust volume without using your phone or talking to Siri (which few people want to do in public). Many of their customization settings are simply inaccessible if you don’t have an iOS device on you. And that ANC, while good, is still inferior in a vacuum to what you get from full-size headphones like the Sony and Bose models above. All that said, they do a better job of justifying their inevitable popularity than the ordinary AirPods do.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bpb-300x210.jpg"
                                    alt="Beats Powerbeats Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Beats Powerbeats Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_52725240" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_52725240">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $249.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/3407IA4">Amazon $249.95</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds%26irclickid%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26irgwc%3D1%26ref%3D198%26loc%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26acampID%3D614286&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $249.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-Black%2F128591554%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_TGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1305166%26clickid%3DTGh06tQMUxyJWYpwUx0Mo38zUkn1o4RtI2tCQ40&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/3407IA4"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fbeats-by-dr-dre-powerbeats-pro-totally-wireless-earphones-black%2F6341988.p%3FskuId%3D6341988%26ref%3D212%26loc%3D1%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26ds_rl%3D1268709%26ds_rl%3D1268706%26ds_rl%3D1266837%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwo9rtBRAdEiwA_WXcFryjABP_F_4QNXJKfjN7m2ehRGrqJPfJraIh3Gk0FNUE8SnVWIwdCxoCXIQQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds%26irclickid%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26irgwc%3D1%26ref%3D198%26loc%3DzhV3xYQpIxyJWmr0TWXZ0S3wUkn1o4WVI2tCQ40%26acampID%3D614286&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71zny7BTRlL._AC_SL1500_-300x256.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple AirPods Pro product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple AirPods Pro                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_89396217" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_89396217">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93">Amazon $234.98</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $249</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-airpods-pro-white%2F5706659.p%3FskuId%3D5706659&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $249.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2pulZ93"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-airpods-pro-white%2F5706659.p%3FskuId%3D5706659&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>UE Wonderboom 2</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"><img alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The UE Wonderboom 2.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/UE-Wonderboom-2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The UE Wonderboom 2.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>For those times when the music needs to be shared, <a href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UE’s Wonderboom 2</a> is a cute, effective, and supremely portable Bluetooth speaker. It measures 104mm high and 95.3mm wide, with a squat design that looks like a small candle holder, so it shouldn’t be tough to toss into a backpack or carry-on. It’s IP67-rated—meaning it’s dustproof and waterproof—and its rugged design can withstand five-foot drops and float in water. An elastic loop built into the speaker allows it to hang from a carabiner (or towel hook), and its huge volume buttons and playback buttons make it largely straightforward to operate.</p>
<p>This is still a small Bluetooth speaker, so it doesn’t sound <em>amazing</em>, but it plays loud for its size, produces some semblance of bass, and does particularly well at keeping vocals and other mids clear. Don’t expect it to totally avoid distortion at maximum volume, but it sounds cleaner than most sub-$100 speakers. Its nine or so hours of battery life isn’t spectacular, and we’d prefer it charge over USB-C instead of microUSB, but it shouldn’t die out so quickly that it becomes an annoyance.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ue-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="UE Wonderboom 2 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">UE Wonderboom 2                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_55204312" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_55204312">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s">Amazon $79.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $79.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2XqzX8s"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-portable-bluetooth-speaker-deep-space%2F6344800.p%3FskuId%3D6344800&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<div><a name='page-3'></a></div>
<h2>DJI Osmo Mobile 3</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"><img alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='DJI&#039;s Osmo Mobile 3.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/osmomobile3_1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">DJI's Osmo Mobile 3.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>DJI's newest gimbal is a great gift for that person in your life who's forever the photographer of your group, the person who's always first to whip out their smartphone to document events in photos or videos. Much of what has made DJI gimbals great remains in the <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Osmo Mobile 3</a>, but the company made this device more compact and more affordable at $119.</p>
<p>The Osmo Mobile 3 folds into itself with one swift motion, reducing it to a size that can easily be stored in a purse or backpack. Although you must rebalance your smartphone each time before using the device, the stabilization is solid, and the accompanying mobile app gives you a ton of ways to shoot video. We particularly like DJI's object tracking, which smoothly tracks the object you tap on in the frame even while you're moving your smartphone camera. You can even charge your smartphone while using it in the Osmo Mobile 3 via the newly included USB port—and with 15 hours of estimated battery life, the Osmo Mobile 3 will likely have some juice to share even while working hard for you.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dji-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="DJI Osmo Mobile 3 product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">DJI Osmo Mobile 3                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_57198873" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_57198873">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2qLYjx3">Amazon $119</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $139.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDJI-Osmo-Mobile-3-Foldable-Mobile-Gimbal%2F562970196&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2qLYjx3"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fdji-osmo-mobile-3-combo-3-axis-gimbal-stabilizer-for-mobile-phones-gray%2F6362961.p%3FskuId%3D6362961&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18.jpg"><img alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/paperwhite2018_18.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Amazon's Kindle Paperwhite e-reader.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<p>Readers who want to take their libraries with them while they travel will get a lot of use out of <a href="https://amzn.to/2KaQp7u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon's Kindle Paperwhite</a>. The paperback-sized e-reader can hold thousands of e-books, and the newest model also holds Audible audiobooks, allowing you to listen to books with a pair of Bluetooth headphones.</p>
<p>The Paperwhite may not provide the tactile satisfaction that reading a physical book does, but it's at least as comfortable if not more. Not only is it lighter than most hardbacks, but its E-Ink display with multiple front lights makes digital reading easy on the eyes (and as close as you'll get to real paper on an electronic device). At $129, it's a gift that won't break the bank and will keep on giving for years to come. But if that's more than your budget will allow, the new $89 Kindle provides the same reading experience, just with a less pixel-dense display and no Audible integration.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/paperwhite-300x300.jpg"
                                    alt="Amazon Kindle Paperwhite product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Amazon Kindle Paperwhite                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_64407318" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2KaQp7u" target="_blank">
                                $129.99 from Amazon                            </a>
                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Nintendo Switch Lite</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1.jpg"><img alt='The Nintendo Switch Lite.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='The Nintendo Switch Lite.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/switchlite-1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Nintendo Switch Lite.</a> </p></div>
<p>While the original Nintendo Switch was (and still is) a convenient portable console, the new <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch Lite</a> is just a bit better-suited for gaming on the go. It's slightly smaller and lighter than the original Switch, and it can play nearly all of the games that the original console can. We say "nearly" mostly because the lack of TV docking in the Switch Lite will make some games a bit more difficult to play—though it is possible.</p>

<p>But all the major titles like <a href="https://amzn.to/2KjRwBM" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em></a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/2pFiuNi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em></a>, <a href="https://amzn.to/37s2jEb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Luigi's Mansion 3</em></a>, and others for the Switch can be played on the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/09/nintendo-switch-lite-is-the-best-portable-system-nintendo-has-ever-made/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch Lite</a>, and the enhanced portability of the latter lets you bring that gameplay wherever you go. Gameplay isn't hindered by the smaller, 5.5-inch, 1280 x 720p display on the Switch Lite, and the newly added d-pad on the left side is a huge improvement over the small directional buttons that sit in its place on the original Switch.</p>
<p>Most sacrifices made in the Switch Lite do not detrimentally affect portable gameplay. The joycons cannot be removed, nor do they have HD rumble or IR sensors, but those features become less important when you're playing on your own and on the go. The biggest downside is that you can't dock the Switch Lite to a TV for larger-screen gameplay. But if you're wanting primarily to play Nintendo titles while on the road, during your commute, or while generally out and about, the Switch Lite is the better option and costs $100 less than the original Switch.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/switchlite-300x249.jpg"
                                    alt="Nintendo Switch Lite product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Nintendo Switch Lite                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_41955838" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_41955838">
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $199.96</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2CAIPia">Amazon $199.96</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-gray%2F6257135.p%3FskuId%3D6257135&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $199.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Lite-Console-Gray%2F907697007&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2CAIPia"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-gray%2F6257135.p%3FskuId%3D6257135&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>

<h2>Apple iPad Air (3rd gen)</h2>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629.jpeg"><img alt='The front of the 2019 iPad Air.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629-640x427.jpeg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629-1280x855.jpeg 2x" alt='The front of the 2019 iPad Air.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/iPad-Air-front-e1555381547629.jpeg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The front of the 2019 iPad Air.</a> (credit: Samuel Axon)</p></div>An iPad is an iPad. You don’t need us to tell you that it remains an ideal computing device for watching movies, reading e-books, browsing the Web, and getting light work done on the go. But with Apple refreshing much of its tablet lineup over the past year, the question of <em>which</em> iPad is best for most people has gotten murkier.</p>
<p>As it stands now, we’re going with <a href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the iPad Air</a>. At $499, it costs a fair bit more than the <a href="https://amzn.to/2r2c5fk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new 10.2-inch iPad</a>—which starts at $329, though both tablets can often be found discounted online—but that premium gets you a number of meaningful quality of life improvements.</p>
<p>The big one is processing power. While the 10.2-inch iPad comes with the same A10 Fusion chip that was introduced with the iPhone 7 in 2016, the iPad Air runs on an A12 Bionic chip that’s two generations newer and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/mini-review-the-2019-ipad-has-a-new-skin-but-its-mostly-the-same-tablet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performs significantly better in benchmarks</a>. To be clear, the 10.2-inch iPad is still powerful enough to do most of the things you’d expect an iPad to do without immediate issue, and it pairs its processor with the same 3GB of RAM as the iPad Air. But the Air is quicker with games and more intensive tasks, and it’s better equipped to handle iPadOS updates as the years roll along. Since an iPad is designed to last several years, that last bit is what’s most important.</p>
<p>Beyond that, the iPad Air’s display is a noticeable step up. It’s laminated, for one, so it doesn’t have the air gap that makes the 10.2-inch iPad’s screen look recessed behind the glass that covers it. It has an anti-reflective coating that makes it more convenient to use in sunlight, support for Apple’s TrueTone display tech—which automatically adjusts colors onscreen to better suit the lighting of your surroundings—and a wider P3 color gamut. The iPad Air’s display is also marginally larger, at 10.5 inches, despite having a smaller overall footprint. (It’s 6.1mm thin, compared to the 7.5mm chassis of the 10.2-inch iPad.) Both tablets have LCD panels with virtually the same resolution, and again, your loved one will likely be perfectly content with the standard model’s display if they never see the two slates side by side. But a tablet is nothing if not a big display, and the iPad Air’s is just more pleasant to look at.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the iPad Air comes with 64GB of storage by default, double the amount of the entry-level iPad. Its front-facing camera is significantly sharper and supports 1080p video, whereas the 10.2-inch iPad’s selfie cam maxes out at 720p. It’s slightly lighter, at 456g compared to the iPad’s 483g, and it’s no worse with battery life.</p>
<p>If you simply want to save cash, the standard iPad is still a fine tablet, with the same support for <a href="https://amzn.to/2OnVhaK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple’s first-gen Pencil stylus</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/37knaZF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Keyboard attachment</a>. The <a href="https://amzn.to/37eVwxk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPad Mini</a> is basically a smaller iPad Air for the niche that still prefers a 7.9-inch tablet, and if you can find the discontinued 10.5-inch iPad Pro for a decent price from a reputable retailer, it’s a better piece of hardware than any current midrange model. (The <a href="https://amzn.to/330Gh7K" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPad Pro</a>, meanwhile, is still too expensive for most use cases and positioned more as a Windows laptop alternative.) But for most would-be iPad owners, the iPad Air is the best blend of performance, size, and build quality. If nothing else, it’ll be a smoother ride than almost any Android tablet in this price range.</p>
    <div class="ars-component-layout ars-component-buy-box align-wide">
        <div class="ars-logo-box">
            <div class="ars-logo-box-content ars-logo-box-content-buy-box">
                <div class="ars-buy-box">
                    <div class="ars-buy-box-content">
                                                <div class="ars-circle-image ars-circle-image-green ars-circle-image-buy-box">
                            <div class="ars-circle-image-container ars-buy-box-image-container">
                                                                <img 
                                    src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/61z85f1XsgL._AC_SL1500_-300x351.jpg"
                                    alt="Apple iPad Air (3rd gen) product image"
                                    class="ars-circle-image-img ars-buy-box-image"
                                >
                                                            </div>
                        </div>
                                                <h3 class="ars-buy-box-title">Apple iPad Air (3rd gen)                                                </h3>
                        <div class="ars-buy-box-button-container">
                            <a id="bb_button_40184549" class="button button-large button-orange ars-buy-box-button" href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb" target="_blank">
                                Buy Now                            </a>
                                                            <select class="ars-link-select ars-link-select-buy-box" data-target-btn="bb_button_40184549">
                                                                    <option value="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb">Amazon $469</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F10-5-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Silver%2F426123983%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Walmart $499.99</option>
                                                                    <option value="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-ipad-air-latest-model-with-wi-fi-64gb-space-gray%2F5985600.p%3FskuId%3D5985600&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019">Best Buy $499.99</option>
                                                                </select>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://amzn.to/2KvQCCb"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1305166/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F10-5-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Silver%2F426123983%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                <a style="display:none;" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/1305166/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-ipad-air-latest-model-with-wi-fi-64gb-space-gray%2F5985600.p%3FskuId%3D5985600&amp;subid1=TravelGifts2019"></a>
                                                                                    </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="ars-component ars-component-affiliate-disclaimer">
            <div class="ars-affiliate-disclaimer-message">(Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="/affiliate-link-policy/">affiliate programs</a>.)</div>
        </div>
    </div>


<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1600093&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>400-year-old warships in Swedish channel may be sisters of doomed Vasa</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nautical archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipwrecks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwater archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vasa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The pair of warships were sunk to block enemy naval access to Stockholm.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/knees-vrak-1-800x534.png" alt="Photo of shipwreck timbers underwater"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/knees-vrak-1.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1474" data-width="2208">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> These curved timbers, called knees, help support deck beams. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.vrakmuseum.se/">Jim Hansson, Vrak Museum of Wrecks</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Two 17th-century shipwrecks on the bottom of a busy Swedish shipping channel may be the sister ships of the ill-fated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasa_(ship)"><em>Vasa</em></a>. Archaeologists with Sweden's Vrak—Museum of Wrecks discovered the vessels in a 35-meter-deep channel near Stockholm during a recent survey. Neither wreck is as well-preserved as <em>Vasa</em> (to be fair, there are probably ships actually sailing today that aren't as well-preserved as <em>Vasa</em>), but they're in remarkably good shape for several centuries on the bottom.</p>
<p>Studying the wrecks could reveal more details about how early naval engineers revised their designs to avoid another disaster like <em>Vasa</em>.</p>
<h2>Hiding in plain sight</h2>
<p>The wrecks may be the remains of two of the four large warships Sweden's King Gustav II Adolf built in the 1620s and 1630s. The earliest of the four ships, <em>Vasa</em>, had a first trip out of port in 1628 that ended in disaster; the top-heavy vessel caught a gust of wind and leaned over far enough to let water rush in through open gun ports. King Gustav's prized warship sank just a few dozen meters offshore in front of hundreds of spectators, killing half the crew onboard.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the three later ships—<em>Äpplet</em>, <em>Kronan</em>, and <em>Scepter</em>—had longer careers. <em>Äpplet</em> sailed with the Swedish fleet to invade Germany in 1630, and <em>Kronan</em> and <em>Scepter</em> sailed against a combined Danish-Norwegian fleet in the 1644 battle of Kolberger Heide.</p>
<p>In the late 1600s, the Swedish navy scuttled the three aging warships to help control access to a narrow sea channel approaching Stockholm. A complex network of channels and straits weaves among the islands of western Sweden, but only two routes offer access to Stockholm by sea. The channel where the wrecked warships now lie is the larger of those two routes, and it's still in use today.</p>
<p>Ferries and cargo ships now unwittingly pass within a few dozen meters of the 17th-century wrecks. "All heavy traffic to Stockholm passes through this narrow sound, so it's always quite strong currents and heavy noise from the ships," Vrak Museum archaeologist Jim Hansson (who coincidentally shares a surname with <em>Vasa</em>'s captain) told Ars.</p>
<p>And beneath all that modern traffic lie the battered but recognizable remains of two 400-year-old warships, sitting upright on the bottom. "The massive hull is standing right on the seabed," Hansson told Ars, describing the better-preserved of the two wrecks, which has a bow that still juts proudly 5m above the sand. Swimming along the first gun deck, where cannon once thundered, Hansson and his colleagues saw deck beams and curved timbers called knees, which supported the heavy beams where they met the sides of the hull.</p>
<p>Those timbers suggested that the two wrecks might be Gustav II Adolf's retired warships. "We took a lot of measurements to understand what kind of ship it was. We needed to have some measurements from some specific ship timbers to compare with <em>Vasa</em>, just to see if it could be one of her sisters," Hansson told Ars. "The measurements were similar to <em>Vasa</em>'s so that's why we think it might be one of them." Each wreck is about 40m long.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Jim-prepare-for-diving-980x653.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Archaeologist Jim Hansson prepares to dive.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.vrakmuseum.se/">Jim Hansson, Vrak Museum of Wrecks</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>The area has seen almost constant construction since the 1500s to maintain the busy shipping channel and control access to the capital. In the years after the warships were scuttled, harbor defenses took the form of "stone coffins," which are enormous boxes built out of several whole logs and filled with large rocks. One of those coffins landed on the stern of the first wreck, smashing the timbers beneath it. And at some point, dynamite blasting farther out in the channel destroyed the port side of the second wreck—but the starboard side of her hull still looms about 5m high, to the level of the deck beams.</p>
<p>There has never been a sonar survey of the area, so archaeologists had no idea what was down there—and knowing how many blockades had been built, dynamited out of the way, and rebuilt over the years, Hansson and his colleagues weren't too optimistic about the survey. "We wanted to see if there were wrecks there, but we had no hope to find any well-preserved [because] there has been a lot of constructions built and blown away by the navy during 500 years," he told Ars.</p>
<p>But the divers braved the frigid water and the strong currents anyway. On one dive, the broad curves of a wooden hull suddenly emerged from the gloom before them, stretching much further than the 3m to 4m they could see underwater. The next day, diving further out in the channel, they found a second wreck lying about 5m away from the first, end-to-end across the channel.</p>
<h2>Long-lost sisters?</h2>
<p><em>Äpplet</em> was scuttled in 1659, and at least a few people in Sweden's navy probably watched the ship vanish beneath the waves with a sense of relief. They'd been trying to get rid of her for years.</p>
<p>"We know that the navy tried to sell her three times," Hansson told Ars. "She was a slow sailer and wasn't used often for more than transportation."</p>
<p>He suggests that shipbuilder Hein Jacobsson built <em>Äpplet</em> wider than <em>Vasa</em>, in an attempt to correct the top-heaviness that doomed the earlier ship. But he may have actually built her too wide, making her sluggish and unwieldy in the water.</p>
<p>"We don't know that yet," Hansson told Ars. "That sort of question, we will hopefully answer after more dives and surveys."</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/374280453?color=ff9933" width="980" height="550" frameborder="0"></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Video taken as divers explored the wrecks. </p></div>
<p><em>Kronan</em> and <em>Scepter</em> had more successful careers, but in the end, they also ended up as sunken blockades in the harbor. Historic documents describe <em>Kronan</em>'s hold being filled with iron bars before other warships aimed their cannons at her waterline to scuttle her. "The ships had sailed and survived several battles, and after 30-40 years in duty, there was no meaning to repair them anymore," Hansson told Ars. "It's a kind of old [form of] recycling."</p>
<p>At the moment, Hansson and his colleagues don't know which two of the three ships they're dealing with—assuming that the wrecks really are <em>Vasa</em>'s sisters. The divers collected wood samples from both wrecks and will radiocarbon date them to confirm when the ships were built. All three of <em>Vasa</em>'s sisters hail from the early 1630s, so if the dates match up, that will be a strong hint.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the archaeologists plan to continue diving on the wrecks, measuring timbers and documenting details of how the ships are put together. Wooden sailing ships were the high-tech military vehicles of their day, and <em>Vasa</em> and her sisters were among the earliest to carry large numbers of heavy cannon. "We didn't have time to do a proper survey but will come back," Hansson told Ars. "It's quite hard to get a grip of such a big wreck in such a short time."</p>
<p>Nearby Djurgården Island is the site of the museum where <em>Vasa</em> now resides in a carefully prepared facility. Her presence is a reminder of what a large, complex, and very expensive undertaking raising these two wrecks could be—so far there are no similar plans for these ships. It's also not clear what sorts of artifacts might turn up; most things of value and most personal effects would have been removed before the scuttling. But the wrecks may help fill in some details about exactly why Vasa sank and how shipbuilders modified their designs in response to the disaster.</p>
<p>"We hope to learn how the construction developed and to see actually why <em>Vasa</em> sank," Hansson told Ars. "This is a tremendous opportunity for us and the <em>Vasa</em> museum. It's not very common we find wrecks with this potential and long, exciting history!"</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604285&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Official Monero website is hacked to deliver currency-stealing malware</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 02:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website hack]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GetMonero.org delivers Linux and Windows binaries that steal users' funds.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/hacked-640x438.jpg" alt="Image of ones and zeros with the word "Hacked" superimposed."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">(credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://pixabay.com/p-823336/">Pixabay</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The official site for the Monero digital coin was hacked to deliver currency-stealing malware to users who were downloading wallet software, officials with GetMonero.org said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The supply-chain attack came to light on Monday when a site user reported that the <a href="https://github.com/monero-project/monero/issues/6151">cryptographic hash for a command-line interface wallet downloaded from the site didn't match the hash listed on the page</a>. Over the next several hours, users discovered that the miss-matching hash wasn't the result of an error. Instead, it was an attack designed to infect GetMonero users with malware. Site officials later confirmed that finding.</p>
<p>"It's strongly recommended to anyone who downloaded the CLI wallet from this website between Monday 18th 2:30 AM UTC and 4:30 PM UTC, to check the hashes of their binaries," GetMonero officials <a href="https://web.getmonero.org/2019/11/19/warning-compromised-binaries.html">wrote</a>. "If they don't match the official ones, delete the files and download them again. <strong>Do not run the compromised binaries for any reason.</strong>"</p>
<p>An <a href="https://bartblaze.blogspot.com/2019/11/monero-project-compromised.html">analysis of the malicious Linux binary</a> found that it added a few new functions to the legitimate one. One of the functions was called after a user opened or created a new wallet. It sent the wallet seed—which is the cryptographic secret used to access wallet funds—to a server located at node.hashmonero[.]com. The malware then sent wallet funds to the servers located at node.xmrsupport[.]co and 45.9.148[.]65.</p>
<p>A malicious Windows version of the CLI wallet carried out an almost identical attack sequence.</p>
<p>At least one person participating in a Reddit forum claimed to have <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/moneromanz/">lost digital coins after installing the malicious Linux binary</a>.</p>
<p>"Roughly 9 hours after I ran the binary a single transaction drained my wallet of all $7000," the person wrote. "I downloaded the build yesterday around 6pm Pacific time."</p>
<p>The user said at the time that it wasn't clear if the malware carried out other nefarious actions on the computer itself. The person made a copy of the malware <a href="https://anonfile.com/bbq8h9Bdn7/monero-wallet-cli">available for download</a> so that researchers can analyze the code. Under no circumstances should people run this binary on anything other than a test machine that has no access to cryptocurrency wallets.</p>
<p>GetMonero's advisory didn't say the site was compromised or if the vulnerabilities that led to the hack had been fixed. Users should stay apprised of this breach in the coming days.</p>
<p>In the meantime, people who want to verify the authenticity of their Monero CLI software can <a href="https://getmonero.org/resources/user-guides/verification-windows-beginner.html">check here for Windows</a> or <a href="https://getmonero.org/resources/user-guides/verification-allos-advanced.html">here</a> for more advanced users of Windows, Linux, or macOS.</p>
<p>The incident is a graphic reminder of why it's crucial to check summaries before installing software. The links in the paragraph above this one explain how to do that.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604573&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google outlines plans for mainline Linux kernel support in Android</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Amadeo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google wants less forking, more modularization for Android's Linux kernel. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Solving_issues_associated_with_modules_and_supplie-980x513.png" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          Google's eventual plan for Android, one kernel for every device, instead of the device-specific kernels that exist now.                       [credit:
                        <a href="https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/sessions/67/#20190910.detailed">Saravana Kannan</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>It seems like Google is working hard to update and upstream the Linux kernel that sits at the heart of every Android phone. The company was a big participant in this year's <a href="https://www.linuxplumbersconf.org/">Linux Plumbers Conference</a>, a yearly meeting of the top Linux developers, and Google <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f2C-gA8jEyY">spent a lot of time</a> talking about getting Android to work with a generic Linux kernel instead of the highly customized version it uses now. It even showed an Android phone running a mainline Linux kernel.</p>
<p>But first, some background on Android's current kernel mess.Currently, three major forks happen in between the "mainline" Linux kernel and a shipping Android device (note that "mainline" here has no relation to Google's own "<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/09/android-10-the-ars-technica-review/#h8">Project Mainline</a>"). First, Google takes the LTS (Long Term Support) Linux kernel and turns it into the "Android Common kernel"—the Linux kernel with all the Android OS-specific patches applied. Android Common is shipped to the SoC vendor (usually Qualcomm) where it gets its first round of hardware-specific additions, first focusing on a particular model of SoC. This "SoC Kernel" then gets sent to a device manufacturer for even more hardware-specific code that supports every other piece of hardware, like the display, camera, speakers, usb ports, and any extra hardware. This is the "Device Kernel," and it's what actually ships on a device.</p>
<p>This is an extremely long journey that results in every device shipping millions of lines of out-of-tree kernel code. Every shipping device kernel is different and device specific—basically no device kernel from one phone will work on another phone. The mainline kernel version for a device is locked in at the beginning of an SoC's initial development, so it's typical for a brand-new device to ship with a Linux kernel that is two years old. Even Google's latest <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/google-pixel-4-review-overpriced-uncompetitive-and-out-of-touch/">and, uh, greatest device</a>, the Pixel 4, shipped in October 2019 with Linux kernel 4.14, an LTS release from November 2017. It will be stuck on kernel 4.14 forever, too. Android devices usually do not get kernel updates, probably thanks to the incredible amount of work needed to produce just a single device kernel and the chain of companies that would need to cooperate to do it. Thanks to kernel updates never happening, this means every new release of Android usually has to support the last three years of LTS kernel releases (the minimum for Android 10 is 4.9, a 2016 release). Google's commitments to support older versions of Android with security patches means the company is still supporting kernel 3.18, which is five years old now. Google's band-aid solution for this so far has been to team up with the Linux community and support mainline Linux LTS releases for longer, and they're now up to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/android-users-rejoice-linux-kernel-lts-releases-are-now-good-for-6-years/">six years of support</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, at Linux Plumbers Conference 2018, <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/771974/">Google announced</a> its initial investigation into bringing the Android kernel closer to mainline Linux. This year it shared a bit more detail on its progress so far, but it's definitely still a work in progress. "Today, we don't know what it takes to be added to the kernel to run on a [specific] Android device," Android Kernel Team lead Sandeep Patil told the group at LPC 2019. "We know what it takes to run <em>Android</em> but not necessarily on any given hardware. So our goal is to basically find all of that out, then upstream it and try to be as close to mainline as possible."</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='Google says that &quot;compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018).&quot; Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kernel_lts_diff.png" alt='Google says that &quot;compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018).&quot; Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Google says that "compared to [Linux] LTS (4.14.0), the Android common kernel has 355 changes, 32,266 insertions, and 1,546 deletions (as of February 2018)." Progress is being made here every year, but keep in mind there are still two more forks after this. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://source.android.com/devices/architecture/kernel/android-common">Google </a>)</p></div>
<p>While there is still work to be done for getting the wider Android ecosystem and myriad device configurations on board, for specific models of device, things seem to be progressing well. Tom Gall, the director of the Linaro Consumer Group, showed off a Xiaomi Poco F1 <em>actually running</em> the mainline Linux kernel under the usual Android OS. Gall told the audience, "There are major, major props to be given to the Google Kernel Team in particular for getting their code upstream so that we can boot devices with a mainline kernel."</p>
<p>Along with the plan to upstream as much kernel code as possible, Google is also aiming to replicate its earlier work at modularizing Android, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/android-8-0-oreo-thoroughly-reviewed/#h1">Project Treble</a>. Just as Treble created a stable interface between the Android OS and the device HALs (Hardware Abstraction Layers), Google's proposal for bringing Android closer to mainline Linux (How is there not a silly "project" name for this yet?) involves stabilizing Linux's in-kernel ABI and having a stable interface for the Linux kernel and hardware vendors to write to. Google wants to decouple the Linux kernel from its hardware support.</p>
<p>The Linux community <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/process/stable-api-nonsense.rst">has been against</a> the idea of a stable interface for some time, with the suggestion that if you want the ability to quickly update a kernel, open source your drivers and get them in the main kernel tree, where any changes will be taken care of for you. Open sourcing drivers is an absolute deal breaker for many hardware companies, though, and no amount of advocacy or product degradation is going to change that. The fact that Google is stuck supporting five-year-old versions of Linux shows this model isn't working.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome.png"><img alt='Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome-980x537.png" alt='Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ABI_Monitoring.pdf_-_Google_Chrome.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Instead of a bunch of forks, Google imagines the new kernel as a series of modules.</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/sessions/67/#20190910.detailed">Matthias Männich</a>)</p></div>
<p>Matthias Männich, a senior software engineer at Google, displayed a diagram labeled "Android Next Generation" that showed what this proposed kernel architecture would look like. Google would ship a "Generic Kernel Image (GKI)" along with several "GKI Modules" that would expose this stable API/ABI in the kernel. The hardware-specific drivers (probably closed source drivers) would be loaded as kernel modules. So instead of forks on top of forks, everything gets modularized into additive packages.</p>
<p>For now, Google is only proposing that the in-kernel ABI be stable for a single LTS version. So this wouldn't allow devices to upgrade from one version of the Linux kernel to another—it would just allow for a single generalized kernel image to work across multiple devices, instead of the device-specific kernel forks we have today. It would definitely allow for easier security updates, and hopefully it would get new LTS releases to market faster.</p>
<p>We would be premature if we said this is a change that is <em>definitely</em> coming to Android and the Linux kernel. There are still tons of problems to solve (both technically and politically, I would imagine), and some of these talks were more like public brainstorming sessions between the Google presenters and the Linux engineers (many of which were also Googlers!) in the audience. This is the second year in a row Google has showed up to LPC and pitched the idea of using the mainline Linux kernel in Android, though, and with Android being one of the biggest Linux sort-of-distros on Earth, it makes sense for everyone to work together, right?</p>
<p>"We have miles to go, and we know that, but we've come along from where we started," Patil told the crowd. "Last year, I talked it into existence. This time, we actually have problems to discuss."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1603607&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>As DirecTV tanks, AT&#038;T says it will “re-bundle” TV with HBO Max</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 23:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hbo max]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[HBO Max will include non-AT&#38;T shows as AT&#38;T aims to rebuild the bundle. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-john-stankey-att-hbo-max-800x525.jpg" alt="AT&T executive John Stankey speaking in front of a backdrop that says "HBO Max.""/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/getty-john-stankey-att-hbo-max.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="672" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> AT&amp;T executive John Stankey at a presentation for investors at Warner Bros. Studios on October 29, 2019, in Burbank, California. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=presley%20ann&amp;assettype=image&amp;sort=newest">Getty Images | Presley Ann</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>AT&amp;T's traditional TV business is tanking, with the company having lost <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/10/att-loses-another-1-3-million-tv-customers-as-directv-freefall-continues/">nearly 5 million</a> satellite and wireline TV customers since the end of 2016.</p>
<p>But AT&amp;T President John Stankey sees a path forward in recreating the traditional cable-TV bundle on the Internet. AT&amp;T's HBO Max is slated to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/hbo-max-will-bring-up-the-streaming-v">launch in May 2020</a> for $14.99 a month, and AT&amp;T has set an ambitious goal of <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/hbo-max-will-reach-50m-u-s-subscribers-by-2024-att-projects-1202770351/">50 million US subscribers</a> within five years.</p>
<p>A subscriber number like that would make HBO Max far bigger than AT&amp;T's DirecTV satellite division and its U-verse wireline TV service. But ultimately, the service customers get could end up looking pretty similar to DirecTV, U-verse, or cable TV.</p>
<p>"Stankey said the vision for HBO Max is to create a bundle of content that includes movies and shows not owned by WarnerMedia in addition to those it creates and licenses on its own," <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/11/18/20970066/hbo-max-netflix-streaming-cable-bundle-john-stankey-warnermedia-cord-cutting">Vox wrote yesterday</a> in a report titled "HBO Max wants to be the next cable bundle instead of the next Netflix." The report summarizes an interview Stankey gave at Recode's Code Media conference.</p>
<p>HBO Max will "at some point in time" be "a platform that we allow others to bring content into," Stankey said. "I don't think, from my point of view, we're ever going to have a lock or a monopoly on creativity."</p>
<h2>“Re-aggregate and re-bundle”</h2>
<p>Stankey, a 34-year AT&amp;T employee who is president and chief operating officer, is second-in-command to AT&amp;T CEO Randall Stephenson and may be in line to become CEO when Stephenson retires. He is also CEO of WarnerMedia, the AT&amp;T division that includes HBO.</p>
<p>Stankey noted that the proliferation of online video services has caused the traditional cable bundle to "fragment" into multiple platforms. Customers are frustrated about "the fragmentation of the bundle," but AT&amp;T can bring the bundle back together, Stankey said.</p>
<p>"We're basically unbundling to re-bundle," Stankey said. "At some point, there will be platforms that re-aggregate and re-bundle, and we'd like the [HBO Max] platform ultimately to be a place where re-aggregation occurs. And that doesn't just mean our content."</p>
<p>You can see the whole Stankey interview in the video below. The bundling discussion starts at 29:10:</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k-gUi8Oju90?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">AT&amp;T's John Stankey and Recode Senior Media Correspondent Peter Kafka onstage at Code Media 2019 in Los Angeles. </p></div>
<h2>With AT&amp;T, expect price increases</h2>
<p>If AT&amp;T fully recreated the cable bundle and still charged $14.99 a month for all of it, that'd be a good deal. But that isn't likely, as AT&amp;T has already developed a history of raising online streaming prices to amounts far greater than the introductory prices.</p>
<p>DirecTV Now, AT&amp;T's online alternative to DirecTV satellite service, was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/11/atts-35-directv-streaming-will-cost-60-unless-you-sign-up-right-away/">initially pitched in 2016</a> as a $35-per-month plan with more than 100 channels. But AT&amp;T has raised prices multiple times and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/03/att-raises-directv-now-price-again-after-promising-lower-post-merger-bills/">lowered the number of channels</a> by removing ones that aren't part of the AT&amp;T-owned Time Warner Inc.</p>
<p>The service, since renamed "AT&amp;T TV Now," today <a href="https://www.atttvnow.com/">costs</a> $65 a month for 45 channels including HBO. Packages with more than 100 channels cost at least $124 a month, while the "Ultimate" package costs $135 a month for 125 channels.</p>
<p>At $14.99 a month, HBO Max's price would be similar to Netflix's standard and premium offerings that cost $12.99 and $15.99, respectively. HBO Max's price would also be identical to the current price of HBO Now, even though HBO Max would have all the HBO content plus other stuff. But as we noted with the DirecTV Now example, it wouldn't be surprising to see AT&amp;T raise HBO Max prices significantly in the years after it launches.</p>
<h2>AT&amp;T scoffs at net neutrality concerns</h2>
<p>AT&amp;T becoming a bigger player in online video would raise net neutrality concerns, because AT&amp;T could use its control over home and mobile broadband networks to steer customers away from rival online services and toward AT&amp;T's.</p>
<p>In yesterday's Recode interview, Stankey claimed that it would be ridiculous for anyone to worry at all about AT&amp;T or other ISPs acting in anti-competitive ways with online streaming.</p>
<p>"You'd be hard-pressed to point to an instance of anybody's behavior that would suggest that there is any kind of discrimination, favoritism, or anything else going on in how people get to content on the Internet over a broadband connection," Stankey said. "It's a problem that's non-existent. There's absolutely nothing that's occurring."</p>
<p>Stankey would prefer that consumers direct their ire elsewhere. "I'd be far more concerned over the scale of what's occurring in terms of distribution platforms on mobile OSes, in terms and conditions associated with new product development on that and what that does to squash innovation, than anything to do with how traffic over the Internet is being treated today," he said.</p>
<p>But Stankey is wrong that AT&amp;T hasn't shown "favoritism" in its treatment of video services. The Federal Communications Commission in January 2017 accused AT&amp;T and Verizon of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/01/tom-wheeler-accuses-att-and-verizon-of-violating-net-neutrality/">violating net neutrality rules</a> by allowing their own video services (including AT&amp;T's DirecTV) to stream on their mobile networks without counting against customers' data caps, while charging other video providers for the same data cap exemptions.</p>
<p>FCC Chairman Ajit Pai <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/02/fcc-rescinds-claim-that-att-and-verizon-violated-net-neutrality/">rescinded that finding</a> shortly after taking over, but that doesn't change the fact that AT&amp;T gave its own video content favorable treatment under the data caps imposed on its mobile service.</p>
<p>Currently, AT&amp;T imposes data caps ranging from <a href="https://www.att.com/esupport/article.html#!/u-verse-high-speed-internet/KM1010099">150GB</a> to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/07/att-boosts-u-verse-data-cap-to-1tb-keeps-dsl-users-at-150gb/">1TB</a> on most of its home broadband plans, which can make it hard for TV watchers to get rid of cable or satellite and use online streaming exclusively. But AT&amp;T gives customers an <a href="https://www.att.com/esupport/article.html#!/u-verse-high-speed-internet/KM1242860/faq/who-is-eligible-unlimited-home-internet-data-usage">upgrade to unlimited data</a> if they pay an extra $30 a month or subscribe to DirecTV or U-verse TV. That means customers who prefer online streaming to AT&amp;T's own TV services could have to pay $30 a month extra to get enough data or pay $10 for each additional 50GB.</p>
<p>Under these schemes, AT&amp;T hasn't intentionally harmed the streaming performance of Netflix and other third-party services. But AT&amp;T has made it more expensive for customers on AT&amp;T broadband connections to make extensive use of those third-party services. The company has also used the unlimited-data perk to push customers toward AT&amp;T's own TV services.</p>
<p>The old net neutrality rules didn't include a ban on data caps or zero-rating schemes that exempt content from data caps, but the FCC evaluated individual implementations to determine whether they were anti-competitive or anti-consumer. Since the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/12/goodbye-net-neutrality-ajit-pais-fcc-votes-to-allow-blocking-and-throttling/">Trump administration's repeal</a>, the FCC hasn't enforced any net neutrality rules or scrutinized data-cap practices. But Washington state is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/net-neutrality-is-still-the-law-in-washington-state/">enforcing a net neutrality law</a>, and states including <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/10/california-delays-net-neutrality-laws-enforcement-until-after-court-case/">California</a> intend to do so in the future after all appeals are exhausted in a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/10/why-ajit-pais-unhinged-net-neutrality-repeal-was-upheld-by-judges/">lawsuit over the FCC's repeal of net neutrality rules</a>.</p>
<p>Stankey says that AT&amp;T won't abuse its control over broadband networks regardless of whether net neutrality rules are enforced in the future. "There was nothing [in terms of ISPs discriminating]. It's not happened," he said yesterday. "We all want a good broadband connection that people can use to get wherever they want to get."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604445&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ayahuasca alters brain waves to produce waking dream-like state, study finds</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 23:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ayahuasca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain imaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroscience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scientists at Imperial College London took EEG readings of subjects under the influence.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua1-800x535.jpg" alt="A highly stylized drawing of kneeling people waving their hands."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="803" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A sketch drawn by study participant of visuals during their experience. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/">Imperial College London/Chris Timmermann</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>People under the influence of a psychedelic brew known as ayahuasca frequently experience vivid visual and aural hallucinations and also report feeling as if they are in a dream. Now <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-019-51974-4">a new study</a> published in Scientific Reports has shown that the drug alters the user's waking brain-wave patterns to produce a mental state that the researchers describe as "dreaming while awake."</p>
<p>Ayahuasca is a bitter tea made from the Brazilian vine <em>banisteriopsis caapi</em>, colloquially known as the "spirit vine," used in shaman-led spiritual ceremonies among native people in the Amazon basin. Its primary active ingredient is dimethyltryptamine (DMT). That's the secret to ayahuasca's powerful psychedelic effects, which can also produce feelings of elation and fear or a sense of epiphany or psychological breakthrough. Those mind-altering properties come at a price, however. Participants in the ceremonies are often advised to bring a bucket, since nausea and vomiting (and sometimes diarrhea) are common reactions to the tea.</p>
<p>The brain controls perception and communication throughout the body via chemical neurotransmitters. Each neurotransmitter attaches to matching areas on nerve cells known as receptors. LSD, for example, targets the brain's serotonin receptors. Ayahuasca contains a compound (banisterine) that latches onto dopamine receptors in the brain. (That's why banisterine holds potential as a treatment for Parkinson's disease, which destroys dopamine receptors.)</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg"><img alt='A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg 2x" alt='A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua2.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A healer starts a yage ceremony in Colombia. Yage is a mixture of the Ayahuasca hallucinogenic liana and a psychoactive bush.</a> (credit: Eitan Abramovich/AFP/Getty Images)</p></div>
<p>Several prior brain-imaging studies involving humans have shown that psychedelics disrupt normal brain activity and boost the random firing of neurons in the visual cortex. For instance, a <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3277566/">2012 study</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Nutt">David Nutt</a> and colleagues at the Imperial College London's Center for Psychedelic Research (CPR) scanned the brains of 30 subjects (all experienced users of psychedelics) while under the influence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psilocybin">psilocybin</a>—aka magic mushrooms. The lab then compared those scans to scans taken after the subjects ingested a saltwater placebo. The overall brain activity dropped in the so-called "default mode," a collection of highly interconnected neuronal networks that typically fire together when the brain is at rest. Psilocybin disrupted that synchronization, which could cause the dissociative aspects—the oft-reported disintegrating sense of self or ego—of hallucinogenic drugs.</p>

<p>In 2016, Nutt <em>et al</em>. <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2016/04/05/1518377113.abstract">published the results</a> of a second fMRI study, this time with subjects under the influence of LSD, compared with a placebo. Once again, there was less synchronization (overall brain activity) among neurons in the default mode. But the researchers also found that certain disparate regions of the brain that normally didn't communicate with each other did so under the influence of LSD, particularly the visual cortex. This could explain the vividly intricate hallucinations experienced by people tripping on acid. The effect <a href="https://www.nature.com/news/brain-scans-reveal-how-lsd-affects-consciousness-1.19727" rel="nofollow">appears to be separate</a> from that of ego dissolution, however; it's possible to experience one without the other.</p>
<p>Yet <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/srep46421" rel="nofollow">another study</a> the following year in Scientific Reports found a sudden increase in randomness in brain activity in subjects under the influence of psychedelic drugs. This is possible evidence for a heightened state of consciousness commonly associated with psychedelics. And earlier this year, a team of Swiss researchers used MRI imaging to follow the brain under the influence of acid. The results <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/116/7/2743">support the idea</a> that hallucinogens cause the breakdown of the system that helps the brain keep track of which information is coming from the real world and which is generated by the brain itself.</p>
<p>As Ars' John Timmer <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/02/watching-brains-on-acid-using-an-mri/">reported in February</a>, "Instead of a general flooding of the cortex, they found that a limited number of specific regions saw increased activity. This suggests the states induced by hallucinogens are distinct from states like anesthesia and sleep, which lead to widespread changes in the cortex."</p>
<p>The current paper is the most recent study out of the Imperial's CPR. The study involved 13 subjects fitted with EEG caps and electrodes to monitor their brain activity while being given an IV infusion of DMT. The team found that the DMT caused a marked drop in alpha waves, a mark of wakefulness, along with a corresponding brief increase in theta brain waves, indicative of a dream state.</p>
      <ul class="gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide">
          <li>
        <div class="gallery-item-content">  
        <div class="gallery-image"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ayahua-placebo-980x808.jpg" alt=""></div>
        <p>
          These are brainwaves measured by EEG under control conditions.                      [credit:
                        <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/">Imperial College London/Chris Timmermann</a>
                        ]
                  </p>
        </div>
      </li>
      </ul>
  

<p>Furthermore, while brain activity has been shown to decrease in subjects under the influence of psilocybin and LSD, the Imperial College researchers found more chaotic brain activity in subjects while under the influence of DMT. That might be why ayahuasca users report more vivid visual effects and a greater sense of immersion than is typically experienced with other psychedelics.</p>
<p>"We saw an emergent rhythm that was present during the most intense part of the experience, suggesting an emerging order amidst the otherwise chaotic patterns of brain activity," <a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/news/193993/ayahuasca-compound-changes-brainwaves-vivid-waking-dream/">said lead author Christopher Timmermann</a>. "From the altered brainwaves and participants' reports, it's clear these people are completely immersed in their experience—it's like daydreaming only far more vivid and immersive, it's like dreaming but with your eyes open."</p>
<p>Future studies could involve extending the time subjects spend on DMT to gather even more brain wave data, or subjecting participants to fMRI imaging while on DMT, as has been done already with psilocybin and LSD.</p>
<p>"It's hard to capture and communicate what it is like for people experiencing DMT, but likening it to dreaming while awake or a near-death experience is useful," said co-author and CPR head Robin Carhart-Harris. "Our sense is that research with DMT may yield important insights into the relationship between brain activity and consciousness, and this small study is a first step along that road."</p>
<p>DOI: Scientific Reports, 2019. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-51974-4">10.1038/s41598-019-51974-4</a> (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604193&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bonkers pricing of “free” flu shots shows what’s wrong with US healthcare</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 22:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aetna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cigna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare costs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influenze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In broken US health system, a flu shot can cost triple what it should.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-111874254-800x533.jpg" alt="A chain pharmacy uses it sign to advertise flu shots."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-111874254.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="2000" data-width="3000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Regardless of the crazy pricing, you should get your flu shot. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/flu-shot-availability-is-advertised-below-cvs-caremark-corp-news-photo/111874254?adppopup=true">Getty | Bloomberg</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The annual flu shots that are free to those with health insurance are not immune from the convoluted and contemptible price-gouging that plague the US healthcare system.</p>
<p>Health insurance companies pay wildly different amounts for the same vaccines depending on how negotiations go with individual medical providers across the country. In some cases, providers have forced insurers to pay upward of three times the price they would pay to other providers, according to <a href="https://khn.org/news/the-startlingly-high-cost-of-the-free-flu-shot/?utm_campaign=KHN%3A%20First%20Edition&amp;utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=79594026&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9j3CgVWTbdvIGCuGfMrRsbldj15PAtJawit8jUwTgslJpMtRcxjew9LY2sLO6SgJt6wGTe3RWUEJSGuhTTcgckztQYMA&amp;_hsmi=79594026">an investigation by Kaiser Health News</a>.</p>
<p>The outlet noted that one Sacramento, California, doctors’ office got an insurer to pay $85 for a flu shot that it offered to uninsured patients for $25.</p>
<p>Though $85 might seem like a trifling amount in the bloated scheme of the US healthcare system, such prices quickly add up as tens of millions of people receive a flu shot each year. And while the Affordable Care Act requires insurers to cover the full costs of all federally recommended vaccines, including the flu vaccine, any extra costs to insurers get passed on to patients through higher insurance premiums, economists told KHN.</p>
<p>Looking further at what insurers paid for flu vaccines, KHN found that costs spanned the whole range from $25 to $85. A doctor in Long Beach, California, got insurer Cigna to pay $47.53 for a shot, while a CVS in downtown Washington, DC, got $32 from Cigna for the same shot. A CVS just 10 miles away in Maryland got $40.</p>
<p>My insurance did a little bit better than those. My doctor’s office in the District of Columbia initially charged my insurer, Aetna, $35 for my flu shot, and Aetna paid them the negotiated rate of $24.50.</p>
<p>But that’s still significantly above federally negotiated rates. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/programs/vfc/awardees/vaccine-management/price-list/index.html">negotiated a price just under $14</a> for the same shot. The agency reported a private-sector cost of around $18. Likewise, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Medicare-Fee-for-Service-Part-B-Drugs/McrPartBDrugAvgSalesPrice/VaccinesPricing">the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services pays out $18</a> for the vaccine.</p>
<p>Aetna paid around 35% more than that for my identical shot—and there was no way for me to know that before I got the shot. Hidden negotiated rates make it impossible for patients to shop around. And this isn’t just a problem for flu shots. Wild price variances occur for everything from diagnostic scans to surgeries.</p>
<p>“We don’t have a functioning health care market because of all this lack of transparency and opportunities for price discrimination,” Glenn Melnick, a health economist at the University of Southern California, told KHN. “Prices are inconsistent and confusing for consumers,” he added. “The system is not working to provide efficient care, and the flu shot is one example of how these problems persist.”</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604409&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Password data for ~2.2 million users of currency and gaming sites dumped online</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal information]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researcher confirms data belongs to users of Gatehub and EpicBot services.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dumping-800x600.jpg" alt="A dump truck is on the verge of emptying its contents."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/dumping.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="768" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/blmalaska/33923188986">Bureau of Land Management Alaska Follow</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Password data and other personal information belonging to as many as 2.2 million users of two websites—one a cryptocurrency wallet service and the other a gaming bot provider—have been posted online, according to Troy Hunt, the security researcher behind the Have I Been Pwned breach notification service.</p>
<p>One haul includes personal information for as many as 1.4 million accounts from the <a href="https://gatehub.net/">GateHub cryptocurrency wallet service</a>. The other contains data for about 800,000 accounts on <a href="https://epicbot.com/">RuneScape bot provider EpicBot</a>. The databases include registered email addresses and passwords that were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_hash_function">cryptographically hashed</a> with bcrypt, a function that's among the hardest to crack.</p>
<p>The person posting the 3.72GB Gatehub database said it also includes two-factor authentication keys, mnemonic phrases, and wallet hashes, although GateHub officials said an investigation suggested wallet hashes were not accessed. The EpicBot database, meanwhile, purportedly included usernames and IP addresses. Hunt said he selected a representative sample of accounts from both databases to verify the authenticity of the data. All of the email addresses he checked were registered to accounts of the two sites.</p>
<p>Another indication that the data in the file belongs to GateHub account holders: <a href="https://twitter.com/aashishkoirala/status/1195001331657957377">this Twitter post</a>. It came from Aashish Koirala, a self-described software developer who said he recently received a notification from the identity protection arm of consumer credit reporting service Experian. The advisory, Koirala said, notified him that "my credentials for @GateHub were found compromised on the Dark Web."</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/troyhunt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@troyhunt</a> Just got word from Experian's IDNotify that my credentials for <a href="https://twitter.com/GateHub?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GateHub</a> were found compromised on the dark web. FYI in case you were getting any news about a GateHub breach or hack.</p>
<p>— Aashish Koirala (@aashishkoirala) <a href="https://twitter.com/aashishkoirala/status/1195001331657957377?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p>While there were 2.2 million unique addresses in the two dumps, it's possible that corresponding password hashes or other data isn't included with each one.</p>
<h2>Unauthorized access</h2>
<p>The Gatehub account data, which was posted to a widely visited hacker site in late August, came three months after the cryptocurrency service <a href="https://gatehub.net/blog/gatehub-investigation-final-statement/">reported that it had been hacked</a>. The attackers, GateHub said, had stolen—or at least tried to steal—a wealth of sensitive information for more than 18,000 user accounts. The wording of the post left unclear exactly what data beyond access tokens was successfully obtained.</p>
<p>GateHub officials wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>As previously suggested in our investigation update, we believe the perpetrator gained unauthorized access to a database holding valid access tokens of our customers. Using these tokens the perpetrator accessed 18,473 encrypted customer accounts, a very small fraction of our total user base. On affected accounts, the following data was being targeted: email addresses, hashed passwords, hashed recovery keys, encrypted XRP ledger wallets secret keys (non-deleted wallets only), first names (if provided), last names (if provided).</p></blockquote>
<p>GateHub's disclosure went on to say that site officials notified users whose accounts were accessed and generated new encryption keys and re-encrypted sensitive information, such as ledger wallet secret keys.</p>
<p>The posting of the database means the breach that the wallet service disclosed in July was much bigger than previously thought. Rather than obtaining only access tokens, the attackers also took 2FA keys, email addresses, password hashes, mnemonic phrases, and possibly wallet hashes. What's more, the breach affected as many as 1.4 million GateHub users, not just the 18,473 mentioned in the disclosure. In an email, an unnamed member of the GateHub security team wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>We are aware of a database posted on RaidForums whose author claims that it belongs to GateHub. The alleged GateHub database is being thoroughly examined by our team, therefore, we are unable to confirm its authenticity at this time. We will make sure to keep you posted of any updates.</p>
<p>From what we have gathered so far, it does not contain wallet hashes. As mentioned before, we are still verifying its authenticity.</p>
<p>One of our initial responses to the cyber attack was to introduce re-encryption to all GateHub accounts. With the new re-encryption, all GateHub accounts were re-encrypted and all of our customers had to change their passwords. This was introduced in July 2019.</p></blockquote>
<p>The statement didn't explain why the investigation has been unable to verify the authenticity of the data 25 days after it was posted and four months after it was first accessed. It was also unclear precisely what officials meant by "re-encrypted."</p>
<p>"There are references to PGP [in the database]," Hunt told me. "There are what appear to be PGP encrypted strings. I'm not sure if that's what they rotated. Are they talking about rotating cryptographic hashes, or are they talking about this section of PGP which is wallet related?"</p>
<h2>Change passwords, mnemonic phrases, etc.</h2>
<p>The EpicBot leak, meanwhile, was posted to the same hacker forum on October 25, the same day as the GateHub dump. Hunt said it contains roughly 800,000 unique email addresses, along with usernames, IP addresses, and bcrypt-hashed passwords. EpicBot officials didn't respond to requests to comment for this post. I couldn't find any mention of a breach on the EpicBot website.</p>
<p>Both sites' use of the bcrypt hashing function, assuming it was implemented correctly, is encouraging. Bcrypt is so compute-intensive that it would require years for even powerful graphic-card equipped clusters to crack all of the passwords. Of course, deploying bcrypt insecurely is easy. Programming errors made by the Ashley Madison cheaters' website, for instance, made it trivial to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/09/once-seen-as-bulletproof-11-million-ashley-madison-passwords-already-cracked/">crack more than 11 million of the 36 million bcrypt hashes</a> leaked in the 2015 hack of the site.</p>
<p>The leaking of other types of personal information for what could be as many as 2.2 million accounts is less admirable, especially since there's little evidence all affected users were notified in a timely fashion. EpicBot users should change their passwords as soon as possible. For GateHub users, a password reset isn't required given the mandatory change done in July. But mnemonic phrases should be replaced, assuming they weren't already.</p>
<p>To ward off the growing threat of credential stuffing attacks, users of both sites should also change passwords for any other sites that used the compromised credentials. Users should also be on the alert for spear phishing and other forms of attack that make use of their personal information.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1604305&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>